<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Stability of the 3-form field during inflation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2012-07-17">17 Jul 2012</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Antonio</forename>
								<surname>De Felice</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Khamphee</forename>
								<surname>Karwan</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Pitayuth</forename>
								<surname>Wongjun</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">ThEP&apos;s CRL</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">NEP</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">The Institute for Fundamental Study</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center of Excellence in Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naresuan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>65000, 10400</postCode>
									<settlement>Phitsanulok, Bangkok</settlement>
									<country>Thailand, Thailand, Thailand</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Stability of the 3-form field during inflation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2012-07-17">17 Jul 2012</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>(Dated: )</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We consider the minimally coupled 3-form field which has been considered as a candidate to realize inflation. We have studied the conditions to avoid ghosts and Laplacian instabilities and found that some classes of potentials, e.g. the Mexican-hat one, will in general be unstable. We then propose other classes of potentials which are instead free from any instability, drive a long-enough slow-roll regime followed by an oscillatory epoch, and as a consequence, can provide successful inflation. Finally, we also provide stable potentials which lead to a small enough propagation speed for the scalar perturbations, giving a possibility for these models to produce non-Gaussianities.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>II. THE MODEL AND THE BACKGROUND EQUATIONS OF MOTION</head>

				<p>Let us start with the following action</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = ˆ d 4 x √ −g M 2 Pl 2 R − 1 48 F αβγδ F αβγδ − V (A αβγ A αβγ ) , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where A αβγ is a 3-form, and F = dA is its Maxwell tensor [24], whose components can be written as F µνρσ = ∇ µ A νρσ − ∇ σ A µνρ + ∇ ρ A σµν − ∇ ν A ρσµ . (2)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>A. The background</head>

				<p>In this subsection, we review the background equations for three-form field. All these equations and quantities were first derived in [22]. Let us now consider a flat Friedmann-Lemaître-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) manifold whose metric element can be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = −dt 2 + a(t) 2 dx 2 , (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and, on this background, considering Eq. (A1) in Appendix, the background 3-form A αβγ can be written as A 0ij = 0 , A ijk = a 3 ǫ ijk X , (4) where ǫ ijk is the three-dimensional Levi-Civita symbol (with ǫ 123 = 1). Let us define the following quantities V = V (y) , V ,y ≡ dV (y) dy , V ,yy ≡ d 2 V (y) dy 2 , where y ≡ A αβγ A αβγ . (5)</p>

				<p>On a FLRW background, we have y = 6X 2 . As a consequence of these definitions, on FLRW, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V (−X) = V (X) , (6) V ,y = dX dy V ,X = V ,X 12X , (7) ˙ V = 12X ˙ XV ,y (8) V ,yy = 1 12X d dX V ,X 12X = XV ,XX − V ,X 144X 3 , (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that we will restrict the form of the potential V to even functions of X. In this case the Friedmann equation can be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E 1 ≡ 3M 2 Pl H 2 − ρ X = 0 , (10) where ρ X = 1 2 ˙ X 2 + V + 9 2 H 2 X 2 + 3HX ˙ X = 1 2 Y 2 + V , (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is the effective energy density of the 3-form, and we have defined Y ≡ ˙</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X + 3HX. The second Einstein equation reads as follows E 2 ≡ M 2 Pl (2 ˙ H + 3H 2 ) + p X = 0 , (12) where p X is the 3-form effective pressure defined as p X = − 1 2 ˙ X 2 + V + 3HX ˙ X + 9 2 H 2 X 2 − 12V ,y X 2 = 2V ,y y − ρ X . (13) The equation of motion for the field gives E X ≡ ¨ X + 3H ˙ X + 3X ˙ H + 12V ,y X = ˙ Y + 12X V ,y = 0 . (14) The equations of motion are not all independent, due to Bianchi identities: indeed we have ˙ E 1 + 3H(E 1 − E 2 ) + Y E X = 0 . (15) One consequence of the equations of motion is M 2 Pl ˙ H = −V ,y y , (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that the universe will be super-accelerating when V ,y &lt; 0.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. LINEAR PERTURBATION THEORY A. Scalar modes</head>

				<p>Let us consider now the metric for the scalar perturbations in the following form [30]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = −(1 + 2α)dt 2 + 2∂ i ψ dt dx i + a 2 (1 + 2Φ)dx 2 , (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we picked a spatial gauge so that the three-dimensional metric is diagonal. As for the 3-form, by using once more Eq. (A1) given in Appendix, we can use a time gauge to fix the scalar perturbations 1 as [27] A 0ij = aǫ ijk ∂ k β(t, x) , A ijk = a 3 ǫ ijk X(t) .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(18)</head>

				<p>By expanding the action at second order in the fields we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S (2) = ˆ dt d 3 x a 3 6V ,y X 2 a 2 (∂ψ) 2 − 2M 2 Pl (Hα − ˙ Φ) ∂ 2 ψ a 2 + 1 2 (∂ 2 β) 2 a 4 + 6V ,y (∂β) 2 a 2 + (Y α + 12V ,y Xψ + 3Y Φ) ∂ 2 β a 2 − 1 2 (6M 2 Pl H 2 − Y 2 )α 2 + 6M 2 Pl H ˙ Φ − 2M 2 Pl ∂ 2 Φ a 2 + 3(Y 2 + 12V ,y X 2 )Φ α − 3M 2 Pl ˙ Φ 2 + M 2 Pl (∂Φ) 2 a 2 + 9 2 Y 2 − 12V ,y X 2 − 144V ,yy X 4 Φ 2 . (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>At a first look, this action has important differences with the general action (for the perturbations) of scalar tensor theories [31]. First of all the presence of the terms (∂ψ) 2 and Φ 2 which, for a second-order general scalar-tensor theory, vanish after using the equations of motion. Both these terms now vanish only when the 3-form is absent. Furthermore the field β is not dynamical and it can be integrated out in Fourier space (together with α and ψ).</p>

				<p>In order to remove these auxiliary fields it is convenient to work in Fourier space: in this case, we can integrate out the fields α, ψ, and β, by using their own equations of motion.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>In Fourier space, with Φ(t, x) = (2π) −3/2 ´ d 3 k ˜ Φ k e ik·x , with reality conditioñ Φ −k = ˜ Φ * k , the equations of motion for the constraints give 12V ,y X 2 ψ + 2M 2 Pl (Hα − ˙ Φ) − 12V ,y Xβ = 0 , (20) (Y 2 − 6M 2 Pl H 2 )α + 2M 2 Pl Hk 2 ψ a 2 + 6M 2 Pl H ˙ Φ + 2M 2 Pl k 2 Φ a 2 + 3(Y 2 + 12V ,y X 2 )Φ − Y k 2 β a 2 = 0 , (21) and k 2 a 2 β + 12V ,y β − Y α − 12V ,y Xψ − 3Y Φ = 0 , (22) where we omitted the tilde of the Fourier modes for simplicity. This last equation can be solved for β as β = a 2 (Y α + 12V ,y Xψ + 3Y Φ) k 2 + 12V ,y a 2 , (23) so that we also have ψ = M 2 Pl 6V ,y X 2 + 2a 2 M 2 Pl X 2 k 2 ˙ Φ + 3a 2 Y Xk 2 Φ − M 2 Pl H 6V ,y X 2 + a 2 (2M 2 Pl H − XY ) k 2 X 2 α , (24) 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here the field Φ in this gauge corresponds to the combination Φ GI = Φ − Hα 0 /Y − HX(∂ 2 ¯ γ)/Y , where, without fixing any gauge, α 0 is defined, following [27], as A ijk = a 3 ǫ ijk (X(t) + α 0 ), and δg ij = a 2 (2Φδ ij + 2∂ i ∂ j ¯ γ). Then we can see that Φ GI is gauge invariant. In other words, we have completely fixed the gauge freedom by setting α 0 = 0 = ¯ γ. This gauge-invariant field Φ GI is well defined as long as Y = ˙ X + 3HX = 0. In particular, this gauge is well defined in X = 0 = y, as long as its speed does not vanish, that is ˙</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X = 0 at X = 0. and finally α = M 4 Pl Hk 2 + 6 M 2 Pl V ,y a 2 (3 HX 2 + 2 M 2 Pl H − XY ) M 2 Pl H [M 2 Pl k 2 H + 6 V ,y a 2 (3 HX 2 + 2 M 2 Pl H − 2 XY )] ˙ Φ + 6 V y M 2 Pl k 2 X 2 + 18 V ,y a 2 X (6 X 3 V ,y + M 2 Pl HY ) M 2 Pl H [M 2 Pl k 2 H + 6 V ,y a 2 (3 HX 2 + 2 M 2 Pl H − 2 XY )] Φ. (25) By substituting these expressions into the action written in Fourier space, we find S = ˆ dtd 3 k Q(t, k 2 ) ˙ Φ k ˙ Φ −k − c 2 X (t, k 2 ) k 2 a 2 Φ k Φ −k . (26) If Q &gt; 0, we can define a canonical field Ψ as Φ = a 2Q Ψ , (27) whose Lagrangian, in conformal time η, reads S = ˆ dηd 3 k 1 2 Ψ ′ k Ψ ′ −k − 1 2 c 2 X k 2 Ψ k Ψ −k − 1 2 m 2 Ψ Ψ k Ψ −k , (28) where m 2 Ψ is m 2 Ψ = 1 2 a ′′ a − a ′ 2 a 2 − Q ′′ Q + Q ′ 2 Q 2 − 1 4 a ′ a − Q ′ Q 2 , (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and a prime denotes differentiation with respect to conformal time.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="1">No-ghost conditions</head>

				<p>The no-ghost condition is then found to be</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Q &gt; 0 , (30) where Q = 6a 5 M 2 Pl V ,y Y 2 M 2 Pl k 2 H 2 + 6 V ,y a 2 (3 H 2 X 2 + 2 M 2 Pl H 2 − 2 XY H) . (31)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It should be noticed that condition (30) should hold at all times during inflation, whether or not the trajectory is in a slow-roll regime. On using the equations of motion (by replacing M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 Pl H 2 with the Friedmann equation and then 3HX = Y − ˙ X) we find that 3 H 2 X 2 + 2 M 2 Pl H 2 − 2 XY H = 1 3 ˙ X 2 + 2 3 V , (32) so that Q = 6a 5 M 2 Pl V ,y Y 2 M 2 Pl k 2 H 2 + 2 V ,y a 2 ( ˙ X 2 + 2V ) . (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This quantity must be positive for all k&apos;s. For high k, we find the condition V ,y &gt; 0. This condition must be satisfied along the trajectory of motion. In some cases, it may be possible that for some (positive) values of y, V ,y is negative, but such values of y are never reached: in this case the model can still be viable. We note here that the condition V ,y &gt; 0, on using Eq. (16), forbids the dynamics to be super-accelerating. It is worth to note that the condition V ,y &gt; 0 was also found in [27], by demanding the background condition p X + ρ X &gt; 0. However, we argue that for general theories the positivity of the sum of the effective pressure and density does not necessarily imply the no-ghost condition (30) (see also [31]). In other words condition (30) is a condition for the instability of the perturbation modes, and not a condition on the background dynamics.</p>

				<p>For low k&apos;s we find another requirement, that is ˙ X 2 + 2V &gt; 0. Once more, this condition must be satisfied along the trajectory of motion. The bottom line is that the two conditions V ≥ 0, V ,y &gt; 0 are sufficient conditions for not having ghosts. If these conditions are not satisfied for all (positive) y&apos;s, one should check that, at least for the values of y along the trajectory of motion for the model, the above mentioned conditions still hold.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Speed of propagation</head>

				<p>The speed of propagation is found as the large-k limit of c 2 X (t, k 2 ) of Eq. (26). One can show that the speed of propagation, on using the background equations of motion, is given as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 2 X = lim k→∞ c 2 X (t, k 2 ) = 1 + 2V ,yy y V ,y = X V ,XX V ,X . (34)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The speed of propagation found here corresponds to the one found by Koivisto and Nunes [27]. In general, only the simple quadratic potential V ∝ y, implies a propagation with speed of light for all dynamics. Since y ≥ 0, then a sufficient condition to avoid also Laplacian instabilities (besides the ghosts, V ,y &gt; 0) is V ,yy ≥ 0.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B. Vector modes</head>

				<p>Let us define the metric perturbation for the vector modes as δg 0i = a G i , and δg ij = a 2 (C i,j + C j,i ) , (35) where G i,i = 0 = C i,i . We will also choose a gauge for which the 3-form has no vector perturbations (uniform field vector-gauge). This choice completely fixes the gauge degrees of freedom. In this case, one can show that the action for the vector modes becomes</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = ˆ dtd 3 x 6a 5 V ,y X 2 ˙ C i ˙ C i + 12a 4 V ,y X 2 ˙ C i Z i + 1 4 M 2 Pl a (∂ j Z i )(∂ j Z i ) + 6a 3 V ,y X 2 Z i Z i , (36)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we introduced the field Z i = G i − a ˙ C i . By introducing Fourier modes, it is possible to integrate out the field</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z i as Z i (t, k) = − 24a 3 V ,y X 2 ˙ ˜ C i (t, k) M 2 Pl k 2 + 24a 2 V ,y X 2 , (37) so that the action for the vector modes becomes S = ˆ dtd 3 k Q V (t, k 2 ) ˙ ˜ C i (t, k) ˙ ˜ C i (t, −k) , (38)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that it is clear that the vector modes do not propagate.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="1">No-ghost condition</head>

				<p>The no-ghost condition for the vector modes corresponds to Q V &gt; 0, that is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Q V = 6k 2 a 5 M 2 Pl V ,y X 2 M 2 Pl k 2 + 24a 2 V ,y X 2 &gt; 0 , (39) implying V ,y &gt; 0 , (40)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which coincides to one of the conditions already found for the scalar modes.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C. Tensor modes</head>

				<p>The tensor modes are not affected by the presence of the 3-form, as this latter one is minimally coupled to gravity and it does not possess tensor degrees of freedom. To show this more in detail, we choose the tensor perturbations as δg ij = h T ij = h + e + ij + h × e × ij , where both the symmetric tensors e ij are transverse and traceless. We also impose the normalization condition, e ij (k)e ij (−k)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>* = 1, for each polarization, whereas e + ij (k)e × ij (−k) * = 0. Therefore the second order action can be written as S T = λ=+,× ˆ dt d 3 x a 3 M 2 Pl 8 ˙ h 2 λ − 1 a 2 (∂h λ ) 2 , (41)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that no stability condition comes from the tensor sector.</p>

				<p>According to the previous section, one of the no-ghost condition can be written as V ,y &gt; 0, where y = 6X 2 ≥ 0. The existence of ghosts in the model depends on the shape of three form potential, but not on the sign of X (as y ∝ X 2 ).</p>

				<p>In fact, in order to search for the form of potentials, which makes the 3-form field ghost-free and without Laplacian instabilities (c 2 X ≥ 0), we need to study more in detail the evolution of y (or, equivalently, X). It is convenient for qualitative analysis to change variables to dimensionless variables and define some quantities. In the first part of this section we will define some quantities and use some dimensionless variables as found in [27]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. From the Friedmann equation, we have ˙ H = − 1 M 2 Pl V ,y y = − 1 2M 2 Pl V ,X X , (42) so that the 3-form field can play the role of a slow-rolling inflaton if V ,X X/M 2 Pl ≪ H 2 . Substituting the above Eq. (42) into the evolution Eq. (14), we get X + 3H ˙ X + V eff,X = 0 , (43) where V eff,X = dV eff dX = V ,X 1 − 3 2 X 2 M 2 Pl , (44) so that the effective potential is given by V eff (X) = ˆ X dξ V ,ξ 1 − 3 2 ξ 2 M 2 Pl . (45) On using the dimensionless variables x ≡ X M Pl , and w ≡ 3x + x ′ √ 6 , (46)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where a prime denotes a derivative with respect to N = ln a, Eq. (43) can be written in the autonomous form as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x ′ = 3 2 3 w − x , (47) w ′ = 3 2 λ(x) (1 − w 2 ) x w − 2 3 , (48) where we have introduced the function λ ≡ V ,x V . (49)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In these variables the slow roll parameter can be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ǫ ≡ − ˙ H H 2 = 3 2 λ (1 − w 2 ) x . (50)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The accelerating expansion of the universe is acquired by demanding ǫ ≪ 1. From this parameter, one can see that the kinetic term does not necessarily need to be small compared to the potential term, as for the standard picture of the inflaton scalar field. Conversely, it requires that w 2 ≈ 1 when x λ(x) ∼ O(1). In order to have inflation, one needs one more requirement to guarantee that the accelerating expansion is long enough. We introduce a parameter to characterize this behavior as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>η ≡ ǫ ′ ǫ − 2ǫ = (1 + c 2 X ) x ′ x , (51) where the inflationary period requires that |η| ≪ 1. Since c 2 X &gt; 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, |η| will be small if x ′ /x is small, that is x needs to be in a slow-roll regime.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>From Eq. (47), it implies that |η| ≪ 1 will be satisfied if x ≃ 2/3w ≃ ± 2/3, where we have imposed also the first slow-roll condition |ǫ| ≪ 1 when x λ(x) ∼ O(1). We note that, as a consequence of the definition of w, we have Y /(M Pl H) = √ 6 w. Therefore, the Friedmann equation (10) implies 1 = ρ X /(3M 2 Pl H 2 ) = w 2 + V /(3M 2 Pl H 2 ) , (52) so that, if V ≥ 0, then 0 ≤ w 2 ≤ 1.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As we have already said, the field will slow-roll when it reaches the points P ≡ (x, w) = (± 2/3, ±1) in phase-space because these points are (de Sitter) fixed points (unless λ(x) is not finite at these points). There might be other fixed points, M , which correspond to the points where λ vanishes, that is M ≡ (x, w) = (¯ x, 3/2¯ x), where λ(x = ¯ x) = 0. It can be seen from Eq. (44) that the points P and M are the values of X which correspond to the extrema of the effective potential.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>A. Stability of the fixed points</head>

				<p>Let us start by studying the stability of the fixed point P . By choosing x = ± 2/3 + δx, and w = ±1 + δw, we can linearize the equations of motion with respect to the small quantities δx and δw, and we find δx ′ = √ 6 δw − 3δx , (53) δw ′ = 0 , (54) with solutions δw = b 1 = constant, δx = 2/3b 1 + b 2 e −3N , and b 1,2 are (small) initial conditions. From the autonomous system in Eq. (47) and Eq. (48), we find that the eigenvalues for this fixed point are (-3, 0). The fact that one of the eigenvalues is zero, implies that, at linear order, we cannot deduce whether the fixed point is stable or not. In order to check the stability of this fixed point, one needs to study also the second-order solution. For the second order perturbation, it is convenient to parametrize the perturbation variables in such that δx ′ = δw ′ = 0. This corresponds to choosing the perturbation variables along the eigenvector which has zero eigenvalue.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>By using δx ′ = 0, one finds that δx = 2 3 δw. Therefore, by keeping the perturbations up to second order, we find δw ′ = −2 √ 6λ(± 2/3) δw 2 , (55) which can be solved as δw = δw 0 1 + 2 √ 6λ(± 2/3)δw 0 N (56) where δw 0 = δw(N = 0). To ensure the stability of the perturbation, one requires a condition λ(± 2/3)δw 0 &gt; 0. (57) Since we have −1 ≤ w ≤ 1, δw 0 must be negative at fixed point (+ 2/3, +1) and δw 0 must be positive at fixed point (− 2/3, −1). Therefore, the condition above becomes λ(+ 2/3) = V ,x V x=+ √ 2/3 &lt; 0 , (58) λ(− 2/3) = V ,x V x=− √ 2/3 &gt; 0. (59)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For viable three-form model, which xV ,x &gt; 0 and V &gt; 0, these conditions show that, at second order, the fixed point is unstable. This second order perturbation analysis is equivalent to one in [27] and also agrees with the numerical calculation in [32]. We note that there is another method to find the stability of the fixed point which has zero eigenvalue as shown in [33]. The fact that this instability appears at second order means that the instability will in general evolve slowly. This instability will make inflation end eventually. Now we have one more condition for viable inflationary model from three-form field which is the point P must be unstable. This requirement is also compatible with ghost-free condition. Furthermore, one can rule out some potential forms by using these condition. By considering various potentials which have been investigated in [27], one finds that the model with Mexican-hat potential, V = V 0 (x 2 − c 2 ) is plagued by a ghost. In the case c &gt; 2/3, there is a ghost and the point P is stable. For the case c &lt; 2/3, even though the point P is not stable, the field x will evolve to oscillate around x = c at the end of inflation and then a ghost eventually appears when x &lt; c. We note that, for the shift-potential V = V 0 (x 2 − c 2 ) + k where k is positive constant, ghost will appear since slope of the potential is the same. For the case c &lt; 2/3, the field x may not cross x = c if this point is stable fixed point. However, the inflation will occur again since the field slowly move to this fixed point.</p>

				<p>To obtain the suitable potential form for inflation, there must contain the oscillating phase which provides the possibility for reheating period. To avoid a ghost during oscillating phase, the viable potential form must have only one minimum locating at x = 0 which is not stable fixed point. Therefore, we will find the property of this fixed point next. As for the fixed point M = (x, w) = (¯ x, 3/2¯ x), where λ(¯ x) = 0, then by choosing x = ¯ x+δx, and w = 3/2¯ x+δw, we find the linearized equations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δx ′ = √ 6δw − 3δx , (60) δw ′ = − √ 6 8 (2 − 3¯ x 2 ) 2 ¯ Γδx , (61) where ¯ Γ = V ,xx V − V ,x V 2 x=¯ x = V ,xx V x=¯ x . (62) The solution leads to δx = d 1 e −N (3+γ)/2 + d 2 e −N (3−γ)/2 , (63) where γ = 9 − 3 ¯ Γ (3¯ x 2 − 2) 2 . (64)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>An instability will appear if γ &gt; 3, or ¯ Γ &lt; 0. For the fixed point which ¯ x = 0, one found that ¯ Γ &gt; 0 for the positive even potential. Thus this fixed point is always stable. One of the way to get the oscillating phase is that λ(x = 0) must be not finite. Therefore, one requires more condition of the potential form that V must vanish at x = 0, V (x = 0) = 0. This requirement will rule out the potential forms which have been investigated in [27]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>such that V = V 0 e αx 2 , V = V 0 (x 2 + α) and V = V 0 (x 4</trash>

					<figDesc>+ α) where α is a positive constant. Now we can summarize that the viable potential forms which have been investigated in [27] are only V = V 0 x 2 and V = V 0 x 4 . Generally, a power law potential of the form V ∝ y p = x 2p will be suitable potential form for inflationary model from three-form. However, on choosing a power law potential of the form V ∝ y p , we immediately notice that Q ∝ y p−1 , which in general vanishes (for p &gt; 1) or diverges (for p &lt; 1) as y → 0, unless p = 1. Since we will focus on values p ≥ 1, most of the potential will allow the field to cross this value (y = 0), so that Q will vanish in the origin. This property represents a problem, in general, as this means that, at that point, the second order Lagrangian vanishes (as c</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>X remains finite for V ∝ y p ), and the theory becomes strongly coupled, i.e. higher order corrections become dominant. In fact, the metric curvature perturbation, in order that perturbation theory makes sense, needs to be smaller than unity for all dynamics. Therefore, in the limit that Q → 0, the whole action, if c 2 X remains finite, will tend to vanish. It is worthy to recall that at the point V ,y = 0 where Q vanishes, the chosen gauge is in general well defined, unless at that point we have that Y = ˙ X + 3HX = 0, which for X = 0, it implies ˙ X = 0. But X = 0 = ˙ X is not a point which is reached by the dynamics in a finite interval of time, in general.</p>

				<p>In order to avoid this possible strong-coupling issue we propose the following generalized power law potential 2 ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V (x 2 ) = V 0 [ (x 2 ) p + bx 2 ] , (65)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where p is a constant which can be, as for now, positive or negative, whereas b &gt; 0. Note that for the potential form, V = V 0 x 2 , it has been investigated in detail in [28]. We can also modify the Gaussian potential in order to satisfy the conditions as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V (x 2 ) = V 0 [e νx 2 − 1] , (66)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ν is a positive constant parameter. We will investigate the properties of these potential forms in the next</p>

				<p><formula>subsection. 1.0 0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 x Vx Figure 1</formula></p>

				<p>. The potential V (x) ∝ x 2 is shown here. In the figure, the bare potential and the effective potential are represented by a solid and dashed line respectively.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B. Power-law potential</head>

				<p>We now investigate cosmological behavior for the potential</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V (x 2 ) = V 0 [(x 2 ) p + b x 2 ] , (67)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where p is a constant which can be, as for now, positive or negative, whereas b &gt; 0. For this form of the potential, we have that the no-ghost condition V ,x x = 2V 0 [p (x 2 ) p−1 + b] &gt; 0 , (68) is always positive for p ≥ 0, and also finite for p ≥ 1. For this reason, from now on, we will consider only the case p ≥ 1. On the other hand, since</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 2 X = (2p − 1) p (x 2 ) p−1 + b p (x 2 ) p−1 + b , (69) c 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>X will be always positive and finite for p ≥ 1. The bottom line is that for p ≥ 1 the model is free from instabilities for any real value of x, that is for any dynamics. It should be noticed that for the value p = 1, the potential reduces to a quadratic power law potential. On the de Sitter fixed point P , we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 2 X (x = ± 2/3) = (2p − 1) p (2/3) p−1 + b p (2/3) p−1 + b ≥ 1 , (70)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the inequality holds for p ≥ 1, and b &gt; 0. Because of Eq. (67), it can be shown that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V eff,x = 2V 0 1 − 3 2 x 2 p x 2p−1 + b x , (71) and V eff = V 0 x 2p 2(p + 1) [2 + p(2 − 3 x 2 )] + bx 2 1 − 3 4 x 2 , (72)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that the extremum points of this potential occur at x = ± 2/3, and x = 0. We also notice that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ(x) x = 2 [p (x 2 ) p−1 + b] [(x 2 ) p−1 + b] , (73) 66 68 70 72 74 0.4 0.2 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 N x 66 68 70 72 74 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 2.0 2.5 3.0</trash>

					<figDesc>N</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Ε Figure 2</head>

				<p>. The evolution of x and ǫ for the potential V = V0(1 + b) x 2 , and p = 1. We chose initial conditions w(0) = 0.99, and x(0) = 3 2/3 w(0). When the field x start to oscillate around the minimum, the parameter ǫ will start to oscillate around ǫ = 3/2. Thus the inflation will end when ǫ ∼ 1 corresponding to N ∼ 72. which, for p ≥ 1, is positive and finite for all x. Furthermore lim x→0 λ x = 2. For illustration, we consider here the simplest case p = 1 whereas, in the next section, we will describe in more detail the case p = 2 (quartic potential). The potential and effective potential for the p = 2 case are plotted in Figure 1. The field that starts at |x| &gt; 2/3 with |w| ∼ 1 is able to drive long-enough inflation. However, this time, the field rolls down the potential from the points A or B and then oscillates around the minimum of the potential without ghosts (V ,y = V 0 (1 + b)/6 &gt; 0) or Laplacian instabilities (c 2 X = 1). We also use a direct numerical integration to confirm both the slow roll and the oscillatory regimes as shown in Figure 2. From the evolution of ǫ in the right panel, inflation ends at N ∼ 72 corresponding to ǫ ∼ 1.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C. Quartic potential</head>

				<p>We study here a particular case of the power law potential introduced in the previous section, namely</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V = V 0 (x 4 + b x 2 ) , (74)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and we plot it (together with its effective potential) in Figure 3. In this case, we also have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3M 2 Pl H 2 V 0 = x 4 + bx 2 1 − w 2 , (75) so that, by introducing a dimensionless cosmic time t, we can write dx dt = M Pl H V 0 /3 dx dN = x 4 + bx 2 1 − w 2 dx dN . (76)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>In Figure 4</head>

				<p>, we show the evolution for both x, and w. The field slow-rolls until an oscillatory regime starts, making inflation end.</p>

				<p>During the slow-roll regime the propagation speed takes the value c</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 X ≈ 3(4+b) 4+3b , whereas, as the solution starts oscillating, c 2</trash>

					<figDesc>X → 1. This behavior is confirmed in Figure 5.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Finally, we show in Figure 6 that after inflation ends, there is an oscillatory regime which mimics a dust dominated universe as we have H 2 ∝ a −3 ∝ e −3N . This behavior is similar to the standard single-field inflationary models, and this is not surprising, because as x → 0, we find V eff ≈ b x 2 ; so that the equation of motion for the field,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eq. (14), reduces tö x + 3H ˙ x ≈ −bx , for |x| ≪ 1 , (77) 1.00 .5 0.0 0.5 1.0 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 x V x V 0 Figure 3. The potential V = V0(x 4 + bx 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>), with b = 1 (the continuous and black curve), together with the effective potential V eff (represented by the dashed curve).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>60 62 64 66 68 70 72 0.2 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 N x 60 62 64 66 68 70 72 1.0 0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 N w Figure 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The evolution of x and w for the potential V = V0(x 4 + bx 2 ), and b = 1. We chose initial conditions w(0) ≈ 0.9991, and x(0) ≈ 0.8158. which exactly matches the equation of motion for standard inflation in the presence of a quadratic inflaton potential.</p>

				<p>In other words, the dynamics of the 3-form, for x → 0, tends to be more and more identical to the dynamics of a single scalar field oscillating around the minimum of a quadratic potential. After inflation ends, during the oscillatory regime, in Figure 4, we see that x → 0, whereas w oscillates between −1 and 1. Furthermore, we also find that dx/dt → 0 together with x, whereas dw/dt keeps oscillating, remaining finite, as shown in Figure 7</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>D. Gaussian potential</head>

				<p>We now consider the exponential potential</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V = V 0 (e νy/6 − 1) = V 0 (e νx 2 − 1) , (78) 60 62 64 66 68 70 72 1.0 1.2 1.4 1.6 1.8 2.0 N c X 2 Figure 5. The evolution of c 2 X for the potential V = V0(x 4 + bx 2 ), and b = 1. The model does not possess any instability. 60 62 64 66 68 70 72 74 20 15 10 5 0 5 N ln 3 M Pl 2 H 2 V 0 Figure 6. The evolution of 3M 2 Pl H 2 /V0 for the potential V = V0(x 4 + bx 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>), and b = 1 (continuous black curve). This figure shows that after inflation ends (around N ≃ 70), the universe enters a matter dominated epoch, as the curve approaches a dashed line, which represents the line ln(3M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 Pl H 2 /V0) = −3N + constant. This means that after inflation H 2 ∝ e −3N ∝ a −3 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ν is a constant parameter which can be positive or negative. For this form of potential, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V ,x x = 2νV 0 e (νx 2 ) , (79)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that the ghost will not exist if ν is positive. The speed of propagation in this case is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 2 X = 1 + 2νx 2 . (80) This implies that if the ghost does not exist, c 2 X is always positive. Substituting Eq. (78) into Eq. (44), one gets V eff,x = 2νxV 0 e νx 2 1 − 3 2 x 2 , (81) or V eff = − V 0 2ν 3 + 2ν + e νx 2 [(3x 2 − 2)ν − 3] , (82) 0.04 0.02 0.00 0.02 0.04 0.10 0.05 0.00 0.05 0.10 x dx dt 1.0 0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 2 1 0 1 2 w dw dt Figure 7</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The evolution of dx/dt as a function of x, and dw/dt as a function of w for the potential V = V0(x 4 + bx 2 ), and b = 1 during the oscillatory regime. We chose initial conditions so that at t = 1, the values of x and w correspond respectively to x(N = 72) ≈ 0.0644, and w(N = 72) ≈ −0.46 of Figure 4. We stop the integration at t = 100. This figure shows that x spiralizes, whereas w keeps on oscillating during the matter dominated regime.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1.0 0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 x V x V 0 Figure 8. The potential V (x) = V0 (e ν x 2</trash>

					<figDesc>− 1) is represented by a solid line (for ν = 1), whereas the effective potential is represented by a dashed line.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>and we plot it, together with the bare potential, in Figure 8. We also notice that as x → 0, then V eff ≃ V 0 νx 2 , so that we expect an oscillatory regime to take place, ending inflation.</p>

				<p>It is easy to see that the effective potential has the extremum at x = ± 2/3 and x = 0. Similar to the analysis for the previous potentials, the field can drive inflation when we initially put it in the region satisfying the condition ǫ ≪ 1, e.g. |x| 2/3 and |w| ∼ 1. The condition |η| ≪ 1 will be satisfied when the field is frozen nearly x = ± 2/3. Since x = ± 2/3 are not stable fixed points, the field can continuously evolve through x = ± 2/3 and then oscillates about x = 0 eventually. This behavior is also shown by using numerical integration methods as seen in Figure 9. Because of this behavior, the speed of propagation will be approximately equal to c</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>X ≈ 1 + 4ν/3 in the slow-roll regime, whereas c 2 X → 1, as x → 0. In Figure 10, we also show the behavior of the Hubble parameter during the oscillatory regime, confirming that a matter-dominated era takes place during this epoch.</p>

				<p>Finally, we show the trajectory of dx/dt and x, together with dw/dt and w in Figure 11</p>

				<p><formula>. 60 62 64 66 68 70 72 74 0.2 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 N x 60 62 64 66 68 70 72 74 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 2.0 2.5 3.0 N Ε</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 9.</head>

					<figDesc>The evolution for x (left panel) and ǫ (right panel) for the potential V0 (e</figDesc>
					<trash>ν x 2 − 1), and ν = 1. We chose initial conditions w(0) ≈ 0.999, and x(0) ≈ 0.815. 60 65 70 75 15 10 5 0 5 N ln 3 M Pl 2 H 2 V 0 Figure 10. The evolution of 3M 2 Pl H 2 /V0 for the potential V = V0(e νx 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>− 1), and ν = 1 (continuous black curve). This figure shows that after inflation ends (around N ≃ 72), the universe enters a matter dominated epoch, as the curve approaches a dashed line, which represents the line ln(3M</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>Pl H 2 /V0) = −3N + constant. This means that after inflation H 2 ∝ e −3N ∝ a −3 .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>E. General form of potential</head>

				<p>From the investigation of the previous subsections, one can see that the viable 3-form models can be characterized by the shape of their potential. The study of power-law potentials suggests that the viable potential form which is free from ghosts and Laplacian instability should have the local minimum at x = 0. This is because when V ,x changes sign around the minimum point (as V is, by construction, an even function of x, V (x) = V (−x)), x also changes sign such that V ,x /x = 12V ,y is always positive (where y = 6X 2 , and x = X/M Pl ). In this situation, c 2 X &gt; 0 around x = 0 because V ,xx &gt; 0. The speed of propagation is still positive as long as x remains significantly far from the nearest local maximum (if it exists) of the potential along the trajectory of motion. Hence, if the bare potential has no local maxima between x = ±x s , where x s is the initial value of x, the field can evolve between x = ±x s without giving rise to ghosts or Laplacian instabilities. In order to avoid the stable fixed point at x = 0, providing the oscillation phase at this point, our investigation also suggests that the value of the potential should be zero, V (x = 0) = 0. We have introduced a class of potentials which are always free of instabilities by constructions. However, this is</p>

				<p><formula>0.2 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 0.4 0.2 0.0 0.2 0.4 x dx dt 1.0 0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 3 2 1 0 1 2 w dw dt Figure 11</formula></p>

				<p>. Phase space plot for the variables dx/dt and x (left panel), and for dw/dt and w (right panel), during the oscillatory epoch.</p>

				<p><formula>60 62 64 66 68 70 72 74 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 2.0 2.5 3.0 N Ε 60 62 64 66 68 70 72 74 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 N c X 2 Figure 12</formula></p>

				<p>. In the left panel, this plot shows the evolution of slow-roll parameter, ǫ, for potential V = V0 tanh(νx 2 ) with ν = 3/4. In the right panel, this plot shows the evolution of speed of propagation, c 2 X , for potential V = V0 tanh(νx 2 ) with ν = 3/4. not the only possibility. In fact, there might be regions of the potentials which can lead to instabilities, nonetheless those same regions are never reached by the dynamics. This fact, can in principle, enlarge the possible inflationary scenarios for these models, especially when we look for particular predictions on some inflationary observables.</p>

				<p>In other words, one can search for potentials which may give rise to some interesting behavior of inflaton. For example, some models of inflation can provide a possibility to generate non-Gaussianities in CMB data. The non- Gaussianities can be characterized by a parameter f NL which, at least for scalar-tensor theories, can lead to observable signatures, whenever the speed of propagation for the field c 2 X is positive but less than unity. In most of the single-field models studied so far, the smaller c 2 X , the larger f NL [31]. Although a more detailed study is necessary to determine f NL for 3-forms, it is interesting to see whether stable and ghost-free 3-forms can lead to a small speed of propagation c 2 X . For the potential we have investigated so far, such as V = V 0 (x 4 + bx 2 ), if we allow negative sign of the first term, the non-Gaussianities may be generated. Let us consider, as an example, the potential V = V 0 tanh(νx 2 ) where ν is a positive constant parameter.</p>

				<p>For the potential V = V 0 tanh(νx 2 ), the propagation speed takes the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 2 X = 1 − 4ν tanh(νx 2 )x 2 . (83)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>There is a region for the parameters in which the model is not viable (as c 2 X &lt; 0). The condition for excluding this region depends on the values of X and ν. If we demand the model to be viable in the region inside X &lt; M Pl , one can set ν = 0.52. Then we obtain c 2 X (x ≈ 2/3) ≈ 0.534. Smaller values for c 2 X will be obtained by restricting the viable region narrower, nearly the fixed point x = 2/3. For example, we obtain c 2 X ∼ 0.076 during inflation when we set ν = 3/4 as shown in Figure 12. Therefore the speed of propagation, c 2 X , can be small (but positive) during inflation, however, finally, c 2 X ∼ 1 during the oscillating phase, as expected. There are other possible potential forms which can give the speed of propagation less than one such as V = V 0 (x 2 − bx 4 +ǫx 6 ) with small ǫ. However, the results are not significantly different from the form we have investigated here. We note that the suitable form of the potential which provides small enough c 2 X satisfies the condition yV ,yy /V ,y ∼ constant during 2/3 &lt; x &lt; 1.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. GENERAL CONSIDERATIONS AND CONCLUSIONS</head>

				<p>We have proposed a class of potentials which are free of instabilities, can drive inflation, and provide a final stage of matter-dominated-like oscillatory epoch, during which reheating can occur. In order to avoid a ghost and instabilities, these potentials should have a local minimum at x = 0 and have no local maximum along the trajectory of motion. The three-form field x can oscillate around this minimum if the potential vanishes at x = 0, i.e., the fixed point M = (x, w) = (0, 0) is unstable. A simple example for such a potential is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V = V 0 bx 2 + (x 2 ) p , with b &gt; 0, p ≥ 1 . (84)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We have introduced this form for the potential because, for simple power-law monomials, i.e. V ∝ y p , with p &gt; 1, the second order action for the perturbations given in Eq. (26) will vanish at y = 0 since Q ∝ V ,y = 0. This corresponds, in general, to a strong coupling limit for the theory. One can avoid this situation by modifying the power-law potential as in Eq. (84). There is no fixed-point at x = 0 for this form of the potential. Therefore, the field can oscillate around x = 0 to provide the mechanism to end the inflation without reaching Q = 0 at y = 0. More in detail, according to the previous section, the points in region |x| &gt; 2/3 (unstable slow-roll fixed point of the dynamical equations of motion) will be forced to move to the region |x| &lt; 2/3, and the inflationary period will be long enough if the field x starts at |x| = x s &gt; 2/3 with |w| ∼ 1, where w ∝ x ′ + 3x. The bottom line is that, in general, the 3-form field can drive long enough inflation without the ghosts or instabilities if its potential has local minimum at x = 0 and has no local maximum between x = ±x s .</p>

				<p>We also give another working example, the Gaussian potential, here defined as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V = V 0 (e νx 2 − 1) , (85)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which has similar properties to the power-law case discussed above. In fact, a long-enough slow-roll regime is followed by an oscillatory epoch where inflation ends. Even if avoiding ghosts (Q &gt; 0) and Laplacian instabilities (c</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>X &lt; 0) are necessary conditions to be satisfied, they are not, however, sufficient, in general, to have a successful period of inflation. In other words, it is not assured that inflation ends for other classes of potentials which are, on the other end, free from instabilities. If the potential V (y) is such that for y ≥ 0, it satisfies the conditions V ≥ 0, V ,y &gt; 0, and V ,yy ≥ 0, then no instabilities arise, as already said. However, if we also impose that as y → 0, we have V (y) ≃ c y, where c is a positive constant, then for x ≈ 0 (and this point can be reached), V eff ∝ x 2 , so that in general, an oscillatory epoch can take place, ending inflation.</p>

				<p>In the last subsection in section IV, a possibility to find non-Gaussianities from three-form model of inflation is investigated. Our results show that some potential forms can provide the small enough speef of propagation for the scalar modes, c 2 X . However, in order to achieve small values for c 2 X and to keep at the same time a stable evolution, we had to restrict the allowed interval for the field dynamics such that X 2/3M Pl .</p>

				<p>We have investigated the stability of the perturbations for a minimally coupled 3-form, whose action has a standard kinetic term and a generic potential function. We have found the conditions for which the inflationary dynamics can be stable, and gave some classes of potentials which can provide enough inflation without generating ghosts or Laplacian instabilities. We will leave the question to constrain the parameter space for this potentials by using the bounds on the spectral index and tensor-to-scalar ratio to a future research project.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head>

				<p>We thank A. Chatrabhuti and A. Ungkitchanukit for their kind hospitality at Chulalongkorn University, where part of this project was written and terminated. We also thank S. Tsujikawa for interesting discussions. We especially thank referee for useful comments. K.K. is supported by Thailand Research Fund (TRF) through grant RSA5480009.</p>

				<p>Appendix A: The dual theory It is possible to define the 1-form or vector dual to the 3-form as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A αβγ = E αβγδ B δ = √ −gǫ αβγδ B δ , (A1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where E αβγδ is the Levi-Civita antisymmetric tensor on curved backgrounds, which on Minkowski reduces to ǫ αβγδ (with ǫ 0123 = 1 = −ǫ 0123 ). Then we also have E αβγδ = ǫ αβγδ / √ −g. It is easy to show that ∇ µ E αβγδ = 0. In the following we will make use of the following relations ǫ αβγδ ǫ µβγδ = −6δ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α µ , and ǫ αβγδ ǫ µνγδ = −2(δ α µ δ β ν − δ α ν δ β µ ). Therefore we obtain A αβγ A αβγ = ǫ αβγδ ǫ αβγµ B µ B δ = −6B µ B µ . (A2) We also have − 1 48 F αβγδ F αβγδ = − 1 2 F 0123 F 0123 = − 1 2 (ǫ 1230 ∇ 0 B 0 − ǫ 0123 ∇ 3 B 3 + ǫ 3012 ∇ 2 B 2 − ǫ 2301 ∇ 1 B 1 ) = × (ǫ 1230 ∇ 0 B 0 − ǫ 0123 ∇ 1 B 1 + ǫ 3012 ∇ 2 B 2 − ǫ 2301 ∇ 1 B 1 ) = 1 2 (∇ µ B µ ) 2 , (A3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that the action is equivalent to the following one</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = ˆ d 4 x √ −g M 2 Pl 2 R + 1 2 (∇ µ B µ ) 2 − V (B 2 µ ) , (A4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which shows that the 3-form action is classically equivalent to a particular class of vector-tensor theories. Relation (A1) can be inverted to give</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B µ = 1 3! 1 √ −g ǫ µαβγ A αβγ , (A5)</trash>

					<figDesc>therefore, once the tensor A is known we can uniquely find B. At the level of the perturbations we find</figDesc>
					<trash>δB µ = 1 3! ǫ µαβγ √ −g A αβγ 2 g ρσ δg ρσ + δA αβγ , (A6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is valid on any background.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:1202.0896v3 [hep-ph] 17 Jul 2012</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> In general, we can choose a larger class of potentials given as V (y) = V 0 c y + i c i y p i , where c &gt; 0, c i ≥ 0, and p i ≥ 1.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Starobinsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Kazanas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J. Mon. Not. R. Astron. Soc. Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>A. H. Guth</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Komatsu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl. . 192</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Reid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mon. Not. Roy. Astron. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">404</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">60</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Linde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">177</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Linde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">748</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Lyth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Riotto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rept</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Smith</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kamionkowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Cooray</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023504</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Friedman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Cooray</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Melchiorri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">123509</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Salopek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Bond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3936</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Gangui</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Lucchin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Mollerach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">430</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">447</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Verde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Heavens</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kamionkowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mon. Not. Roy. Astron. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">313</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">141</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Komatsu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Spergel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">063002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Ford</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">967</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Yokoyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Soda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kanno</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kimura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Soda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Yokoyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Watanabe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kanno</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Soda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0808</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="005" to="034" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Koivisto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Mota</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page">021</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Golovnev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Mukhanov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Vanchurin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Golovnev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Mukhanov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Vanchurin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page">018</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Himmetoglu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Contaldi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Peloso</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">111301</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Karciauskas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Dimopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Lyth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023509</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Golovnev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Vanchurin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103524</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Himmetoglu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Contaldi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Peloso</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">123530</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Germani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kehagias</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page">028</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Koivisto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Mota</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Pitrou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page">092</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Sotiriou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Faraoni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys. Living Rev. Rel</title>
		<editor>A. De Felice and S. Tsujikawa</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Misner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Thorne</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Wheeler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
			<biblScope unit="page">71</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>San Francisco</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Kobayashi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Yokoyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page">004</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Germani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kehagias</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page">005</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Koivisto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Nunes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103509</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Koivisto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Nunes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">685</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Koivisto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Urban</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>astro. -ph.CO]</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Bardeen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Kodama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sasaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Prog</forename>
				<surname>Theor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Mukhanov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Feldman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Brandenberger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rept. Wands, Rev. Mod. Phys. Phys. Rept</title>
		<editor>B. A. Bassett, S. Tsujikawa and D K. A. Malik and D. Wands</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">475</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1882" to="537" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">De</forename>
				<surname>Felice</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Tsujikawa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jcap</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Gao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Steer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>A. De Felice, S. Tsujikawa, J. Elliston and R. Tavakol, JCAP 1108 A. De Felice, T. Kobayashi and S. Tsujikawa</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">706</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="029" to="083504" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Ngampitipan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wongjun</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JCAP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">036</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Boehmer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Chan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Lazkoz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
