<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Review of χ cJ (1P ) Decays at BESIII and CLEO-c</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-10-28">October 28, 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Ryan</forename>
								<forename type="middle">E</forename>
								<surname>Mitchell</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>47405-7105</postCode>
									<settlement>Bloomington</settlement>
									<region>Indiana</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Review of χ cJ (1P ) Decays at BESIII and CLEO-c</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2013-10-28">October 28, 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The χ cJ (1P ) states consist of a charm and an anticharm quark in a spin-1 (spinaligned ) state and with one unit of orbital angular momentum (P -wave) between them (Fig. 1). The total spin J is thus 0, 1, or 2. Since the χ cJ are found abundantly in ψ(2S) radiative decays, they can be most easily accessed at e + e − colliders where the ψ(2S) can be directly produced. The χ cJ decays covered in this review were collected by either the CLEO detector (starting with 26 million ψ(2S) decays produced at the Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR)) or BESIII (starting with 106 million ψ(2S) decays produced at the Beijing Electron Positron Collider (BEPCII)).</p>

				<p>Decays of the χ cJ can be used as important probes of strong force dynamics. The</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>!c(1 1 S0) J/&quot;(1 3 S1) &quot;#(2 3 S1) &quot;##(1 3 D1) hc(1 1 P1) $c0(1 3 P0) $c1(1 3 P1) $c2(1 3 P2) !c#(2 1 S0) 3.0 3.2 3.4 3.6 3.8 2MD 0 %+ 1 %% 1 +% 0 ++ 1 ++ 2 ++ E1-Dominated Transitions M1-Dominated Transitions MASS [GeV/c 2 ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>J PC Figure 1: The charmonium system. The χ cJ (1P ) decays included in this review were obtained from ψ(2S) radiative decays. Figure 2: The lowest order perturbative QCD diagrams for electromagnetic (left) and strong (right) decays of the χ c0 and χ c2 . mass is large enough that the decays can be treated perturbatively and the lowest order diagrams are quite simple (Fig. 2), consisting of only charm-anticharm quark annihilation into two photons (for the lowest order electromagnetic process) or into two gluons (for the lowest order strong process).</p>

				<p>The lowest order diagram for χ c0,2 → γγ is pure QED, but the process is sensitive to QCD corrections. Since several theoretical uncertainties cancel in the ratio of χ c2 to χ c0 two-photon widths, the ratio R, defined as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R = Γ(χ c2 → γγ) Γ(χ c0 → γγ) , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is particularly important. Section 2 will cover a new BESIII result for R and the two-photon widths of the χ c0 and χ c2 .</p>

				<p>The lowest order perturbative QCD diagrams for strong decays of the χ cJ are shown in Fig. 3. The lowest order perturbative QCD diagrams do a poor job in many cases of predicting the patterns of χ cJ decays. This has led some to consider the possibility that the χ cJ exists partially in a color octet state, where gluons play a role as constituent particles. In this case, the simplest diagram is shown in the lower part of Fig. 3 and calculations have been performed using a Color Octet Model (COM) [1]. Sections 3 and 4 will review recent BESIII results for strong decays of the χ cJ .</p>

				<p>In addition to decay dynamics, exclusive χ cJ decays are also a good source of light quark states, which is useful for both light quark meson and baryon spectroscopy. The rich set of final states available in χ cJ decays allows one to isolate quantum numbers. Section 5 will review a recent analysis from CLEO, where an amplitude analysis was performed on the decays χ c1 → η () π + π − and evidence was found for a light quark state with exotic quantum numbers decaying to η π. While CLEO concluded data-taking in 2008, the BESIII experiment continues to collect additional data in the charmonium region. We thus expect further improvements in our understanding of χ cJ decays in the near future. Figure 3: The lowest order perturbative QCD diagrams for strong decays of the χ cJ .</p>

				<p>The bottom figure assumes the initial χ cJ is in a color octet state.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Electromagnetic Decays</head>

				<p>As mentioned in the introduction, the lowest-order diagrams for χ c0,2 → γγ are purely QED, but the process is sensitive to higher-order QCD effects, such as radiative or relativistic corrections. To lowest order in QED, the ratio of two-photon widths of the χ c0 and χ c2 , R, defined in Eqn. 1, is 4/15 ≈ 0.27. With QCD corrections, the predicted value ranges from 0.09 to 0.36 depending on the model [2, 3]. Thus, precision measurements of R are important for arbitrating between models. BESIII recently published new measurements of χ c0 and χ c2 two-photon widths (and thus R) [4], using the 3-photon process ψ(2S) → γχ c0,2 ; χ c0,2 → γγ. Results are shown in Fig. 4. The energy of the lowest-energy photon (called γ 1 in Fig. 4) was used to tag the χ c0 or χ c2 . The shape of the background, which is dominated by non-ψ(2S) QED processes, was derived from data taken off-resonance at 3650 MeV. The signal shapes were taken from a control sample of ψ(2S) → γχ c0,2 ; χ c0,2 → K + K − .</p>

				<p>ratio of the partial two-photon widths for the helicity-zero and helicity-two amplitudes is predicted to be less than 0.5% [5]. Thus the signal MC for the decay c 0 ! 1 c2 ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>an th ty gr m pe IV th no th w 3: go w pe e þ ge an Q fi Events / 0.005 GeV 0 200 400 600 800 1000 c2 χ ↑ c1 χ ↑ c0 χ ↑ ) (GeV) 1 γ E ( 0.10 0.15 0.20 0.25 0.30 0.35 0.40 χ -4 0 4 1 γ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>FIG. 1 (color online). Upper plot: The fitted E 1 spectrum for the c 0 data sample. The expected positions of E 1 from c0 , c1 , c2 are indicated by arrows. The dashed curve shows the background line shape fixed to the shape in Fig. 2. Lower plot: The number of standard deviations, , of data points from the fitted curves.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>112008-4 f bg ðE 1 Þ ¼ p 0 þ p 1 Â E 1 þ p 2 Â ðE 1 Þ a ; (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where p 0 , p 1 , p 2 and a are parameters which are obtained in a fit to the c ð3770Þ data in Fig. 2. In the nominal fit to the c 0 data, the background shape is fixed to Eq. (2), but its normalization is allowed to float. The shapes of the c0 and c2 resonances used in the fit are extracted from a nearly background-free c 0 ! 1 c0;2 , c0;2 ! K þ K À sample shown in Fig. 3. The purity of the sample is larger than 99.2%. The shapes of the signal peaks in the E 1 spectrum are fixed to the smoothed histograms of the c 0 ! 1 c0;2 , c0;2 ! K þ K À sample, and the yields are allowed to float.</p>

				<p>Bðc 0 ! c2 Þ ¼ ð8:75 AE 0:35Þ Â 10 À2 ;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Àð c2 Þ ¼ ð1:97 AE 0:11Þ MeV; (4) to determine Bð c0;2 ! Þ, À ð c0;2 Þ and R. These are also listed in Table II.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Several sources of systematic uncertainties in the measurement of the branching fractions are considered, including uncertainties on the photon detection and reconstruction; the number of c 0 decays in the data sample ; the kinematic fitting; the fitting procedure and peaking background subtraction. Table III lists a summary of all sources of systematic uncertainties. Most systematic uncertainties are determined from comparisons of special clean, high statistics samples with results from MC simulations. The number of c 0 events, N c 0 , used in this analysis is determined from the number of inclusive hadronic c 0 decays following the procedure described in detail in [14]. The result is N c 0 ¼ ð1:06 AE 0:04Þ Â 10 8 , where the error is systematic. Three photons in the final states include a soft photon 1 from the radiative transition and two energetic photons 2 3 from c0;2 decays. The photon detection efficiency and its uncertainty for low energy photons are studied using three different methods described in Ref. [28]. On average, the efficiency difference between data and MC</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>) (GeV) 1 γ E ( 0.10 0.15 0.20 0.25 0.30 0.35 0.40 Events / 0.005 GeV 0 500 1000 1500 2000 2500</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>FIG. 3. The E 1 spectrum for the radiative photon in the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>samples c 0 ! 1 c0;2 , c0;2 ! K þ K À . TABLE II.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Results of the present measurements. The first error is statistical, the second is systematic, and the third is due to the PDG values used. The common systematic errors have been removed in determining R</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. B 1 Bðc 0 ! c0;2 Þ, B 2 Bð c0;2 ! Þ, and À À ð c0;2 ! Þ. Quantity c0 c2 B 1 Â B 2 Â 10 5 2:17 AE 0:17 AE 0:12 2:81 AE 0:17 AE 0:15 B 2 Â 10 4 2:24</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>AE 0:19 AE 0:12 AE 0:08 3:21 AE 0:18 AE 0:17 AE 0:13 À (keV) 2:33 AE 0:20 AE 0:13 AE</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0:17 0:63 AE 0:04 AE 0:04 AE 0:04 R 0:271 AE 0:029 AE 0:013 AE 0:027 112008-5 Figure 4: Precision measurements of B 1 (ψ(2S) → γχ c0,2 ) × B 2 (χ c0,2 → γγ) from BESIII [4]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The figures show the energy distribution of the photon from the ψ(2S) to χ c0,2 transition and the χ distribution resulting from the fit. The table shows the results, where Γ γγ is the two-photon widths of the χ c0,2 and R is the ratio of the widths. The first errors are statistical, the second systematic, and the third from PDG inputs (for B 1 and the full widths of the χ c0 and χ c2 ).</p>

				<p>The final results are also listed in Fig. 4, where B 1 ≡ B(ψ(2S) → γχ c0,2 ) and B 2 ≡ B(χ c0,2 → γγ). For normalization, B 1 and the full widths of the χ c0 and χ c2 were taken from the PDG [5]. The final result for R, perhaps surprisingly, is consistent with the lowest-order QED calculation.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Strong Decays to Mesons</head>

				<p>The decays of the χ cJ into two vector mesons (J P C = 1 −− ), for example χ cJ → ωω, ωφ, φφ, have a number of interesting features. First, from perturbative QCD, one would expect the branching fractions to be smaller than 10 −3 . Second, the helicity selection rule predicts the decays of the χ c1 to two vector mesons to be suppressed. And finally, the decays χ cJ → φφ, ωω are only singly OZI-suppressed (as are all charmonium decays), while the decays χ cJ → ωφ are doubly OZI-suppressed. This can be seen in the diagrams shown in Fig. 5. BESIII published new results on χ cJ → ωω, φφ, ωφ in 2011 [6] that address these issues. The results are shown in Fig. 6, where the small peaking backgrounds have been estimated from ω or φ sidebands. First, the branching fractions are on the order of 10 −3 , somewhat higher than one would expect from perturbative QCD. Second, there are substantial rates for the χ c1 decays, which appears to contradict expectations from the helicity selection rule. Finally, BESIII made the first observations of the doubly OZI-suppressed χ cJ → ωφ decays, with branching fractions roughly an order of magnitude down from the singly OZI-suppressed decays. The resulting numbers are shown in Fig. 7.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 5:</head>

					<figDesc>Diagrams for single and double OZI-violating decays of the χ cJ to two vector states (ω, φ). The lowest order diagrams for the decays χ cJ → ωφ are double OZI-violating. backgrounds from misidentified charged particles are negligible. The levels of the peaking backgrounds are evaluated from N AB ¼ r A N</figDesc>
					<trash>dt A À r B N dt B , where N dt A ðN dt</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>B Þ is the number of data events falling into box A (B), as indicated in Fig. 1(a), and the normalizing factors r i ¼ N</figDesc>
					<trash>MC sig =N MC i with i ¼ A or B are determined from MC simulation for modes cJ ! K þ K À and 2ðK þ K À Þ, three pions are ass artificial !-pair pea of this !-selection 2ð þ À 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Þ. A sca pair versus the othe and the M þ À 0 di against an ! candida spectrum is shown prominent. The MC in the !! signal reg cJ ! ! þ À 0 a grounds from the c ð without intermediat misidentified charg backgrounds from ! 2ð þ À 0 Þ As in the cJ ! backgrounds from are evaluated by sel boxes A and B, resp peaking background of MC events falling into the sidebands. backgrounds is fixed</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>To study cJ ! K þ K À þ À 0 fin mass closest to the candidate. A scatter that for þ À 0 M þ À 0 distributio shown in Fig. 1(f), þ À 0 signals ar spectra are shown Similar to the case f ing backgrounds fro and K þ K À þ À 0 falling into sideban dicated in the inse backgrounds are no events falling into t the sidebands. The grounds is fixed in t The numbers of o the M VV distributio 2 Events / 5 MeV / c 0 50 100 150 200 250 2 Events / 5 MeV / c 0 20 40 60 80 100 2 Events / 5 MeV / c 0 50 100 150 200 250 3.30 3.35 3.40 3.45 3.50 3.55 3.60 ) 2 ( GeV/c VV M 2 Events / 10 MeV / c 0 5 10 15 20 25 30 35 (a) (b) (c) (d) FIG. 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(color online). Invariant mass of VV for (a) mode in the 2ðK þ K À Þ final state, (b) mode in the þ À 0 K þ K À final state, (c) !! mode in the 2ð þ À 0 Þ final state, and (d) ! mode in the þ À 0 K þ K À final state. The points with error bars are the data; the solid lines are the fit results; and dotted lines represent the signal components. The shaded and open histograms in (a),(b) and (c), respectively, are peaking backgrounds . In (c), the shaded histogram denotes the non-cJ backgrounds . In (d) the long dash line is background normalized by a simultaneous fit to ! sidebands, and the dash-dot line is non-cJ background. PRL 107, 092001 (2011)</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>P H Y S I C A L R E V I E W L E T T E R S Figure 6</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>: Measurements of χ cJ decays to (a,b) φφ, (c) ωω, and (d) ωφ from BESIII [6].</p>

				<p>In (b), one of the φ decays to π + π − π 0 . In all other cases the φ decays to K + K − . Fig. 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(e)]. The peaking backgrounds are normalized</figDesc>
					<trash>ground estimatio from branching K þ K À , ! ! þ caused by MDC charged track [1 tion is evaluated due to the photon each photon [1 c ð3686Þ decays kinematic fit are the given 2 4C va selected from da c ð3686Þ ! 0 and c ð3686Þ ! kinematic-fit unc mode) to 3.7% ( ties of the pe 2ðK þ K À Þ are estimates to the cJ ! K þ K À uncertainties are boxes. The unc estimates are les normalization fa total systematic 2ðK þ K À Þ mode, cJ ! , ! TABLE I.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Summary of the branching fractions (B) for cJ ! , !!, and !. Here N net is the number of signal events, is the detection efficiency. The upper limit is estimated at the 90% C.L.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Mode N net (%) BðÂ10 À4 Þ c0 ! 433 AE 23 22.4 7:8 AE 0:4 AE 0:8 c1 ! 254 AE 17 26.4 4:1 AE 0:3 AE 0:4 c2 ! 630 AE 26 26.1 10:7 AE 0:4 AE 1:1 ! 2ðK þ K À Þ c0 ! 179 AE 16 12.8 9:2 AE 0:7 AE 1:0 c1 ! 112 AE 12 15.3 5:0 AE 0:5 AE 0:6 c2 ! 219 AE 16 14.9 10:7 AE 0:7 AE 1:2 ! K þ K À þ À 0 Combined: c0 ! Á Á Á Á Á Á 8:0 AE 0:3 AE 0:8 c1 ! Á Á Á Á Á Á 4:4 AE 0:3 AE 0:5 c2 ! Á Á Á Á Á Á 10:7 AE 0:3 AE 1:2 c0 ! !! 991 AE 38 13.1 9:5 AE 0:3 AE 1:1 c1 ! !! 597 AE 29 13.2 6:0 AE 0:3 AE 0:7 c2 ! !! 762 AE 31 11.9 8:9 AE 0:3 AE 1:1 ! 2ð þ À 0 Þ c0 ! ! 76 AE 11 14.7 1:2 AE 0:1 AE 0:2 c1 ! ! 15 AE 4 16.2 0:22 AE 0:06 AE 0:02 c2 ! ! &lt;13 15.7 &lt;0:2 ! K þ K À þ À 0 092001-5</trash>

					<head>Figure 7:</head>

					<figDesc>The number of observed events (N net ), the efficiencies (), and the branching fractions (B) for the decay modes listed in the first column. The results are from BESIII [6].</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Strong Decays to Baryons</head>

				<p>The simplest baryon decays of the χ cJ , namely χ c1 → pp and χ c2 → pp, have long presented a theoretical challenge. While the perturbative QCD calculations, assuming the χ cJ is in a color singlet state, predict B(χ c1 → pp) = 0.29 × 10 −5 and B(χ c2 → pp) = 0.84 × 10 −5 , the experimental measurements are an order of magnitude larger. Furthermore, the decay χ c0 → pp (and χ c0 decays to baryon anti-baryon pairs in general) should be suppressed in perturbative QCD by the &quot; helicity selection rule, &quot; which links the final state hadrons to the helicities of the intermediate gluons. But experimentally, substantial χ c0 decay rates have been found. To address the discrepancy between theory and experiment in χ c1 and χ c2 pp decays, a &quot; color octet model &quot; (COM) was devised, which allows the χ cJ to have a color octet component in which there is a valence gluon [1]. This model was able to bring the theoretical pp branching fractions into alignment with experiment, but still underestimated other baryon-antibaryon decays such as ΛΛ. A comparison of COM predictions and experimental measurements from the PDG are shown in Fig. 8. Inspired by these COM predictions, there has recently been a series of analyses from BESIII looking at χ cJ decays to baryon pairs [7, 8]. The new results from BESIII are also listed in Fig. 8. The first BESIII measurements are of χ cJ decays to ΛΛ, Σ 0 Σ 0 , and Σ + Σ − . The signals are shown in Fig. 9 and the χ c1 and χ c2 branching fractions are listed in Fig. 8</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>1 χ c1 Decays (units of 10 −5 ) χ c2 Decays (units of 10 −5 ) Decay Mode COM PDG NEW from BESIII COM PDG NEW from BESIII pp 6.5 7.3 ± 0.4 – 7.8 7.2 ± 0.4 – nn 6.5 – – 7.8 – – ΛΛ 3.9 11.8 ± 1.9 12.2 ± 1.1 ± 1.1 3.5 18.6 ± 2.7 20.8 ± 1.6 ± 2.2 Σ 0 Σ 0 3.3 &lt; 4 3.8 ± 1.0 ± 0.5 5.0 &lt; 8 4.0 ± 1.1 ± 0.4 Σ + Σ − 3.3 &lt; 6 5.4 ± 1.5 ± 0.4 5.0 &lt; 7 4.9 ± 1.9 ± 0.6 Ξ 0 Ξ 0 2.5 &lt; 6 – 3.7 &lt; 11 – Ξ − Ξ + 2.5 8.4 ± 2.3 – 3.7 15.5 ± 3.5 – ∆∆ 3.9 – – 6.3 – – Σ + * (1385)Σ − * (1385) 2.1 – 4.4 ± 2.5 ± 0.6 (&lt; 10) 3.6 – 7.9 ± 4.0 ± 0.9 (&lt; 17) Σ − * (1385)Σ + * (1385) 2.1 – &lt; 5.7 3.6 – &lt; 8.5 Ξ * Ξ * 1.1 – – 2.1 – – Λ(1520)Λ(1520) – – &lt; 8.6 – – 51 ± 13 Figure 8: The Color Octet Model (COM) [1]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>predictions, the Particle Data Group (PDG) [5] values, and new BESIII measurements [7, 8] of branching fractions of χ c1 and χ c2 decays to various di-baryon final states. All branching fractions are in units of 10 −5 .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 9:</head>

					<figDesc>Preliminary measurements of branching fractions of χ cJ decays to ΛΛ,</figDesc>
					<trash>Σ 0 Σ 0 , and Σ + Σ − from BESIII.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The ΛΛ branching fractions are still significantly larger than the COM predictions, while the ΣΣ decays appear to be consistent, although with large statistical errors. Interestingly, the χ c0 branching fractions, which are predicted to be suppressed by the helicity selection rule, are far larger than those of the χ c1,2 . The preliminary results from BESIII for the χ c0 decays are B(χ c0 →</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ΛΛ) = (33.3 ± 2.0 ± 2.6) × 10 −5 , B(χ c0 → 13 ) 2 (GeV/c (1385)) # (w/o - ! + ! &quot; &quot; M 3.25 3.3 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 ) 2 Events / ( 0.005 GeV/c 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 18 20 (a) ) 2 (GeV/c +c.c. - ! &quot; + (1385) # M 3.25 3.3 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 ) 2 Events / ( 0.005 GeV/c 0 5 10 15 20 25 (b) ) 2 (GeV/c +c.c. + ! &quot; - (1385) # M 3.25 3.3 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 ) 2 Events / ( 0.005 GeV/c 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 18 20 22 (c) ) 2 (GeV/c - (1385) # + (1385) # M 3.25 3.3 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 ) 2 Events / ( 0.005 GeV/c 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 (d) ) 2 (GeV/c + (1385) # - (1385) # M 3.25 3.3 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 ) 2 Events / ( 0.005 GeV/c 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 (e) ) 2 (GeV/c (total) - ! + ! &quot; &quot; M 3.25 3.3 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 ) 2 Events / ( 0.005 GeV/c 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140</trash>

					<figDesc>(f) FIG. 3</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. The invariant mass distributions of Λ ¯ Λπ + π − in the following data samples: (a) dataset-1, (b) dataset-2, (c) dataset-3, (d) dataset-4, (e) dataset-5 and (f) total dataset.</p>

				<p>The selections of dataset-j (j = 1, · · · 5) are defined in Sec. V. Points with error bars are data. The solid curves show the sum of the fitted curves, while the dashed lines are the backgrounds. proportion of the χ cJ decays are poorly known and their simulations based on the BESIII</p>

				<figure>
					<head>LundCharm model have large uncertainty, we investigate possible underestimated peaking backgrounds beneath the χ cJ peaks.</head>

					<figDesc>One major source could be from χ cJ → ΛK</figDesc>
					<trash>* + ¯ p → p¯ pπ + π − K 0 s → p¯ p2π + 2π − (c.c.); however, the π + and π − invariant mass distributions of</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 10:</head>

					<figDesc>BESIII measurements of χ cJ yields in decays to ΛΛπ + π − in regions corresponding to (a) no Σ(1385), (b) the Σ(1385)</figDesc>
					<trash>+ , (c) the Σ(1385) − , (d) the Σ(1385) + and Σ(1385) − , (e) the Σ(1385) − and Σ(1385) + , and (f) all regions [7]. Σ 0 Σ 0 ) = (47.8 ± 3.4 ± 3.8) × 10 −5 , and B(χ c0 → Σ + Σ − ) = (45.4 ± 4.2 ± 2.5) × 10 −5 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The second BESIII measurements [7] consist of χ cJ decays to ΛΛπ + π − and all of the intermediate processes that can be produced with the Σ(1385). Of particular interest for comparison with the COM are the χ c1,2 decays to Σ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1385) + Σ(1385) − and Σ(1385) − Σ(1385)</trash>

					<figDesc>+ . The χ cJ peaks for various regions of ΛΛπ + π − sub-masses are shown in Fig. 10. Since the Σ(1385) is fairly wide, and overlaps significantly with ΛΛπ + π − phase space, the various branching fractions (with different combinations of Σ(1385)) were extracted using a matrix of efficiencies and overlaps determined from signal Monte Carlo. The results are listed in Fig. 11. The χ c1 and χ c2 decays are consistent with the COM predictions (within large statistical errors). But again, the TABLE III. Results of the branching ratios (×10 −5 ) for different decay modes. &apos;UL&apos; stands for the upper limit of the branching ratio at the 90% C.L. &apos;S&apos; stands for the statistical significance. The first errors are statistical and the second systematic.</figDesc>
					<trash>χ cJ decay mode χ c0 χ c1 χ c2 B UL S B UL S B UL S Λ ¯ Λπ + π − (w/o Σ(1385)) 28.6±12.6±2.7 &lt;54 2.2 26.2±5.5±3.3 4.8 71.8±14.5±8.2 6.4 Σ(1385) + ¯ Λπ − + c.c. 34.8±13.2±3.4 &lt;55 2.2 &lt;14 0.3 23.6±11.8±2.7 &lt;42 1.7 Σ(1385) − ¯ Λπ + + c.c. 24.6±12.7±2.4 &lt;50 1.6 &lt;14 0.0 37.8±11.8±4.4 &lt;61 2.6 Σ(1385) + ¯ Σ(1385) − 16.4±5.7±1.6 3.1 4.4±2.5±0.6 &lt;10 1.9 7.9±4.0±0.9 &lt;17 2.0 Σ(1385) − ¯ Σ(1385) + 23.5±6.2±2.3 4.3 &lt;5.7 0.9 &lt;8.5 0.0 Λ ¯ Λπ + π − (total) 119.0±6.4±11.4 &gt; 10 31.1±3.4±3.9 &gt; 10 137.0±7.6±15.7 &gt; 10 VIII. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The BESIII collaboration thanks the staff of BEPCII and the computing center for their hard work. This work is supported in part by the Ministry of Science and Technology</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>of China under Contract No. 2009CB825200; National Natural Science Foundation of</head>

				<p>China (NSFC) under Contracts Nos. 10625524, 10821063, 10825524, 10835001, 10935007, 10905091, 11079030, 11125525;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Joint Funds of the National Natural Science Foundation of China under Contracts Nos. 11079008, 11179007; the Chinese Academy of Sciences (CAS) Large-Scale Scientific Facility Program; CAS under Contracts Nos. KJCX2-YW-N29, KJCX2-YW-N45; 100 Talents Program of CAS; Research Fund for the Doctoral Program of Higher Education of China under Contract No. 20093402120022; Istituto Nazionale di Fisica</trash>

					<head>Figure 11:</head>

					<figDesc>BESIII measurements of χ cJ branching fractions to ΛΛπ + π − and various combinations of internal Σ(1385) decays [7]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Branching fractions (B) are in units of 10 −5 and upper limits (UL) are at 90% confidence level. The significance of each channel is given in the S column. χ c0 decays appear to be dominant. Finally, BESIII has also measured the decays χ cJ → Λ(1520)Λ(1520) using the final state K + K − pp. Signal and sideband regions were defined in M (pK + ) and M (pK − ) and a simultaneous fit was performed to these regions, as shown in Fig. 12.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The final results are also listed in Fig. 12. Perhaps surprisingly, the rates for χ c0 and χ c2 decays to Λ(1520)Λ(1520) are as large as those to ΛΛ (which were already larger than the COM predictions).</p>

				<p>As can be seen in Fig 8, the COM is successful (within experimental uncertainties) in describing many χ c1 and χ c2 decays into baryons and anti-baryons. The ΛΛ channel is the notable exception. Since the BESIII measurements were inspired by the COM, the focus has been on comparisons between experiment and that model. Note that other models exist, however, and can be found extensively reviewed in [9].</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>channels, namely, c 0 ! cJ ! &quot; pK þ Ãð1520Þ, c 0 ! cJ ! pK À &quot; Ãð1520Þ, and c 0</trash>

					<figDesc>! cJ ! p &quot; pK þ K À , are to estimate the background in the signal region S of the data. The mass spectra obtained from the signal and scaled sideband background events in Fig. 4</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>(a) are simultaneously fit using Breit-Wigner functions convolved with Gaussian resolution functions. The Breit-Wigner masses and the instrumental resolutions used for the Gaussians are left as free parameters in the fit. Other background is described by a flat distribution. The differences between the results of the fits to the signal and scaled sideband events, shown in Fig. 4(b), are used to extract the cJ !</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520Þ yield. We find 28:1 AE 9:8 events for c0 ! Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520Þ and 28:9 AE 7:4 events for c2 ! Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520Þ. No distinct c1 ! Ãð1520Þ &quot;</trash>

					<figDesc>Ãð1520Þ signal is observed, and a 90% C.L. upper limit is given using the Bayesian method.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The branching fractions are calculated according to:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Bð cJ ! Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520ÞÞ ¼ N obs N c 0 Á Bðc 0 ! cJ Þ Á BðÃð1520Þ ! pK À Þ Á Bð &quot; Ãð1520Þ ! &quot; pK þ Þ Á &quot; ; and the upper limit at the 90% C.L. is calculated as Bð c1 ! Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520ÞÞ &lt; N obs N c 0 Á Bðc 0 ! c1 Þ Á BðÃð1520Þ ! pK À Þ Á Bð &quot; Ãð1520Þ ! &quot; pK þ Þ Á &quot; Á ð1 À sys Þ ;</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the detection efficiencies are determined from MC simulation, which assumes an angular distribution of 1 þ cos 2 for the two-body decays, and the value for is estimated by fitting the cos distribution of data separately for the c0 , c1 , and c2 states, is the polar angle of a particle in the rest frame of its mother particle, and sys denotes the systematic error (discussed below). The results are summarized in Table III</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>E. cJ ! p p The K þ K À invariant mass distributions and fits to the spectra are presented in Fig. 5 for the c0 , c1 , and c2 . signals are observed clearly in the decays of c0 [Fig. 5(a)] and c2 [Fig. 5(c)]. The fits use Breit-Wigner functions convolved with Gaussians for the signals, where the Breit-Wigner masses and instrumental resolutions are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>) 2 ) (GeV/c - M(pK 1.5 1.6 1.7 1.8 ) 2 ) (GeV/c + K p M( 1.5 1.6 1.7 1.8 ) 2 ) (GeV/c - K + K p M(p 2 Events /0.0025 GeV/c 0 5 10 15 20 25 ) 2 ) (GeV/c - K + K p M(p 3.35 3.4 3.45 3.5 3.55 3.6 2 Events /0.0025 GeV/c 0 5 10 15 20 25 (a) (b)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Fitting curve of Signal Region</head>

				<p>Fitting curve of 2D Sideband FIG. 4 (color online). (a) Scatter plot of Mð &quot; pK þ Þ versus MðpK À Þ; (b) Invariant mass spectrum and fits to p &quot; pK þ K À , where dots with error bars are events from the signal region. The solid line is the fitting curve for the events from signal region, and the dashed lines represent background estimated from the two-dimensional mass sidebands of regions &apos;&apos;A, B, C&apos;&apos; as shown in (a).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>TABLE III.</head>

				<p>The branching fractions for cJ ! Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520Þ. The errors are statistical only, and the upper limit is at the 90% C.L.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Quantity c0 c1 c2 N obs 28:1 AE 9:8 &lt;6:9 28:9 AE 7:4 &quot;ð%Þ 17:1 AE 0:1 16:3 AE 0:1 12:2 AE 0:1 BðÃð1520Þ ! pKÞð%Þ 22.5 22.5 22.5</trash>

					<figDesc>M. ABLIKIM et al. PHYSICAL REVIEW D 83, 112009 (2011)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>event generator. The contributions of each item are summarized in Table V</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>for cJ ! p &quot; pK þ K À , Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520Þ and Table VI for &quot; pK þ Ãð1520Þ þ c:c: and p &quot; p. From analyses of very clean J=c ! K Ã K and J=c ! p &quot; p þ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>À decays, the tracking efficiency for MC simulated events is found to agree with that determined using data to within 2% for each charged track. Hence, 8% is taken as the systematic uncertainty for the four charged track final state.</p>

				<p>The candidates of the selected final state require tracks be identified as p, &quot; p, K þ , or K À .</p>

				<p>Comparing data and MC event samples for J=c ! þ À p &quot; p and J=c ! K Ã K, a difference in MC and data particle identification efficiency of 2% is obtained for each particle. Hence, 8% is taken as the systematic uncertainty for p &quot; pK þ K À identification. Photon reconstruction efficiency is studied using c 0 ! þ À J=c ! þ À p &quot; p, and the difference between data and MC is about 1% per photon [12].</p>

				<p>To estimate the uncertainty from kinematic fitting, a c 0 ! cJ ! p &quot; p þ À sample is selected to study efficiency differences between data and MC. Errors of 1.4%, 1.6%, and 2.3% are obtained for decays of c0 , c1 , and c2 , respectively. not available. Their branching fractions are taken conservatively as 5 Â 10 À6 , and the systematic uncertainties are the differences between with and without the intermediate states.</p>

				<p>The total number of c 0 events with an uncertainty of 4% is obtained by studying inclusive hadronic c 0 decays [12]. The total systematic uncertainty is obtained by summing up uncertainties contributed from all individual sources in quadrature.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>VII. RESULTS AND DISCUSSION</head>

				<p>The measured branching fractions for the 12 decay modes decaying to p &quot; pK þ K À are summarized in Table VII. From the 106 Â 10 6 c 0 decays observed by BESIII at BEPCII, we report first measurements of these branching fractions with uncertainties ranging from 20% to 40%. With larger statistics in future BESIII running, we expect to improve these measurements and to be able to observe Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520Þ in c1 decays. The excited baryon Ãð1520Þ &quot;</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Ãð1520Þ decays provide new information for evaluating model predictions of cJ hadronic decays. TABLE VII. Summary of branching fractions for 12 cJ decay modes to p &quot; pK þ K À . The first errors are statistical, and the second ones are systematic. The upper limits are at the 90% C.L. including the systematic errors.</figDesc>
					<trash>c0 c1 c2 Bð cJ ! p &quot; pK þ K À Þ ð10 À4 Þ 1:24 AE 0:20 AE 0:18 1:35 AE 0:15 AE 0:19 2:08 AE 0:19 AE 0:30 Bð cJ ! &quot; pK þ Ãð1520Þ þ c:c:Þ (10 À4 ) 3:00 AE 0:58 AE 0:50 1:81 AE 0:38 AE 0:28 3:06 AE 0:50 AE 0:54 Bð cJ ! Ãð1520Þ &quot; Ãð1520ÞÞ ð10 À4 Þ 3:18 AE 1:11 AE 0:53 &lt;1:00 5:05 AE 1:29 AE 0:93 Bð cJ ! p &quot; pÞ (10 À5 ) 6:12 AE 1:18 AE 0:86 &lt;1:82 3:04 AE 0:85 AE 0:43 112009-8</trash>

					<head>Figure 12:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>BESIII measurements of χ cJ → ppK + K − and its submodes involving Λ(1520) → pK − , Λ(1520) → pK + , and φ → K + K − . The upper plots show the selection of the Λ(1520)Λ(1520) signal region (left) and the resulting χ cJ peaks (right). The solid (blue) line is a fit in the signal region and the dotted (red) line is a fit in the sidebands. The table lists the resulting branching fractions.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>12</head>

				<p>Decays of the χ cJ are not only important for the study of the strong force through the dynamics of their decays, but they also serve as a source of light quark states. The large number of available final states, and the fact the initial state can have J = 0, 1, 2, depending on the χ cJ state, allows one to optimize searches for light quark mesons with specific quantum numbers. The decays χ c1 → ηπ + π − and χ c1 → η π + π − , for example, are an ideal place to search for resonances with exotic J P C = 1 −+ quantum numbers decaying to ηπ or η π. The possible resonances produced in χ c1 → η () π + π − decays are listed in Fig. 13. Here the only allowed S-wave decay of the χ c1 goes through the exotic π 1 state, which in turn decays to η () π. all of the decay modes of the and . We select the c1 by requiring that the energy of the photon radiated from the c ð2SÞ be between 155 and 185 MeV (indicated by the arrows in Fig. 3). Our final data samples consist of 2498 and 698 events in the c ð2SÞ ! c1 ; c1 ! þ À and c ð2SÞ ! c1 ; c1 ! 0 þ À decay chains, respectively . The background is estimated by fitting the data in Fig. 3 using a reverse Crystal Ball shape [15] to describe the signal. The background and c2 peak are described by a where either and th ð0Þ ) p respec isobar The distrib cohere scribe define space, where index photon variab compl amplit TABLE II. A list of c1 decay modes for all possible isobars with J 4.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c1 Decay Mode L Isobar J PC a 0 ; a 0 ! ð0Þ P 0 þþ 1 ; 1 ! ð0Þ S, D 1 Àþ a 2 ; a 2 ! ð0Þ P, F 2 þþ a 4 ; a 4 ! ð0Þ F, H 4 þþ f 0 ð0Þ ; f 0 ! P 0 þþ f 2 ð0Þ ; f 2 ! P, F 2 þþ f 4 ð0Þ ; f 4 ! F, H 4 þþ 112009-4 Figure 13</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: A list of allowed decays of the χ c1 that result in the final state η () π + π − , the angular momentum (L) of the initial χ c1 decay, and the J P C of the intermediate state. Notice that the decay through the exotic π 1 state is the only allowed S-wave decay and thus could be enhanced relative to other decay modes.</p>

				<p>The CLEO Collaboration has recently published an amplitude analysis of the decays χ c1 → η () π + π − [10]. Clean samples of the χ c1 , shown in Fig. 14, were obtained from 26 million ψ(2S) decays. An amplitude analysis was then performed using the amplitudes listed in Fig. 13. Breit-Wigner distributions were used to parameterize most resonance decays, while a Flatte distribution was used for a 0 (980) decays, and a phenomenological distribution taken from ππ scattering data was used for the ππ S-wave (called f 0 in Fig. 13). Projections of the fit results are shown in Fig. 15 and the results are listed in Fig. 16. In the χ c1 → η π + π − channel, CLEO found evidence for an exotic π 1 state decaying to η π, which is consistent with previous claims of a π 1 (1600) state produced in other that the þ À invariant mass be between 335 and 895 MeV=c 2 , which is motivated by the apparent dominance in the þ À system. One additional background for the c ð2SÞ ! c1 ; c1 ! 0 þ À decay chain with 0 ! þ À is from c ð2SÞ ! c0 ; c0 ! 2ð þ À Þ where the radiated photon converts to an e þ e À pair outside the tracking region. This is suppressed by requiring that the total energy of the two resulting showers is not consistent with the energy of the photon from c ð2SÞ ! c0 , i.e., not between 225 and 295 MeV, and that the cosine of the angle between the two showers is less than 0.97. Figure 3 shows the invariant mass distributions of (a) the þ À and (b) the 0 þ À candidates after combining all of the decay modes of the and 0 . We select the c1 by requiring that the energy of the photon radiated from the c ð2SÞ be between 155 and 185 MeV (indicated by the arrows in Fig. 3). Our final data samples consist of 2498 and 698 events in the c ð2SÞ ! c1 ; c1 ! þ À and c ð2SÞ ! c1 ; c1 ! 0 þ À decay chains, respectively . The background is estimated by fitting the data in Fig. 3 using a reverse Crystal Ball shape [15] to describe the signal. The background and c2 peak are described by a second order polynomial and a double Gaussian, r tively. Peaking backgrounds have been subtracted by the c candidate mass distribution in ð0Þ mass side such backgrounds are negligible in all cases exce 0 ! þ À decay mode. The estimated signal pur the þ À ( 0 þ À ) decay channel is 97.5% (9 with an uncertainty of 0.3% (1.3%).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. AMPLITUDE ANALYSIS</head>

				<p>We perform amplitude analyses to disentangle th structure present in the c1 ! þ À and 0 þ À decays. We assume that the three-hadron d of the c1 proceed through a sequence of two-body d where one participant is the &apos;&apos;isobar,&apos;&apos; a bound st either ð0Þ AE or þ À with total angular momen and the other is a stable, noninteracting meson (the ð0Þ ) produced with an orbital angular momentum L respect to the isobar. All possible c1 decays th isobars with J 4 are listed in Table II.</p>

				<p>The general idea of an amplitude analysis is to distribution of events observed with the detecto coherent sum of physically-motivated amplitudes th scribes the dynamics of the intermediate states. W define IðxÞ, the number of observed events per unit space, as FIG. 3 (color online). The invariant mass distributions of the (a) þ À and (b) 0 þ À candidates from selected c þ À and c ð2SÞ ! 0 þ À decays, respectively, after all background suppression criteria have been applied. The solid indicate the regions used to select the c1 signals.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>TABLE II. A list of c1 decay modes for all possible isobars G. S. ADAMS et al. PHYSICAL REVIEW D 84, 112009 Figure 14</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>: The selection of χ c1 decays to ηπ + π − (left) and η π + π − (right) from CLEO [10]. The signal purities are estimated to be 97.5% and 94.6%, respectively. production mechanisms [11]. This is the first evidence of a light quark meson with exotic quantum numbers in a charmonium decay, and opens many new possibilities for other amplitude analyses of χ cJ decays into other final states. separate the various ðÞ S ð0Þ contributions given in Eq. (10). In the fits to the c1 ! 0 þ À sample, we fix the S-wave parameter c in Eq. (10) to zero; allowing this parameter to float yields a value that is statistically consistent with both zero and the value obtained in the higher-statistics c1 ! þ À fits. In all cases, the parameters describing the masses and widths of the intermediate resonances are fixed in our baseline fits to enhance the stability of the fit. Both the 1 ð1600Þ and f 4 ð2050Þ parameters are fixed to values that maximize the likelihood . We systematically explore uncertainties on the parametrization of the amplitudes as discussed in Sec. V. A quantitative summary of the baseline fits appears in Table III. From the fit, one can compute the total acceptance-corrected event yield in either the 0 þ À or þ À final states, which is the denominator of Eq. (16). If we denote this quantity Nð þ À Þ or Nð 0 þ À Þ, respectively, then we can compute the branching fractions for to these final states, Bð !</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Bð c1 ! ð0Þ þ À Þ ¼ pNð ð0Þ þ À Þ N c ð2SÞ Bðc ð2SÞ ! c1 Þ P i B i ð ð0Þ Þ ; (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where N c ð2SÞ is the number of initial c ð2SÞ, 2:59 Â 10 7 , and we use Bðc ð2SÞ ! c1 Þ ¼ ð9:2 AE 0:4Þ Â 10 À2 [13]. The sum over and 0 branching fractions encompasses all and 0 decay modes in our signal MC sample, indicated in Table I. The value p is the purity of the data sample in the c1 region in Fig. 3, which is obtained as discussed in Sec. II.</p>

				<p>In what follows, we discuss the results of the fits to each of the samples in detail, highlighting the key results obtained from each fit. For each c1 decay mode, we also compute the product Bð c1 ! ð0Þ þ À Þ Â F , which can be interpreted as the branching fraction for the c1 decay to the isobar and spectator multiplied by the branch- FIG. 8 (color online). Invariant mass projections from the analysis of the c1 ! þ À (a,b) and c1 ! 0 þ À (c,d) decays.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>AMPLITUDE ANALYSES OF THE DECAYS . . . PHYSICAL REVIEW D 84, 112009 (2011)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Figure 15: The fit results for χ c1 → ηπ + π − (top) and χ c1 → η π + π − (bottom) from CLEO [10]. The points are data and the solid black line is the total fit result. The other lines show contributions from individual amplitudes. The exotic π 1 signal decaying to η π can be seen in the lower left. final state. Dividing products with common factors (discussed in Sec. IV C) yields c1 and isobar branching ratios.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A. c1 ! þ À decays The AE and</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>þ À invariant mass projections and corresponding amplitude contributions from the fit to the c ð2SÞ ! c1 ; c1 ! þ À sample are shown in Figs. 8(a) and 8(b). The dominant amplitude in this data set is the a 0 ð980Þ, which, consequently, must be adequately parametrized to obtain a satisfactory fit to the data. To determine the a 0 ð980Þ parameters, we exclude the data with þ À invariant mass below 1:7 GeV=c 2 , which removes any correlation with the þ À S-wave amplitudes.</p>

				<p>The fit to this restricted data set includes the a 0 ð980Þ, a 2 ð1320Þ, and f 4 ð2050Þ amplitudes, and we allow all four a 0 ð980Þ parameters to float. The resulting a 0 ð980Þ parameters are given in Table IV, where the first error is statistical and the second error is systematic, obtained by tryin various combinations of isobars to fit the region i þ À invariant mass around 2:0 GeV=c 2 , a peak attrib uted to the f 4 ð2050Þ resonance in the baseline fit. Th a 0 ð980Þ Flatté distribution parameters, which are consi tent with a previous determination by CLEO [20], ar subsequently fixed in the baseline fit to the full data sam ple. It is worth noting that the a 0 ð980Þ line shape in rather insensitive to the a 0 ð980Þ ! 0 coupling g 0 . I fact, the fit prefers a coupling of zero, but with larg uncertainty. Our analysis of c1 ! 0 þ À data, pre sented later, directly extracts information related to th coupling constant. The S-wave is parametrized as described in Eq. (11 with the parameters c and k floating in the fit. In Table II we list the contributions of the three individual componen of the S-wave. In principle, the magnitude and phase o the total S-wave can be constructed by using th entries in this table to normalize three components de picted in Fig. 6. In order to fit the þ À invariant mass distributio around 2:0 GeV=c 2 , we tried various known reso nances with J ¼ 0, 2, and 4 and masses ranging from 2 to 2:3 GeV=c 2 . The best fit is obtained with a single spin four resonance that has parameters consistent with th f 4 ð2050Þ state listed by the Particle Data Group (PDG [13]. The mass and width of the f 4 ð2050Þ, as determined b</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>TABLE III. Summary of results of the baseline fits. The first and second errors are statistical and systematic, respectively. The third error, where reported, is from the external value of Bðc ð2SÞ ! c1 Þ. Amplitudes that are preceded by an asterisk (*) are not part of the baseline fits but have been included to determine upper limits. The listed fit fractions and significances (N ) are obtained when the amplitude is added to the baseline fits.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c1 Decay Mode F ½% Bð c1 ! ð0Þ þ À Þ Â F [10 À3 ] N þ À Á Á Á 4:97 AE 0:08 AE 0:21 AE 0:22 Á Á Á a 0 ð980Þ 66:2 AE 1:2 AE 1:1 3 :29 AE 0:09 AE 0:14 AE 0:15 &gt;10 a 2 ð1320Þ 9:8 AE 0:8 AE 1:0 0 :49 AE 0:04 AE 0:05 AE 0:02 9.7 ð þ À Þ S 22:5 AE 1:3 AE 2:5 1 :12 AE 0:06 AE 0:13 AE 0:05 &gt;10 S 0 12:1 AE 1:7 AE 5:6 0 :60 AE 0:08 AE 0:28 AE 0:03 &gt;10 S 1 3:4 AE 0:9 AE 1:5 0 :17 AE 0:05 AE 0:07 AE 0:01 6.0 S KK 3:1 AE 0:6 AE 0:4 0 :15 AE 0:03 AE 0:02 AE 0:01 9.4 f 2 ð1270Þ 7:4 AE 0:8 AE 0:6 0 :37 AE 0:04 AE 0:04 AE 0:02 &gt;10 f 4 ð2050Þ 1:0 AE 0:3 AE 0:3 0 :05 AE 0:01 AE 0:02 AE 0:00 5.2 Ã 1 ð1600Þ Á Á Á &lt;0:031 0.7 0 þ À Á Á Á 1:90 AE 0:07 AE 0:08 AE 0:09 Á Á Á a 0 ð980Þ 11:0 AE 2:3 AE 1:8 0 :21 AE 0:04 AE 0:04 AE 0:01 8.4 a 2 ð1320Þ 0:4 AE 0:5 AE 0:6 &lt;0:031 1.4 ð þ À Þ S 21:6 AE 2:7 AE 1:2 0 :41 AE 0:05 AE 0:03 AE 0:02 10.2 S 0 0 7:0 AE 2:2 AE 2:3 0 :13 AE 0:04 AE 0:04 AE 0:01 6.6 S KK 0 8:4 AE 1:5 AE 1:3 0 :16 AE 0:03 AE 0:02 AE 0:01 7.5 f 2 ð1270Þ 0 27:0 AE 2:9 AE 1:7 0 :51 AE 0:06 AE 0:04 AE 0:03 &gt;10 Ã f 4 ð2050Þ 0 Á Á Á &lt;0:010 0.4 1 ð1600Þ 15:1 AE 2:7 AE 3:2 0 :29 AE 0:05 AE 0:06 AE 0:01 7.2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>TABLE IV. The values of a 0 ð980Þ parameters compared to the previous CLEO analysis [20]. The first error is statistical and the second error is systematic, as explained in the text.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Parameter [GeV=c 2 ]</head>

				<p>Ref. [20] [GeV=c 2 ]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m 0 0:998 AE 0:006 AE 0:015 1:002 AE 0:018 g 0:60 AE 0:02 AE 0:03 0:64 AE 0:05 g KK 0:56 AE 0:06 AE 0:09 0:52 AE 0:15 G. S. ADAMS et al. PHYSICAL REVIEW D 84, 112009 (201</trash>

					<head>Figure 16:</head>

					<figDesc>Results from the CLEO amplitude analyses of χ c1 → η () π + π − showing the fit fractions (F) of different submodes, the branching fraction of χ c1 → η () π + π</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>− times the fit fractions (B × F), and the significance of each fit component (N σ ) [10].</p>

				<p>The first errors are statistical, the second systematic, and the third, where applicable, are from the external measurement of B(ψ(2S) → γχ c1 ).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Conclusion</head>

				<p>While data taking has concluded at CLEO, and no new χ cJ analyses are anticipated, BESIII continues to collect data in the charmonium region. The BESIII results presented here are based on 106 million ψ(2S) decays, but more statistics are expected.</p>

				<p>With larger statistics, we expect to learn more about strong decay dynamics and perform more searches for light quark states in χ cJ decays.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M H</forename>
				<surname>Wong</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149903236</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">643</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Gupta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Johnson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Repko</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">549606349</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2075</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Godfrey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Isgur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">189</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ablikim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BESIII Collaboration] Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">112008</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Particle Data Group Collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Nakamura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. G G</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">075021</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ablikim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Achasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>An</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Q</forename>
				<surname>An</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>An</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
				<surname>Bai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Baldini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Ban</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>BESIII Collaboration</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1075646</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0920011207</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>BESIII Collaboration</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ablikim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">112009</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Brambilla</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Eidelman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Heltsley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Vogt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Bodwin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Eichten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Frawley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Meyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1534</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Adams</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CLEO Collaboration Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">112009</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Particle Data Group Collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Beringer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">010001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
