<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The hadronic vacuum polarization with twisted boundary conditions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-10-18">18 Oct 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Christopher</forename>
								<surname>Aubin</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Engineering Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fordham University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10458</postCode>
									<settlement>Bronx</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Thomas</forename>
								<surname>Blum</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Connecticut</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06269</postCode>
									<settlement>Storrs</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Maarten</forename>
								<surname>Golterman</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institut de Físicad&apos;AltesEnergies(IFAE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitatAutonomadeBarcelona</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E-08193</postCode>
									<settlement>Bellaterra, Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Santiago</forename>
								<surname>Peris</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">DepartmentofPhysics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitatAutonomadeBarcelona</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E-08193</postCode>
									<settlement>Bellaterra, Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">DepartmentofPhysicsandAstronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">SanFranciscoStateUniversity</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94132</postCode>
									<settlement>SanFrancisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The hadronic vacuum polarization with twisted boundary conditions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2013-10-18">18 Oct 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The leading-order hadronic contribution to the muon anomalous magnetic moment is given by a weighted integral over the subtracted hadronic vacuum polarization. This integral is dominated by euclidean momenta of order the muon mass, i.e., momenta not accessible on current lattice volumes with periodic boundary conditions. Twisted boundary conditions can in principle help in accessing momenta of any size even in a finite volume, but their use leads to a modification of the Ward–Takahashi identity that normally guarantees transver-sality of the vacuum polarization. As a result, the vacuum polarization contains a non-transverse, quadratically divergent term, which arises as an artifact of using twisted boundary conditions in a finite volume. In this article, we show how to determine and remove this term from the vacuum polarization. † Permanent address:</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>The leading-order hadronic (HLO) contribution to the anomalous magnetic moment a µ = (g − 2)/2 of the muon is given by the integral [1, 2]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 a HLO µ = 4α 2 ∞ 0 dp 2 f (p 2 ) Π em (0) − Π em (p 2 ) , (1.1) f (p 2 ) = m 2 µ p 2 Z 3 (p 2 ) 1 − p 2 Z(p 2 ) 1 + m 2 µ p 2 Z 2 (p 2 ) , Z(p 2 ) = (p 2 ) 2 + 4m 2 µ p 2 − p 2 /(2m 2 µ p 2 ) , where m</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>µ is the muon mass, and for non-zero momenta Π em (p 2 ) is defined from the hadronic contribution to the electromagnetic vacuum polarization Π em µν (p):</p>

				<p><formula>Π em µν (p) = p 2 δ µν − p µ p ν Π em (p 2 ) (1.2)</formula></p>

				<p>in momentum space. Here p is the euclidean momentum flowing through the vacuum polar- ization. The integrand in Eq. (1.1) is dominated by momenta of order the muon mass; it typically looks as shown in Fig. 1, with the peak located at p 2 ≈ (m µ /2) 2 . For a precision computation of this integral using lattice QCD, one would therefore like to access the region of this peak.</p>

				<p>In a finite volume with periodic boundary conditions, the smallest available non-vanishing momentum is 2π/L, with L the linear size of the lattice volume. Setting 2π/L ≈ m µ /2 leads to a value of L equal to about 25 fm, which is out of reach of present lattice computations, if the lattice spacing a is chosen to be such that one is reasonably close to the continuum limit. Clearly, a different method for reaching such small momenta is needed. In this article, we discuss the use of twisted boundary conditions in order to vary momenta arbitrarily in a finite volume. Twisted boundary conditions have already been used in order to access the connected part of Π em (p 2 ) at momenta smaller than 2π/L [4]. 2 However, as we will show here, any current used in the definition of Π em µν (p) with twisted boundary conditions cannot be conserved, and thus Π em µν (p) is necessarily not purely transverse.</p>

				<p>In other words, in the presence of twisted boundary conditions, Π em µν (p) cannot be written as in Eq. (1.2) above. The relevant Ward– Takahashi identity (WTI) gets modified by twisting, leading to an extra term proportional to δ µν in the vacuum polarization. While this extra term is a finite-volume artifact, it turns out to be quadratically divergent, and thus a potentially significant obstruction to the extraction of Π em (p 2 ) from Π em µν (p). This article is organized as follows. In Sec. II, we briefly review the application of twisted boundary conditions to the computation of the vacuum polarization with arbitrary momentum . Then, in Sec. III, we formulate the WTI, and demonstrate that this identity contains a contact term originating from the fact that any current used in order to define the vacuum 1 For an overview of lattice computations of the muon anomalous magnetic moment, see Ref. [3] and references therein. 2 In Ref. [4], Π em (q 2 ) is extracted from the off-diagonal components of the vacuum polarization tensor, so the contact terms to be discussed here do not contribute to Π</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>em µν . 0.01 0.02 0.03 0.04 0.05 0.005 0.010 0.015</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>FIG. 1: Typical shape of the integrand in Eq. (1.1), with p 2 in GeV 2 on the horizontal axis, and arbitrary units on the vertical axis. polarization with non-zero twist is necessarily not conserved in a finite volume. This leads to the appearance of non-transverse terms in the vacuum polarization, and in Sec. IV we show how these can be computed and subtracted, in order to allow the determination of Π em (p 2 ). In Sec. V we verify that indeed the WTI is satisfied numerically on a typical gauge configuration, and we have a first look at the numerical size of the contact term relative to the complete vacuum polarization. Section VI contains our conclusions, and an appendix verifies the WTI to leading order in weak-coupling perturbation theory.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. TWISTED BOUNDARY CONDITIONS</head>

				<p>The aim is to compute the connected part of the two-point function of the electromagnetic current,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>J em µ (x) = i Q i q i (x)γ µ q i (x) , (2.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in which i runs over quark flavors, and quark q i has charge Q i e, in a finite volume, but with an arbitrary choice of momentum. In order to do this, we will employ quarks which satisfy twisted boundary conditions [5–7],</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>q t (x) = e −iθµ q t (x + ˆ µL µ ) , (2.2a) q t (x) = q t (x + ˆ µL µ ) e iθµ , (2.2b)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the subscript t indicates that the quark field q t obeys twisted boundary conditions, L µ is the linear size of the volume in the µ direction (ˆ µ denotes the unit vector in the µ direction), and θ µ ∈ [0, 2π) is the twist angle in that direction.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3 For a plane wave u(p)e ipx , boundary condition (2.2a) leads to the allowed values p µ = 2πn µ + θ µ L µ , n µ ∈ {0, 1, . . . , L µ − 1} . (2.3) The twist angle can be chosen differently for the two quark lines in the connected part of the vacuum polarization, resulting in a continuously variable momentum flowing through the diagram. (Clearly, this trick does not work for the disconnected part. For examples of connected and disconnected diagrams in this context, see Fig. 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>.) If this momentum is chosen to be of the form (2.3), then allowing θ µ to vary over the range between 0 and 2π allows p µ to vary continuously between 2πn µ /L µ and 2π(n µ + 1)/L µ . This momentum is realized if, for example, we choose the anti-quark line in the vacuum polarization to satisfy periodic boundary conditions (i.e., Eq. (2.2) with θ µ = 0 for all µ), and the quark line twisted boundary conditions with twist angles θ µ .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>4</head>

				<p>This choice can be viewed as following from the use of a mixed action [8]. The vacuum polarization is made out of two different valence quarks: one with periodic boundary conditions , and one with twisted boundary conditions, but otherwise equal to the periodic valence quark. If the dynamical (sea) quarks are also periodic, the first valence quark is identical to the sea quark, but the twisted quark is not present in the sea, i.e., it is quenched. In a path-integral definition of the theory, one would thus introduce a ghost quark with the same twisted boundary conditions in order to cancel the determinant for the twisted quark. Denoting the twisted valence quark as q t , as in Eq. (2.2), and the periodic quark as q, the connected vacuum polarization then is a linear combination of terms of the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 J + µ (x)J − ν (y) = − tr γ µ S qt (x, y)γ ν S q (y, x) , (2.4) with J + µ (x) = q(x)γ µ q t (x) , (2.5) J − µ (x) = q t (x)γ µ q(x) ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and where the trace is over Dirac and color indices. S q (x, y) is the full propagator for the periodic quark q and S qt (x, y) is the full propagator for the twisted quark q t , equal to exp(i µ θ µ (x µ − y µ )/L µ ) times a periodic function of x and y with period L µ in the µ direction. (In a slight abuse of notation, the average on the right-hand side of Eq. (2.4) is only over the gauge fields, while the average on the left is over both gauge and quark fields.) The dependence of Eq. (2.4) on the twist angles θ µ is a finite-volume effect, and goes away in the limit L µ → ∞, in which all momenta become continuous.</p>

				<p>The use of twisted boundary conditions immediately carries over to the lattice, where, of course, we need to specify a discretization of the quark action. In the following we will choose to use naive lattice quarks, but the discussion generalizes to any choice of lattice quarks for which a conserved vector current can be defined. In particular, our discussion applies directly to staggered quarks as well. The reason is that staggered quarks are nothing else than naive quarks in a basis on which the gamma matrices are diagonal, but with the resulting four-fold taste degeneracy removed. This diagonalization does not affect the discussion of the currents (2.6) below: All one needs to do is replace the gamma matrices γ µ by the staggered phases η µ (x), and drop the spin index on the quark fields. For naive quarks with a nearest-neighbor Dirac operator, the currents (2.5) get replaced by the point-split currents</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>j + µ (x) = 1 2 q(x)γ µ U µ (x)q t (x + ˆ µ) + q(x + ˆ µ)γ µ U † µ (x)q t (x) , (2.6) j − µ (x) = 1 2 q t (x)γ µ U µ (x)q(x + ˆ µ) + q t (x + ˆ µ)γ µ U † µ (x)q(x) , where U µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(x) are the color gauge-field link variables. In infinite volume, with conserved currents j ± µ (x), the construction of a transverse vacuum polarization Π µν (x − y) on the lattice is then standard, and its Fourier transform Π µν (p) takes the form (1.2) because of current conservation, 6 and one obtains Π(p 2 ) by dividing by p 2 δ µν − p µ p ν (for non-zero p). However, in finite volume, the boundary conditions break the symmetry that relates q and q t , and thus the currents j ± µ (x) are not conserved for nonvanishing θ µ . We derive the corresponding modification of the relevant Ward–Takahashi identity in the next section, and discuss the construction of Π µν (x − y) in the presence of twisted boundary conditions.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>III. WARD–TAKAHASHI IDENTITY We consider the field transformations δq(x) = iα + (x)e −iθx/L q t (x) , δq(x) = −iα − (x)e iθx/L q t (x) , (3.1) δq t (x) = iα − (x)e iθx/L q(x) , δq t (x) = −iα + (x)e −iθx/L q(x) , in which we abbreviate θx/L = µ θ µ x µ /L µ , (3.2) and where α</trash>

					<figDesc>± (x) are periodic functions of x. The phases exp(±iθx/L) have been inserted in order to ensure that the transformed quark fields obey the same boundary conditions as the untransformed fields.</figDesc>
					<trash>6 We are ignoring order-a 2 terms of the form δ µν κ p 4 κ − p 3 µ p ν , (δ µν p 2 − p µ p ν )p 2 ν , etc. For more discussion of Lorentz-covariance</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>violating terms, see for example Ref. [9].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Following the standard procedure, this transformation leads to the WTI</figDesc>
					<trash>µ ∂ − µ j + µ (x)j − ν (y) + 1 2 δ(x − y) q t (y + ˆ ν)γ ν U † ν (y)q t (y) − q(y)γ ν U ν (y)q(y + ˆ ν) − 1 2 δ(x − ˆ ν − y) q(y + ˆ ν)γ ν U † ν (y)q(y) − q t (y)γ ν U ν (y)q t (y + ˆ ν) = 0 , (3.3) where ∂ − µ is the backward lattice derivative, which, in Eq. (3.3) as well as Eqs. (3.5) and (3.9) below always acts on x: ∂ − µ f (x) = f (x) − f (x − ˆ µ) . (3.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>If we would take θ µ = 0 in all directions, the fields q and q t would be identical, and this identity would simplify to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µ ∂ − µ j + µ (x)j − ν (y) (3.5) + 1 2 δ µν δ(x − y) q(y + ˆ ν)γ ν U † ν (y)q(y) − q(y)γ ν U ν (y)q(y + ˆ ν) = 0 .</trash>

					<figDesc>The quantity inside parentheses then defines Π µν (x − y), and its Fourier transform is defined by Π µν (x − y) = 1 V p e ip(x−y)+i(pµ−pν )/2 Π µν (p) , (3.6)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>in which V = µ L µ and p is summed over the momenta (2.3) with θ µ = 0. In momentum space, the WTI (3.5) then takes the form µ ˆ p µ Π µν (p) = 0 , ˆ p µ ≡ 2 sin (p µ /2) , (3.7) from which the transverse form as in Eq. (1.2) follows (in the continuum limit). The necessary presence of the contact term in Eq. (3.5) is standard on the lattice [10]. With twisted boundary conditions, a natural generalization of Eq. (3.5) is to define Π µν (x − y) similarly, but averaging the contact term on the left-hand side of Eq. (3.5) over the two quark fields q and q t , leading to the definition</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Π +− µν (x − y) = j + µ (x)j − ν (y) (3.8) − 1 4 δ µν δ(x − y) q(y)γ ν U ν (y)q(y + ˆ ν) − q(y + ˆ ν)γ ν U † ν (y)q(y) + q t (y)γ ν U ν (y)q t (y + ˆ ν) − q t (y + ˆ ν)γ ν U † ν (y)q t (y) . However, Π +− µν (x − y) is not transverse, but instead obeys the identity µ ∂ − µ Π +− µν (x − y) + 1 4 (δ(x − y) + δ(x − ˆ ν − y)) j t ν (y) − j ν (y) = 0 , (3.9) in which j ν (x) and j t ν (x) are currents defined by j µ (x) = 1 2 q(x)γ µ U µ (x)q(x + ˆ µ) + q(x + ˆ µ)γ µ U † µ (x)q(x) , (3.10) j t µ (x) = 1 2 q t (x)γ µ U µ (x)q t (x + ˆ µ) + q t (x + ˆ µ)γ µ U † µ (x)q t (x) .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is important to note that other choices for Π +− µν (x − y) are possible, but there will always be a non-vanishing contact term in the WTI. The reason is that the contact term in Eq. (3.9) (or, equivalently, in Eq. (3.3)) cannot be written as a derivative, because the fact that q and q t fields satisfy different boundary conditions breaks explicitly the isospin-like symmetry that otherwise would exist. (For α ± constant and θ = 0, Eq. (3.1) is an isospin-like symmetry of the action. As a check, we see that for q t = q, i.e., for θ = 0, the contact term in Eq. (3.9) vanishes.) The resulting non-transverse part of Π +− µν therefore will need to be subtracted. We discuss the properties of the contact term, as well as its subtraction, in the next section. For completeness, we also give the corresponding WTI for the case that the local current j ν (y) = q t (y)γ ν q(y) (3.11) is used instead of the current j − ν in the construction of the vacuum polarization. In that case, the WTI reads</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µ ∂ − µ j + µ (x)j ν (y) + δ(x − y) q t (y)γ ν q t (y) − q(y)γ ν q(y) = 0 . (3.12)</trash>

					<figDesc>The structure of this WTI is the same as that of Eq. (3.3): one obtains Eq. (3.12) from Eq. (3.3) by omitting the link variables in the contact term, and omitting ν in the arguments of the fields and the delta function in Eq. (3.3). Again, no vacuum polarization can be constructed that is purely transverse.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>IV. SUBTRACTION OF CONTACT TERM</head>

				<p>Because of axis-reversal symmetry j ν (y) = 0 in Eq. (3.9), 7 but this is not true for j t ν (y), because twisted boundary conditions break this symmetry. Instead, we have that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>j t ν (y) = −i c a 2 ˆ θ ν 1 + O( ˆ θ 2 ) , (4.1) ˆ θ µ = θ µ /L µ ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where c is a numerical constant, and where we made the lattice spacing a explicit. This expansion is valid when θ is small compared to both 1/a and the quark mass m. Equation (4.1) follows from dimensional analysis and the fact that if we let θ µ → −θ µ under an axis reversal in the µ direction, this axis reversal would be a symmetry of the theory. The contact term in Eq. (3.9) is quadratically divergent (at fixed L µ ), and cannot be ignored.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The vacuum polarization Π +− µν (x − y) defined in Eq. (3.8) can be written as Π +− µν (x − y) = e iaθ(x−y)/L F +− µν (x − y) , (4.2) where F +− µν</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(x − y) is a periodic function of x − y with period L µ in the µ direction. This implies that the Fourier transform of Π +− µν (x − y) is defined as in Eq. (3.6), but now with the momentum p summed over the values (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.3). Let us decompose Π +− µν (ˆ p) = ˆ p 2 δ µν − ˆ p µ ˆ p ν Π +− (ˆ p 2 ) + δ µν a 2 X ν (ˆ p) , (4.3)</trash>

					<figDesc>in which a quadratically divergent term X ν (ˆ p) has been added to the transverse part, in order to accommodate the explicit breaking term in the WTI (3.9). In momentum space,</figDesc>
					<trash>Eq. (3.9) takes the form i µ ˆ p µ Π +− µν (ˆ p) = − cos (ap ν /2)j t ν (0) (4.4) = i a 2 ˆ p ν X ν (ˆ p) , where in the second line we substituted Eq. (4.3). In the appendix, we verify Eqs. (4.4) and (4.1) to one loop. Using Eq. (4.1), we find X ν (ˆ p) = i 2 cot (ap ν /2) a 3 j t ν (0) (4.5) = 1 2 c cot (ap ν /2) a ˆ θ ν 1 + O( ˆ θ 2 ) .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that this result for X ν (ˆ p) does not have a pole. The cotangent only has a pole when its argument is equal to zero, modulo π. But, using Eq. (2.3), this would require that πn ν + θ ν /2 = kπL ν /a , k integer , (4.6) which is only possible for θ ν = 0, given the allowed range for θ ν . However, for θ ν = 0, j t ν (0) = 0, and thus X ν = 0 as well. Equations (4.4) and (4.5) show how to compute X ν (ˆ p) from Π +− µν (p) or j t ν (0), while Eq. (4.5) makes the momentum dependence explicit. One can then subtract δ µν X ν (ˆ p)/a 2 from Π +− µν (p), so that Π +− (ˆ p), needed in order to compute a HLO µ (cf. Eq. (1.1)), can be determined. Of course, for µ = ν no subtraction is needed. Some comments are in order. First we wish to emphasize that the counter term proportional to X ν is a pure finite-volume artifact; it will disappear in the infinite-volume limit at fixed lattice spacing. If we keep p ν = (2πn ν + θ ν )/L ν fixed in the factor cot(ap ν /2) in Eq. (4.5) while taking L ν → ∞, clearly X ν goes to zero, and thus there is no need for a counter term in Eq. (4.3). Then, the decomposition (4.3) is not exact at non-zero lattice spacing in a finite volume. The only tensor structure allowing for a power-like divergence with the lattice spacing is δ µν , as in Eq. (4.3), because δ µν is the only 2-index tensor with mass dimension zero. But, for example, there could be terms proportional tô θ µ ˆ θ ν , ˆ p µ ˆ θ ν , ˆ θ µ ˆ p ν , or p µ ˆ p ν that are not transverse. Such terms are not divergent in the continuum limit, because both p µ and θ µ have mass dimension one. Furthermore, since any non-transverse terms originate from the use of twisted boundary conditions, such terms must have at least one factor of θ µ = θ µ /L µ , cf. Eq. (4.1). Therefore, they disappear in the infinite-volume limit.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>8 0 5 10 15 20 p ^ 2 (GeV 2 ) 0.997 0.998 0.999 1 1.001 1.002 1.003 Ward-Takahashi Identity Ratio FIG. 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: Ratio of the left-hand and right-hand sides of the WTI (4.4), for a typical gauge-field configuration from the asqtad MILC ensemble with L 3 × T = 48 3 × 144, 1/a = 3.35 GeV, am = 0.0036, θ x = θ y = θ z = 0.28π, θ t = 0.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. NUMERICAL TESTS</head>

				<p>The WTI (4.4) holds on each gauge configuration, making it straightforward to test the identity numerically. We did so on a number of configurations from a MILC asqtad ensemble, always finding the two sides of the WTI to agree within the numerical precision employed. As an example, in Fig. 3 we show the ratio of both sides of the WTI (4.4), computed on a typical configuration (for parameters, see the figure caption). The conjugate-gradient stopping condition was 10 −8 on the residual. We observe that the WTI is satisfied with a precision of order a few permille, and about an order of magnitude better than that for</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p 2 ∼ &lt; 4 GeV 2 . We replaced j t ν (0) on the right-hand side of Eq. (4.4) by j t ν (0) − j ν (0), conform Eq. (3.9) (for the arbitrary choice y = 0), because on a single configuration generically j ν (0) = 0. 9 9</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In addition, for the same reason, Π +− µν is not translation invariant, and thus a function of the source and sink points x and y.</p>

				<p><formula>-1 0 1 2 3 4 5 p ^ 2 (GeV 2 ) 0 5 10 15 20 25 30 X ν / Π νν +- Ratio</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 4: Ratio of the second term on the right-hand side and the left-hand side of Eq. (4.3), for the same gauge-field configuration as used for Fig. 3. In Fig. 4 we show, for the same gauge field configuration, the ratio</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X ν (ˆ p) a 2 Π +− νν (ˆ p) , (5.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with choices for the momentum p such that the denominator does not vanish. Here Π +− µν (ˆ p) was obtained as the Fourier transform of Π +− µν (x), taking y = 0 in Eq. (3.8), and X ν (ˆ p) was obtained from Eq. (4.5), with again j t ν (0) replaced by j t ν (0) − j ν (0).</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Fig. 4 we see that for some momenta (especially in the low-momentum region) the size of the counter term in Eq. (4.3) can be significant. We also find that averaging (over volume or over configurations) appears to reduce the effect of the counter term. While the effect of averaging is at present still under investigation, the result shown in the figure indicates that at least on single configurations the effect of the counter term cannot be ignored.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>VI. CONCLUSION</head>

				<p>In this article, we investigated the use of twisted boundary conditions in a finite volume, in order to compute the hadronic vacuum polarization on a lattice for all values of the euclidean momenta, instead of only those allowed with periodic boundary conditions. As we explained in the Introduction, this is important for a high-precision computation of the leading-order hadronic contribution to the muon anomalous magnetic moment.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In order to vary the momentum flowing through the vacuum polarization, the quark and anti-quark lines constituting the connected contribution to the vacuum polarization should obey boundary conditions with different twist angles. 10 This implies that the isospin-like symmetry relating these two quark lines is broken explicitly. This breaking shows up as an extra contact term in the relevant Ward–Takahashi identity that cannot be removed by a local redefinition of the currents, and which we showed to be quadratically divergent. Correspondingly, the vacuum polarization is not transverse, but instead contains a quadratically divergent term which needs to be subtracted. We emphasize that this extra term is a finite-volume artifact caused by the use of twisted boundary conditions. A consequence of this is that the point-split currents considered in this article still do not renormalize, so that no Z factors appear if the currents j ± µ of Eq. (2.6) are used in order to define the vacuum polarization.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>11</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The analysis leading to this conclusion also leads to a recipe for removing the unwanted term from the vacuum polarization, as discussed in Sec. IV. The subtracted vacuum polarization is still not exactly of the desired form (1.2), but the remaining violations are lattice and finite-volume artifacts that should automatically disappear in the continuum and infinite-volume limits. Without the removal of the quadratically divergent term this would not the case. Of course, while the quadratically divergent nature of the contact term tends to increase the importance of this effect at smaller lattice spacing, the fact that it is a finite-volume effect will help suppress the effect on larger volumes. It thus remains to be seen how numerically significant the effect is in practice on realistic lattices with a given lattice spacing.</figDesc>
					<trash>fermions, we find Π +− µν (p) = − N c V k tr γ µ cos (k µ + p µ /2) i κ γ κ sin(k κ + p κ ) + m γ ν cos (k ν + p ν /2) i λ γ λ sin k κ + m (A1) + i 2 δ µν N c V k tr γ ν sin k ν i κ γ κ sin k κ + m + sin (k ν + ˆ θ ν ) i κ γ κ sin (k κ + ˆ θ κ ) + m ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in which p is one of the momenta specified in Eq. (2.3), and k is summed over periodic momenta, with components k µ = 2πn µ /L µ with n µ ∈ {0, . . . , L µ − 1}; N c is the number of colors. Using trigonometric identities, it is straightforward to show that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>i µ ˆ p µ Π +− µν (p) = (A2) −2i cos (p ν /2) N c V k sin(2k ν ) κ sin 2 k κ + m 2 − sin(2(k ν + ˆ θ ν )) κ sin 2 (k κ + ˆ θ k ) + m 2 = 2i cos (p ν /2) ˆ θ N c V k 2 cos(2k ν ) k sin 2 k κ + m 2 − sin 2 (2k ν ) ( k sin 2 k κ + m 2 ) 2 + O( ˆ θ 3 ) .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The quantity in square brackets on the last line is quadratically divergent in the continuum limit, and leads to a one-loop result for j t ν (y) of the general form (4.1). In manipulating the sums over k, one should keep in mind that only shifts by periodic momenta are allowed. For instance, to obtain Eq. (A2), we made use of the shift k µ → k µ −p µ + ˆ θ µ , which is allowed because p µ − ˆ θ µ = 2πn µ /L µ for some integer values of n µ . A shift k µ → k µ − ˆ θ µ is not allowed, and thus the right-hand side of Eq. (A2) does not vanish for θ ν = 0. Equations (A1) and (A2) hold also for staggered fermions, if the right-hand side of these two equations is divided by four.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">† Permanent address: Department of Physics and Astronomy, San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA 94132, USA</note>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:1307.4701v3 [hep-lat] 18 Oct 2013</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> If anti-periodic boundary conditions are used in the time direction, that corresponds to the choice θ 4 = π.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> If anti-periodic boundary conditions in the time direction are chosen for both quarks, the vacuum polarization still satisfies periodic boundary conditions. Only the relative twist between the quark and anti-quark lines introduces a twist in the boundary conditions for the vacuum polarization as well. 5 It is straightforward to generalize our analysis to the choice of arbitrary twist angles in both valence quarks.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> Recall that we assume dynamical quarks to have periodic, and not twisted, boundary conditions.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> Other tensor structures are possible on the lattice, but these are all of order a 2 , and thus vanish in the continuum limit, see footnote 6.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> As mentioned before, this method therefore does not apply to the disconnected part. 11 As usual, a non-trivial Z factor appears if the local current j µ of Eq. (3.11) is used.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>We would like to thank USQCD for the computing resources used to generate the vacuum polarization as well as the MILC collaboration for providing the configurations used. TB and MG are supported in part by the US Department of Energy under Grant No. DE-FG02- 92ER40716 and Grant No. DE-FG03-92ER40711. MG has also been supported in part by the Spanish Ministerio de Educación , Cultura y Deporte, under program SAB2011-0074. SP is supported by CICYTFEDER-FPA2011-25948, SGR2009-894, the Spanish</p>
				<figure>
					<trash>Ingenio 2010 Program CPAN (CSD2007-00042).</trash>
				</figure>
			</div>

		<div type="annex">
				<p>Appendix A: Vacuum polarization at one loop</p>

				<p>In this Appendix, we verify the WTI and the occurence of the quadratic divergence in Π µν (x − y) at one loop. We set a = 1 again. At one loop, the vacuum polarization of Eq. (3.8) is just that in the theory of free quarks, and, using the Feynman rules for naive</p>

		</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Blum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">052001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Lautrup</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Peterman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>De Rafael</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nuovo</forename>
				<surname>Cim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<biblScope unit="page">238</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Blum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Hayakawa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Izubuchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Della</forename>
				<surname>Morte</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Jä</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Jü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Wittig</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">JHEP 1203</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page">055</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Bedaque</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">593</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">82</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>De Divitiis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Petronzio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Tantalo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">595</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">408</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Sachrajda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Villadoro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">609</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">73</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Della</forename>
				<surname>Morte</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Jü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Shintani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Aoki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Fukaya</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Kaneko</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Onogi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yamada</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">074505</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Karsten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Smit</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">183</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">103</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
