<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Leading-order hadronic contribution to the anomalous magnetic moment of the muon from N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass fermions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 29 -August 3, 2013 15 Nov 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Florian</forename>
								<surname>Burger</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: florian.burger@physik.hu-berlin.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Xu</forename>
								<surname>Feng</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Grit</forename>
								<surname>Hotzel</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Karl</forename>
								<surname>Jansen</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Marcus</forename>
								<surname>Petschlies</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: m.petschlies@cyi.ac.cy</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Dru</forename>
								<forename type="middle">B</forename>
								<surname>Renner</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Institut für Physik</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>D-12489</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">High Energy Accelerator Research Organization (KEK)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>305-0801</postCode>
									<settlement>Tsukuba</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Institut für Physik</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>D-12489</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">DESY</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">NIC</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Plantanenallee 6</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-15738</postCode>
									<settlement>Zeuthen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Jefferson Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Cyprus Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>12000 Jefferson Avenue</addrLine>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 27456</postBox>
									<postCode>1645, 23606</postCode>
									<settlement>Nicosia, Newport News, Mainz</settlement>
									<region>VA</region>
									<country>Cyprus, USA, Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Leading-order hadronic contribution to the anomalous magnetic moment of the muon from N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass fermions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">July 29 -August 3, 2013 15 Nov 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>DESY 13-222, HU-EP-13/67, SFB/CPP-13-94 31st International Symposium on Lattice Field Theory -LATTICE 2013 * Speaker. † Current address: Los Alamos National Laboratory c Copyright owned by the author(s) under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike Licence.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present results for the leading order QCD correction to the anomalous magnetic moment of the muon including the first two generations of quarks as dynamical degrees of freedom. Several light quark masses are examined in order to yield a controlled extrapolation to the physical pion mass. We analyse ensembles for three different lattice spacings and several volumes in order to investigate lattice artefacts and finite-size effects, respectively. We also provide preliminary results for this quantity for two flavours of mass-degenerate quarks at the physical value of the pion mass. Leading hadronic contribution to (g − 2) µ from N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass fermions Grit Hotzel</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>In search of physics beyond the standard model (SM) of elementary particle interactions, the anomalous magnetic moment of the muon, a µ , is considered as one promising quantity which might disclose the nature of this new physics. There exists a discrepancy between the experimental determination [1, 2] of this observable and the SM calculation varying between 2.4σ [3] and 4.9σ [4]. The big variation in the significance of the difference arises from the determination of the hadronic contribution, a had µ , in the theoretical computation, since this cannot be computed reliably in perturbation theory and therefore usually a dispersion relation is applied which relates a had µ to other experimental data. Hence, for the standard method employed so far the theoretical determination of this important quantity depends not only on various model assumptions but also on the choice of experimental data.</p>

				<p>In recent years, it has been shown that the lattice formulation of QCD constitutes a firstprinciple , ab-initio alternative to quantify at least the leading-order hadronic contribution to a had µ due to the insertion of the hadronic vacuum polarisation [5, 6, 7, 8], a hvp µ , which currently is the largest source of uncertainty in the SM calculation. These older computations, however, only took up to N f = 2 + 1 dynamical quark flavours into account. Therefore, they could not unambiguously be compared with the results from the dispersive analyses because those as well as the experimentally obtained values for a µ at the current level of precision are sensitive to the complete first two generations of quarks. We remedy this shortcoming by performing computations on ensembles incorporating N f = 2 + 1 + 1 dynamical twisted-mass fermions generated by the European Twisted Mass Collaboration (ETMC) [9]. Preliminary results have been presented at Lattice 2012 [10]. Here, we additionally investigate systematic effects and for the first time attempt to perform the continuum limit. In particular, we check the validity of our chiral extrapolation performed along the lines of Ref. [7] for the light quark contribution, a hvp µ,ud , by comparing the extrapolated value at the physical point with the outcome of the calculation on an N f = 2 ensemble featuring the physical pion mass [11]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Basic Definitions</head>

				<p>The leading-order hadronic contribution to the muon anomalous magnetic moment can be computed directly in Euclidean space-time [5]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a hvp µ = α 2 ∞ 0 dQ 2 Q 2 w Q 2 m 2 µ Π R (Q 2 ) (2.1) from the known function w and the renormalised vacuum polarisation function Π R (Q 2 ) = Π(Q 2 ) − Π(0) . (2.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The vacuum polarisation function is related to the vacuum polarisation tensor by the requirement of transversity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Π µν (Q) = (Q µ Q ν − Q 2 δ µν )Π(Q 2 ) . (2.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Therefore, we first have to determine the vacuum polarisation tensor. It is given by the correlator of two electromagnetic vector currents.</p>

				<p>Leading hadronic contribution to (g − 2) µ from N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass fermions</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Grit Hotzel</head>

				<p>Details on the lattice calculation as well as on the four-flavour twisted-mass ensembles analysed for this work can be found in [12]. Besides those N f = 2 + 1 + 1 ensembles we have also performed the calculation of the light quark contribution on a new N f = 2 ensemble possessing a pion mass very close to its physical value. For details concerning this ensemble we refer to [11]. Since the N f = 2 + 1 + 1 ensembles exhibit pion masses m PS ≥ 227 MeV, the question of how to extrapolate to the physical point still remains important for our computation of a hvp µ . As mentioned before, we closely follow Ref. [7] and use a modified lattice definition</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a hvp µ = α 2 ∞ 0 dQ 2 Q 2 w Q 2 H 2 H 2 phys m 2 µ Π R (Q 2 ) (2.4) which goes to a hvp</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>µ for m PS → m π , i.e. when the hadronic scale H determined at unphysical pion masses, m PS , attains its physical value H phys . This can also be viewed as a lattice redefinition of the muon mass m µ = m µ · H H phys . (2.5)</p>

				<p>For the sake of consistency, we will always use H = m V , the unphysical ρ-meson mass, even for the contributions originating from the heavy quark currents. As mentioned before, the target of the lattice computation is the determination of the vacuum polarisation function in order to use this as input for the integrals in Eqs. (2.1) and (2.4). Recently, there have been several suggestions for fitting the vaccuum polarization function [13, 14]. Our way of performing the fits is described in detail in [12]. Note that this differs from what is referred to as VMD+ (vector meson dominance plus a linear term in Q 2 ) in [14]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>3. Results 3.1 The light quark contribution, a hvp µ,ud a = 0.061 fm, L = 2.9 fm a = 0.061 fm, L = 1.9 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 3.7 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 2.5 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 1.9 fm a = 0.086 fm, L = 2.8 fm N f = 2 result m 2 PS GeV 2 a ud µ 0.25 0.2 0.15 0.1 0.05 0 6e-08 5.5e-08 5e-08 4.5e-08 4e-08 3.5e-08 3e-08 2.5e-08 2e-08</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Light-quark contribution to a</figDesc>
					<trash>hvp µ on N f = 2 + 1 + 1 sea. CL with linear fit in a 2 CL with constant fit data extrapolated to mπ a 2 fm 2 a ud µ 0.01 0.008 0.006 0.004 0.002 0 6.5e-08 6e-08 5.5e-08 5e-08 4.5e-08</trash>

					<head>Figure 2:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Continuum extrapolation of a hvp µ,ud .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The contribution of the valence up and down quarks to the total a hvp µ on the four-flavour sea is depicted in Fig. 1. Here, we have employed the redefiniton of Eq. (2.4), a hvp µ,ud , with H = m V , the unphysical value of the ρmass. The extrapolation to the physical point can be performed by a simple linear fit in the squared pseudo-scalar mass (black dotted line with light-grey error band). For comparison we also show the result of a quadratic fit (dark-green solid line with dark-grey error band). A fit including an a 2 -term gives a coefficient of this term which is compatible with zero. This finding is also corroborated by first extrapolating linearly to the physical point for each individual lattice spacing and then taking the limit a → 0 as can be seen in Fig. 2. Hence, at the current level of accuracy of our data we cannot distinguish lattice artefacts in a hvp µ,ud and thus extrapolate the data from lattices of different lattice spacings simultaneously.</p>

				<p>Comparing the result of our linear fit with the one obtained on a two-flavour sea [7]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a hvp µ,ud = 5.67(11) · 10 −8 (N f = 2 + 1 + 1) a hvp µ,ud = 5.72(16) · 10 −8 (N f = 2) , (3.1</trash>

					<figDesc>) we find compatible results showing that the influence of the heavy sea quarks on the light valence quark contribution is small. This together with the finding that we cannot discriminate lattice artefacts at the moment allows us to check the validity of the redefinition and our chiral extrapolation by performing the calculation directly at the physical point for our new N f = 2 ensemble [11]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. a = 0.061 fm, L = 2.9 fm a = 0.061 fm, L = 1.9 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 3.7 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 2.5 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 1.9 fm a = 0.086 fm, L = 2.</p>

				<p><formula>8 fm N f = 2 result Preliminary m 2 PS GeV 2 a ud µ 0.25 0.2 0.15 0.1 0.05 0 6.0e-08 5.0e-08 4.0e-08 3.0e-08 2.0e-08 1.0e-08 0.0e+00</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3:</head>

					<figDesc>Light-quark contribution to a hvp µ with filled symbols representing points obtained with Eq. (2.4) and open symbols obtained using Eq. (2.1).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Fig. 3 besides the results already shown in Fig. 1 also the values obtained with the standard definition Eq. (2.1) are depicted as open symbols. In particular, the preliminary value at the physical point has been computed employing Eq. (2.1) and agrees within its rather large uncertainty with the result obtained by linearly extrapolating the two-flavour results on the four-flavour sea. This provides confidence in the validity of the redefinition in Eq. (2.4) and the related simple linear extrapolation in the squared pion mass.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>3.2</head>

				<p>The three-flavour contribution, a hvp µ,uds</p>

				<p>Adding the strange quark in the valence sector, we find that lattice artefacts can no longer be neglected as shown in Fig. 4. Here, only the contribution of the strange quark, a hvp µ,s , at a fixed pion mass of about 320 MeV is depicted. We have again used our redefinition Eq. (2.4) with the ρ-meson mass as hadronic scale H. This observation is confirmed when performing a combined chiral and Leading hadronic contribution to (g − 2) µ from N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass fermions</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Grit Hotzel</head>

				<p>continuum extrapolation as we now get a non-zero coefficient of the a 2 term. In the following, we use this combined extrapolation to obtain the results at the physical point in the continuum limit</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a µ (m PS , a) = A + B m 2 PS +C a 2 (3.2) with A, B,C denoting the free parameters of the fit. CL with linear fit data at fixed mPS ≈ 320 MeV 2 a 2 fm 2 a s µ 0.01 0.008 0.006 0.004 0.002 0 1.1e-08 1.0e-08 9.0e-09 8.0e-09 7.0e-09 6.0e-09 5.0e-09</trash>

					<head>Figure 4:</head>

					<figDesc>Continuum extrapolation of a</figDesc>
					<trash>hvp µ,s at m PS ≈ 320 MeV. a µ (m PS , 0.086 fm) a µ (m PS , 0.078 fm) a µ (m PS , 0.061 fm) a = 0.086 fm, L = 2.8 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 3.7 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 2.5 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 1.9 fm a = 0.061 fm, L = 2.9 fm a = 0.061 fm, L = 1.9 fm dispersive analysis &amp; pheno a → 0 result m 2 PS GeV 2 a uds µ 0.25 0.2 0.15 0.1 0.05 0 7e-08 6e-08 5e-08 4e-08 3e-08 2e-08</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 5:</head>

					<figDesc>Three-flavour contribution to a hvp</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>µ . The phenomenological value is extracted from [15] assuming quark-hadron duality.</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Fig. 5 our three-flavour value obtained in this way in the limit a → 0 is represented by the red triangle slightly displaced from the physical pion mass to facilitate the comparison with the dispersive result. However, in order to compare the three-flavour contribution with a result from a dispersive analysis, we need to disentangle the quark flavours. There are different possibilities to carry out such a reweighting of the total a hvp µ from a dispersive analysis. We have reweighted the values given in [15] with the sum of squared charges of the active flavours assuming quark-hadron duality. We indicate by the abbreviation &quot; pheno &quot; that a certain phenomenological analysis has been employed.</p>

				<p>Comparing our lattice result with this phenomenological extraction method leads to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a hvp µ,uds = 6.55(21) · 10 −8 (N f = 2 + 1 + 1) a hvp µ,uds = 6.79(05) · 10 −8 (pheno) (3.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we find, at least within the errors, an agreement. Our three-flavour result is also compatible with the other lattice computations of Refs. [8]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>3.3</head>

				<p>The four-flavour contribution, a hvp µ Incorporating the charm quark contribution according to Eq. (2.4) again using H = m V we are able to directly compare to experimental values and those from different dispersive analyses without the ambiguity of any additional phenomenological analysis. Since the charm quark is even heavier than the strange quark, we again use a combined fit of the form stated in Eq. (3.2). In this way, we arrive at the picture shown in Fig. 6. Here, our result obtained in the continuum limit and</p>

				<p>Leading hadronic contribution to (g − 2) µ from N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass fermions</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Grit Hotzel a µ (m PS , 0.086 fm) a µ (m PS , 0.078 fm) a µ (m PS , 0.061 fm) a = 0.086 fm, L = 2.8 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 3.7 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 2.5 fm a = 0.078 fm, L = 1.9 fm a = 0.061 fm, L = 2.9 fm a = 0.061 fm, L = 1.9 fm dispersive analysis a → 0 result m 2 PS GeV 2 a udsc µ 0.25 0.2 0.15 0.1 0.05 0 7e-08 6.5e-08 6e-08 5.5e-08 5e-08 4.5e-08 4e-08 3.5e-08 3e-08</trash>

					<head>Figure 6:</head>

					<figDesc>N f = 2 + 1 + 1 result for a</figDesc>
					<trash>hvp µ . Davier et al. (τ ) Davier et al. (e + e − ) Jegerlehner, Szafron Hagiwara et al. HLS estimate This work a hvp µ 7.4e-08 7.2e-08 7e-08 6.8e-08 6.6e-08</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 7:</head>

					<figDesc>Comparison of our first fourflavour lattice result of a</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>hvp µ with different results based on dispersion relations: Davier et al. [3], Jegerlehner and Szafron [16], Hagiwara et al. [17], and HLS [4] at the physical value of the pion mass, represented by the red triangle, can now be unambiguously confronted with the corresponding one from a dispersive analysis [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>
					<trash>a hvp µ = 6.74(21)(18) · 10 −8 (N f = 2 + 1 + 1) a hvp µ = 6.91(01)(05) · 10 −8 (dispersive analysis) . (3.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first uncertainty is of statistical nature whereas the second one is the systematic uncertainty, in our case from the choice of fit function and excited state contamination in the correlator fits. All other systematic effects investigated in [12] have been found to be negligible. Now a convincing agreement between the two ways of determining this important quantity is found. The value of the total a hvp µ can also be compared with the outcome of other calculations utilising a dispersion relation as shown in Fig. 7. Due to the larger uncertainty of the lattice calculation it is not yet possible to discriminate between the various phenomenological results.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Summary and Outlook</head>

				<p>In this proceeding contribution we have reported on the first four-flavour determination of the leading-order hadronic contribution to the muon anomalous magnetic moment including also for the first time the continuum limit of this quantity. The result agrees with various results employing the dispersion relation. However, the uncertainty of the lattice calculation is still about five times bigger than those of the dispersive analyses. This uncertainty includes an estimate of systematic effects. In particular, we have checked the chiral extrapolation of the light quark contribution by performing the computation on ETMC&apos;s new N f = 2 ensemble directly at the physical point.</p>

				<p>In order to be competitive with the phenomenological determinations of this fundamental quantity, we will have to improve the accuracy of our calculation. To this end, all-mode-averaging introduced in [18] looks like a promising method. We also plan to repeat the calculation on N f = 2 + 1 + 1 twisted mass ensembles featuring the physical value of the pion mass.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>We thank Andreas Ammon for providing us with the information of the matching K-and Dmeson masses in the mixed-action setup with their physical values. This work has been supported in part by the DFG Corroborative Research Center SFB/TR9. G.H. gratefully acknowledges the support of the German Academic National Foundation (Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes e.V.) and of the DFG-funded Graduate School GK 1504. K.J. was supported in part by the Cyprus Research Promotion Foundation under contract ΠPOΣEΛKYΣH/EMΠEIPOΣ/0311/16. This manuscript has been coauthored by Jefferson Science Associates, LLC under Contract No. DE-AC05-06OR23177 with the U.S. Department of Energy. The numerical computations have been performed on the SGI system HLRN-II at the HLRN Supercomputing Service Berlin-Hannover, FZJ/GCS, BG/P, and BG/Q at FZ-Jülich.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Bennett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Muon G-2 Collaboration]</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">072003</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Roberts</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chin. Phys. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">741</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Davier</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hoecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Malaescu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Zhang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1515</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Benayoun</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>David</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Delbuono</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Jegerlehner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2453</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Blum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">052001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Aubin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Blum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0608011</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">114502</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Feng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Jansen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Petschlies</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Renner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">081802</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Boyle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Debbio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Kerrane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Zanotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>Della Morte, B. Jäger, A. Jüttner and H. Wittig</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="074504" to="1203" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">111 [arXiv:1004</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Baron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Twisted Mass Collaboration Comput. Phys. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10065284</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">182</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">299</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Feng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hotzel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Jansen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Petschlies</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Renner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Kostrzewa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Twisted Mass Collaboration]</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Burger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Feng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hotzel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Jansen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Petschlies</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Renner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Aubin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Blum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Golterman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Peris</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">054509</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Maltman and S. Peris, arXiv:1309.2153 [hep-lat]; arXiv:1310</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Golterman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Jegerlehner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Suppl</title>
		<meeting>. Suppl</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="182" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Jegerlehner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Szafron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Eur</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1632</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hagiwara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Liao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Martin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Nomura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Teubner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. G</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">085003</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Blum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Izubuchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Shintani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
