<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Precision of future experiments measuring primordial tensor fluctuation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2014-08-05">5 Aug 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Yi</forename>
								<surname>Wang</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Centre for Theoretical Cosmology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">DAMTP</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CB3 0WA</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Yin-Zhe</forename>
								<surname>Ma</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Astronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z1</postCode>
									<settlement>Vancouver</settlement>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Precision of future experiments measuring primordial tensor fluctuation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2014-08-05">5 Aug 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term> forecaset</term>
					<term>B-mode polarization</term>
					<term>BICEP2</term>
					<term>tensor spectral index</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recently the second phase of Background Imaging of Cosmic Extragalactic Polarization (BICEP2) claimed a detection of the tensor-to-scalar ratio (r) of primordial fluctuation at 5σ confidence level. If it is true, this large and measurable amplitude (r ≃ 0.2) of B-mode polarization indicates that it is possible to measure the shape of CMB B-mode polarization with future experiments. We forecast the precision of r and the tensor spectral index nt measurements, with nt as a free parameter, from a Planck-like experiment, and from Spider and POLARBEAR given the current understanding of their experimental noise and foreground contamination. We quantitatively determine the signal-to-noise of the measurement in r-nt parameter space for the three experiments. The forecasted signal-to-noise ratio of the B-mode polarization somewhat depends on nt, but strongly depends on the true value of r.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>Introduction– Recently the BICEP2 experiment claimed a more than 5σ detection of CMB B-mode polarization [1]. This detection, if confirmed by ongoing and forthcoming experiments, implies a large amplitude of primordial tensor fluctuations and therefore has profound theoretical implications. For instance, given the current detected amplitude r = 0.2, the inflationary potential and the associated derivatives can be completely reconstructed around a few number of e-folds [3]. However , on the other hand, several other groups claimed recently that the BICEP2 results may come from the spurious signal of the polarized dust [2].</p>

				<p>Assuming the BICEP2 result is correct and therefore the primordial tensor fluctuation is measurable, it is possible to measure not only the amplitude but also the shape of the primordial tensor power spectrum with future experiment. The BICEP2 measured B-mode power spectrum has power excess at small scales, indicating a blue tilt (n t ) of the spectrum [26]. The statistical significance of such a blue tensor spectrum is found to be in between 1σ and 2σ [7, 8].</p>

				<p>The hint of blue n t becomes stronger when the BICEP2 data is combined with Wilkinson Microwave Anisotropy Probe (WMAP ) and Planck data [8–10]. In fact, before the tensor mode is detected, the theoretical prediction of temperature power spectrum is around 5%–10% higher than the measurement on ℓ &lt; 50 [11]. The detected tensor-to-scalar ratio r = 0.2 will further enhance the low-ℓ temperature power spectrum (C TT ℓ ) by 10% since the primordial gravitational wave preserves only on very large scales. This ensures that the standard model even more inconsistent with the observational data.</p>

				<p>The possibility of a blue power spectrum with positive n t can reconcile the tension between model and the * Electronic address: yw366@cam.ac.uk † Electronic address: mayinzhe@phas.ubc.ca data. With positive n t , the contribution to C TT ℓ (ℓ &lt; 50) is less than red tensor spectrum, making the model prediction more consistent with the data [12]. It has been shown that once n t is released to be a free parameter in the likelihood analysis, a positive n t is found to be at 3σ confidence level (CL) [10, 13]. A similar hint for a blue power spectrum is also found in the results of global fittings [14, 15]. Given the current BICEP2 constraints on r and n t , in this paper we will investigate how precisely the on-going and future experiments can measure these two parameters and therefore determine the tensor spectrum. Specifically , we will forecast the precision of measurement from a Planck-like full-sky CMB experiment [27], and from the Spider [16] and POLARBEAR [17] experiments with the current understanding of their experimental noise and foreground contamination. The primordial tensor power spectrum can be expanded in power law form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P t (k) = A t (k 0 ) k k 0 nt , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where k 0 is the pivot wave number at which n t and A t are evaluated. The amplitude of tensor power spectrum, A t (k 0 ) is related to the tensor-to-scalar ratio as given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>r = A t (k 0 ) A s (k 0 ) , (2) where A s (k 0 ) is the scalar amplitude at k 0 . In our data analysis, we use k 0 = 0.01 Mpc −1 . Then the power spectrum C BB ℓ is related to P t (k) by C BB ℓ = π 4 P t (k)∆ B ℓ (k) 2 d ln k, (3) where ∆ B ℓ (k</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is the transfer function for each multipole ℓ which can be obtained from public code camb [18].</p>

				<p>Constraining r and n t from BICEP2 and Planck data– Here we make use of the public code CosmoMC [19] to constraint r and n t . The other cosmological parameters are fixed at the best-fitting value from Planck. With BICEP2 data and marginalizing over r, we can obtain the likelihood on n t as 1.24 ± 0.90 (1σ CL). By combining BICEP2 data with Planck (2013) and WMAP polarization (WP) data, we find n t = 1.76 ± 0.54 (1σ CL). When marginalizing over n t , the likelihood on r are r = 0.20 ± 0.06 and r = 0.18 ± 0.05 at 1σ CL for BICEP2 only and BICEP2+Planck (2013)+WP, respectively . The 1σ and 2σ contours are plotted on Figure 1, where the blue contours are for BICEP2 only, and the red contours are for BICEP2+Planck (2013)+WP. It is worth noting that the inclusion of Planck (2013)+WP does not change the contour significantly at large positive n t part, but it sets strong limit on small n t . Therefore, the negative n t (red tilted power spectrum) is disfavored at more than 3σ CL. This is clearly inconsistent with the consistency relation of the single-field slow-roll inflation where n t is slightly negative given the current measurement of r. If the positive n t is found to be true, this clearly indicates some new physics for inflation.</p>

				<p>FIG. 1: Signal-to-noise ratio of Planck (black lines), Spider (purple lines) and POLARBEAR (orange lines) as functions of r and nt. Solid lines denote signal-to-noise ratio r/∆r = 5 and the dashed lines denote signal-to-noise ratio r/∆r = 3. Current observations are also plotted. Blue contours are the 1σ and 2σ constraints from BICEP2. Red contours are the combined constraints from BICEP2+Planck (2013)+WMAP polarization (WP). Current POLARBEAR 3σ exclusion region is plotted in green. Nearly vertical red dash-dotted line is the consistency relation r = −8nt predicted by the minimal model of inflation. Forecast for future experiments– The tensor-to-scalar ratio is claimed to be 0.18 at k 0 = 0.01 Mpc −1 by BICEP2 experiment [1]. It now is required to determine if n t</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 10 50 100 500 1000 10 7 10 5 0.001 0.1 10 1C BB 2Π ΜK 2 Spider POLARBEAR Future Planck noise Lensing Primordial nt0.025 Primordial nt2.6 Primordial nt0 r0.18 k 0 0.01 Mpc 1 FIG. 2: Comparison between B-mode polarization power spectra of models with nt = 0 (flat power spectrum), nt = −r/8 = −0.025 (consistency relation) and nt = 2.6 (2σ upper limit of current constraint) and noise level for Planck, Spider and PO- LARBEAR experiments. Purple dashed line is the B-mode signal induced by gravitational lensing (non-primordial). 5 10 50 100 500 1000 10 6 10 4 0.01 1 1C BB 2Π ΜK 2 BICEP2 POLARBEAR current Spider POLARBEAR Future Planck noise Primordial nt0.025Lensing Primordial nt2.6Lensing Primordial nt0Lensing r0.18 k0 0.01 Mpc 1 FIG. 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: Comparison between the total B-mode polarization power spectra (primordial plus lensing) of the same three models as described previously and noise level for Planck, Spider and POLARBEAR experiments. Brown and purple data with error-bars are the band-power data from the current experi- ments.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 10 50 100 500 1000 10 5 10 4 0.001 0.01 0.1 1 10 C BB C BB nt2, POLARBEAR nt1, POLARBEAR nt0, POLARBEAR nt2, Spider nt1, Spider nt0, Spider nt2, Planck nt1, Planck nt0, Planck r0.18 FIG. 4: Signal to noise (∆C BB ℓ is calculated through eq. (4)) at</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>each ℓ for Planck (solid lines), Spider (long-dashed lines) and POLARBEAR (short-dashed lines). Value of nt is taken to be 0 (red), 1 (blue) and 2 (black). Value of r is fixed to be 0.18 at pivot scale k0 = 0.</p>

				<p><formula>01 Mpc −1 . 0.2 0.1 0.05 0.02 1. 10. 5. 2. 20. 3. 1.5 15. 7. r rr POLARBEAR Planck Spider n t 0 1 0 1 2 3 10. 5. 20. 3. 15. 7. n t rr POLARBEAR Planck Spider r0.18</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 5: Predicted signal-to-noise of measurements of r for varying r (left panel) and nt (right panel).</p>

				<p><formula>0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 2.0 2.5 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 n t n t 0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 2.0 2.5 0 2 4 6 8 10 n t n t n t POLARBEAR, r0.1 POLARBEAR, r0.18 Spider, r0.1 Spider, r0.18 Planck, r0.1 Planck, r0.18</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 6: Predicted ∆nt (left panel) and signal-to-noise |nt|/∆nt (right panel) for varying nt, with r = 0.18 and r = 0.1.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Model Experiment ℓ ≤ 100 100 &lt; ℓ &lt; 3000 Planck 7.57 1.98 n t = 0 Spider 14.89 4.18 POLARBEAR 8.41 6.59 Planck 5.65 2.72 n t = 1 Spider 12.87 5.28 POLARBEAR 8.27 9.64 Planck 5.87 5.70 n t = 2 Spider 13.48 8.55 PPOLARBEAR 8.50 22.8</trash>

					<figDesc>TABLE I: Signal-to-noise ratio of the two bands for three</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>experiments, i.e., SNR= ℓmax ℓ min (C BB ℓ /∆C BB ℓ ) 2</formula></p>

				<p>varies, how precisely can future experiments measure the B-mode polarization.</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Figure 2, we plot the theoretical prediction of C BB ℓ with three n t values, using three different noise levels.</p>

				<p>The first corresponds to that of a Planck-like experiment having the idealised noise performance described in Ref. [22], and the second and third to the Spider and POLARBEAR experiments. We note that for the Plancklike experiment, we have not attempted to model the real performance of Planck, or the effects of systematics, and so every time &apos;Planck&apos; is mentioned below in the context of forecasted results, this refers to results from an idealised Planck-like experiment only. We choose the three representative values of n t : (1) n t = 0, flat tensor spectrum (red solid line); (2) n t = −r/8, the n t value that satisfies the consistency relation for single-field slow-roll inflation model [20] (green solid line); (3) n t = 2.6, the current 3σ upper limit of Planck+BICEP2 constraint (blue dashed line). We can see that the n t = −r/8 = −0.025 line does not differ significantly from the flat tensor spectrum. However, as n t becomes more positive, the C BB ℓ tends to have more powers on small scales and less power on large scales, due to the blue tilted power spectrum. In addition, we follow the recipes in ref. [21] to calculate the noise level of the each experiment. It has been seen that Spider has lower noise than Planck at low-ℓ, but the effective noise blows up at high ℓ because of the large beam. The noise from POLARBAER is systematically lower than Planck and Spider, making it a powerful measurement on primordial tensor mode. We also plot the gravitational lensing signal as the purple dashed line in Figure 2. The gravitational lensing can convert primordial E mode into B mode, therefore add an effective noise to the true primordial B-mode signal. In Figure 2, we can see that this signal peaks at ℓ ≈ 1000 which is the typical galaxy cluster scale. The C len ℓ is fixed with a certain set of cosmological parameters and therefore can be outputted from camb [18].</p>

			<div>
				<head>In Figure 3</head>

				<p>, we plot the added signal of primordial tensor mode with gravitational lensing, and the current measurement from BICEP2 [1] and POLARBAER [17]. We can see that current data is consistent with the tensor mode with amplitude r = 0.18, while it still allows a fairly large range of spectral index n t .</p>

				<p>Assuming each ℓ is independent, uncertainties of each ℓ of B-mode polarization power spectrum is computed as:</p>

				<p><formula>∆C BB ℓ = 2 (2ℓ + 1)f sky C BB ℓ + N BB ℓ , (4)</formula></p>

				<p>where N ℓ is the effective noise of each experiment, which includes the instrumental noise, residual foreground contamination , and the gravitational lensing. The value of f sky is the effective area of sky that each experiment observes , which are 0.65, 0.5, 0.024 for Planck [22], Spider [16] and POLARBEAR [17], respectively.</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Figure 4, we plot the signal-to-noise of each ℓ for the three experiments. We can see that for each experiment, as the n t value becomes more positive, one gains less signal to noise from large scales, but more from small scales. The Spider experiment, because of the large beam, cannot obtain consistent result on large ℓs, but its measurement on low-ℓ is better than that of Planck. The future POLARBEAR experiment is better than both Spider and Planck. We list the contribution to total signal to noise from ℓ ≤ 100 and ℓ &gt; 100 in Table I.</p>

				<p>Let us forecast for the constraints achievable with future experiments. With the assumption that each parameter is Gaussian-distributed, we calculate the Fisher matrix F αβ [23, 24] such that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F αβ = 1 2 Tr[C ,α C −1 C ,β C −1 ], (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where C is the total covariance matrix, which includes both signal and noise contributions. In case of B-mode only, where each ℓ and m mode is independent of each other, then</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C ℓ1m1ℓ2m2 = (C BB ℓ1 + N BB ℓ1 )δ ℓ1ℓ2 δ m1m2 . (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this case, the Fisher matrix can be simplified [23, 24] as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F αβ = ℓmax ℓ=ℓmin 2ℓ + 1 2 f sky (C BB ℓ ) ,α (C BB ℓ ) ,β (C BB ℓ + N BB ℓ ) 2 . (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For Planck and Spider experiment, since the observation is nearly full sky, we perform the summation in eq. (7) to be ℓ min = 2 till ℓ max = 3000. For the ground-based POLARBEAR, the summation is performed from ℓ min = 21 to ℓ max = 3000, since POLARBEAR cannot cover the largest angular scales because of the corresponding finite survey areas.</p>

				<p>The inverse of the Fisher matrix F −1 can be regarded as the best achievable covariance matrix for the parameters given the experimental specification. The Cramer- Rao inequality suggests that no unbiased method can measure the ith parameter with an uncertainty less than 1/ √ F ii [23]. If the other parameters are not known and considered as free parameters, the minimum standard deviation is (F −1 ) 1/2 ii [23]. Therefore the best prospective signal-to-noise ratio can be estimated as α/∆α, where ∆α = (F</p>

				<p><formula>−1 ) 1/2 αα .</formula></p>

				<p>In the left panel of Figure 5, we plot the r/∆r as a function of true value of r. We can see that the higher the value of r is, the more signal to noise one can obtain from each experiment. The POLARBEAR and Spider experiments provide stronger constraints on r than Planck.</p>

				<p>In the right panel of Figure 5, we vary the value of n t and calculate the r/∆r for each assumed value of n t . It can be seen that the for Planck, the measured signal to noise of r is not exceedingly sensitive to the true value of n t . But for Spider, as the n t value becomes bigger, the signal to noise decreases because Spider is incapable of measuring high-ℓ power accurately. For POLARBEAR, the signal to noise of r is all high across all values of n t .</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Figure 6, we plot the noise ∆n t and the signal-tonoise ratio n t /∆n t respectively, for varying n t . In the left panel of Figure 6, ∆n t is about 0.1 near n t = 0. Thus it is still challenging for the upcoming experiments to measure the inflationary consistency relation (if n t = −r/8). In the right panel of Figure 6, It can be seen that assuming r ≥ 0.1 and n t ∼ 1, Planck and Spider are able to confirm the hint for positive n t and POLARBEAR will be sufficiently precise to make a detection.</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Figure 1, we put together the current joint constraints with the forecasted signal-to-noise measurement of parameters r-n t . The green region is the excluded by current POLARBEAR experiment at 3σ CL, while the blue and purple contours are the BICEP2 only and Planck +WMAP Polarization(WP)+BICEP2 data. It can be seen that the joint constraint favors a positive range of n t values. We also plot the r/∆r = 5 and 3 lines in the same figure for Planck, POLARBEAR and Spider experiments. Comparing Planck forecasted lines with the current constraints, one can see only if r &lt; 0.1 and 2 &lt; n t &lt; 3 Planck may not be able to constrain r at 3σ CL. In all other parameter ranges, Planck can constrain the value better than 3σ CL. Specifically, if r &gt; 0.15, Planck should be able to measure it in more than 5σ CL. Spider and POLARBEAR can do much better than Planck since they can measure nearly the whole parameter space with r &gt; 0.05 in more 5σ CL. In addition, as we can see from Figure 1, there is a possibility for future experiments to test the inflationary consistency relation as shown in dashed (nearly vertical) line. But current Planck +BICEP2+WP data favors a large positive value, which does not cover this line at 2σ CL. Therefore, future experiments will set up a rigorous test on this consistency relation. Conclusions– The B-mode polarization power spectrum is a unique probe of the primordial tensor fluctuations . Current observations BICEP2 claim that the tensor-to-scalar ratio r is 0.18 at 0.01 Mpc −1 . If BICEP2 data is correct, n t is constrained to be n t = 1.24 ± 0.90 (1σ CL) for BICEP2 only, indicating a blue tensor spectrum . By combining the BICEP2 data with Planck data and WMAP polarization data, we find n t = 1.76 ± 0.54 (1σ CL).</p>

				<p>Assuming the true value of r is large and detectable, we forecast the detectability of the parameters r and n t for a Planck -like experiment with the same noise as projected in Ref. [22], and for balloon-borne Spider data and ground-base POLARBEAR data with the current understanding the foreground emission and their experimental noise. We used the Fisher matrix to calculate the forecasted signal-to-noise ratio. We found that if r &gt; 0.1 and 2 &lt; n t &lt; 3, Planck can measure r in more than 3σ confidence level. POLARBEAR and Spider data are even more powerful than Planck, since they can measure nearly the whole parameter space r &gt; 0.05 by more than 5σ CL. The detectability of tensor-to-scalar ratio r for Planck, Spider and POLARBEAR is relatively independent on the details value of n t since the r/∆r = 3 and 5 lines in Figure 1 are nearly horizontal. However, we caution the reader that if the BICEP2 result is found to be largely due to uncleaned polarized foreground, the true value of r could be significant less than 0.2. In this case, the signal-to-noise lines of r in Figure. 1 will be very low and might be undetectable. In addition, in our study, we do not consider the running of spectral index (dn t /d ln k) for tensor power spectrum, which in principle , can be nonzero if the spectral index is large. In addition, successful delensing can significantly boost the signal-to-noise ratio, particularly when n t is positive [25], which is beyond the scope of this paper.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>Acknowledgments– We thank BAUMANN D. and ZHAO W. for helpful discussions. This work was supported by a CITA National Fellowship, a Starting Grant of the European Research Council (ERC STG Grant No. 279617) and the Stephen Hawking Advanced Fellowship . Part of this work was undertaken on the COS- MOS Shared Memory system at DAMTP, University of Cambridge operated on behalf of the STFC DiRAC HPC Facility. This equipment was funded by BIS National E-infrastructure capital grant ST/J005673/1 and STFC grants ST/H008586/1, ST/K00333X/1.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">BICEP2 I: Detection Of B-mode polarization at degree angular scales. arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Bicep2</forename>
				<surname>Collaboration</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Toward an Understanding of Foreground Emission in the BICEP2 Region</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Colin</forename>
				<surname>Flauger R</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Spergel</forename>
				<surname>Hill J</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reconstructing the local potential of inflation with BICEP2 data. arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Wang</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evidence for bouncing evolution before inflation after BICEP2. arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
				<surname>Xia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Non- singular bouncing cosmologies in light of BICEP2</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Quintin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Saridakis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exploring bouncing cosmologies with cosmolog- ical surveys. Sci China-Phys Mech Astron</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="1111" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blue gravity waves from BICEP2? arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gerbino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marchini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Pagano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inflation and alternatives with blue tensor spectra. arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Xue</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Non-bunch-Davis initial state reconciles chaotic models with BICEP and Planck. arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ashoorioon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Dimopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sheikh-Jabbari M M</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">6099</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On quantifying and resolving the BICEP2/Planck tension over gravita- tional waves</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Smith</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Dvorkin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Boyle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Planck 2013 results. XV. CMB power spectra and likelihood arXiv:1303</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Planck</forename>
				<surname>Collaboration</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pre-inflationary genesis with CMB B-mode polarization. arXiv:1405.1188 [astro- ph</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z-G</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y-S</forename>
				<surname>Piao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CO</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Testing quantum gravity effects with latest CMB observations. arXiv:1404</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Wang</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cosmological parameter fittings with the BICEP2 data. arXiv:1403</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Wu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Lu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Global fitting analysis on cos- mological models after BICEP2</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
				<surname>Xia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Zhang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SPIDER: A balloon-borne large-scale CMB polarimeter</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Crill</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ade</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P A R</forename>
				<surname>Battistelli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SPIE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7010</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">79</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A measurement of the cos- mic microwave background B-mode polarization power spectrum at sub-degree scales with POLARBEAR</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Polarbear</forename>
				<surname>Collaboration</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient computation of cosmic microwave background anisotropies in closed Friedmann-Robertson-Walker models Cosmological parameters from CMB and other data: A Monte Carlo approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Lewis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Challinor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Lasenby</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys J Phys Rev D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">538</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="476" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cold dark matter density perturbation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Liddle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Lyth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rept</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">231</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing early Universe models from B-mode polarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Zhao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Brown</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Cosmol Astropart Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">007</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planck: The scientific programme</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Planck</forename>
				<surname>Collaboration</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Space Agency No. ESA–SCI</title>
		<editor>Efstathiou G</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ESA Publications, No- ordwijk</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>ESA Publications, No- ordwijk</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Karhunen-Loeve eigen- value problems in cosmology: How should we tackle large data sets</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tegmark</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Taylor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Heavens</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">480</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring cosmological parameters with galaxy surveys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tegmark</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3806" to="3809" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gravitational lensing as a contam- inant of the gravity wave signal in CMB</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Seljak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Hirata</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">043005</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The preliminary cross-correlation between BICEP2 and the Keck array does not support such power excess. However, the BICEP2-Keck cross correlation has power deficit at large scales, which also slightly prefers a blue tensor spectrum; For other possible explanations, see, for example, refs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We use the Planck noise model in [22] to forecast the constraints, which may differ from the real Planck exper- iment noise model. So here we call it a Planck-like exper- iment, though for brevity it will continue to be labelled &apos;Planck&apos; in most of the following discussion</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
