<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">τ → µµ¯ µ and τ → µe¯ e Decays in String Models with E 6 Symmetry</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1992-12">Dec 1992 Nov. 1992</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Jizhi</forename>
								<surname>Wu</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>TX77843</postCode>
									<settlement>College Station</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Shinichi</forename>
								<surname>Urano</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>TX77843</postCode>
									<settlement>College Station</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Richard</forename>
								<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>TX77843</postCode>
									<settlement>College Station</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">τ → µµ¯ µ and τ → µe¯ e Decays in String Models with E 6 Symmetry</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1992-12">Dec 1992 Nov. 1992</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A detailed analysis on the rare τ decay via τ → µe¯ e and τ → µµ¯ µ in the string models with E 6 symmetry is reported. It is found that Γ(τ → µe¯ e) ∼ (6 − 7)Γ(τ → µµ¯ µ) and these rates are in general about 1000 times less than that of Γ(µ → eγ). It is also found that the outgoing muon in τ → µe¯ e is almost 100% right-handed polarized and the outgoing electrons would be predominately parallel to each other. These decay processes may be accessible at the SSC.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The existence of a huge number of the degenerate vacua makes it difficult to investigate the experimental consequences of the superstring theory. Nevertheless, progress has already been made in extracting the phenomenological implications of the heterotic string models [1,2,3], despite the lack of a theoretical frame work to determine the true vacuum of the theory. Here, one takes a less fundamental attitude by imposing the phenomenological requirements that the theory must reduce to the standard model at low energies [4].</p>

				<p>In this paper, we focus on a class of three-generation heterotic string models which have a symmetry structure</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E 6 × (N = 1 Supergravity) × (Hidden Sector) (1.1) at the compactification scale M C close to the Planck scale M PL = 2.4 × 10 18 GeV. This class</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>of models arises naturally from the compactifications of the ten dimensional heterotic string [5] on the Calabi-Yau manifolds [6], and from the N=2 superconformal constructions [7], which allow for the breaking of the E 6 group to [SU(3)] 3 ≡ SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>by</head>

				<p>Wilson loops at M C . The massless multiplets are then in the 27, 27 and singlet representations of E 6 .</p>

				<p>In terms of the [SU(3)] 3 quantum numbers, these states are:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>27 i = L i (1, 3, ¯ 3) ⊕ Q i (3, ¯ 3, 1) ⊕ Q c i ( ¯ 3, 1, 3); 27 j = ¯ L j (1, ¯ 3, 3) ⊕ ¯ Q j ( ¯ 3, 3, 1) ⊕ ¯ Q c j (3, 1, ¯ 3), (1.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where i, j are generation indices, i.e., i = 1, 2, · · · , n+3, j = 1, 2, · · · , n for a three generation model. The notations for these massless multiplets, in terms of the Standard Model particle notation, are L = [l = (ν, e); e</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c ; H; H ′ ; ν c , N ], Q = [q a = (u a , d a ); H a 3 ≡ D a ] and Q c = [q c a = (u c a , d c a ); H ′ 3a ≡ D c a ], where l, H, H ′ and q a are SU(2) L doublets, e c , u c a and d c a are the conjugate singlets, D a and D c a are the color Higgs triplets of the SU(5) 5 and ¯ 5 representations (a = 1, 2, 3 is the SU(3) C index), ν c is a SU(5) singlet and N an O(10) singlet.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The breaking of the [SU(3)] 3 into the standard model gauge group can be achieved by the VEV growth of the standard model singlet fields ν c and N at a lower scale M I &gt; ∼ O(10 16 )</p>

				<p>GeV.</p>

				<p>In order to prevent too rapid decay of the proton, the structure of the couplings must preserve matter parity [8] at M PL . Then, it can be proved [9] that the spontaneous breaking of [SU(3)] 3 symmetry to the standard model SU(3) C × SU(2) L × U(1) Y , triggered by the nonrenormalizable interactions and the supersymmetry breaking mass of O(1 TeV), occurs at an intermediate scale M I &gt; ∼ O(10 16 ) GeV in a way such that the lowest lying extremum of the effective potential is the one that preserves simultaneously both SU(2) × U (1) and matter parity. This breaking is accomplished in one step in the sense that N i and ν c i must grow VEV&apos;s at the same time and with the same order of magnitude O(M I ).</p>

				<p>The following theorem regarding the low energy spectrum below the intermediate scale was established in Ref. [2]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Theorem For any string model having the symmetry structure of Eq. (1.1) and a matter parity invariance at the Plank scale with (i) Breaking of E 6 → [SU(3)] 3 ≡ SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R at a scale M C ∼ M PL , (ii) Intermediate scale breaking of [SU(3)] 3 → SU(3) C × SU(2) L × U(1) Y at a scale M I , where M PL &gt; M I &gt; 10 16 GeV, triggered by a mass m &lt; O(1 TeV), and (iii) VEVs of N i , ν c i obeying N i ν c i = 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, then there exist, in addition to the three generations of light states of the Standard Model, always at least two new non-E 6 singlet light chiral multiplets given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n 1 = (N 1 + ¯ N 1 )/ √ 2, ˆ ν c 2 = (ν c 2 + ¯ ν c 2 )/ √ 2, (1.3) and in some cases four new non-E 6 singlet light chiral multiplets, with the additional possible light state given by n 2 = cosθN 2 + sinθ¯ ν c 1 , ¯ n 2 = cosθ ¯ N 2 + sinθν c 1 . (1.4) Here tanθ = ν c 2 /N 1 , and a basis has been chosen in generation space such that N i = N 1 δ i1 and ν c i = ν c 2 δ i2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In addition there may also be a number of light E 6 singlet multiplets, φ a .</p>

				<p>We will investigate the phenomenological consequences of this theorem in this paper.</p>

				<p>In Sec. 2., we discuss the interactions of these new particles with the standard model particles [10,2] and their implications on rare τ and µ decays. Sec. 3 briefly summarizes the results of Ref. [3] on the fermion family violating processes τ → µγ and µ → eγ. Sec. 4. represents a detailed analysis on the decays of τ particle via τ → µµ¯ µ and τ → µe¯ e where the conclusion is reached that these decay processes may be accessible at the SSC. Sec.5. is devoted to conclusions. 2. Low-Energy Effective Interactions and τ and µ Decays The appearance of the new light particles can be regarded as the low energy remnants of the Planck scale physics dictated by superstring theory. Thus their detection, either direct or indirect, could be regarded as the confirmation of the dynamics induced by superstring theory. Since these new particles are Standard Model singlets and presumably have a large mass ∼ O(1 TeV) compared to the Standard Model particles, they are most likely to be detected indirectly by the new phenomena not predicted by the Standard Model, but which involve the Standard</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Model particles</head>

				<p>The interactions of these new particles can be determined by examining the mass matrix below M I and the Yukawa and gauge couplings. One finds then [10,2] from the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(27) 3 and (27) 3 pieces in the superpotential, W ef f =(λ (l) pp ′ H ′ e c p l p ′ + λ (u) pp ′ Hq p u c p ′ + λ (d) pp ′ H ′ q p d c p ′ ) + {[λ p Hl p n 2 + ¯ λ p Hl p ¯ n 2 + (λ 1 n 1 + ˆ λ 2 ˆ ν c 2 )HH ′ ] + (λ (0) ap φ (0) a Hl p + λ (e) ap φ (e) a H ′ H) + (m 1 n 2 ¯ n 2 + m 2 n 2 n 2 + m 3 ¯ n 2 ¯ n 2 ) + (m 4 n 1 ˆ ν c 2 + m 5 n 1 n 1 + m 6 ˆ ν c 2 ˆ ν c 2 ) + m ab φ a φ b } + W seesaw , (2.1) and from the gaugino (λ (−) L ) interaction L gaugino =g L U † pλ l p γ 0 [λ (g) pp ′ e c p ′ H † + 1 √ 2 (sn 1 − cˆ l † p=1 + (λ ′ n 2 + ¯ λ ′ ¯ n 2 )H ′ † + H(λn † 2 + ¯ λ¯ n † 2 )] + h.c., (2.2) where s = sin θ and c = cos θ. In eqs. (2.1) and (2.2), the λ&apos;s are various effective coupling</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>constants which are related to the elementary coupling constants by various unitary transformations onto the light fields. φ a = (φ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(0) a , φ (e)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>a ) are the C-odd, C-even E 6 -singlet fields that remain light. The H † , H ′ † , ˜ l † , etc., are scalar fields, e.g., ˜ l p=1 is the slepton partner of p = 1 lepton, where p = 1, 2, 3 are the three light generations of the Standard Model.</p>

				<p>The terms in the parentheses in Eq. (2.1) are just the low-energy Standard Model superpotential. Eq. (2.2) and the terms in the curly brackets in Eq. (2.1) are the interactions involving the new low-energy particles. These represent the new physics predicted by the heterotic string models that obey the Standard Model at low energies. There are also seesaw masses coming from ν p -Higgs boson-superheavy interactions, obtained by integrating out the heavy fields. The consequences of these terms for neutrino masses and neutrino oscillations were discussed in Ref. [1] where it was found that the experimental smallness of neutrino masses, m ν &lt; O(10 eV), leads to restrictions on Yukawa couplings that naturally explains the smallness of m e /m τ = O(10 −3 ), and the ν e,µ ↔ ν τ are the dominant oscillations. Here we are interested in the implications of these new particles and new couplings on the lepton family number violating processes such as τ and µ lepton decays channels.</p>

				<p>The interactions of the new light particles discussed above can trigger lepton family number violating processes such as τ → µγ, µ → eγ, τ → µµ¯ µ and τ → µe¯ e, not predicted by the Standard Model. Figure 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>demonstrates how τ → µγ arises from the n 1 and ν c 2 interactions. There are quite a few sources contributing to these processes: (i) ν</figDesc>
					<trash>c 2 and n 1 through the gaugino interactions Eq. (2.2): L g = −c g L √ 2 U † p(−) l p γ 0 ˆ ν c 2 ˜ l † p=1 + s g L √ 2 U † p(−) l p γ 0 n 1 ˜ l † p=1 , (2.3) where the unitary matrices U † p(−) are defined from the projection of the SU(3) L gauginos, λ (−) L , onto the light lepton doublets, λ (−) L = l p U † p(−) +heavy fields. This interaction is always present regardless what the E 6 singlet couplings are. (ii) n 2 and ¯ n 2 from W ef f W n 2 ¯ n 2 = λ p Hl p n 2 + ¯ λ p Hl p ¯ n 2 , (2.4) which is present if n 2 and ¯ n 2 also remain light. (iii) E 6 singlets φ (0) a give W φ = λ (0) ap φ (0) a l p H. (2.5) These are present provided φ (0) a remain light.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>An estimate on the relative sizes of these sources is given in Ref. [3]. Thus for the entire reasonable range of ε ≡ tan θ, i.e., 10 −3 &lt; ε &lt; 1, the dominant effects come from ν c 2 and n 1 which are always present independent of E 6 singlet couplings. Since thê ν c 2 and n 1 couplings hold for all models satisfying the conditions of the Theorem stated above, these decay processes are essentially a universal prediction for all phenomenologically acceptable models of this type. We shall hereafter consider only contributions from ν c 2 and n 1 and for simplicity we shall set their masses to a common valuê m. 3. µ → eγ and τ → µγ Decays These processes were studied in Ref. [3], we briefly summarize the results here. We may parametrize the µ → eγ decay by an effective</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>La- grangian L = e 4m µ F αβ ¯ µσ αβ (a (µ) R P R + a (µ) L P L )e + h.c. (3.1)</trash>

					<figDesc>where µ(x) and e(x) are the lepton fields. The coefficients a L and a R were determined to</figDesc>
					<trash>be a (µ) R ≃ α 8π sin 2 θ w m µ ˆ m 2 L(x) m e m τ (1 + r 2 ) 1/2 ε 4 a (µ) L = m e m µ a (µ) R ≪ a (µ) R (3.2) where x = m ˜ e / ˆ m 2 and L(x) is the loop integral L(x) = 1 (1 − x) 4 1 3 + 1 2 x − x 2 + 1 6 x 3 + x ln x (3.3) and r ∼ 3.5. The total decay rate is proportional to a 2 (µ) ≡ 1 / 2 (a 2 L + a 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>R ). A similar analysis for the τ → µγ decay yields a (τ ) = (m</figDesc>
					<trash>2 τ /m 2 µ )(δ 2 /ε) −1 a (µ) , where δ 2 is yet another</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>parameter of the E 6 model and maybe determined from the electron and tau lepton mass ratio, m e /m τ =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(δ 2 /ε)(1 + r 2 ) 1/2 [1]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The following relation is then obtained</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B(τ → µγ) = m τ m µ 5 m τ m µ 2 (1 + r 2 ) −1 Γ µ Γ τ B(µ → eγ), (3.4) which implies B(τ → µγ) ≃ 2 × 10 5</trash>

					<figDesc>B(µ → eγ). Thus the theory predicts a definite relation between the two lepton number violating decays. As a consequence of thê ν c 2 and n 1 couplings (which arise from the gaugino couplings), the out-going leptons would be almost 100% right-handed polarized. This leads to a characteristic angular distribution of the out-going leptons relative to the spin of the initial lepton even if the spin of the out-going lepton is not measured.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>4. τ → µµ¯ µ and τ → µe¯ e Decays These processes arise when the out-going photon in Figure 1 converts into an electron-positron pair or a muon-anti-muon pair. These processes cannot be described by an effective Lagrangian as simple as Eq. (3.1) which was obtained utilizing the fact that all the particles involved, in particular the outgoing photon, are on shell. Here, the intermediate photon is not on-shell, but we may still use the fact that the in-coming tau particle and the out-going muon arising from the gaugino vertex are on shell. Then the τ − µ − γ vertex can be written as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>J α (p, q) = −i eg 2 U † 2(−) U † 3(−) 64π 2 ˆ m 2 [P L (γ α F L + f α L ) + P R (γ α F R + f α R )] , (4.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where p and q are four-momenta for the in-coming τ and the out-going µ respectively,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P L,R = 1 / 2 (1 ∓ γ 5 ), and F L =2m µ m τ (L 2 (x) − L 3 (x)) (4.2a) f α L = − m µ (L 2 (x) − 2 3 L 3 (x))p α + (L 2 (x) − 4 3 L 3 (x))q α (4.2b) F R =(L 2 (x) − 4 3 L 3 (x))(m 2 τ + m 2 µ ) + 2 3 L 3 p · q (4.2c) f α R = − m τ (L 2 (x) − 4 3 L 3 (x))p α + (L 2 (x) − 2 3 L 3 (x))q α (4.2d) and L 2 and L 3 are loop integrals defined by L n (x) = 1 0 dy y n 1 + (x − 1)y , n = 2, 3, x = m 2 ˜ e ˆ m 2 . (4.3) Notice that F R and f α R are much larger than F L and f α L .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The differential decay rate for the process τ → µl ¯ l, where l denotes either electron or muon, is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dΓ(τ → µl ¯ l) = 1 2m τ |M| 2 d 3− → q 2E(2π) 3 d 3− → q 1 2E 1 (2π) 3 d 3− → q 2 2E 2 (2π) 3 (2π) 4 δ 4 (p − q − q 1 − q 2 ), (4.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where M is the amplitude. The total rate can be calculated from integrating over q, q 1 and q 2 . In the rest frame of the in-coming τ lepton, the total decay rate is reduced into the following form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dΓ(τ → µl ¯ l) = m 5 τ (4π) 3 ˆ m 4 e 2 g 2 L U † 2(−) U † 3(−) 4(4π) 2 2 |M ′ | 2 dE 1 dE 2 δ(cos β − f (E 1 , E 2 ))θ(1 − E 1 − E 2 − m µ ), (4.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where all the energy and masses are scaled by m τ , β is the angle between two out-going l</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>particles, and f (E 1 , E 2 ) = (1+2m 2 l −m 2 µ −2(E 1 +E 2 )+2E 1 E 2 )/(2 (E 2 1 − m 2 l )(E 2 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>− m 2 l )). The prefactor in Eq. (4.5) can be written as A = m 5 τ (4π) 3 ˆ m 4 e 2 g</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 L U † 2(−) U † 3(−) 4(4π) 2 2 = 1 16(4π) 3 m 5 τ ˆ m 4 α 2 α 2 2 (U † 2(−) U † 3(−) ) 2 , (4.6) where α 2 = g 2 2 /4π. The values of quantities in the above expression are U † 2(−) ∼ U † 3(−) ∼ 1, α = 1/137 and α 2 = 0.03322. We have dΓ(τ → µl ¯ l) = 3.4318 × 10 −11 m 4 |M ′ | 2 dE 1 dE 2 , (4.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the three body phase space (the range of E 1 and E 2 ) is determined by the δ-and</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>θ-functions in Eq. (4.5) to be: (1 + 2m 2 l − m 2 µ − 2(E 1 + E 2 ) + 2E 1 E 2 ) 2 ≤4(E 2 1 − m 2 l )(E 2 2 − m 2 l ), (4.8a) E 1 + E 2 + m µ ≤1. (4.8b) For τ → µe¯ e decay, we have |M ′ | 2 = 1 4(p − q) 4 (tr/ q 1 γ α / q 2 γ β − m 2 e trγ α γ β ) tr(/ p + 1)R β / qR α + tr(/ p + 1)(L β / qL α + m µ (R β L α + L β R α )) (4.9) where L α = γ α F L + f α L , R α = γ α F R + f α R . (4.10) After integrating over the phase space, we have Γ(τ → µe¯ e) = 1.5501 × 10 −10 m 4 (L 3 − 0.987L 2 ) 2 + 1.8237 × 10 −3 L 2 L 3 (4.11) Similarly, for τ → µµ¯ µ, we have |M ′ | 2 = 1 2 A(q 1 , q 2 ) (p − q 2 ) 4 + A(q 2 , q 1 ) (p − q 1 ) 4 − B(q 1 , q 2 ) + B(q 2 , q 1 ) (p − q 1 ) 2 (p − q 2 ) 2 , (4.12) where A(q 1 , q 2 ) = 1 2 tr(/ q − m µ )γ α (/ q 1 + m µ )γ β tr (/ p + 1)(L α 2 P R + R α 2 P L )(/ q 2 + m µ )(P L L β 2 + P R R β 2 ) (4.13a) B(q 1 , q 2 ) = 1 2 tr (/ p + 1)(L α 2 P R + R α 2 P L ) (/ q 2 + m µ )γ β (/ q − m µ )(/ q 1 + m µ ) (P L L β 2 + P R R β 2 ) (4.13b)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where q 1 and q 2 are the momenta of the out-going muons and q is that of the out-going anti-muon, and L α i and R α i are given by Eq. (4.10) by replacing q by q i for i = 1, 2. After integrating over the phase space, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ(τ → µµ¯ µ) = 3.8217 × 10 −11 m 4 (L 3 − 0.9235L 2 ) 2 + 5.8093 × 10 −3 L 2 L 3 . (4.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The decay rates Γ(τ → µe¯ e) and Γ(τ → µµ¯ µ) as functions of x = m ˜ e 2 / ˆ m 2 are listed in Table 1. We see that for the physically interesting range of x, i.e., 0.01 &lt; x &lt; 100.0, Γ(τ → µe¯ e) is about 6 ∼ 7 times Γ(τ → µµ¯ µ). These decay rates are about 1000 times less than that of Γ(µ → eγ), and therefore have much less chance to be detected. One nice feature about τ → µe¯ e is that the out-going muon is almost 100% right-handed polarized which may be used as a distinguishing feature for its detection. Figure 2 and Figure 3 are Dalitz plots for the processes τ → µe¯ e and τ → µµ¯ µ respectively. Figure 4 draws the differential event rate of τ → µe¯ e as the function of the angles between the out-going e¯ e pair (normalized to 1000 events). One finds that aboout 55 % of events have the e¯ e pair coming out with angles less than 5 • between them, and about 97 % are forward with angles between the e¯ e pair being less than 90 • . One concludes than that the out-going e¯ e pair will be predominately parallel to each other. Thus, for m = 0.5 TeV and x = 0.04 (corresponding to a selectron mass of 100 GeV which is in accord with the experimental lower bound of m ˜ e &gt; ∼ 65 GeV [11]), Eqs. (4.3), (4.11) and (4.14) imply that B(τ → µe¯ e) = 7.16 × 10 −11 and B(τ → µµ¯ µ) = 9.25 × 10 −12 . The SSC with a luminosity of L = 10 33 − 10 34 cm −2 s −1 and a B-production cross section of σ B ∼ 0.5 mb will produce 5 × 10 11 to 5 × 10 12 τ events per year. Therefore, one would expect to have about 30 to 300 events of τ → µe¯ e and about 4 to 40 events of τ → µµ¯ µ at the SSC per year. With an event acceptance of 10% and the cleanness of the three lepton events, we conclude that the rare τ decay modes, τ → µe¯ e and τ → µµ¯ µ, may be accessible at the SSC.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusions</head>

				<p>In conclusion, string models with E 6 symmetry are possible viable models from the low-energy phenomenological viewpoints. The rare τ -decays via τ → µe¯ e and τ → µµ¯ µ, which may be accessible at the SSC, give yet one more channel to confront these models and hence superstring theory with experiments.</p>

				<p>This research is supported in part under National Science Foundation Grant No.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>PHY-916593. We thank Dr. J. White and Dr. T. Kamon for discussions. (1992).</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Figure Caption Figure 1</head>

				<p>. Decay τ → µγ arising from intermediatê ν c 2 and n 1 . This decay is also induced by φ a , n 2 and ¯ n 2 fermions. Additional diagrams exist with the photon emitted by the initial and final fermions. The decays τ → µe¯ e and τ → µµ¯ µ arise when the out-going photon converts into e-¯ e pair or µ-¯ µ pair. Figure 2. Dalitz plot of τ → µe¯ e (in the rest frame of τ ). The variables along the two axises are (p − q 1 ) 2 and (p − q 2 ) 2 where p, q 1 and q 2 are the momenta of τ and the out-going e and ¯ e, respectively. x = m 2 ˜ e / ˆ m 2 is taken to be 1. Figure 3. Dalitz plot of τ → µµ¯ µ (in the rest frame of τ ). The variables along the two axises are (p − q 1 ) 2 and (p − q 2 ) 2 where p, q 1 and q 2 are the momenta of τ and the two out-going µ&apos;s, respectively. x = m 2 ˜ e / ˆ m 2 is taken to be 1. Figure 4. The differential event rate of τ → µe¯ e as the function of the angles between e¯ e pair, normalized to 1000 events, for x = m 2 ˜ e / ˆ m 2 = 1. One sees that the e¯ e pair would mostly come out parallel to each other, e.g., 55 % of them will have an angle between e¯ e pair less than 5 • .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Table 1.</head>

					<trash>Decay Rates as Functions of x = m 2 ˜ e / ˆ m 2 , with m in GeV. x = m 2 ˜ e / ˆ m 2 Γ τ →µe¯ e × ˆ m 4 Γ τ →µµ¯ µ × ˆ m 4 Ratio 0.0001 2.44 × 10 −11 1.51 × 10 −11 1.61 0.001 1.81 × 10 −11 6.43 × 10 −12 2.81 0.01 1.33 × 10 −11 2.21 × 10 −12 6.00 0.1 6.67 × 10 −12 8.41 × 10 −13 7.93 1.0 9.91 × 10 −13 1.46 × 10 −13 6.78 10.0 3.02 × 10 −14 4.90 × 10 −15 6.17 100.0 3.88 × 10 −16 6.40 × 10 −17 6.05 1000.0 4.00 × 10 −18 6.65 × 10 −19 6.03</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page">203</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2948</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2708</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dine</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Kaplunovsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Mangano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Nappi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Seiberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">259</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">549</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Gross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Harvey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Martinec</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Rohm</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Nucl. Phys. B256 and Nucl. Phys. B267</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<biblScope unit="page">75</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Candelas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Horowitz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Nucl. Phys. B258 and in Symp. on Anomalies</title>
		<editor>W. A. Bardeen and A. R. White</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Geometry, Topology ; Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>World Scientific</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">For a review, see: D. Gepner, Lectures on N = 2 string theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Gepner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Nucl. Phys. B296 SUPERSTRINGS&apos;89, Proceedings of the Trieste Spring School</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Green, R. Iengo, S</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Randjbar-Daemi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sezgin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Scientific</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Bento</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Hall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Lazarides and Q. Shafi, Nucl. Phys. B308</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page">451</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Wu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Texas A&amp;M and Northeastern Preprint</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989-09" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3031" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">191</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Particle Data Group: Review of Particle Properties</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="1" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
