<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">P</forename>
								<surname>Rama</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Institute of Mathematical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">C.I.T.Campus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Madras-600 113</addrLine>
									<settlement>Taramani</settlement>
									<country key="IN">INDIA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Devi</forename>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Institute of Mathematical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">C.I.T.Campus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Madras-600 113</addrLine>
									<settlement>Taramani</settlement>
									<country key="IN">INDIA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">T</forename>
								<forename type="middle">R</forename>
								<surname>Govindarajan</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Institute of Mathematical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">C.I.T.Campus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Madras-600 113</addrLine>
									<settlement>Taramani</settlement>
									<country key="IN">INDIA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">R</forename>
								<forename type="middle">K</forename>
								<surname>Kaul</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Institute of Mathematical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">C.I.T.Campus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Madras-600 113</addrLine>
									<settlement>Taramani</settlement>
									<country key="IN">INDIA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9212110v1 18 Dec 1992 IMSc/92/55 9th Dec 92 Three Dimensional Chern-Simons Theory as a Theory of Knots and Links III : Compact Semi-simple Group</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Chern-Simons field theory based on a compact non-abelian gauge group is studied as a theory of knots and links in three dimensions. A method to obtain the invariants for links made from braids of upto four strands is developed. This generalizes our earlier work on SU(2) Chern-Simons theory. email: rama,trg,kaul@imsc.ernet.in</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>These can be used to obtain invariants for many links. In section 5, we present the results of explicit calculations of the invariants for some links for the SU(N) case as illustrations. Concluding remarks are presented in the last section 6. Appendix contains a brief discussion of the duality matrices for the four-point correlators of the associated</p>

				<p>Wess-Zumino conformal field theory on an S 2 .</p>

				<p>2. Generalized Alexander-Conway Relations For a link L consisting of component knots C 1 , C 2 , . . . C s carrying representations (colours) R 1 , R 2 . . . R s of the gauge group G respectively,we have the Wilson link operator:</p>

				<p><formula>W R 1 ,R 2 ,...Rs [L] = s i=1 tr R i exp C i A (2.1)</formula></p>

				<p>where A is matrix valued connection one-form for the gauge group G. Here the trace is over the representation matrices corresponding to representations R i . We shall be interested in the functional averages of these operators in Chern-Simons theory in S 3 .</p>

				<p>V R 1 R 2 ...Rs [L] = [dA]W R 1 R 2 ...Rs [L]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>e</figDesc>

				</figure>

			<div>
				<head>ikS [dA]</head>

				<p>e ikS</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = k 4π tr(AdA + 2 3 A 3 ) (2.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Both the integrand as well as the measure in the functional integrals are metric independent[10]. Thus the functional averages (2.2) are link invariants.</p>

				<p>Following our earlier papers[5, 6], we now obtain recursion relations relating these link invariants. For this purpose, let us first consider a link L 2m in S 3 as shown in Fig.2.1a. It consists of a room A with two strands entering from below carrying representations R and R ′ . These two strands are half twisted 2m times and then connected to the strands leaving the room A from above which carry representations R, R ′ . This link can be thought of as made from gluing two balls B 1 and B 2 as shown in Fig.2.1b along their oppositely oriented boundaries, each an S 2 .</p>

				<p>Like in refs[1, 5, 6]. the Chern-Simons functional integrals over these two balls will be represented by vectors |ψ 2m (A) and ¯ ψ 0 |. These belong to the Hilbert spaces H and ¯ H associated with the boundaries of these two balls respectively.</p>

				<p>The dimensionality of these two vector spaces is given by the number of conformal blocks of the G k Wess-Zumino conformal field theories on these boundaries, each an S 2 with</p>

				<p>four punctures carrying representations R, R ′ , ¯ R, ¯ R ′ . This is given by the number of ways group singlets can be made from these four representations in accordance with the fusion rules of the conformal field theory. For sufficiently large k, R ⊗ R ′ = ⊕R s , s = 0, 1, . . . n, as allowed by group theory.</p>

				<p>Glueing the two balls B 1 and B 2 can be represented by natural contraction of the vectors |ψ 2m (A) and ¯ ψ 0 | :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V R,R ′ [L 2m (A)] = ¯ ψ 0 |ψ 2m (A) (2.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The vector |ψ 2m (A) is related to the vector |ψ 0 (A) corresponding to ball B 1 with no half-twists in the central two strands through the half-twist matrix B</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(R, R ′ ) as B 2m (R,R ′ ) |ψ 0 (A) = |ψ 2m (A) (2.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The matrix B here introduces right-handed half-twists in parallelly oriented strands carrying representations R and R ′ . It is an (n + 1) × (n + 1) matrix, where n + 1 is the number of irreducible representations in the product R ⊗ R ′ . Its eigenvalues are given by monodromy properties of the four-point correlator of primary fields in representations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R, ¯ R, R ′ , ¯ R ′ in the Wess-Zumino field theory for group G on S 2 : λ + s (R, R ′ ) = (−1) ∈s exp iπ (2h R + 2h R ′ + |h R − h R ′ | − h Rs ) (2.5) Here h R = C R /(k + C V ) (C R,V are the quadratic Casimir invariants for the representation</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>R and adjoint representation respectively) is the conformal weight of the primary field in representation R . The factor exp πi(h R + h R ′ + |h R − h R ′ |) here compensates the change of framing introduced by a half unit twist. The fore factor (−) ∈s , ∈ s = ±1 counts whether the irreducible representation R s in the product R ⊗ R ′ occurs symmetrically or antisymmetrically. Introducing the variable q = exp(2πi/(k + C V )), these eigen values can be rewritten as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ + s (R, R ′ ) = (−1) ∈s q C R +C R ′ +|C R −C R ′ |/2−C Rs /2 (2.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Now we write the characteristic equation for the half-twist matrix B</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(R, R ′ ) as n+ℓ+1 j=ℓ α j−ℓ (B 2 ) j = 0 (2.7) where coefficients α 0 , α 1 , . . . α n+1 are related to the eigenvalues above. Apply this equation on the vector |ψ 0 (A) above to obtain n+ℓ+1 j=ℓ α j−ℓ |ψ 2j (A) = 0 (2.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We take the inner product with ¯ ψ 0 | to obtain our first recursion relation:</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Theorem 1.</head>


				</figure>

				<p>For the links L 2m (A) shown in Fig.2.1a, the link invariants are related as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n+ℓ+1 j=ℓ α j−ℓ V [L 2j (A; R, R ′ )] = 0; ℓ = 0, ±1, ±2 . . . (2.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the coefficients are related to the eigenvalues of the half-twist matrix B</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(R, R ′ ) above as follows : α 0 (R, R ′ ) = (−) n+1 n s=0 λ + s (R, R ′ ) 2 α 1 (R, R ′ ) = (−) n s 1 =s 2 =···sn (λ + s 1 ) 2 (λ + s 2 ) 2 · · · (λ + sn ) 2 . . . α n−1 (R, R ′ ) = (−) 2 s 1 =s 2 (λ + s 1 ) 2 (λ + s 2 ) 2 α n (R, R ′ ) = (−) (λ + s ) 2 α n+1 (R, R ′ ) = 1 (2.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For links of the type shown in Fig.2.1a where R and R ′ are the same representation, a more powerful recursion relation can be obtained:</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Theorem 2.</head>

					<figDesc>For links L m (A; R, R) as shown in Fig.2.2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. the link invariants are related as :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n+ℓ+1 j=ℓ β j−ℓ (R, R)V [L j (A; R, R)] = 0 (2.11) where the coefficients are related to the eigenvalues of half-twist matrix B(R, R) : β 0 (R, R) = (−) n+1 s λ + s (R, R) β 1 (R, R) = (−) n s 1 =s 2 =···sn (λ + s 1 λ + s 2 · · · λ + sn ) . . . β n−1 (R, R) = (−) 2 s 1 =s 2 (λ + s 1 λ + s 2 ) β n (R, R) = (−) (λ + s ) β n+1 (R, R) = 1 (2.12)</trash>

					<figDesc>Here n + 1 is the number of irreducible representations in the product, R ⊗ R = ⊕ n s=0 R s . Next we present the recursion relation amongst the links L 2m ( ˆ A; R, ¯ R ′ ) as shown in Fig.2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.3a. These links can again be thought as obtained by glueing two balls shown in Fig.2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.3b. The functional integrals over these two balls are represented by vectors |χ 2m ( ˆ A) and ¯ χ 0 | belonging to the Hilbert spaces associated with the oppositely oriented boundaries of these balls. Now here vector |χ 2m ( ˆ A) can be written as</figDesc>
					<trash>|χ 2m ( ˆ A) = ( ˆ B(R, ¯ R ′ )) 2m |χ 0 ( ˆ A) (2.13) where the matrix B(R, ¯ R ′ ) now introduces a half twist in oppositely oriented strands carrying representations R, ¯ R ′ .Its eigen values in contrast to twist matrix B(R, R ′ ) above are λ − s = (−) ∈s q −|C R −C ′ R |/2 + C Rs /2 (2.14) where now R⊗R ′ = ⊕R s . A similar analysis as above then yields us the following recursion relation: Theorem 3. The invariants for links L 2m ( ˆ A; R, ¯ R ′ )as shown in Fig 2.3a are related as: n+ℓ+1 j=ℓ α j−ℓ (R, ¯ R ′ )V [ ˆ L 2j ( ˆ A; R, ¯ R ′ )] = 0 (2.15) where the coefficients are related to the eigenvalues of half twist matrix B(R, ¯ R ′ ) as : ˆ α 0 (R, R ′ ) = (−) n+1 n s=0 λ − s (R, ¯ R ′ ) 2 ˆ α 1 (R, R ′ ) = (−) n s 1 =s 2 =···sn (λ − s 1 ) 2 (λ − s 2 ) 2 · · · (λ − sn ) 2 . . . ˆ α n−1 (R, R ′ ) = (−) 2 s 1 =s 2 (λ − s 1 ) 2 (λ − s 2 ) 2 ˆ α n (R, R ′ ) = (−) (λ − s ) 2 ˆ α n+1 (R, R ′ ) = 1 (2.16) 3. Invariants for links obtained as closures of two-strand braids Now we shall consider special case of links Figs.2.1 and 2.2 and 2.3. We take the room A in Fig.2.1a as A TT T T ¯ R ¯ R ′ R ′ R = T T R ′</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>R</head>

				<p>The functional integral over the ball B 1 of Fig.2.1b with room A as above will be called |ψ 2m (R, R ′ ). We expand this vector in terms of eigen functions of the twist matrix B(R, R ′ ) which introduces half twists in the central two strands :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B(R, R ′ )|φ s = λ + s (R, R ′ )|φ s (3.1) and |ψ 0 (R, R ′ ) = n s=0 µ s |φ s (3.2a) |ψ 2m (R, R ′ ) = µ s (λ + s (R, R ′ )) 2m |φ s (3.2b)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here we assume µ s to be independent of R, R ′ which we justify later. Similarly for the functional integral over the ball B 2 of Fig.2</p>

				<p><formula>.1b. ¯ ψ 0 | = n s=0 µ s φ s | (3.2c)</formula></p>

				<p>in terms of basis vectors of the dual Hilbert space, ¯ H, which are also eigen functions of the matrix B. The pairing of the basis vectors forH and ¯ H are given by φ s |φ s ′ = δ s s ′ . Then the invariants for links L(R, R ′ ) obtained as the closure of two-strand braids with 2m half-twists as shown in Fig.3</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>.1a are V [L 2m (R, R ′ )] = s µ s µ s (λ + s ) 2m (3.3) Now notice for L 0 (R, R</trash>

					<figDesc>′ ) is two unlinked unknots carrying representations R and R ′ .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The invariant for this link is simply the product of invariants for two individual unknots, V R [U]V R ′ [U]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. Thus n s=0 µ 2 s = V R [U]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>V R ′ [U]. Now we use the fact that for two cabled knots such as unknots the invariants obey the fusion rules, V R [U]V R ′ [U] = s V Rs [U]. Consistent with this, the invariant for unknot is the q-dimension of the representation living on it: V R [U] = dim q R. For example for the case of G = SU(N), the invariant for the unknot carrying N dimensional representation is its q-dimension = [N]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= (q N/2 − q −N/2 )/(q 1/2 − q −1/2 ). Thus µ s = dim q R s justifying our earlier statement after Eq.3.2b.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This discussion leads us to the following theorem : Theorem 4. For links L 2m (R, R ′ ) as shown in Fig.3.1a obtained as closure of parallely oriented two-strand braids with representations R, R ′ , the invariants are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V [L 2m (R, R ′ )] = s (dim q R s )(λ + s (R, R ′ )) 2m (3.4) where R ⊗ R ′ = ⊕R s .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Analysing links of the type shown in Figs.2.2 and 2.3a in similar fashion leads to two similar results.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Theorem 5.</head>

					<figDesc>For links L m (R, R) as shown in Fig.3.1b obtained as closure of parallely oriented braids made of two strands carrying the same representation R, the invariants</figDesc>
					<trash>are V [L m (R, R)] = s (dim q R s )(λ + s (R, R)) m (3.5) where R ⊗ R = ⊕R s . Theorem 6. For links L 2m (R, ¯ R ′ ) as shown in Fig.3.1c obtained as closure of braids made from two anti-parallely oriented strands carrying representations R and ¯ R ′ respectively the invariants are V [ ˆ L 2m (R, ¯ R ′ )] = (dim q R s )(λ − s (R, ¯ R ′ )) 2m (3.6) where R ⊗ ¯ R ′ = ⊕R s .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>After presenting these simple theorems which give us invariants for links made of closure of two-strand braids, we would like to present functional integrals on some manifolds with boundaries which can be used to obtain invariants for more complicated links. 4. Some Building Blocks In order to develop the method further, we shall write the functional integrals over some manifold with boundaries carrying four Wilson lines. These can be used as building blocks to obtain invariants for more complicated links. Consider the rooms Q</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V m   . . R R ′   and Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′  </trash>


				</figure>

				<p>each a 3-ball with four Wilson lines as indicated in Fig.4.1a. In the first room Q</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V m   . . R R ′   , the lower two markings (inlets) carry representations R and R ′ respectively and the upper two markings (outlets) denoted by dots are ¯ R and ¯ R ′ or ¯ R ′ and ¯</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>R as m is even or odd. These two rooms have been redrawn in Fig.4</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.1b. The functional integral over these two balls have been called |ψ(Q</figDesc>
					<trash>V m   . . R R ′   ) and |ψ(Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′   ) respectively. These can be constructed from the vectors |ψ(Q V 0   ¯ R ¯ R ′ R R ′   ) and |ψ(Q H 0   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R </trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc> )by applying the half-twist matrix B on the central two strands and B on the first two side strands respectively. These two vectors from the discussion in previous section can be expanded in terms of the convenient basis vectors |φ Rt ( ¯ RRR ′ ¯ R ′ ) which form the eigen functions of braid matrix which twists the parallel central two strands (with eigenvalues λ</figDesc>
					<trash>+ t (R, , R ′ ) where R ⊗ R ′ = ⊕R t ) and | ˆ φ s ( ¯ R ′ RR ′ ¯</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>R) which are the eigenfunctions of the braid matrix B that twists the first two anti-parallel strands (with eigen-values λ</figDesc>
					<trash>− Rs (R, ¯ R ′ ) with R ⊗ ¯ R ′ = ⊕R s ), respectively : |ψ(Q V 0   ¯ R ¯ R ′ R R ′   ) = t dim q R t |φ Rt ( ¯ RRR ′ ¯ R ′ ) |ψ(Q H 0   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   ) = s dim q R s | ˆ φ Rs ( ¯ R ′ RR ′ ¯ R) (4.1) The two bases |φ Rs and | ˆ φ Rt are related by the duality matrix of the associated four point correlators of the corresponding Wess-Zumino model : | ˆ φ Rs (R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4 ) = Rt a RsRt   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4   |φ Rt (R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4 ) (4.2) where R 1 ⊗ R 2 = ⊕R s , R 2 ⊗ R 3 = ⊕R t and the four representations R 1 , R 2 , R 3 , R 4 form a singlet. The duality matrix a RsRt   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4 </trash>


				</figure>

				<p> above, as in the SU(2) k case, are related to q-Racah coefficients for the non abelian group G. In the Appendix we have given the expression for these in terms of q C − G coefficients and listed their other useful properties.</p>

				<p>The above discussion can be put together in the form of a theorem :</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Theorem 7.</head>

					<figDesc>The normalized functional integral over the 3-balls for |ψ(Q</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>V m   . . R R ′   ) and |ψ(Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′ </formula></p>

				<p> ) as shown in Fig.4</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.1b can be written in terms of basis referring to the central two strands as |ψ(Q</figDesc>
					<trash>V m   . . R R ′   ) = Rt µ Rt (Q V m   . . R R ′   ) |φ Rt (·RR ′ ·) |ψ(Q H 2p+1 (   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′   ) = Rt µ Rt (Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′   )|φ Rt ( ¯ R ′ RR ′ ¯ R (4.3) where R ⊗ R ′ = ⊕R t and µ Rt (Q V m   . . R R ′   ) = (λ + Rt (R, R ′ )) m dim q R t µ Rt (Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′   ) = Rs (λ − Rs (R, ¯ R ′ )) 2p+1 a RsRt   ¯ R ′ R R ′ ¯ R   dim q R s (4.4) where R ⊗ ¯ R</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>′ = ⊕R s . The braid matrix eigen values for a pair of parallel and anti-parallel strands are given by Eqns.2.6 and 2.14 respectively. A similar discussion can be developed for the functional integral over 3-balls containing</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>rooms Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   , ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   and Q H ′ p   R ′ . R .</formula></p>

				<p>  as drawn in Fig.4.2a. These balls have been redrawn in Fig.4</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.2b. The vectors |χ( ˆ</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   ), |χ( ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   ) and |χ( ˆ Q H ′ p   R ′ . R . </formula></p>

				<p> ) respectively represent the functional integral over these three balls.</p>

				<p>We present these functional integrals in the form of a theorem.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Theorem 8.</head>

					<figDesc>The functional integral | ˆ</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>χ(Q V 2m   . . R ¯ R ′   ), |χ( ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   ) and |χ( ˆ Q H ′ p   R ′ . R . </formula></p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc> ) for the three balls shown in Fig.4.2b can be expanded in terms of the basis referring to the central two strands in each case as :</figDesc>
					<trash>|χ( ˆ Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   ) = Rs µ Rs ( ˆ Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   )| ˆ φ Rs (·R ¯ R ′ ·) |χ( ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   ) = Rû µ Ru ( ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   )| ˆ φ Ru ( ¯ R ′ R ¯ RR ′ ) |χ( ˆ Q H ′ 2p   R ′ ¯ R ′ R ¯ R   ) = Rû µ Ru ( ˆ Q H ′ 2p   R ′ ¯ R ′ R ¯ R   )| ˆ φ Ru (R ′ R ¯ R ¯ R ′ ) |χ( ˆ Q H ′ 2p+1   R ′ ¯ R R ¯ R ′   ) = Rs µ Rs ( ˆ Q H ′ 2p+1   R ′ ¯ R R ¯ R ′   )| ˆ φ Rs (R ′ R ¯ R ′ ¯ R) (4.5) where R ⊗ ¯ R ′ = ⊕R s , R ⊗ ¯ R = ⊕R u , and ˆ µ Rs ( ˆ Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   ) = (λ − Rs (R, ¯ R ′ )) m dim q R s ˆ µ Ru ( ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   ) = Rs dim q R s a RsRu   ¯ R ′ R ¯ R R ′   (λ − Rs ( ¯ R ′ R)) 2p µ Ru ( ˆ Q H ′ 2p   R ′ ¯ R ′ R ¯ R   ) = Rt dim q R t a RtRu   R ′ R ¯ R ¯ R ′   (λ + Rt (R ′ R)) 2p µ Rs ( ˆ Q H ′ 2p+1   R ′ ¯ R R ¯ R ′   ) = Rt dim q R t a RtRs   R ′ R ¯ R ′ ¯ R   (λ + Rt (RR ′ )) 2p+1 (4.6) where R ⊗ R ′ = ⊕R t .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This generalizes theorem 6 of [6].</p>

				<p>Now we may extend our discussion to functional integrals over three manifolds with more than two boundaries. For example consider the manifold with r boundaries, each boundary an S 2 with four punctures and Wilson lines connecting them as shown in Fig.4.3. The four representations on each of these boundaries are such that they make a group singlet. Then the functional integral over this manifold is given by the following theorem:</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Theorem 9.</head>

					<figDesc>The normalized functional integral for the manifold with r boundaries as shown in Fig.4.3 in terms of the basis |φ (i)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Rs of the Hilbert spaces H (i) , i = 1, 2, . . . r associated with these boundaries with four punctures each as indicated is given by ν r =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Rs |φ (1) Rs |φ (2) Rs · · · |φ r Rs (dim q R s ) r−2 2 (4.7) These bases |φ (i)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Rs &gt; refer to the parallel side-two strands in each case. The functional integral is normalised by multiplying a factor (N) (r−1)/2 , where N is the functional integral over the empty boundaryless manifold S 3 . The summation over R s is over those irreducible representations which are common to the products R 1 ⊗R 2 , R 3 ⊗R 4 , R 5 ⊗R 6 . . . R 2r−1 ⊗R 2r .</p>

				<p>This theorem in the case of manifolds with one and two boundaries as shown in Figs</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>.4.4 (a) and (b) reduces to ν 1 = Rs dimR s |φ (1) Rs (R 1 R 2 ¯ R 2 ¯ R 1 ) (4.8) ν 2 = Rs |φ (1) Rs (R 1 R 2 ¯ R 3 ¯ R 4 )|φ (2) Rs ( ¯ R 1 ¯ R 2 R 3 R 4 ) (4.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The proof of theorem 9 can easily be developed by induction, by successively glueing the manifold shown in Fig.4.4(a) onto one of the boundaries of the manifold shown in Fig.4.3</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Some explicit calculations</head>

				<p>With the building blocks presented above, we are in a position to evaluate the invariants for all links made of upto four strands. This we shall now illustrate by studying some examples. For definiteness let us take the gauge group G to be SU(N) and place representation given by Youngs tableaux containing n boxes in a row, R n = &apos; E n on all the component knots of a link. Then the eigen values of the braid matrix that introduces right handed half-twist in parallely oriented strands carrying this representation are (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eqn.2.5) : λ + ℓ (R n , R n ) = (−) n−ℓ ω n/2 q n(n+1) 2 − ℓ(ℓ+1) 2 ; ℓ = 0, 1, . . . n (5.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have introduced a convenient variable ω = q N −1 . Here these eigen values for ℓ = 0, 1, 2, . . . n correspond respectively to the irreducible representation in the product</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R n ⊗ R n = ⊕ n ℓ=0 ρ ℓ as &apos; E n ⊗ R n &apos; E n R n = ⊕ n ℓ=0 ρ ℓ &apos; E n − ℓ &apos; E 2ℓ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the other hand, the eigenvalues of the braid matrix that introduces right-handed half-twists in anti-parallely oriented strands (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eqn.2.14) is given by λ − ℓ (R n , ¯ R n ) = (−) ℓ ω ℓ/2 q ℓ 2 /2 ; ℓ = 0, 1, . . . , n (5.2) Here these eigenvalues for ℓ = 0, 1, 2, . . . n correspond respectively to the irreducible representations in the product R n ⊗ ¯ R n = ⊕ˆ R n = ⊕ n ℓ=0 . . . . ˆ ρ ℓ &apos; E ℓ &apos; E ℓ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here a box with dot represents a column of length N − 1.</p>

				<p>Using these eigenvalues of the braid matrix and the building blocks developed earlier, we have as illustrations calculated explicitly the invariants for some knots shown in Fig.5.1. The results are as follows :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 1 : V = dim q R n 3 1 : V = n ℓ=0 dim q ρ ℓ (−) n−ℓ ω −3n/2 q −3(n(n+1)/2−ℓ(ℓ+1)/2) 4 1 : V = n ℓ,j=0 dim q ˆ ρ j dim q ˆ ρ ℓ a ˆ ρ j ˆ ρ ℓ ω j 2 − ℓ 2 q j 2 2 − ℓ 2 2 5 1 : V = n ℓ=0 dim q ρ ℓ (−) n−ℓ ω −5n/2 q −5(n(n+1)/2−ℓ(ℓ+1)/2) 5 2 : V = n ℓ,j=0 dim q ˆ ρ j dim q ρ ℓ a ˆ ρ j ¯ ρ ℓ ω n+ 3j 2 q n(n+1)−ℓ(ℓ+1)+ 3j 2 2 6 1 : V = n ℓ,j=0 dim q ˆ ρ j dim q ˆ ρ ℓ a ˆ ρ j ˆ ρ ℓ ω −ℓ+2j q −ℓ 2 +2j 2 7 1 : V = n ℓ=0 dim q ρ ℓ (−) n−ℓ ω −7n/2 q −7(n(n+1)/2−ℓ(ℓ+1)/2) 7 2 : V = n ℓ,j=0 dim q ˆ ρ j dim q ρ ℓ a ˆ ρ j ¯ ρ ℓ ω −n− 5j 2 q −n(n+1)+ℓ(ℓ+1)− 5j 2 2 Here the duality matrices a ˆ ρ i ˆ ρ j   ¯ R n R n ¯ R n R n   and a ˆ ρ i ¯ ρ j   R n ¯ R n ¯ R n R n   have been written simply as a ˆ ρ i ˆ ρ j and a ˆ ρ i ¯ ρ j respectively. In particular for n = 1 and n = 2 (R 1 = and R 2 = ) the duality matrices are explicitly given by: a ˆ ρ i ˆ ρ j = 1 dim q R 1   dim q ˆ ρ 0 √ dimˆim q ˆ ρ 1 − dim q ˆ ρ 0   (5.5) and a ˆ ρ i ˆ ρ j = 1 dim q R 2      dim q ˆ ρ 0 dim q ˆ ρ 1 dim q ˆ ρ 2 dim q ˆ ρ 1 dimq ρ 2 dimqR 2 −1 − 1 − √ dimq ρ 1 dimq ρ 2 dimqR 2 −1 dim q ˆ ρ 2 − √ dimq ρ 1 dimq ρ 2 dimqR 2 −1 1−dimq ρ 2 +dimq ρ 1 dimqR 2 −1      (5.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The other duality matrix a ˆ ρ i ¯ ρ j can also be written down exploiting the &quot; orthoganality &quot; and symmetry properties given in the Appendix.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Conclusions</head>

				<p>Here we have presented a method to obtain the expectation values of Wilson link operators for links made up of upto four strands in a Chern-Simons theory on S 3 , based on an arbitrary compact non-abelian gauge group G. This generalises our discussion based on SU(2) presented in refs[5, 6]. A whole variety of new link invariants are thus obtained. As a special case for gauge group SU(N) with the N dimensional fundamental representation placed on all the component knots yields the two variable generalization of Jones polynomial, the so called HOMFLY invariant. Another special case when the representation of SU(N) is placed on the component knots leads to the two variable generalized polynomial of Akutsu,Deguchi and Wadati[11]. While this method can be used to obtain invariants for all links which can be made from upto four strands, the others still stay elusive.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Appendix The duality matrix a R (s) R (t)   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>  introduced in the text tells us how the conformal blocks for four-point correlators of primary fields in representations R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4 in SU(N) k Wess-Zumino conformal field theory transform into each other under duality transformation :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E d d d d E c d d d d d d d d d d a R (s) R (t)   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4   R 1 R 2 R (s) ¯ R (s) R 4 R 3 ¯ R (t) R (t) R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4 (A.1)</trash>

					<figDesc>Here R (s) are the irreducible representation in R 1 ⊗ R 2 such that ¯ R (s) is contained in R 3 ⊗ R 4 . And also R (t) are contained in R 2 ⊗ R 3 such that ¯ R (t) are in R 1 ⊗ R 4 . These duality matrices are given by the SU(N) q Racah coefficients. These relate two ways of combining the four representation R 1 , R 2 , R 3 , R 4 of SU(N) q into singlets. For example we could first combine R 1 and R 2 into R</figDesc>
					<trash>(s) 12 . This combined with R 3 should yield ¯ R 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which then with fourth representation R 4 will give a singlet. Alternatively we could first combine R 2 and R 3 to give R (t) 23 . This with R 1 then would have to give ¯ R 4 which with R 4 would give a singlet. Calling these vectors |φ (s) and |φ ′(t) in (A.1) above respectively, we can write them in terms of the representation vectors |R 1 µ 1 , |R 2 , µ 2 , |R 3 µ 3 , |R 4 µ 4 (where µ i are corresponding weights) through q − CG coefficients of SU q (N) :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|φ (s) = µ 1 ,µ 2 ,µ 3 ,µ 4 ,µ (s) 12 C R (s) 12 µ (s) 12 R 1 µ 1 R 2 µ 2 C ¯ R 4 −µ 4 R (s) 12 µ (s) 12 R 3 µ 3 C 00 ¯ R 4 −µ 4 R 4 µ 4 |R 1 µ 1 |R 2 µ 2 |R 3 µ 3 |R 4 µ 4 (A.1) |φ ′(t) = λ 1 ,λ 2 ,λ 3 ,λ 4 ,λ (t) 23 C R (t) 23 λ (t) 23 R 2 λ 2 R 3 λ 3 C ¯ R 4 −λ 4 R 1 λ 1 R (t) 23 λ (t) 23 C 00 ¯ R 4 −λ 4 R 4 λ 4 |R 1 λ 1 |R 2 λ 2 |R 3 λ 3 |R 4 λ 4 (A.2) Here C&apos;s are the q − CG coefficients. Now from these a R (s) R (t)   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4   ≡ φ ′(t) |φ (s) = f ixµ 4 C R (s) 12 µ (s) 12 R 1 µ 1 R 2 µ 2 C ¯ R 4 −µ 4 R (s) 12 µ (s) 12 R 3 µ 3 C R (t) 23 µ (t) 23 R 2 µ 2 R 3 µ 3 C ¯ R 4 −µ 4 R 1 µ 1 R (t) 23 µ (t) 23 (A.3)</trash>

					<head>These duality matrices satisfy the following relations :</head>

					<trash>a R (s) 12 R (t) 23   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4   = a ¯ R (s) 12 R (t) 23   R 3 R 4 R 1 R 2   = a R (t) 23 R (s) 12   R 3 R 2 R 1 R 4   = a ¯ R (t) 23 ¯ R (s) 12   R 1 R 4 R 3 R 2   and the &quot; orthogonality &quot; relation. R (t) 23 a R (s) 12 R (t) 23   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4   a R (s ′ ) 12 R (t) 23   R 1 R 2 R 3 R 4   = δ R (s) 12 R (s ′ ) 12 (A.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure Captions: Fig.2</head>

					<figDesc>.1 Composition of two balls B 1 , B 2 leads to the multicoloured (with representations R and R ′ ) link L 2m (A; R, R ′ ) in S 3 . Fig.2.2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Composition of two balls B 1 , B 2 leads to the knot/link L m (A; R, R) in S 3 . Fig.2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.3 Composition of two balls B 1 , B 2 leads to the multicoloured link L 2m ( ˆ A; R, ¯ R ′ ) in S 3 . Fig.3</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.1 Closure of (a,b) parallely and (c) antiparallely oriented two-strand braids with 2m,m,2m half-twists, L 2m (R, R ′ ),L m (R, R) and L 2m (R, ¯ R ′ ) respectively. Fig.4</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.1 (a) Rooms Q</figDesc>
					<trash>V m   . . R R ′   and Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′   and (b) corresponding states |ψ(Q V m   . . R R ′   and |ψ(Q H 2p+1   ¯ R ′ ¯ R R R ′   ) Fig.4.2 (a) Rooms Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   , ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   and Q H ′ p   R ′ . R .   and (b) corresponding states |χ(Q V m   . . R ¯ R ′   ), |χ( ˆ Q H 2p   ¯ R ′ R ′ R ¯ R   ) and |χ( ˆ Q H ′ p   R ′ . R .   ) Fig.4</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.3 Functional integrals over a manifold with r boundaries (with orientation ∈= +) ν r</figDesc>
					<trash>of Eqn.4.7 Fig.4.4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Diagrammatic representation of functional integrals ν 1 and ν 2 . Fig.5</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.1 Some knot projections upto seven crossings.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">351</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F R</forename>
				<surname>Jones</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Bull</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AMS Ann. of Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">335</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Geometry and Physics of Knots</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Atiyah</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>Cambridge Univ.Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Birmingham</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Blau</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Rakowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Thompson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">209</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Freyd</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Yetter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B R</forename>
				<surname>Hoste</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Lickorish</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Millet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ocneanu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bull. AMS Kobe J. Math</title>
		<editor>239</editor>
		<editor>J.H.Przytycki and K.P.Traczyk</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">115</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Kaul</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Govindarajan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">293</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">380</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">IMSc-92/08.(To appear in Nucl</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Kaul</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Govindarajan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.B)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M F</forename>
				<surname>Labastida</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Ramallo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Letts</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">228</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">214</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">B348 (1991) 651</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Labastida</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Llatas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nucl</forename>
				<surname>Ramallo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">J M</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M F</forename>
				<surname>Isidro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Labastida</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ramallo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Us-</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Yamagishi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M-L</forename>
				<surname>Ge</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y-S</forename>
				<surname>Wu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Letts. Math. Phys. Int.Jour.Modern Phys. J.H.Horne, Nucl.Phys</title>
		<editor>Y. Wu and K. Yamagishi</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="334" />
			<date type="published" when="1165" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knots and Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Kauffman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Scientific</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Kaul</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Rajaraman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Letts</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">249</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">433</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Wadati</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Deguchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Akutsu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">180</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">247</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
