<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Theoretical Interpretation of the NE18 Experiment on Nuclear Transparency in A(e, e ′ p) Scattering</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1993-07-23">July 23, 1993</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">N</forename>
								<forename type="middle">N</forename>
								<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">L.D.LandauInstituteforTheoreticalPhysics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>GSP-1, ul.Kosygina2</addrLine>
									<postCode>117940, V-334</postCode>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<surname>Szczurek</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">InstituteofNuclearPhysics</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>PL-31-342</postCode>
									<settlement>Krakow</settlement>
									<country key="PL">Poland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Speth</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Wambach</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">DepartmentofPhysics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversityofIllinoisatUrbana-Champaign</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>61801</postCode>
									<settlement>Urbana</settlement>
									<region>IL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">B</forename>
								<forename type="middle">G</forename>
								<surname>Zakharov</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">L.D.LandauInstituteforTheoreticalPhysics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>GSP-1, ul.Kosygina2</addrLine>
									<postCode>117940, V-334</postCode>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">V</forename>
								<forename type="middle">R</forename>
								<surname>Zoller</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Forschungszentrum JülichGmbH</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>5) 1) IKP(Theorie)</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-52425</postCode>
									<settlement>Jülich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">InstituteforTheoreticalandExperimentalPhysics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>ul.B.Cheremushkinskaya25</addrLine>
									<postCode>117259</postCode>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Theoretical Interpretation of the NE18 Experiment on Nuclear Transparency in A(e, e ′ p) Scattering</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1993-07-23">July 23, 1993</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:nucl-th/9402016v1 9 Feb 1994</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A b s t r a c t The spectral function, measured in A(e, e ′ p) reactions, is distorted by the final-state interaction of the struck proton with the residual nucleus. This causes a broadening of the observed transverse-momentum distribution which is large even in the d(e, e ′ p) reaction. We discuss the effects of this p ⊥-broadening on the nuclear transparency measured in the recent NE18 experiment. Within conventional Glauber theory we can describe the measurements. Transparency effects are thus small in agreement with our earlier predictions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>


				<p>Theoretical Interpretation of the NE18 Experiment on Nuclear Transparency in A(e, e ′ p) Scattering</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N.N.Nikolaev 1,2) , A.Szczurek 1,3) , J.Speth 1) , J.Wambach 1,4) , B.G.Zakharov 2) and V.R.Zoller 5) 1) IKP(Theorie), Forschungszentrum Jülich GmbH., D-52425 Jülich , Germany 2) L.D.Landau Institute for Theoretical Physics, GSP-1, 117940, ul.Kosygina 2, V-334 Moscow, Russia 3) Institute of Nuclear Physics, PL-31-342 Krakow, Poland 4) Department of Physics, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, IL 61801, USA 5) Institute for Theoretical and Experimental Physics, ul.B.Cheremushkinskaya 25, 117259 Moscow, Russia</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A b s t r a c t The spectral function, measured in A(e, e ′ p) reactions, is distorted by the final-state interaction of the struck proton with the residual nucleus. This causes a broadening of the observed transverse-momentum distribution which is large even in the d(e, e ′ p) reaction . We discuss the effects of this p ⊥ -broadening on the nuclear transparency measured in the recent NE18 experiment. Within conventional Glauber theory we can describe the measurements. Transparency effects are thus small in agreement with our earlier predictions.</p>

				<p>The recently completed SLAC NE18 experiment [1] on A(e, e ′ p) scattering concludes that, up to Q 2 ∼ &lt; 7 (GeV/c) 2 , there is no conclusive evidence for color transparency (CT). A slow onset of CT was predicted by us [2,3] in an approach which is based on CT sum rules and the quark-hadron duality. It was shown that CT and/or weak final-state interaction (FSI) in A(e, e ′ p) reactions arises from delicate cancellations of contributions from elastic (|i = |p) and inelastic (|i = |p ) intermediate states |i propagating inside the nucleus [2,3]. At Q 2 ∼ &lt; 7 (GeV/c) 2 the contributions from inelastic rescatterings is still small, however, and hence the very small signal in the NE18 experiment (for a general review on CT see [5-7]). Another very interesting aspect of the experiment is the evidence for substantial FSI effects already in the deuteron.</p>

				<p>A quantitative description of the NE18 data [1] is an important check for our understanding of the FSI at large Q 2 and the purpose of this communication is to provide such a description. To do so, one should realize that, because of the finite spectrometer acceptance in the missing energy E m and missing momentum p m = (p m,z , p ⊥ ) (the z-axis is chosen along the q direction), the sum-rule technique of refs. [2,3] is not applicable. It has been argued in [1] that one should compare the (partially integrated) measured spectral function S(E m , p m ) to the calculated S P W IA (E m , p m ) in the plane-wave impulse approximation (PWIA). We will show, however, that the spectral function does not factorize as S P W IA (E m , p m ) times a (E m , p m )-independent attenuation factor. This is due to the fact the FSI of the struck proton significantly distorts the p ⊥ -distribution [8]. Evidently, elastic rescatterings deflect the struck proton and only the inelastic pN cross section σ in (pN) contributes to the attenuation of the p ⊥ -integrated cross section [2,8]. In parallel kinematics ( p ⊥ = 0), on the other hand, the attenuation is controlled by σ tot (pN) [8]. Thus, because of the finite p ⊥ -acceptance in the NE18 experiment, an accurate evaluation of the FSI effects is necessary for the quantitative interpretation of the data.</p>

				<p>We begin with the analysis of the d(e, e ′ p) scattering. At Q 2 ∼ &gt; 1 (GeV/c) 2 the kinetic energy of the struck proton is large, T kin ≈ Q 2 /2m p , and we can use the Glauber approximation for the FSI of the struck proton with the spectator neutron [8]. Then the momentum distribution, f d ( p m ), of the observed protons can be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f d (p m,z , p ⊥ ) = φ d (p m,z , p ⊥ ) − σ tot (pn) 16π 2 d 2 k φ d (p m,z , p ⊥ − k) exp − 1 2 B k 2 2 , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where φ d ( k) is the momentum-space wave function of the deuteron, and B denotes the diffraction slope for elastic pn scattering. The measured transparency factor</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T d (p m,z = 0) = p max ⊥ d 2 p ⊥ f d ( p ⊥ )/ p max ⊥ d 2 p ⊥ |φ d ( p ⊥ )| 2 (2) explicitly depends on the values p ⊥ ≤ p max ⊥ accepted in the spectrometer. In NE18, p max ⊥ = 170 MeV/c</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>while the p m,z -acceptance is very small [1]. Since B ≪ R</p>

			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>d , where R d denotes the radius of the deuteron, the rescattering term in (1) is almost constant over this range of p ⊥ . On the other hand, (R d p</figDesc>
					<trash>max ⊥ ) 2 ≫ 1. This leads to a simple estimate of the attenuation effect 1 − T d ∼ σ tot (pn) 2πR 2 d ∼ 0.07 , (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is about twice as large as the Glauber&apos;s shadowing effect in σ tot (pd) [9,10]. Using a realistic Bonn wave function for the deuteron [11], the detailed predictions at p m,z = 0 are shown in Fig. 1. An extension to heavier targets is straightforward. With the broad E m -acceptance of the NE18 experiment closure becomes applicable and, in the absence of FSI, one would obtain the single-particle momentum distribution, dσ P W IA ∝ n F (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p) with n F ( p) = 1 Z dE m S P W IA (E m , p) = 1 A(2π) 3 d r 1 d r 1 ′ ρ 1 ( r 1 , r 1 ′ ) exp[i k ′ ( r 1 − r 1 ′ )] , (4) where ρ 1 ( r, r</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>′ ) denotes the one-body density matrix while Z and A are the charge and mass number of the nucleus, respectively. With allowance for FSI [6,8,12], on the other hand,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dσ A ∝ 1 Z dE m S(E m , p m ) = d r ′ d r ρ 1 ( r, r ′ ) exp[i p m ( r ′ − r)] · exp − 1 2 (1 − iα pN )σ tot (pN)t( b, z) − 1 2 (1 + iα pN )σ tot (pN)t( b ′ , z ′ ) · exp t( b, max(z, z ′ ))ξ( ∆) . (5) where r = ( b, z), r ′ = ( b ′ , z ′ ), ∆ = r − r ′ , t(b, z) = ∞ z dz ′ n A (b, z</trash>

					<figDesc>′ ) and n A ( r) is the matter density. Furthermore, α pN denotes the ratio of the real and imaginary parts of the forward pN scattering amplitude and ξ( ∆) = d 2 q [dσ el (pN)/d 2 q] exp(i q ∆) . Since k F R A ≫ 1, Eq. (5) can be further simplified by employing the local-density approximation [13], ρ 1 ( r, r ′ ) = ρ( ∆)n A ( R) , where R = ( r + r ′ )/2. The FSI has two effects: (1) besides the attenuation, there appears a phase factor exp[iσ tot (pN)α pN n A (b, z)(z − z ′ )] which</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>makes the measured missing momentum p m,z different from the longitudinal momentum k z of the target proton by an amount k z − p m,z = ∆p m,z ≈ σ tot (pN)α pN n A ∼ α pN · 70 (MeV/c) . (6) This momentum shift is the main contributor to distortion of the p m,z -distribution as compared to the PWIA where p m,z = k z . All the other corrections are small [12]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. (2) the factor exp t( b, z)ξ( ∆) in the integrand of Eq. (5) causes a broadening of the p ⊥ distribution [6,8]: f A ( p ⊥ ) = 1 Z dE m dp m,z S(E m , p m,z , p ⊥ ) = ∞ ν=0 W (ν) f (ν) ( p ⊥ ) . (7) The probability, W (ν) , for ν-fold elastic rescattering equals W (ν) = 1 A dzd 2 b n A ( b, z) exp −σ tot (pN)t( b, z) [t( b, z)σ el (pN)] ν ν! (8) and f (ν) ( p ⊥ ) = d 2 s [B/νπ] exp −Bs 2 /ν f P W IA ( p ⊥ − s) , (9) where f P W IA ( p ⊥ ) = dk z</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>n F (k z , p ⊥ ) is the p ⊥ -distribution in PWIA. For the purpose of the present analysis it is sufficient to assume f (0) ( p ⊥ ) = f P W IA ( p ⊥ ) [12]. The normalization of f A is such that d 2 p ⊥ f A (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p ⊥ ) = ν=0 W (ν) = T A , where T A = 1 A dzd 2 b n A ( b, z) exp −σ in (pN)t( b, z) = 1 Aσ in (pN) d 2 b {1 − exp[−σ in (pN)T (b)]} (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is total transmission factor or &apos;nuclear transparency factor&apos; [2]. The quasielastic knockout in parallel kinematics, p ⊥ = 0, is dominated by the ν = 0 (PWIA) component of f A ( p ⊥ ) and the corresponding transmission factor W (0) is given by Eq. (10) with σ in (pN) replaced by σ tot (pN). The difference between σ tot (pN) and σ in (pN), and consequently between W (0) and T A , is very large at moderate energies [14] (Fig. 1).</p>

				<p>The above discussion proves that the distortion effects do not allow a factorization of the measured spectral function S(E m , p m ) into S P W IA (E m , p m ) and an overall attenuation factor. Experimentally, one compares the observed nuclear cross section to the PWIA cross section integrated over the acceptance domain D in the (E m , p m,z , p ⊥ ) space [1].</p>

				<p>In order to extract the attenuation effect, it is therefore necessary to include the shift ∆p m,z in the PWIA cross section, such that the proper definition of nuclear transparency, relevant to the NE18 experiment, should be T A (NE18) = D dE m dp m,z dp ⊥ S(E m , p m,z , p ⊥ ) D dE m dp m,z dp ⊥ S P W IA (E m , p m,z + ∆p m,z , p ⊥ )</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>. (11)</head>

				<p>At values of T kin of the NE18 experiment the real part of the pN elastic amplitude is rather large, α pN ∼ −0.5 [14], and the effective shift (6) of the missing longitudinal momentum ∆p m,z ∼ −35 MeV/c. The effect of the shift ∆p m,z vanishes for a wide p m,z -acceptance, but for a narrow acceptance centered at p m,z = p * one has T A (∆p m,z ) T A (∆p m,z = 0)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>≈ 1 + 5 2 · (∆p m,z + p * ) 2 − (p * ) 2 k 2 F (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which enhances T A by ∼ 5% at p * = 0. This is still within the NE18 error bars. At Q 2 ∼ &lt; 1 (GeV/c) 2 , i.e., at T kin ∼ &lt; 0.5 GeV, both σ pN and α pN change rapidly with T kin [14] and the momentum shift may lead to a spurious Q 2 dependence of the spectral function and of the y-scaling function. This point has been missed in the discussion of FSI effects in [15]. The effects of the momentum shift (6) and the p ⊥ -broadening effect approximately factorize. The NE18 cut p ⊥ ∼ &lt; p max = 250 MeV/c [1] partly includes struck protons which are elastically rescattered, and we calculate T A (NE18) for this cutoff making use of Eq. (7) for the p ⊥ -distribution.</p>

				<p>As can be seen from Fig. 1 we find very good quantitative agreement between our predictions for T A (NE18) and the data. This leads to the following conclusions: (1) the Glauber theory gives an adequate description of the FSI at moderately large Q 2 , (2) the signal of CT in A(e, e ′ p) reactions is still negligibly small at Q 2 ≤ 7 (GeV/c) 2 , in agreement with our prediction ([2,3,5-7]). For 12 C(e, e ′ p) scattering we estimate the threshold for CT at Q 2 ∼ 5 (GeV/c) 2 and CT effects shown as the short-dashed curve in Fig. 1 increase T C by ∼ 5% at the largest Q 2 of the NE18 experiment (Fig. 1). For heavier nuclei the CT signal is even smaller. The main reason is the smallness of the contribution from inelastic intermediate states because the amplitudes for the diffraction excitations p + p → i + p are small as compared to the amplitude of elastic rescattering p + p → p + p [12,3,5,7].</p>

				<p>In summary, we have calculated the effects of distortions on the spectral function for the nuclear transparency experiment NE18 at SLAC [1]. It has been shown that the FSI, when treated in the Glauber approximation, is able to explain the large shadowing effect observed in d(e, e ′ p) reaction. Glauber&apos;s multiple-scattering theory is also found to provide a good description of the experimental results on heavier targets. In spite of the small CT effect in the data, even at the highest Q 2 , the possibility of observing a signal in dedicated 4 He(e, e ′ p) experiments at CEBAF should not be ruled out. A discussion of this reaction will be presented elsewhere [18].</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure captions:</head>

					<figDesc>Fig. 1 Predictions for the Q 2 dependence of the p ⊥ -integrated nuclear transparency T A (dashed lines), the transparency W (0) for parallel kinematics (dotted lines) and the transparency T A (NE18) including the acceptance cuts of the NE18 experiment [1]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The dot-dashed curve in panel for 12 C indicates the effect from the onset of color transparency.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgement</head>
				<p>Thanks are due to B.Fillipone, A.Lung and R.McKeown for discussions and communications on the NE18 experiment and to H. Holtmann for assistance in preparing the manuscript. This work was supported in part by the Polish KBN grant 2 2409 9102 and the NSF grant PHY-89-21025.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NE18 Collaboration: B.Fillipone, preliminary results reported at PANIC, Perugia</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Szczurek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Speth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wambach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Zoller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jü</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Kfa-Ikp</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">to be published in Nucl.Phys. A, and paper in preparation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Szczurek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Speth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wambach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Zoller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">287</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Szczurek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Speth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wambach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Zoller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">281</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Speth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The ELFE Project on an Electron Laboratory for</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Europe</title>
		<editor>J.Arvieux and E.De Sanctis, Editrice Compositori</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Color Transparency: Novel Test of QCD in Nuclear Interactions Surveys in High Energy Physics (1993), in press; N.N.Nikolaev, High Energy Nuclear Reactions in QCD: Color Transparency Aspects, in: Lecture notes of</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaevfujiwara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kondo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Landau Inst. preprint Landau RCNP Kikuchi School</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="93128" />
			<date type="published" when="1992-11-19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Color transparency after the NE18 and E665 ex- periments, Jü preprint KFA-IKP(Th)-1993-30; to be published in Proceed- ings of the Workshop on Electron Nucleus Scattering</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<pubPlace>Elba International Physics Center, Marciana Marina, Elba</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Szczurek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Speth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wambach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Zoller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jü</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Kfa-Ikp</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Th)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1993" to="31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Glauber</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Matthiae</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">135</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Dakhno</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sov</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">590</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Machleidt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Holinde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ch</forename>
				<surname>Elster</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>paper. in preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Negele</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Vautherin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1472" to="1081" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Lechanoine-Leluc</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Lehar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">47</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Benhar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Fabrocini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Fantoni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Miller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Pandharipande</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Sick</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2328</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JETP Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">82</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Zotov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Zarev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<editor>G.Alberi and G.Goggi</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Nikolaev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Szczureck</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Speth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wambach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Zoller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. be published</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
