<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Braided Hopf Algebras and Differential Calculus *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1994-03-16">16 Mar 1994 February 1994</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Michael</forename>
								<surname>Schlieker</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Bruno</forename>
								<surname>Zumino</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Theoretical Physics Group Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<region>California</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Braided Hopf Algebras and Differential Calculus *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1994-03-16">16 Mar 1994 February 1994</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9403093v1 ae † Supported in part by a Feodor-Lynen Fellowship. Disclaimer This document was prepared as an account of work sponsored by the United States Gov-ernment. Neither the United States Government nor any agency thereof, nor The Regents of the University of California, nor any of their employees, makes any warranty, express or implied, or assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of any information, apparatus, product, or process disclosed, or represents that its use would not infringe privately owned rights. Reference herein to any specific commer-cial products process, or service by its trade name, trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise, does not necessarily constitute or imply its endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the United States Government or any agency thereof, or The Regents of the University of California. The views and opinions of authors expressed herein do not necessarily state or reflect those of the United States Government or any agency thereof of The Regents of the University of California and shall not be used for advertising or product endorsement purposes. Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory is an equal opportunity employer. — 2 —</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We show that the algebra of the bicovariant differential calculus on a quantum group can be understood as a projection of the cross product between a braided Hopf algebra and the quantum double of the quantum group. The resulting super-Hopf algebra can be reproduced by extending the exterior derivative to tensor products.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>On the superalgebra of the bicovariant differential calculus on a quantum group † A we introduce a Hopf algebra structure in two different ways. The first approach starts from a set of commutation relations between the Hopf algebra maps of A and the bicovariant exterior differential d. These commutation relations yield a consistent super-Hopf algebra structure on the differential algebra. The resemblance of this structure with the ordinary Hopf algebra of inhomogeneous quantum groups leads to the second approach. Starting from the braided Hopf algebra of the Maurer-Cartan one-forms it is possible to obtain a Hopf algebra by a bosonization procedure. This Hopf algebra contains the quantum double of A as a subgroup. By introducing an appropriate projection it is possible to reproduce the results of the first approach.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Hopf structure for bicovariant Differential calculus on Quantum Groups</head>

				<p>We first recall the general notions for a bicovariant first order differential calculus on a quantum group A with multiplication m, comultiplication ∆, antipode S and counit ǫ introduced by Woronowicz in ref. [Wor]. A bicovariant first order differential calculus is a differential calculus (Γ, d) such that Γ is a left and right A-comodule and d satisfies :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d : A → Γ d(uw) = (du)w + u(dw) ∆ R (du) = (d ⊗ id)∆(u) and ∆ L (du) = (id ⊗ d)∆(u) , (1.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ∆ R and ∆ L are left and right coactions of A on Γ. Furthermore we require that Γ is a bimodule over A ([Wor]). The explicit bimodule relations compatible with the coactions on the space of one-forms have been studied in terms of R-matrices in refs.:[CSWW], [Jur], [Zum].</p>

				<p>In the following we use a left-invariant basis Θ for the above defined bicovariant bimodule Γ. These basis elements Θ are expressed in terms of the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Cartan forms ω i j = m(S ⊗ d)∆(t i j ) ( t i j are the generators of the quantum group A ) through ω i j = Θ k l χ l k (t i j ) , (1.2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) † For simplicity we assume that the quantum group is of type A n−1 — 3 — where χ are the vector fields on the quantum group A defined through du = (χ l k * u)Θ k l (compare [CSWW], [Jur], [SWZ], [Wor], [Zum]). The bimodule relations have the form :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Θ i j u = ((l +i k S(l − ) l j ) * u)Θ k l , (1.3) where l + , l</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>− are the generators of A * introduced in [FRT]. Using the above relations, the algebra corresponding to the bicovariant differential calculus can be defined in the following way</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A := C I &lt; t i j , Θ i j &gt; (I, J, K) , (1.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where I is the defining ideal of the quantum group A, J is the ideal which is generated by the bimodule relations (1.3) and K is given by K :</p>

				<p><formula>= P r jl ik Θ i j Θ k l , (1.5)</formula></p>

				<p>where P r are the projectors defined in [CSWW] by the following equations:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P r (1 − σ) = 0 , r = 1, 2 σ ii ′ l ′ l jj ′ k ′ k = (l +i k S(l − ) l j )(S(t i ′ k ′ )t l ′ j ′ ) . (1.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the so defined differential algebra we now obtain a (super-) Hopf algebra structure starting from the following requirements,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d(a ⊗ b) = da ⊗ b + (−1) |a| a ⊗ db , [∆, d] = 0 , [S, d] = 0 , [ǫ, d] = 0 , S(ab) = (−1) |a|·|b| S(b)S(a) , (1 ⊗ a)(b ⊗ 1) = (−1) |a|·|b| (b ⊗ a), a, b ∈ A are homogeneous elements of degree |a|, |b| . (1.7)</trash>

					<figDesc>The algebra homomorphism property of the comultiplication with respect to the bimodule relations which generate the ideal J follows directly from the definition of the bicovariant bimodule Γ. The algebra homomorphism property with respect to eq.(1.5) can be shown as follows: using eq. (1.2) it is easy to calculate the coproduct, the counit and the antipode for the Θ&apos;s, ∆(Θ</figDesc>
					<trash>i j ) = Θ k l ⊗ S(t i k )t l j + 1 ⊗ Θ i j , ǫ(Θ i j ) = 0 , S(Θ i j ) = −Θ k l (S(S(t i k )t l j )) . (1.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Inserting this comultiplication in eq.(1.5) and using the definition of the projectors from eq.(1.6) together with the bimodule relations one verifies immediately that the comultiplication on the forms leaves the ideal K invariant. All other Hopf algebra axioms can be checked directly. Writing the comultiplication, the antipode and the counit in terms of the basis forms Θ exhibits a close resemblance between the differential (super-) Hopf algebra and the Hopf algebra of inhomogeneous quantum groups as introduced in reference [SWW]. It was shown by Majid [Maj1] that one can reconstruct the Hopf algebra of inhomogeneous quantum groups through a bosonization procedure from the braided Hopf algebra of pure translations. In the next chapter we recall the notions in [Maj1] and then we show that the above defined differential Hopf algebra is related to a Hopf algebra which fits in the general bosonization scheme as defined in refs.:[Maj2][Maj3]. The procedure defined in eq.(1.7) is applicable to every bicovariant differential calculus on a Hopf algebra if the differential algebra has a basis of left invariant one-forms Ω</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I with quadratic relations R IJ Ω I Ω J = 0 and satisfies R IJ (∆ R (Ω I )∆ L (Ω J ) + ∆ L (Ω I )∆ R (Ω J )) = 0 . (1.9)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Bosonization of the braided Maurer-Cartan Hopf algebra</head>

				<p>Following e.g. ref. [Maj3]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>B = (B, ∆, S, ǫ) is called a braided Hopf algebra if B is an algebra and the maps ∆ : B → B ⊗ B, ǫ : B → C I, S : B → B satisfy the Hopf algebra axioms with respect to the following algebra structure in B ⊗ B: (a ⊗ b) · (c ⊗ d) = aΨ(b ⊗ c)d , (2.1) with Ψ replacing the normal transposition τ ( the detailed properties of Ψ are listed in [Maj3]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>). The antipode is braided antimultiplicative</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S(ab) = mΨ(S(a) ⊗ S(b)) . (2.2)</trash>

					<figDesc>The algebra M of the Maurer-Cartan forms Θ with relations (1.5) can be turned into a braided Hopf algebra using the following definitions:</figDesc>
					<trash>∆(Θ) = Θ ⊗ 1 + 1 ⊗ Θ = Θ (1) ⊗ Θ (2) , ǫ(Θ) = 0 , S(Θ) = −Θ. (2.3) The Braiding is given by Ψ(Θ i j ⊗ Θ k l ) = (−1)σ −1 (Θ i j ⊗ Θ k l ) . (2.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In the following ⊗ stands for a graded tensor product with standard grading (compare eq.(1.7)). The braiding Ψ satisfies all the properties listed in [Maj3]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Now we consider — 5 — the coaction of the Hopf algebra A on the braided Hopf algebra of the Maurer-Cartan forms. In the following we assume that the one-forms Θ transform trivially under the left coaction and form a representation space for the right adjoint coaction. Therefore we are able to follow the construction by Majid ([Maj1]). First of all one has to identify the braiding introduced in (2.4) as being the adjoint representation of some universal structure defined with respect to the Hopf algebra A, i.e. if X, Y are two right comodules of the quasitriangular Hopf algebra A then the braiding can be written in the form :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ψ(x ⊗ y) = y (1) ⊗ x (1) R(x (2) ⊗ y (2) ) , (2.5) where Φ(x) = x (1) ⊗ x (2) , Φ(y) = y (1) ⊗ y (2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) are the right coactions and R is the universal R-matrix of A. The algebra relations for this generalized semidirect product are given by:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(x ⊗ 1)(1 ⊗ a) = (1 ⊗ a (1) )(x ⊳ a (2) ⊗ 1) , (2.6) with x ∈ X and a ∈ A and x ⊳ a := x (1) R(x (2) ⊗ a) . (2.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the case of the braided Hopf algebra of Maurer-Cartan forms one has to be more careful in defining the bosonized Hopf algebra because applying eqs.(2.6),(2.7) in a naive way would lead to a trivial differential calculus where the scalar one-form X (see [CSWW]) commutes with all the elements of A. Such a differential calculus does not coincide with the calculus defined in section 2. Even allowing for some function of R in eq. (2.6) does not solve the problem because the right transformation of X is trivial and therefore does not respect the definition of the exterior derivative on forms. This problem can be solved by realizing that the dual Hopf algebra A * can be embedded as a * -Hopf subalgebra in the quantum double D(A * ) of A * defined by [RS] (see [CEJSZ], [Jur2], [Pod] for the involution properties): m = (m ⊗ m)σ 12 ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∆ = R −1 23 τ 23 (∆ ⊗ ∆)R 23 , ǫ = ǫ ⊗ ǫ , S = R 21 (S ⊗ S)R −1 12 , R = R −1 41 R −1 42 R 13 R 23 , (a ⊗ b) † = R 21 (b † ⊗ a † )R −1 21 . (2.8) (</trash>

					<figDesc>In the following we will use the Hopf algebra (D(A * ), R −1 3412 )). The Hopf subalgebra embedding is given by ∆(A * ). The connection to the bosonization procedure described above is done using the following identity:</figDesc>
					<trash>R −1 3412 (S(t) i j ⊗ t k l ⊗ id ⊗ id) = ∆(l +i j S(l − ) k l )(id ⊗ id) . (2.9) Eq. (2.9) implies that ∆ R : B → B ⊗ D(A * ) * , with ∆ R (Θ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p><formula>i j ) = Θ k l ⊗ S(t) i k ˆ ⊗t l j = Θ (1) ⊗ Θ (2) , (2.10) — 6 —</formula></p>

				<p>where a ˆ ⊗b is the bicrossproduct in D(A * ) * and satisfies (a ˆ ⊗b)(c ˆ ⊗d) = m(R 32 * (a ⊗ b ⊗ c ⊗ d) * R</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−1 32 ) . (2.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the other hand eq.(2.9) also shows that adopting this convention is enough to reproduce the bicovariant differential calculus described in section 2 because the half representation of the universal R-matrix defined in eq.(2.9) lies already in the Hopf algebra embedding of A * in D(A * ). Therefore it is not necessary to extend the coproduct on A to a mapping to A ⊗ D(A * ) * .</p>

				<p>The coproduct of the Maurer-Cartan forms Θ in the bosonized Hopf algebra M &gt;&lt;|D(A * ) * is defined through (1 is the unit in D</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(A * ) * ) † ∆(Θ ⊗ 1) = (Θ (1) (1) ⊗ 1) ⊗ (1 ⊗ Θ (2) (1) )(Θ (2) ⊗ 1) . (2.12) Using (2.5), (2.6) and (2.9) we obtain the following expression for the algebra relations in M &gt;&lt;|D(A * ) * (Θ i j ⊗ 1)(1 ⊗ a ˆ ⊗b) = (1 ⊗ a (1) ˆ ⊗b (1) )(Θ k l ⊗ 1) R −1 3412 (S(t) i k ⊗ t l j ⊗ a (2) ⊗ b (2) ) = (1 ⊗ a (1) ˆ ⊗b (1) )(Θ k l ⊗ 1) (l +i k S(l − ) l j )(a (2) b (2) ) . (2.13)</trash>

					<figDesc>As already pointed out earlier, eq.(2.13) shows that the commutation relation do not distinguish between elements from the quantum double of A and A itself. Therefore it is possible to introduce the following * -homomorphism from the quantum double to the original Hopf algebra A ϕ : D(A * ) * → A, with ϕ(a ˆ ⊗b) = m(a ˆ ⊗b) . (2.14) The homomorphism property can be verified directly using the definition of the product in the quantum double (2.11). The application of the projection ϕ on M &gt;&lt;|D(A * ) * (where ϕ is the identity on M ) yields the Hopf algebra defined in section 2 through eq.(1.7). Therefore we obtain the following equivalence:</figDesc>
					<trash>(M &gt;&lt;|D(A * ) * , ∆, S, ǫ) ϕ −→ (A, ∆, S, ǫ) . (2.15</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>) † For simplicity we use the same symbol for the coproduct in D(A * ) * and M &gt;&lt;|D(A * ) * .</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Complex Quantum Enveloping Algebras as Twisted Tensor Products</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Cejsz ] Chryssomalakos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Engeldinger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Jurč</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Schlieker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Zumino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bicovariant differential calculus on quantum groups SU q (N )</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Carow-Watamura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Schlieker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Watamura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Weich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. SO q (N</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">605</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantization of Lie groups and Lie algebras</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Faddeev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Reshetikhin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Takhtajan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Algebra and Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">178</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differential calculus on quantized simple Lie groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Jurč</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">177</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">More on quantum groups from the quantization point of view. ASI TU preprint</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Jurč</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Braided momentum in the q-Poincare group</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Majid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Quantum Double as Quantum Mechanics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Majid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Preprint DAMTP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross products by Braided Groups and Bosonization. Preprint DAMTP/91-11, to appear in J. Algebra. [Pod] Podle´ quantum groups and their real representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Majid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RIMS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">754</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum R-matrices and factorization problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Reshetikhin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Semenov-Tian-Shansky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.G.P</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="533" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inhomogeneous Quantum Groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sww</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Schlieker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Weich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Weixler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z.Phys. C-Particles and Fields</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">79</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bicovariant Quantum Algebras and Quantum Lie Algebras</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Schupp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Watts</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Zumino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">305</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differential calculus on compact matrix pseudogroups (quan- tum groups)</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Woronowicz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">125</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to the Differential Geometry of quantum groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Zumino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mathematical Physics X, K. Schmü Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
