<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Regularization in the gauged Nambu–Jona-Lasinio model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1994-07">July 1994</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Tony</forename>
								<surname>Gherghetta</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>e-mail: tonyg@yukawa.uchicago.edu</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Enrico Fermi Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60637</postCode>
									<settlement>Chicago</settlement>
									<region>IL</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Regularization in the gauged Nambu–Jona-Lasinio model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1994-07">July 1994</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-ph/9408225v1 3 Aug 1994 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Various prescriptions employed for regulating gauged Nambu–Jona-Lasinio type models such as the top-quark condensate model are discussed. The use of dimensional regularization maintains gauge invariance but destroys the quad-ratic divergence in the gap equation. If instead a simple ultraviolet momentum cutoff is used to regulate loop integrals, then gauge invariance is destroyed by a quadratically divergent term as well as by ambiguities associated with arbitrary routing of loop momenta. Finally it is shown that one can use dispersion relations to regulate the top-quark condensate model. This prescription maintains gauge invariance and does not depend on arbitrary shifts in loop momenta.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="2">The NJL model and dimensional regularization</head>

				<p>Let us begin with the minimal top-condensate model of Bardeen, Hill and Lindner [3]. The NJL Lagrangian for the Standard Model at the scale Λ is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = L kinetic + G( ¯ Ψ La t a R )( ¯ t Rb Ψ b L ) ; Ψ L = t L b L (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where a and b are colour indices and L kinetic contains only the gauge boson and fermion kinetic energy terms. Note that (1) is an effective Lagrangian of some renormalizable interaction above the cutoff scale Λ and that the four-fermion coupling constant, G must be positive to ensure an attractive interaction.</p>

				<p>The induced top quark mass resulting from the four-fermion interaction in (1) is obtained by solving the gap equation to leading order in N colour</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 = 2GN c i d 4 k (2π) 4 1 k 2 − m 2 t . (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Assuming that (1) describes physics up to the scale Λ the integral (2) can be regularized with an ultraviolet Euclidean momentum cutoff Λ. This leads to the gap</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>equation 1 = GN c 8π 2 Λ 2 − m 2 t ln Λ 2 m 2 t , (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have only kept leading order terms. Notice that there is a quadratically divergent term in the gap equation (3) which is nothing other than the reincarnation of the Higgs boson mass quadratic divergence in the Standard Model and leads to the usual gauge-hierarchy problem. The low energy effective Lagrangian (1) is clearly gauge invariant because it only contains the gauge boson kinetic energy. When the scalar ¯ tt condensate forms, the gauge bosons must acquire mass in a SU(2) × U(1) gauge invariant manner because an explicit mass term would break gauge invariance. In the top-quark condensate model the gauge boson mass arises from the fermion mass dependence of the gauge boson self-energy, and so one cannot simply discard all the non-gauge invariant terms in the self-energy. If one employs dimensional regularization then it turns out that only the fermion mass dependent non-gauge invariant terms survive and they combine with terms from the Nambu-Goldstone mode contributions, so that the gauge bosons become massive in a gauge invariant manner. However the unfortunate feature of the dimensional regularization scheme is that it also kills all quadratic divergences. This is because in dimensional regularization</p>

				<p><formula>lim m 2 →0 d D k k 2 − m 2 = 0 . (4)</formula></p>

				<p>While this is fine for the quadratically divergent non-gauge invariant terms in the gauge boson self-energy, it is a disaster for the gap equation because dimensionally regularizing the integral in (2) destroys the quadratic divergence in (3). In particular the gap equation without the quadratically divergent term is given by</p>

				<p><formula>1 = − GN c 8π 2 m 2 t ln µ 2 m 2 t + 1 , (5)</formula></p>

				<p>where µ is the renormalization scale. Eq. (5) would mean that the four-Fermi coupling G &lt; 0, corresponding to a repulsive interaction. This would contradict the assumed attractive interaction between top quarks in (1). Clearly we need a regulator that is sensitive to the quadratic divergences.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Ambiguities in the NJL model</head>

				<p>The simplest prescription for regulating divergent integrals that does not destroy the quadratic divergences in the gap equation is to use an ultraviolet Euclidean momentum cutoff Λ. Let us now examine the consequences of using this simple prescription for the top-condensate model. Consider the sum of fermion-fermion scattering amplitudes depicted in Figure 1, where the amplitudes are summed to leading order in N colour and the QCD coupling constant is zero (fermion bubble approximation). Assuming that the gap equation is satisfied, the fermion-fermion scattering amplitude in the scalar ¯ tt channel is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ s (p 2 ) = iG 2 1 − iG 2 N c d 4 l (2π) 4 Tr 1 l / + (1 − α)/ p − m t 1 l / − α/ p − m t −1 ≃ (4π) 2 2N c 1 2 ∆(α)p 2 + (p 2 − 4m 2 t ) 1 0 dx ln Λ 2 m 2 t − p 2 x(1 − x) −1 , (6) where α is an arbitrary routing parameter introduced in the loop momentum (see Figure 2) and ∆(α) = (1 − 2α + 2α 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). Normally the parameter α is neglected because the momentum integration variable can be shifted by a finite amount for integrals which are at most logarithmically divergent. However for integrals which are more divergent, this shift of integration variable results in the appearance of an extra &quot; surface term &quot; which depends on α [6]. This causes the pole in the scattering amplitude (6) to shift by an amount proportional to ∆</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(α)/ ln(Λ 2 /m 2 t ) from the usual value at p 2 = 4 m 2 t . However since Λ is necessarily finite and α is an unrestricted constant, the = + + + ...</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>

					<figDesc>The infinite sum of fermion bubble diagrams. The scalar ¯</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>tt channel has a pole at 2m t which corresponds to the composite Higgs scalar. The pseudoscalar ¯ tt and flavoured tb channels give rise to three massless Nambu-Goldstone bosons. pole receives an arbitrary correction and so makes the relation between the top and physical Higgs boson mass arbitrary. Note that when there is no routing ambiguity or α = 0, the correction to the pole term is negligible for large Λ. This momentum routing ambiguity, in the context of the NJL model, was first noticed by Willey [5] and is the result of using a momentum cutoff regulator. It should be remarked that this routing ambiguity is completely different from an earlier ambiguity noted by Hasenfratz et al. [7], who considered a lattice formulation of the NJL theory. In the lattice theory, higher derivative interaction terms can be added to the NJL Lagrangian, which are in equivalent universality classes, in the sense of defining the theory by going to a critical point. These terms introduce additional arbitrary constants and give an ambiguous prediction for the ratio m</p>

				<p><formula>2 σ /m 2 f .</formula></p>

				<p>However assuming that the non-renormalizable four-Fermi interaction arises from a renormalizable gauge theory at high energy, it can be shown that the additional arbitrary constants associated with higher derivative interaction terms are numbers of O(1) and do not greatly influence the BHL predictions [8]. Similarly in the neutral pseudoscalar ¯ tt channel the arbitrary surface term, ∆(α) will appear. The scattering amplitude is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ P (p 2 ) ≃ (4π) 2 2N c p 2 ∆(α) 2 + 1 0 dx ln Λ 2 m 2 t − p 2 x(1 − x) −1 , (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the gap equation has again been invoked. Notice that the neutral Nambu- Goldstone pole still occurs at p = 0, except that now the coupling constant depends on the arbitrary parameter α. A similar dependence on the arbitrary parameter α occurs for the charged Nambu-Goldstone modes when one performs the fermion bubble sum in the flavoured tb channel. Assuming m b ≃ 0 one obtains for the scattering amplitude in the tb channel</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ F (p 2 ) ≃ (4π) 2 8N c p 2 ∆(α) 4 + 1 0 dx (1 − x) ln Λ 2 m 2 t (1 − x) − p 2 x(1 − x) −1 . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Again notice that the routing ambiguity affects only the coupling constant and not the masslessness of the charged Nambu-Goldstone boson.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p → k + (1 -α) p k -α p p →</trash>

					<head>Figure 2:</head>

					<figDesc>The loop momentum routing in a fermion bubble diagram.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The gauge bosons in the NJL model become massive by &quot; eating &quot; up the dynamically generated Nambu-Goldstone modes. This corresponds to a dynamical Higgs mechanism. Since there are routing ambiguities in the Nambu-Goldstone modes it is clear that the gauge boson masses will also be afflicted with this arbitrariness.</p>

				<p>The question of whether gauge invariance can survive this arbitrariness needs to be checked. Consider first the W-boson propagator, where the gauge fields are rescaled so that the kinetic energy is −1/(4g 2 )F µν F µν . In the fermion bubble approximation, corrections to the propagator arise from the diagrams depicted in Figure 3. Again we will choose to regularize all divergent integrals with an ultraviolet cutoff, Λ and introduce an arbitrary parameter, α to represent the routing ambiguity in the loop momentum. The W-boson inverse propagator is given by the sum of three terms</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 g 2 2 D W µν (p) −1 = 1 g 2 2 (p µ p ν − g µν p 2 ) + Π µν (p) − 1 8 J µ (p)Γ F (p 2 )J ν (p) , (9) where g 2 is the SU(2) coupling constant and Π µν (p) = i 8 d 4 l (2π) 4 Tr γ µ (1 − γ 5 ) 1 l / + (1 − α)/ p − m b γ ν (1 − γ 5 ) 1 l / − α/ p − m t , (10) J µ (p) = i d 4 l (2π) 4 Tr γ µ (1 − γ 5 ) 1 l / + (1 − α)/ p − m b (1 + γ 5 ) 1 l / − α/ p − m t . (11) In Eq.(9</trash>

					<figDesc>) Π µν is the usual one loop gauge boson self-energy. There will be two types of divergent integrals appearing in (10) and (11) which are not invariant under an arbitrary shift of the loop momentum. These are given by</figDesc>
					<trash>d 4 l (2π) 4 l µ [(l + χp) 2 − M 2 ] 2 = d 4 l (2π) 4 −χp µ (l 2 − M 2 ) 2 + i 32π 2 χp µ , (12) d 4 l (2π) 4 l µ l ν [(l + χp) 2 − M 2 ] 2 = d 4 l (2π) 4 (l µ l ν + χ 2 p µ p ν ) (l 2 − M 2 ) 2 + i 96π 2 χ 2 (g µν p 2 − p µ p ν ) + i 4π 2 χ 4 p µ p ν p 2 1 0 dy 1 0 dz y 3 z 2 M 2 − χ 2 p 2 y(1 − y + yz(1 − z)) , (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where χ is an l and p independent constant. Using these expressions and assuming the top quark mass satisfies the gap equation (3) the W-boson vacuum polarization + +</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3:</head>

					<figDesc>Diagrams contributing to the gauge boson vacuum polarization in the fermion bubble approximation.</figDesc>
					<trash>becomes 1 g 2 2 D W µν (p) −1 = p µ p ν p 2 − g µν p 2 ¯ g 2 2 (p 2 , α) − ¯ f 2 (p 2 , α) − g µν ¯ h 2 (p 2 , α) , (14) where 1 ¯ g 2 2 (p 2 , α) = 1 g 2 2 + N c (4π) 2 1 0 dx 2x(1 − x) ln Λ 2 M 2 (x) − 13 18 + 5 3 α(1 − α) − 8B(α, M) , (15) ¯ f 2 (p 2 , α) = m 2 t N c (4π) 2 1 0 dx (1 − x) ln Λ 2 M 2 (x) − 1 2 ( 1 2 + α) 2 1 0 dx (1 − x) ln Λ 2 M 2 (x) − 1 2 ( 1 2 + α − α 2 ) , (16) ¯ h 2 (p 2 , α) = N c (4π) 2 1 2 Λ 2 − m 2 t A(α, M) + p 2 ( 1 3 − α + α 2 + 8B(α, M)) , (17) A(α, M) = α(1 + α) 1 0 dx (1 − x) ln Λ 2 M 2 (x) − 1 4 α(1 + 3α) 1 0 dx (1 − x) ln Λ 2 M 2 (x) − 1 2 ( 1 2 + α − α 2 ) , (18) B(α, M) = p 2 1 0 dx 1 0 dy 1 0 dz (x − α) 4 y 3 z 2 M 2 (x) − (x − α) 2 p 2 y(1 − y + yz(1 − z)) , (19) and M 2 (x) = m 2 t (1 − x) − p 2 x(1</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>− x). The expression for the W-boson inverse propagator (14) contains a quadratic divergence (∝ g µν Λ 2 ) which does not appear in the corresponding expression from BHL [3]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. This stems from the fact that an ultraviolet cutoff has been used instead of dimensional regularization. This quadratic term destroys gauge invariance and was first noticed a long time ago by Wentzel [9]. Apart from this quadratically divergent term, which would appear irrespective of loop momentum ambiguities, note that the arbitrary constant α is enough by itself to destroy gauge invariance. Unfortunately the ambiguity in the one loop W-boson self-energy and the Nambu-Goldstone boson term do not combine together to save gauge invariance. Similarly for the neutral gauge bosons we consider the contributions arising from the diagrams in Figure 3</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>and include all surface terms arising from divergent integrals. Working in the (B − W 3 ) basis we obtain in the limit m b ≃</figDesc>
					<trash>0 1 g i g j D 0 µν (p) −1 = p µ p ν p 2 − g µν 1 g 2 1 (p 2 ,α) 0 0 1 g 2 2 (p 2 ,α) p 2 − 1 −1 −1 1 f 2 (p 2 , α) −g µν 20 9 0 0 4 3 Q t + 2 9 0 0 2 3 Q b − 1 −1 −1 1 h 2 (p 2 , α) (20) where g 1 is the U(1) gauge coupling constant, g 2 is the SU(2) gauge coupling constant and 1 g 2 1 (p 2 , α) = 1 g 2 1 + N c (4π) 2 1 0 dx x(1 − x) 20 9 ln Λ 2 M 2 t (x) + 2 9 ln Λ 2 M 2 b (x) − 11 9 ( 13 18 − 5 3 α(1 − α)) − 80 9</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>B(α, M t ) − 8 9 B(α, M b ) , (21) 1 g 2 2 (p 2 , α)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= 1 g 2 2 + N c (4π) 2 1 0 dx x(1 − x) 4 3 ln Λ 2 M 2 t (x) + 2 3 ln Λ 2 M 2 b (x) − 13 18 + 5 3 α(1 − α) − 16 3 B(α, M t ) − 8 3 B(α, M b ) , (22) f 2 (p 2 , α) = N c (4π) 2 p 2 3 1 0 dx x(1 − x) ln M 2 b (x) M 2 t (x) − 4B(α, M t ) + 4B(α, M b ) + 1 2 m 2 t ( 1 0 dx ln Λ 2 M 2 t (x) − 1) 2 1 0 dx ln Λ 2 M 2 t (x) + 1 2 ∆(α) − 1   , (23) Q i (p 2 , α, m i ) = N c (4π) 2 1 4 Λ 2 − m 2 i + p 2 ( 1 3 − α + α 2 + 8B(α, M i )) , (24) h 2 (p 2 , α) = N c (4π) 2   m 2 t 4   (∆(α) − 1 3 ) 1 0 dx ln Λ 2 M 2 t (x) + 1 3 − 7 6 ∆(α) 1 0 dx ln Λ 2 M 2 t (x) + 1 2 ∆(α) − 1   + 2 3 p 2 (B(α, M t ) − B(α, M b ) , (25) with M 2 t (x) = m 2 t − p 2 x(1 − x) and M 2 b (x) = m 2 b − p 2 x(1 − x</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). Again we note that gauge invariance is destroyed by ambiguities coming from the surface terms of the linearly and quadratically divergent integrals as well as from the Wentzel term. In the limit that all surface terms are zero and ignoring the quadratic divergence arising from the cutoff regulator, the above expressions reduce to the results of BHL [3]. Thus by regulating divergent loop integrals with an ultraviolet momentum cutoff, one finds that the gauged NJL model is plagued with the problems of a non gauge-invariant Higgs mechanism and ambiguous quantitative predictions resulting from arbitrary loop momentum routing. These problems are solely an artifact of using a simple momentum cutoff.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Dispersion relations</head>

				<p>An alternative prescription for regulating the top-quark condensate model is to use dispersion relations. This prescription was previously employed by Nambu and Jona- Lasinio [2] in their dynamical model of elementary particles. In this prescription one first calculates the imaginary part of an amplitude A by means of Cutkosky&apos;s rule [10] and then forms the complete amplitude by use of the unsubtracted dispersion relation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A(p 2 ) = 1 π L dκ 2 ImA(κ 2 ) κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ , (26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where L is some cut along the real axis and the surface term at infinity has been neglected by assumption. In general the high energy behaviour of A makes the righthand side of (26) divergent. This ultraviolet divergence is regulated by replacing the upper limit of integration by a cutoff scale 4Λ 2 , which represents the maximum total energy squared. For energies greater than this scale ImA = 0. The first immediate consequence of the dispersion relation (26) is that quadratically divergent amplitudes are no longer dependent on an arbitrary parameter α resulting from loop momenta shifts. This is because to calculate the imaginary part of a one loop amplitude, for example, the intermediate particle states must be put on-shell according to Cutkosky&apos;s rule. As a result the arbitrary dependence cancels out and quantitative predictions will not be jeopardized.</p>

				<p>In the NJL model the fermion mass satisfies a gap equation and so we need to reformulate this self consistent condition using dispersion relations. Consider first the sum of fermion bubbles in the pseudoscalar ¯ tt channel (γ 5 ). The scattering amplitude is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ P (p 2 ) = G 2 1 1 − J P (p 2 ) , (27) where J P (p 2 ) = GN c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 4m 2 t dκ 2 κ 2 κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 − 4m 2 t κ 2 . (28) Requiring J P (0) = 1 or 1 = GN c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 4m 2 t dκ 2 1 − 4m 2 t κ 2 , (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>leads to a pole at p 2 = 0, which is the massless neutral Nambu-Goldstone mode. Evaluating the integral in (29) to leading order gives rise to the self consistent</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>tion 1 = GN c 8π 2 2Λ 2 − m 2 t ln Λ 2 m 2 t . (30)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is equivalent to the gap equation obtained earlier, (3), by noting that the ultraviolet Euclidean momentum cutoff (Λ E ) used in sections 2 and 3 is related to the dispersion integral cutoff by Λ E = √ 2 Λ. Similarly for the scattering amplitude in the scalar ¯ tt channel we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ S (p 2 ) = − G 2 1 1 − J S (p 2 ) , (31) where J S (p 2 ) = GN c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 4m 2 t dκ 2 κ 2 − 4m 2 t κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 − 4m 2 t κ 2 . (32)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>If we invoke the condition, (29) then J S (4m 2 t ) = 1 and Γ S will have a pole at p 2 = 4m 2 t . This is the dynamically generated scalar bound state or Higgs mode. The remaining flavoured tb channels will similarly give rise to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ F (p 2 ) = − G 4 1 1 − J F (p 2 ) , (33) where J F (p 2 ) = GN c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 m 2 t dκ 2 κ 2 κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 − m 2 t κ 2 2 , (34)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the bottom mass has been neglected (m b = 0). Again invoking the self-consistent condition, (29) leads to the massless charged Nambu-Goldstone modes (J F (0) = 1). Thus in the dispersion relation approach the gap equation is replaced by the condition requiring massless Nambu-Goldstone modes.</p>

				<p>In the absence of spontaneous symmetry breaking, on-shell quantities are always gauge invariant. When the symmetry is spontaneously broken we need to check that the gauge bosons receive their mass in a gauge invariant manner. As depicted in Figure 3, the gauge bosons acquire their mass by absorbing the massless Nambu-Goldstone modes. In particular, evaluating the W-boson vacuum polarization diagrams using dispersion relations, one obtains for the W-boson inverse propagator</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 g 2 2 D W µν (p) −1 = p µ p ν p 2 − g µν p 2 ¯ g 2 2 (p 2 ) − ¯ f 2 (p 2 ) , (35) where the dispersion integrals for ¯ g 2 2 and ¯ f 2 are 1 ¯ g 2 2 (p 2 ) = 1 g 2 2 + 1 3 N c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 m 2 t dκ 2 1 κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 + 2m 2 t κ 2 1 − m 2 t κ 2 2 , (36) ¯ f 2 (p 2 ) = m 2 t 2 N c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 m 2 t dκ 2 1 κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 − m 2 t κ 2 2 . (37)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that the W-boson inverse propagator is transverse and corresponds to a gauge invariant Higgs mechanism. The induced W-boson mass appears as a pole in the propagator and is a solution of the equation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M 2 W ¯ g 2 2 (M 2 W ) − ¯ f 2 (M 2 W ) = 0 . (38)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To leading order in Λ and assuming M W ≪ m t , the W-boson mass is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M 2 W = g 2 2 N c (4π) 2 m 2 t 2 log Λ 2 m 2 t , (39)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is similar to the mass relation derived by BHL. As an aside we note that (39) is the same as the one loop correction to the W-boson mass in the Standard Model with an elementary Higgs scalar. The effective top Yukawa coupling, f t obtained from (31)</p>

				<p><formula>is 1 f 2 t = N c (4π) 2 log Λ 2 m 2 t , (40)</formula></p>

				<p>and this is easily seen to be compatible with (39), where M</p>

				<p><formula>2 W = 1 2 g 2 2 m 2 t /f 2 t .</formula></p>

				<p>Finally for completeness we give the dispersion integrals for the neutral gauge boson propagators. Working in the (B −</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>W 3 ) basis leads to 1 g i g j D 0 µν (p) −1 = p µ p ν p 2 − g µν 1 g 2 1 (p 2 ) 0 0 1 g 2 2 (p 2 ) p 2 − 1 −1 −1 1 f 2 (p 2 ) , (41) where 1 g 2 1 (p 2 ) = 1 g 2 1 + 20 9 J (m 2 t , p 2 , Λ 2 ) + 2 9 J (m 2 b , p 2 , Λ 2 ) , (42) 1 g 2 2 (p 2 ) = 1 g 2 2 + 4 3 J (m 2 t , p 2 , Λ 2 ) + 2 3 J (m 2 b , p 2 , Λ 2 ) , (43) f 2 (p 2 ) = 1 3 p 2 J (m 2 t , p 2 , Λ 2 ) − 1 3 p 2 J (m 2 b , p 2 , Λ 2 ) + m 2 t K(m 2 t , p 2 , Λ 2 ) , (44) and the dispersion integrals are given by J (m 2 , p 2 , Λ 2 ) = 1 6 N c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 4m 2 dκ 2 1 κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 + 2m 2 κ 2 1 − 4m 2 κ 2 , (45) K(m 2 , p 2 , Λ 2 ) = 1 2 N c (4π) 2 4Λ 2 4m 2 dκ 2 1 κ 2 − p 2 − iǫ 1 − 4m 2 κ 2 . (46)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is apparent from (41) that the neutral gauge boson will become massive in a gauge invariant manner. Thus in the case of spontaneous symmetry breaking Eqs. (35) and (41) show that gauge invariance is saved by the Nambu-Goldstone mechanism when dispersion relations are used.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The high energy renormalization group running of the SU(2) and U(1) gauge coupling constants can be obtained from the dispersion integral expressions (</figDesc>
					<trash>36),(42) and (43). Assuming that p 2 ≫ m 2 t one obtains 16π 2 p 2 d dp 2 1 g 2 1 (p 2 ) = − 11 27 N c , (47) and 16π 2 p 2 d dp 2 1 ¯ g 2 2 (p 2 ) = 16π 2 p 2 d dp 2 1 g 2 2 (p 2 ) = − N c 3 . (48)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that the SU(2) gauge coupling running obtained from the charged gauge boson and neutral gauge boson expressions have identical high energy running as expected. Let us now compare Eqs.(47) and (48) with the usual β-functions. The Standard Model one-loop β-functions for the SU(</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2) and U(1) gauge coupling constants are given by 16π 2 dg 1 dt = 1 6 + 11 27 N c n q + n l g 3 1 , (49) 16π 2 dg 2 dt = − 43 6 + N c 3 n q + 1 3 n l g 3 2 , (50)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where n q (n l ) are the number of quark (lepton) generations. One can see that the single generation quark loop contributions to the Standard Model β-functions agree with the high energy running (Eqs.(47) and (48)) obtained in the fermion bubble approximation from the dispersion integral expressions for the gauge coupling constants. This agreement further establishes the consistent equivalence between the minimal top-condensate model and the Standard Model when dispersion relations are used. Clearly, in order to go beyond the fermion bubble approximation in the topcondensate model one can utilize the full one-loop β-functions of the Standard Model to obtain definite predictions for the top and Higgs mass as originally advocated by Bardeen, Hill and Lindner [3]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusion</head>

				<p>The choice of a consistent regulator in the gauged NJL model is important in order to establish a qualitative equivalence with the Standard Model. The use of an ultraviolet Euclidean momentum cutoff Λ to regulate divergent loop integrals is not a good regularization prescription for the gauged NJL model. This is because the prescription suffers from ambiguities associated with quadratic divergences, which destroy the gauge invariance of the theory. The dependence on the arbitrary parameter α also means that no quantitative conclusions could be drawn from the model if this regulator were used. In addition, the simple cutoff prescription produces the well known quadratic divergence (∝ g µν Λ 2 ) which destroys gauge invariance. An alternative prescription would be to use dimensional regularization which would eliminate this quadratically divergent term and give rise to a gauge invariant Higgs mechanism. However the quadratic divergences in the gap equation would also be destroyed, leading to an inconsistent theory.</p>

				<p>A more suitable regularization prescription for the top-quark condensate model that maintains gauge invariance without destroying the quadratic terms is to use unsubtracted dispersion relations. In this case the gap equation is equivalent to the condition requiring the masslessness of the Nambu-Goldstone bosons. Arbitrary shifts in the loop momenta do not affect quantitative predictions because intermediate particle states are put on-shell when the imaginary part of an amplitude is calculated. Thus provided the gap equation is satisfied, the dynamical Higgs mechanism is gauge invariant with no corresponding routing ambiguities. If the high energy running of the gauge coupling constants is obtained from the dispersion integral expressions in the fermion bubble approximation then the usual fermion loop contributions to the Standard Model β-functions are obtained. This consistently shows that the top-quark condensate model is equivalent to Standard Model when dispersion relations are used. The BHL predictions for the top and Higgs mass are then obtained by employing the full one-loop β-functions of the Standard Model and imposing the compositeness conditions of the gauged NJL model.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-ph/9408225v1 3 Aug 1994</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> e-mail: tonyg@yukawa.uchicago.edu</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>I would like to thank Professor Y. Nambu for initially suggesting this problem and for many helpful discussions and comments. I would also like to acknowledge Dr. C. Hill and Dr. W. Bardeen for useful comments. This work was supported in part by NSF contract PHY-91-23780.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Singapore 1989); and EFI preprint 89-08</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Nambu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Miransky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tanabashi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Yamawaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Mod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">New Theories in Physics, Proceedings of the XI International Symposium on Elementary Particle Physics</title>
		<editor>Z. Ajduk, S. Pokorski and A. Trautman</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Kazimierz, Poland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1043" />
			<biblScope unit="page">177</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Nambu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Jona-Lasinio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">345</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bardeen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Hill</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Lindner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1647</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Hill</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Nucl. Phys</title>
		<editor>C. T. Hill, C. N. Leung and S. Rao</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">262</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="517" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Willey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2877</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Theory of Photons and Electrons</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Jauch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Rohrlich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
			<publisher>Addison- Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Reading, Massachusetts</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hasenfratz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Hasenfratz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Jansen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kuti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Shen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">See also J. Zinn-Justin, ibid. B367</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="105" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fermilab preprint FERMILAB-CONF-90-269-T (1990); C. T. Hill, Phys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Bardeen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page">419</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1070</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Cutkosky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">429</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
