<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Boundary S-matrix for the Integrable q-Potts Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Leung</forename>
								<surname>Chim</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: CHIM@ruhets.rutgers.edu</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Astronomy Rutgers University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O.Box 849</postBox>
									<postCode>08855-0849</postCode>
									<settlement>Piscataway</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Boundary S-matrix for the Integrable q-Potts Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9404118v1 20 Apr 1994 †</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The 2D off-critical q-state Potts model with boundaries was studied as a factorizable relativistic scattering theory. The scattering S-matrices for particles reflecting off the boundaries were obtained for the cases of &quot; fixed &quot; and &quot; free &quot; boundary conditions. In the Ising limit, the computed results agreed with recent work[5].</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Introduction</head>

				<p>In the past decade, many advances were made in 2 dimensional statistical mechanic systems by applying the idea of conformal invariance[1]. Their critical points are well described by conformal field theory (CFT) and their universality can be classified by a</p>

				<p>Virasoro central charge c[2]. When such a model is perturbed off their critical point, the conformal symmetry is broken and the theory develops finite correlation lengths. However, for certain perturbations, residue symmetries survives in the form of an infinite set of</p>

				<p>commuting integrals of motion and renders the theory integrable[3]. Such &quot; perturbed conformal field theories &quot; can often be described by a relativistic scattering theory of massive particles where the S-matrix is factorizable. All physical information about the field theory can then be obtained from the S-matrix by constructing correlation functions using the form-factors method[4].</p>

				<p>Recently, statistical systems with boundaries were studied using the above method[5].</p>

				<p>It was found that one can choose certain boundary conditions which perserves the integrability of the bulk theory. Such integrable boundary conditions can be represented by the boundary S-matrix describing the scattering of particles from the boundary. In this work, such boundary S-matrices are obtained for the q-state Potts model (for 0 &lt; q &lt; 4) with free and fixed boundary conditions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Integrable q-states Potts Model</head>

				<p>In the lattice q-Potts model[6], the spins a(x) at the sites of the lattice are allowed to be in one of the q possible states (1, 2, ..., q). The partition function has the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z = {a(x)} (x,y)=&lt;nn&gt; (1 + Kδ a(x),a(y) ), (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is invariant under the permutation group S q . The phase transition point of this model occurs at</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>K = K c = √ q. (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For 0 &lt; q &lt; 4, this is a second order phase transition, and its critical point is described by the CFT with central charge[7]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c = 1 − 6 p(p + 1) where √ q = 2sin( π 2 p − 1 p + 1 ). (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The energy density ǫ(x) of the Potts model then corresponds to the degenerate primary</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>field Φ (2,1) with dimension ∆ ǫ = 1 4 + 3 4p . (4) This field is also a relevent operator in the theory, and preturbation of the CFT action by this field leads to an off-critical theory with action A q,τ = A CF T (c) + τ ǫ(x)d 2 x (5) where τ = K c − K K c , (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and A CF T (c) is the &quot; action &quot; of the CFT with central charge c. This action describes the scaling domain of the q-Potts model, and is shown in [8] to be an integrable field theory (ie possess nontrival higher-spin local integrals of motion). Following [8], we consider the low temperature phase K &gt; K c of this theory. The field theory (5) has q degenerate vacua | a; a = 1, ..., q, with S q acting by permutations of these vacuum states. Its particle content must then contain q(q − 1) &quot; kinks &quot; A ab ; a, b = 1, ..., q; a = b, which corresponds to the domain wall separating vacua a and b. The antiparticles can be identified by ¯ A ab = A ba .</p>

				<p>The masses of these particles are taken to be equal to M ∼ | τ | 1 1−∆ ǫ .</p>

				<p>The scattering of these asymptotic particles is governed by the S-matrix and the integrability of (5) implies that this S-matrix is factorizable. Recall that the energymomentum of particles can be parametrized by their rapidity θ, where</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E = M chθ, P = M shθ. (7) The asymptotic particles states are generated by the &quot; particle creation operator &quot; A ab (θ) satisfying the quadratic commutation relations A ab (θ 1 )A bc (θ 2 ) = d =a,d =c S bd ac (θ 12 )A ad (θ 2 )A dc (θ 1 ), (8) where θ 12 = θ 1 − θ 2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The S q symmetric two-kink S-matrix elements (Fig.1) were computed in [8] to be (for a = b = c =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d) S bd ac (θ) = S 0 (θ) = sh(λθ)sh(λ(iπ − θ)) sh(λ(θ − 2πi 3 ))sh(λ( iπ 3 − θ)) Π( λθ iπ ); (9a) S bb ac (θ) = S 1 (θ) = sin(λ 2π 3 ) sin(λ π 3 ) sh(λ(iπ − θ)) sh(λ( 2πi 3 − θ)) Π( λθ iπ ); (9b) S bd aa (θ) = S 2 (θ) = sin(λ 2π 3 ) sin(λ π 3 ) sh(λθ) sh(λ(θ − iπ 3 )) Π( λθ iπ ); (9c) S bb aa (θ) = S 3 (θ) = sin(λπ) sin(λ π 3 ) Π( λθ iπ ), (9d) where λ = 3 2 p − 1 p + 1 (10) and Π(x) = − Γ(1 − x)Γ(1 − λ + x)Γ( 7 3 λ − x)Γ( 4 3 λ + x) Γ(1 + x)Γ(1 + λ − x)Γ( 1 3 λ + x)Γ( 4 3 λ − x) ∞ k=1 Π k (x)Π k (λ − x); Π k (x) = Γ(1 + 2kλ − x)Γ(2kλ − x)Γ(1 + (2k − 1 3 )λ − x)Γ((2k + 7 3 )λ − x) Γ(1 + (2k + 1)λ − x)Γ((2k + 1)λ − x)Γ(1 + (2k − 4 3 )λ − x)Γ((2k + 4 3 )λ − x) . (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The amplitudes S 1 (θ) possess a &quot; bound-state &quot; pole at θ = 2πi 3 (Fig.2a) while S 2 (θ) have the &quot; cross-channel &quot; pole at θ = πi 3 (Fig.2b). Likewise S 0 (θ) have both the above poles (Fig.2c) with residues</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Res θ= 2πi 3 S 0 (θ) = Res θ= 2πi 3 S 1 (θ) = −Res θ= iπ 3 S 0 (θ) = −Res θ= iπ 3 S 2 (θ) = if 2 (λ), (12) where f (λ) = 1 λ sin( 2π 3 λ)exp{ ∞ 0 (1 − e −(1− 4 3 λ)t )(1 − e − 2 3 λt )(1 − e 1 3 λt )e −λt 2(1 − e −t )(1 + e −λt ) dt t } (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is the &quot; three-kink coupling &quot; (Fig.3).</p>

				<p>As is shown in [8], the complete particle spectrum of field theory (5) for 3 &lt; q &lt; 4 is quite complicated with the appearance of exotic excitation and bound states. For simplicity, we will restrict our attention to the range 0 &lt; q ≤ 3.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Boundary S-Matrix</head>

				<p>It is natural to consider the Potts model in the presence of boundaries with some boundary conditions imposed on the boundary spins. In [5], it was shown that certain boundary conditions preserves the integrability of the bulk theory (ie an infinite subset of the bulk integrals of motion survives with the introduction of the boundaries). For a relativistic scattering theory of massive particles, one can associate these integrable boundary conditions with certain boundary S-matrix which describe the scattering of particles with the boundary.</p>

				<p>To be more precise, consider the model defined on an semi-infinite plane (say x ∈ (−∞, 0], y ∈ (−∞, ∞), the y-axis being the booundary). Let us suppose that there exists integrable boundary conditions for the Potts model with the modified action</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A = A q,τ +CBC + ∞ −∞ dyΦ B (y), (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where A q,τ +CBC is the action (5) with certain conformal boundary conditions (CBC), and Φ B (y) is some relevant boundary operator[9,5]. One can think of (14) as a perturbation of CBC, and the corresponding Fock states can be classified as asymptotic scattering states.</p>

				<p>In particular, the boundary with boundary spins in the state &quot; a &quot; can be associated with a stationary impenetrable particle B a of infinite mass at x = 0. Then the asymptotic n-kink scattering state can be written as the product</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A a 1 a 2 (θ 1 )A a 2 a 3 (θ 2 )...A a n−1 a n (θ n−1 )A a n a (θ n )B a , (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the vacua a 1 , a 2 , ..., a n satisfy the restrictions a i = a i+1 , and a n = a.</p>

				<p>If the initial &quot; in-state &quot; of scattering is the asymptotic state (15) with θ 1 &gt; θ 2 &gt; ... &gt; θ n &gt; 0 (ie n kinks moving towards the boundary of state &quot; a &quot; ), then in the infinite future, this state becomes a superposition of the final &quot; out-states &quot; . Integrability of (14) constraints &quot; out-states &quot; to have the form A b 1 b 2 (−θ 1 )...A b n−1 b n (−θ n−1 )A b n b (−θ n )B b , (16) with b i = b i+1 and b n = b. Thus we have the relation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A a 1 a 2 (θ 1 )A a 2 a 3 (θ 2 )...A a n−1 a n (θ n−1 )A a n a (θ n )B a = b 1 ... b n b R b 1 ...b n b a 1 ...a n a (θ 1 , ..., θ n )A b 1 b 2 (−θ 1 )...A b n−1 b n (−θ n−1 )A b n b (−θ n )B b , (17) which defines the n-kink Boundary S-matrix. When n=1, we have the simple commutation relation A ba (θ)B a = c R c ba (θ)A bc (−θ)B c , (18) where R c ba (θ) are</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>elements of the boundary S-matrix for the reflection of one particle off the boundary(Fig.4</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>). It follows from the factorizability of the scattering that R</figDesc>
					<trash>b 1 ...b n b a 1 ...a n a can be written as a product of bulk amplitudes S bd ac , and boundary amplitudes R c ba . For example, when 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>kinks scatter off the boundary, the amplitude for this scattering can be factorized in two equivalent ways(Fig.5</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>), leading to</figDesc>
					<trash>g f R f ba (θ 1 )S bg cf (θ 1 + θ 2 )R e gf (θ 2 )S gd ce (θ 2 − θ 1 ) = g ′ f ′ S bg ′ ca (θ 2 − θ 1 )R f ′ g ′ a (θ 2 )S g ′ d cf ′ (θ 1 + θ 2 )R e df ′ (θ 1 ), (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is known as the &quot; boundary Yang-Baxter equation &quot; [10]. As is known, the amplitudes R c ba (θ) have to satisfy several conditions in addition to (19). Firstly we have the &quot; boundary unitarity condition &quot; (Fig.6</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>)</figDesc>
					<trash>c =b R c ba (θ)R d bc (−θ) = δ d a , (20) which is a direct analog to the unitarity condition for the bulk S-matrix. To obtain the crossing symmetry condition for the boundary scattering, it is necessary to use the &quot; cross amplitude &quot; [5] K abc (θ) = R c ba ( iπ 2 − θ). (21) As shown in [5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, this amplitude K abc (θ) has to satisfy the so-called &quot; boundary</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>unitarity condition &quot; K abc (θ) = d =a,c S db ca (2θ)K adc (−θ), (22) which is illustrated in Fig.7</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. Finally we have the &quot; boundary bootstrap equation &quot; [11] which describes the scattering of &quot; bound-state &quot; particles with the boundary. In the bulk theory, the kink A ab can appear as a bound-state particle in the two particle scattering (see Fig.2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>)</figDesc>
					<trash>A ac (θ + iπ 3 )A cb (θ − iπ 3 ) → f A ab (θ) (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where f is the 3-particle coupling in (13). Applying the algebras (8), (18) and (23) to the &quot; in-state &quot; A ac (θ + iπ 3 )A cb (θ − iπ 3 )B b , we obtained the bootstrap equation(Fig.8</p>

				<p><formula>) R d ab (θ) = f =c,e e =a,d R f cb (θ − iπ 3 )S ce af (2θ)R d ef (θ + iπ 3 ) (24)</formula></p>

				<p>for the S q symmetric Potts model.</p>

				<p>Equations (19) through (24) allows the boundary S-matrix elements R c ab (θ) to be determined up to some CDD factors[5]. For boundary conditions which respect the S q symmetry, we can expect R c ab (θ) to have a pole at θ = iπ 6 (Fig.9a</p>

				<p><formula>) with residue R c ab (θ) ≃ i 2 f g c b θ − iπ 6 , (25) where g c</formula></p>

				<p>b is the amplitude for coupling of the particle A cb to the boundary(Fig.10).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Furthermore , if g c a , g a b = 0, the element R c ab (θ) has another pole at θ = iπ 2</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(Fig.9b</head>

				<p><formula>) where R c ab (θ) ≃ i 2 g c a g a b θ − iπ 2 ; (26)</formula></p>

				<p>this pole is shown in Fig.10. Of course the presence of the above poles depends on the boundary condition, as we shall see when we consider the two simplest cases: &quot; free &quot; and &quot; fixed &quot; boundary conditions. Both cases are conformal boundary conditions (i.e. Φ B (y) = 0) and we conjecture that they also preserves integrability in the off-critical Potts model.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Fixed Boundary Condition</head>

				<p>In this simple boundary condition, the boundary spins are all fixed to one state, say &quot; a &quot; . The corresponding boundary S-matrix element</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R a ba (θ) = R f (θ) (27) satisfies the boundary Yang-Baxter equation (19) automatically. To determine this amplitude , one appeals to the unitarity condition (20) R f (θ)R f (−θ) = 1; (28) and the crossing symmetry condition (22) K f (θ) = [(q − 2)S 2 (2θ) + S 3 (2θ)]K f (−θ), (29) where K f (θ) = R f ( iπ 2 − θ) (30)</trash>

					<figDesc>is the crossing amplitude. Since all boundary states are fixed, we do not expect R f (θ) to possess any poles in the physical domain 0 ≤ θ ≤</figDesc>
					<trash>iπ 2 . The solution to (28) and (29) can be factorized as R f (θ) = F 0 (θ)F 1 ( λθ iπ ), (31) where F 1 (X) solves F 1 (X) = Π(λ − 2X) sin(2π(λ − X)) sin(2π( λ 3 − X)) F 1 (λ − X); (32) F 1 (−X)F 1 (X) = 1, (33) and its minimal solution can be written as F 1 (X) = ∞ k=1 Σ k (X) Σ k (−X) , (34a) with Σ k (X) = Γ[(4k − 1)λ + 2X]Γ[(4k − 3)λ + 2X + 1]Γ[(4k − 3)λ + λ 3 + 2X]Γ[(4k − 2)λ + λ 3 − 2X] Γ[4kλ + 2X]Γ[4(k − 1)λ + 2X + 1]Γ[(4k − 2)λ − λ 3 + 2X + 1]Γ[(4k − 1)λ − λ 3 − 2X + 1], (34b) up to some CDD factors.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The factor F 0 (θ) can be obtained from the fixed boundary bootstrap equation (24)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R f (θ) = [S 1 (2θ) + (q − 3)S 0 (2θ)]R f (θ − iπ 3 )R f (θ + iπ 3 ), (35) which reduces to F 0 (θ) = −tan( π 4 + iθ 2 )cot( π 12 + iθ 2 )cot( 5π 12 + iθ 2 )F 0 (θ − iπ 3 )F 0 (θ + iπ 3 ), (36) with simple solution F 0 (θ) = −tan( π 4 + iθ 2 ). (37) In the Ising limit (q = 2, λ = 3 4 ), the boundary S-matrix have the form R f (θ) = itan( iπ 4 − θ 2 ), (38) as obtained in [5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>by field theoretic method.</p>

				<p>In the other interesting limit q = 3 (λ = 1), suppose the boundary are fixed in the state &quot; A &quot; , the solution simplifies as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R f (θ) = − sin( π 3 + iθ 2 ) sin( π 3 − iθ 2 ) . (39)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Free Boundary Condition</head>

				<p>In contrast to the fixed boundary condition, we have the &quot; free &quot; case where the boundary spins can be in any one of the q states. The corresponding boundary S-matrix has to respect the S q symmetry and the algebra (18) simplifies to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A ba (θ)B a = R 1 (θ)A ba (−θ)B a + c =a,b R 2 (θ)A bc (−θ)B c , (40)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the amplitudes R 1 (θ) and R 2 (θ) are shown in Fig.10. The boundary Yang-Baxter equation (19) provides three non-trivial equations:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R 1 S 3 R 2 S 1 + R 2 S 1 R 1 S 1 + (q − 3)R 2 S 1 R 2 S 1 + (q − 3)R 1 S 2 R 2 S 0 +(q − 3)R 2 S 0 R 1 S 0 + (q − 3)(q − 4)R 2 S 0 R 2 S 0 = (q − 2)R 2 S 2 R 1 S 2 + (q − 3)R 1 S 0 R 2 S 2 + (q − 3) 2 R 2 S 0 R 2 S 2 +R 1 S 1 R 2 S 3 + R 2 S 3 R 1 S 3 + (q − 3)R 2 S 1 R 2 S 3 ; (41a) R 1 S 1 R 2 S 2 + (q − 3)R 2 S 1 R 2 S 2 + R 2 S 2 R 1 S 3 + (q − 3)R 2 S 0 R 2 S 3 +(q − 3)R 2 S 2 R 1 S 2 + R 2 S 3 R 1 S 2 + (q − 3)R 1 S 0 R 2 S 2 + (q − 3)(q − 4)R 2 S 0 R 2 S 2 = R 1 S 2 R 2 S 1 + (q − 3)R 1 S 2 R 2 S 0 + (q − 3)R 2 S 0 R 2 S 1 + (q − 3) 2 R 2 S 0 R 2 S 0 ; (41b) R 1 S 3 R 2 S 0 + R 1 S 2 R 2 S 1 + (q − 4)R 1 S 2 R 2 S 0 + R 2 S 1 R 1 S 0 + R 2 S 0 R 1 S 1 +(q − 4)R 2 S 0 R 1 S 0 + (q − 3)R 2 S 1 R 2 S 0 + (q − 4)R 2 S 0 R 2 S 1 + (q − 4) 2 R 2 S 0 R 2 S 0 = R 1 S 1 R 2 S 2 + R 1 S 0 R 2 S 3 + (q − 4)R 1 S 0 R 2 S 2 + R 2 S 3 R 1 S 2 + R 2 S 2 R 1 S 3 +(q − 3)R 2 S 2 R 1 S 2 + (q − 3)R 2 S 1 R 2 S 2 + (q − 4)R 2 S 0 R 2 S 3 + [(q − 3) + (q − 4) 2 ]R 2 S 0 R 2 S 2 ; (41c)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the argument in each term has the form R i (θ 1 )S j (θ 1 + θ 2 )R k (θ 2 )S l (θ 2 − θ 1 ).</p>

				<p>Equation(41) can be solved for the ratio R 1 (θ 1 )/R 2 (θ 1 ) when we take the limit θ 2 → iπ 2 and noting that both R 1 (θ 2 ) and R 2 (θ 2 ) have a simple pole in this limit with the same</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>residue Res θ 2 = iπ 2 R 1 (θ 2 ) = Res θ 2 = iπ 2 R 2 (θ 2 ) = i 2 g 2 (42)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for some boundary coupling g.</p>

				<p>The solution to (41) can then be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R 1 (θ) = (q − 3) sinh λ( iπ 3 + 2θ) sinh λ(iπ − 2θ) P ( λθ iπ ) (43a) R 2 (θ) = sin 2πλ 3 sin πλ 3 sinh 2λθ sinh λ(iπ − 2θ) sinh λ( iπ 3 + 2θ) sinh λ( iπ 3 − 2θ) P ( λθ iπ ), (43b)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we use the fact that R 2 (θ) has a simple pole at θ = iπ 6 , which is absent in R 1 (θ). We do not expect R 1 (θ) and R 2 (θ) to have any other poles in the physical domain (0 ≤ θ ≤</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>iπ 2 ). The normalization factor P ( λθ iπ ) is constrained by the unitarity conditions (20) and (21), which reduces to P (θ)P (−θ) = 1, (44a) and P ( iπ 2 − θ 2 ) = −Π( λθ iπ ) sinh λ(iπ + θ) sinh λ( iπ 3 − θ) sinh λ( 4iπ 3 + θ) sinh λ( 4iπ 3 − θ) P ( iπ 2 + θ 2 ), (44b) respectively. The minimal solutions can be written as P (X) = ∞ k=1 Ω k (X) Ω k (−X) , (45a) where Ω k (X) = Γ[(4k − 1)λ + 2X]Γ[(4k − 3)λ + 2X + 1]Γ[4kλ + λ 3 − 2X]Γ[4(k − 1)λ − λ 3 − 2X + 1] Γ[4kλ + 2X]Γ[4(k − 1)λ + 2X + 1]Γ[(4k − 3)λ + λ 3 − 2X]Γ[(4k − 1)λ − λ 3 − 2X + 1], (45b)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>up to some CDD factors. The sign in (45) can be justified by the boundary bootstrap equation (24).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>In the Ising limit (λ → 3 4 ), the boundary S-matrix element simplifies to R 1 (θ) = − cot( π 4 + iθ 2 ), (46) in agreement with [5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. For the q = 3 Potts model (λ → 1), the two scattering amplitudes have the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R 1 (θ) = 0 R 2 (θ) = sin( π 12 − iθ 2 ) sin( π 4 − iθ 2 ) sin( π 12 + iθ 2 ) sin( π 4 + iθ 2 ) . (47) Finally, a simple computation give us g(λ) = − (3 − q) λ sin( 4π 3 λ)exp{ ∞ 0 dt t e −t−4λt 2(1 − e −t )(1 + e −2λt ) [(1 − e −λt )(1 − e 3λt−t ) + e λt 3 −t (1 − e −2λt+ λt 3 +t )(1 − e 3λt )]} (48)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for the boundary coupling constant.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Conclusion</head>

				<p>In this study, the q-Potts model boundary S-matrix for free and fixed boundary conditions were dervied. It would be interesting to apply the techniques of Thermodynamics Bethe Ansatz to study these S-matrices. In particular, one can investigate the renormalization group flow between these two boundary conditions[5,13]. This work is in progress.</p>

				<p>Finally, we would like to note that it may be possible to use these boundary S-matrices to compute the crossing probabilities for the percolation problem (q = 1) in a finite region[12].</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Figure Captions Fig.1</head>

				<p>. The scattering processes for the bulk S-matrix elements S 0 (θ), S 1 (θ), S 2 (θ) and S 3 (θ) defined in (9); with a = b = c = d. Fig.2. Space-time diagrams associated with the pole at θ = 2πi 3 in S 1 (θ) [Fig.(a)] and the corresponding cross-channel pole in S 2 (θ) [Fig.(b)]. The amplitude S 0 (θ) possess both poles as shown in [Fig.(c)]; the states a, b, c, d are all different. Fig.3. Tree-kink vertex associated with the &quot; coupling constant &quot; f Fig.4. The boundary scattering processes described by the amplitude R c ba (θ), with b = a, c. Fig.5. Boundary Yang-Baxter Equation. The variables g, f, g ′ , f ′ = 1, 2, ..., q satisfies the &quot; admissibility conditions &quot; g = c, e; f = b, g; g ′ = a, c; f ′ = d, g ′ . Boundary conditions can also place further constraints on these variables. Fig.6. Scattering processes described by the boundary unitarity condition (20); b = a, c and c = b. Fig.7. Scattering processes for the cross-unitarity condition (22); b = a, c and d = a, c. Fig.8. Boundary bootstrap equation where states e and f must satisfy the &quot; admissibility condition &quot; and the boundary condition. Fig.9. Physical poles of the boundary S-martix with conditions a = b = c in [Fig.(a)], and a = b, c in [Fig.(b)]. Here g c b is the boundary coupling constant for the particle A cb . Fig.10. Boundary S-martix elements for the free boundary condition with a, b, and c all different.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>b a c a b a b d a b c d b a c d (a) (b) (c) c θ a b a b θ a b a c θ a b d θ a b d b 0 s 1 s 2 s 3 s Fig. 1 Fig. 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This figure &quot;fig1-1.png&quot; is available in &quot;png&quot;&quot; format from: http://arxiv.org/ps/hep-th/9404118v1</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>b a c = f a b c θ − θ = R ba c</trash>

					<figDesc>(θ) Fig. 3 Fig. 4</figDesc>
					<trash>a b c d e f g a b c d e f&apos; g&apos; ΣΣ g&apos; f&apos; = ΣΣ g f θ 1 θ 2 −θ 2 −θ 1 −θ 1 −θ 2 θ 2 θ 1 Fig. 5</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This figure &quot;fig1-2.png&quot; is available in &quot;png&quot;&quot; format from:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a b d c θ θ −θ Σ c = δ a d Fig. 6 a b c a c b d −2θ 2θ 2θ = Σ d θ θ − θ − θ Fig. 7 b c a d b c a d f e = ΣΣ f e θ − iπ/3 θ − iπ/3 θ + iπ/3 θ + iπ/3 − θ − θ Fig. 8</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This figure &quot;fig1-3.png&quot; is available in &quot;png&quot;&quot; format from:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a b a a b c θ − θ θ − θ R 1 (θ) R 2 (θ) = = Fig. 10 g a b c a b c b c Fig. 9(a) 9(b)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-th/9404118v1 20 Apr 1994</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>LC was supported by a Eleanor Sophia Wood Travelling Scholarship (Sydney University )and would like to thank Prof. A.B. Zamolodchikov for many useful discussions.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Itzykson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Saleur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conformal Invariance and Applications to Statistical Mechanics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Belavin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Polyakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Zamolodchikov. Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Zamolodchikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advanced Studies in Pure Mathematics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">641</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formfactors in Completely Integrable Models of QFT</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Smirnov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Series in Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Boundary S-Matrix and Boundary State in Two-Dimensional Integrable Qunatum Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ghoshal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Zamolodchikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Potts</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Cambridge Phil</title>
		<meeting>. Cambridge Phil</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1952" />
			<biblScope unit="page">106</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Vl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Dotsenko</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Fateev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="240" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Chim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Zamolodchikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int.J.Mod.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5317</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.Cardy. Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">324</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">581</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Cherednik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theor.Math.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">35977</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Factorized Scattering in the Presence of Reflecting Boundaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Fring</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Koberle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Critical Percolation in Finite Geometries</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cardy</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exact Theory of Polymer Adsorption in Analogy with the Kondo Problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Fendley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Saleur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">9403095</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
