<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">How reliable are the HQET-sum rule predictions?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1995-01">January 1995</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">S</forename>
								<surname>Narison</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Theoretical Physics Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">CERN</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire de Physique Math ematique</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Universit e de Montpellier II Place Eug ene Bataillon</addrLine>
									<postCode>CH -1211, 34095</postCode>
									<settlement>Geneva 23 and, -Montpellier Cedex 05</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">How reliable are the HQET-sum rule predictions?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1995-01">January 1995</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>CERN-TH.7549/94 PM/95-02 Q o : CERN-TH.7549/94</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We test the internal consistencies and the reliability of the existing estimates of the decay constant f B in the static limit, the meson-quark mass gap and the kinetic energy K of a heavy quark obtained from the heavy quark eeective theory (HQET)-sum rules. Finite energy local duality sum rules (FESR) have also been used to x approximatively the value of the continuum energy and to study the correlations among these diierent parameters. Then, we deduce to two-loop accuracy: = (0:65 0:05) GeV, K = (0:5 0:2) GeV 2 , implying the value of the pole mass in HQET: M b = (4:61 0:05) GeV. By combining the results from the sum rules in HQET and in the full theory, we obtain f 1 B = (1:98 0:31)f and the quark mass dependence of the pseudoscalar decay constant: f P p M P = (0:33 0:06) GeV 3=2 1== 1 s n 1 2 s =3 1:1=M Q + 0:7=M 2</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>There has been a lot of eeort during these last two years for estimating the parameters of the heavy quark eeective theory (HQET) 1] using QCD spectral sum rules (QSSR) 2, 3] in the innnite mass limit 4]{{14]. Among other existing estimates, we shall focus our discussion on the determinations of the decay constant f B in the static limit, the meson-quark mass gap and the kinetic energy K of a heavy quark. Our aim is to test the reliability of the existing estimates of these quantities and to try to extract the most reliable information from the sum rules analysis. In so doing, we shall rst reconsider the HQET sum rules analysis by using an update of the QCD parameters and by testing the stability of the results with the variation of the Laplace sum rule variable and/or of the continuum threshold E c 1 . If this stability exists, then, we shall compare it with the corresponding conservative values of the set (; E c ) obtained from QCD spectral sum rules (QSSR) in the full theory 2 . We shall also use local duality nite energy sum rule (FESR) to x approximatively E c and study the diierent correlations among these diierent parameters.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Deenitions and normalizations</head>

				<p>The decay constant of the pseudoscalar meson is deened as:</p>

				<p><formula>h0jJ 5 jBi = p 2f B q f = 93:3 MeV; (1) where J</formula></p>

				<p>5 is the axial current of the full QCD theory. In HQET, the decay constant reads:</p>

				<p><formula>h0j ~ J 5 jBi = i p 2 ~ f B v ; (2)</formula></p>

				<p>to which corresponds the RGI coupling:</p>

			<note>^ f B = ~ f B () ( s ) 1= 1 1 s () ! ; (3)</note>

				<p>where 1 = 1=2(11 2n f =3) is the rst coeecient of the -function and &apos; 0:23 for n f = 4 avours; v is the heavy quark velocity; ~ J 5 is the axial current in HQET, which is related to the former J 5 of the full theory by:</p>

				<p><formula>J 5 &apos; ~ J 5 1 2 3 s () ! ; (4)</formula></p>

				<p>such that the decay constant of the full theory can be expressed as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f B q M B 1 &apos; ~ f B ( s (M b )) 1== 1 1 2 3 s (M b ) ! ; (5) The meson-quark mass gap is deened as 1] 3 : M B = M b + 1 2M b (K + 33) ; (6) where: K = 1 2M B hB(v)jKjB(v)i and = 1 6M B hB(v)jSjB(v)i (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>corresponds respectively to the matrix elements of the kinetic and chromomagnetic oper- ators:</p>

				<p><formula>K h(iD) 2 h and S 1 2 hh F h; (8)</formula></p>

				<p>where h is the heavy quark eld and F the electric eld tensor.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">HQET sum rules</head>

				<p>Let us start our discussion from the relativistic Laplace sum rule (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>LSR) 2, 3]: L R ( r ) = Z tc 0 dt e ttr 1 Im(t); (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where t c ; r are respectively the QCD continuum threshold and the Laplace sum rule variable, which a priori are free external parameters in the sum rule analysis; is a generic notation of the hadronic Green&apos;s function. HQET sum rules correspond to the limit of LSR where the heavy quark mass tends to innnity.</p>

				<p>In this case, it is more convenient to introduce the non-relativistic variables and E, which are related to the former as:</p>

				<p><formula>t (E + M Q ) 2 ; e r M Q 2 1 + O 1 M Q !! ; (10) or: ! 2E; ! r M Q ; (11)</formula></p>

				<p>which remain nite when M Q tends to innnity. These non-relativistic sum rules have been discussed earlier 9, 10], and have been exploited in the context of HQET in 4]{{8]. They have also been used in full QCD but for increasing the value of M Q in 11]{{14] in order to reach the HQET regime from below. It has also been shown 12] that the Laplace and moments sum rules are equivalent, when the number of derivatives n of the n-th moments and M Q are large, but their ratio n=M Q remains nite 4 . Therefore, without loss of generality, it is suucient to work, in the following, with the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>relativistic Laplace sum rule: L( e ) = Z Ec 0 dE e Ee 1 Im(E); (12) or equivalently with: L( ! ) = Z !c 0 d! e !! 1 Im(!); (13) both</trash>

					<figDesc>sum rules have been used in the literature. The apparent advantage of Eq. (13)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>is that it optimizes at a value of ! &apos; e /2, which is a trivial fact due to their intrisic deenitions, but it is psychologically more comfortable to reach the stability at a value of 1 around 1 but not 2 GeV 1 , therefore giving a better justiication for the convergence of the Operator Product Expansion. 4 The mass gap and the decay constant ~ f B The sum rule for the decay constant and for the mass gap is well-known in the literature.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>It reads 4]{{6], 3, 12]: 2 ~ f 2 B e 2 &apos; 3 8 2 Z !c 0 d! ! 2 e ! ( 1 + s () 17 3 + 4 9 2 4 ln !== ) h uui() ( 1 + s () 2 + 16 1 ! M 2 0 4 2 2=(3 1 ) s ) ; (14) where ! ; = 704=9 112 2 =27 5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, but its eeect is not signiicant in the analysis.</p>

				<p>The subtraction point can be naturally chosen at = 1==, as dictated by the RGE which governs the Laplace sum rule 18]. However, in order to study the -dependence of the results, we shall take it from 1 GeV to 2/ e , which covers the choice done in the literature. The mass gap can be deduced from the log-derivative of Eq. (14) with respect to . We shall use the values of the QCD scale for 4 avours to two-loops:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>4 = (317 84) MeV; (15) corresponding to s (M Z ) &apos; 0:118 0:006 19], and of the QCD non-perturbative parameters 3]: M 2 0 = (0:80:01) GeV 2 h uui(1 GeV) &apos; (0:223 GeV) 3 h s G 2 i = (0:060:03) GeV 4 : (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We study the -behaviours of ~ f B and of in Figs. 1a, c for a xed value of E c . At the approximation where the correlator is computed, there is a good stability for the values of in the range of 1 to 2 GeV 1 . The dependence of these optima on E c are shown in Fig. 1b, d, where ~ f B has a much better stability than . Taking the conservative range of E c suggested by the analysis of f B from QSSR in the full theory</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3], 11]{{14]: E c &apos; 1 1:6 GeV; (17) one can deduce the optimal estimate: ~ f B &apos; (0:21 0:28) GeV 3=2 &apos; (0:52 0:70) GeV: (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The weak dependence of the results on E c shows the irrelevance of the criticisms of 7] on the choice of E c done in 11], while the ones of 16] do not concern the working regions of the sum rules. It should be noticed that the eeect of the subtraction scale in the range proposed previously is not important. Varying s within the error bar given previously, one aaects and ~ f B respectively by 2 and 7%. The error due to the quark condensate is much smaller. The most signiicant error not taken into account in the HQET-literature with the exception of 12] is the one due to the unknown 2 s -term. This is important for ~ f B as the perturbative radiative correction is huge, which is of the order of the lowestorder term in the two-point correlator. In the absence of an evaluation of this term, a reasonable estimate is obtained by assuming that its coeecient grows like a geometric sum or, more conservatively that its eeect cannot be as large as the known s -term. In this way, an error of about 25 % on ~ f B is introduced 5 . Then: ~ f B &apos; (0:25 0:04 0:06) GeV 3=2 ;</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(19)</head>

				<p>where the rst error is due to the sum rule procedure and the second one is mainly dominated by the unknown 2 s -term. The values of ~ f B and of are in agreement with the previous results in 5, 6], but the error for ~ f B must have been underestimated there. We show in Fig. 1d the result of 6] (dashed line). The small diierence comes from the diierent value of 4 used in the analysis. Moreover, these values are also in agreement with the ones from the sum rule in the full theory, obtained by increasing the quark mass-value 12]:</p>

				<p><formula>~ f B &apos; (0:33 0:06) GeV 3=2 ; &apos; (0:6 0:8) GeV; (20) where ~ f B corresponds to: f B q M B 1 &apos; (0:42 0:07) GeV 3=2 : (21)</formula></p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">The kinetic energy K</head>

				<p>The sum rules for the kinetic energy have been proposed in 6, 8], where the two-point and three-point functions have been used respectively. However, although the two-point function is a convenient quantity to work with, one cannot disentangle there the diierent contributions, which are of the same order in 1=M Q . Therefore, we shall only consider the three-point function analysis from 8]. The sum rule reads:</p>

				<p><formula>~ f 2 B K e &apos; Z Ec 0 dE Z Ec 0 dE 0 e (E+E 0 )=2 (( 3 2 E 4 (E E 0 ) &quot; 1 + s () 41 9 + 4 2 9 2 ln E ! # 2 (E + E 0 )(E 2 + E 02 jE 2 E 02 j) + 4 3 s () h uui() h E(E 0 ) + E 0 (E) + (E + E 0 )(E E 0 ) i 1 4 h s G 2 i(E E 0 ) + 3 8 2=(3 1 ) s M 2 0 h uui()(E)(E 0 ) ) ; (22) where e .</formula></p>

				<p>The kinetic energy K can be obtained by taking the ratio of the sum rules in Eqs. (22) and (14). A similar analysis can be done here, which is summarized in Fig. 2a, b. Again a good stability in is reached for E c 0:8 GeV. This suggests the phenomenological but not rigorous lower bound:</p>

				<p><formula>jKj 0:4 GeV 2 : (23)</formula></p>

				<p>However, the dependence on E c is violent. Hopefully, a slight innexion point appears for E c &apos; 1 1:2 GeV, at which one can extract the optimal result: K &apos; (0:5 0:6) GeV 2 ;</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(24)</head>

				<p>but our conndence level in this estimate is less than for the previous parameters. A more conservative attitude is to consider the whole range spanned in Eqs. (23) and (24) and to enlarge the error by a factor 2. Thus, one obtains:</p>

				<p><formula>K &apos; (0:5 0:2) GeV 2 : (25)</formula></p>

				<p>Though in agreement with that of 8], this result suggests that a lower value of K about -0.3 GeV 2 is not absolutely excluded.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Local duality FESR constraints</head>

				<p>Let us now test the consistency of the previous estimates by using local duality FESR. The constraints from the lowest FESR moments can be derived from the LSR by taking the limit ! 0. In this way, one can deduce the set of approximate equations:</p>

				<p><formula>3 4 E c ( 1 + 2 E 3 c h uui ) 2 ~ f 2 B 1 2 E 3 c ( 1 + s 17 3 + 4 9 2 2 E 3 c h uui ) K 3 5 E 2 c ( 1 10 9 s + 2 E 3 c h uui 1 5 8 M 2 0 E 2 c !) : (26)</formula></p>

				<p>We solve these constraints by using as input the value of obtained previously, which is quite stable versus the variation of E c and which is also less aaected by the radiative correction than ~ f B . This gives:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E c 1 GeV (27) and therefore: ~ f B (0:40 0:07) GeV 3=2 K 0:41 GeV 2 ; (28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which agrees within the errors with the previous estimates and indicates the consistency of the whole results from the LSR and FESR.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="7">Conclusions</head>

				<p>Using the LSR and local duality FESR, we have derived the values of the HQET parameters , at which the results are consistent with each other. We conclude that, besides the eventual contribution of renormalons, the most reliable estimate is that of , although it is slightly aaected by the variation of E c . Indeed, contrary to ~ f B , its radiative correction is quite small (ratio of sum rules). We can consider as the best estimate, the interaction region between the HQET and full QCD sum rules results in Eqs. (18) and (20), which suggests: &apos; (0:65 0:05) GeV:</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(29)</head>

				<p>This value is slightly higher than the existing estimates 6, 5] and the recent average 22], which is based on a more precise value &apos; (0:55 0:05) GeV from HQET sum rule than the one in Eq. (18). For the kinetic energy, the result is inaccurate due to the huge dependence of the estimate on the change of the value of E c . Our conservative estimate in Eq. (25), which spans the range of values provided by the LSR and FESR methods is 6 :</p>

				<p><formula>K &apos; (0:5 0:2) GeV 2 : (30)</formula></p>

				<p>By combining the previous results with the well-known estimate of the chromomagnetic matrix element to leading order in 1=M b :</p>

				<p><formula>&apos; 1 4 (M 2 B M 2 B ) = 0:119 GeV 2 ; (31)</formula></p>

				<p>one can deduce from Eq. (6), the value of the quark mass to two-loop accuracy entering in HQET: M b &apos; (4:61 0:05) GeV:</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(32)</head>

				<p>This value is in agreement (within the errors), with previous analysis from HQET-sum ruless6] and with the most recent determinations of the pole mass to two loops from the relativistic sum rules t of the B and B masses in the full theory 22]:</p>

				<p><formula>M b &apos; (4:63 0:08) GeV; (33)</formula></p>

				<p>and from a non-relativistic sum rule analysis of the bottomium systems:</p>

				<p><formula>M b &apos; (4:69 0:03) GeV; (34)</formula></p>

				<p>The consistency of these results gives a strong support to the negligiblity of higher order contributions in 1=M b to the relation given in Eq. (6). It may also indicate that the still quantitatively less controlled renormalon eeects to the quark mass deened in HQETT23], is small regardless the deenition of introduced in the analysis. 7 . For the decay constant ~ f B , the radiative correction is huge, and it amounts to about 100% of the lowest-order contribution in the corresponding two-point correlator. Therefore, in the absence of an evaluation of the 2 s -term, one can only suggest the conservative range spanned by the results of the two diierent HQET sum rules. Then, we obtain ~ f B &apos; (0:34 0:16) GeV 3=2 ; (35) where, as already mentioned, the error is mainly due to the estimate of the unknown 2 s -corrections. This result can be transformed into the value of the decay constant in the so-called static limit, by using the relation in Eq. (5). Therefore, one obtains: f 1 B &apos; (2:02 0:9)f : (36) This result is in agreement with the value: f 1 B &apos; (1:97 0:33)f (37) obtained from the sum rule in the full theory 12], which does not however suuer from a large s -correction and therefore has a much smaller error. One can combine these two results and quote the final value of the decay constant in the static limit from the sum rules: f 1 B &apos; (1:98 0:31)f and ~ f B &apos; (0:33 0:06) GeV 3=2 :</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(38) This result is in good agreement with the present lattice results f 1 B &apos; (1:74 0:27)f compiled by 20]. This result can be used for xing the coeecients A and B of the 1=M Q and 1=M 2 Q corrections on f P from Eq. (5): f P</figDesc>

				</figure>

			<note>q M P &apos; ~ f B ( s (M Q )) 1== 1 1 2 3 s (M Q ) A M Q + B M 2 Q ! ; (39)</note>

				<p>In so doing, we shall use the values 22,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>12, 24]: f D &apos; (1:37 0:04 0:06)f and f B &apos; (1:49 0:06 0:05)f : (40)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>First, we use a linear t and x simply A from the ratio f B =f D . We obtain: A = (0:6 0:1) GeV; (41) which agrees within the errors with the previous ndings 11], 5]{{8], 12]. Secondly, we determine A and B by solving numerically these three equations. We obtain:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A 1:1 GeV and B 0:7 GeV 2 ; (42) where</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A and B have large errors. These two terms agree within the errors with the earlier results 11], which suggests that the 1=M 2 Q correction is smaller than the 1=M Q one even at the charm quark mass. been Figure captions Fig. 1 : Analysis of the -(a, c)) and E c -(b, d) behaviours of ~ f B and for 4 = 0:317</p>

				<p>GeV. The dashed line is the prediction of 6] using 4 = 0:25 GeV. Fig. 2 : The same as Fig. 1 but for K. In a), we show the eeect of the subtraction point.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The meaning of this stability has been discussed in 9] in quantum mechanics , by taking the Laplace transform of the eigenvalue solution of an harmonic oscillator and by comparing the approximate series with the known complete solution. The optimal result is obtained at the minimum or at the innexion point of the curves. 2 These conservative values correspond to the value of E c comprised between that at which the stability is reached and that where we have E c -stability. These criteria include all diierent alternative criteria used in the literature and gives a more precise meaning of the so-called sum rule window of SVZ.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We are aware of the fact that in the lattice calculations, deened in this way can be aaected by renormalons 15]. 4 However, it has to be noticed that in the analysis of the heavy-to-light transitions, the optimal results are obtained at small n-values 17], such that, the Moments sum rule does not tend to the Laplace one, when M Q is large.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> In the following this error will be systematically included.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> We are aware of the importance of this quantity in the analysis of the inclusive B-meson decays 21].</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> An indication of the smallness of this eeect can also be inferred from the comparison of the values of the pole mass from relativistic and non-relativistic bottomium sum rules 22]</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">For a recent review, see e.g: T. Mannel, talk given at QCD 94</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Supp.); M. Neubert, CERN-TH</title>
		<meeting>. Supp.); M. Neubert, CERN-TH<address><addrLine>Montpellier</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">94</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. appear in</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Shifman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Vainshtein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Zakharov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">385</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="448" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">QCD spectral sum rules Heavy quarks from QCD spec- tral sum rules, talk given at QCD 94</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Supp.)</title>
		<editor>e.g. S. Narison</editor>
		<meeting>. Supp.)<address><addrLine>Montpellier</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. appear in Nucl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Broadhurst</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Grozin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="421" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Bagan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ball</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Braun</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Dosch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">278</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">457</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Heidelberg preprint HD-THEP-93-52 (1993) and references therein</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Dosch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Neubert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">245</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1076" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>259. and references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Eletskii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Shuryak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ball</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Braun</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="2472" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Bell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bertlmann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. Phys. Lett</title>
		<editor>R.A. Bertlmann</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">177</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">218</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="417" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Shuryak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">198</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">C55 (1992) 55; Phys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">285</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">137</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">322</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Zalewski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Cern-Th</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">talk given at the Third Workshop on the Tau-Charm Factory</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Marbella, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">320</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Sachrajda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cracow Epiphany Conference on Heavy Quarks, K. Zalewski fest</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Dominguez</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">talk given at the Third Workshop on the Tau-Charm Factory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett.B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">384</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>De Rafael</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">57</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bethke</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Supp.); B. Webber, talk given at the Glasgow IHEP Conference</title>
		<meeting>. Supp.); B. Webber, talk given at the Glasgow IHEP Conference<address><addrLine>Montpellier</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. appear in</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rome preprint 94</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Allton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1041</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>private. communication from L. Lellouch</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Bigi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cracow Epiphany Conference on Heavy Quarks, K. Zalewski fest</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">341</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Beneke</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Supp.)</title>
		<meeting>. Supp.)<address><addrLine>Montpellier</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. appear in</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Narison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page">198</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
