<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Revisit of Weinberg&apos;s sum rules</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2008-02-01">February 1, 2008</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Bing</forename>
								<forename type="middle">An</forename>
								<surname>Li</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Astronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Kentucky Lexington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>40506</postCode>
									<region>KY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Revisit of Weinberg&apos;s sum rules</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2008-02-01">February 1, 2008</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-ph/9504305v1 14 Apr 1995</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>By applying the Ward identity found by Weinberg two new relations of the amplitude of a 1 → ρπ with other physical quantities have been found.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>One of the most important features revealed from quantum chromodynamics (QCD) is the chiral symmetry in the physics of ordinary hadrons. However, chiral symmetry has been extensively applied to study hadron physics before QCD created. Weinberg&apos;s sum rules of ρ and a 1 mesons[1] are among those pioneer works. In ref.[1] by applying SU(2) L ×SU(2) R and current algebra two Ward identities of vector and axial-vector currents have been obtained and two sum rules have been found. However, in order to obtain the second sum rule(eq.(4) of ref.(1)) one additional assumption has been made[1]. Using VMD and combining Weinberg&apos;s sum rules with KSFR sum rule[2], the relationship between the masses of ρ and a 1 mesons m 2 a 1</p>

			<div>
				<head>= 2m</head>

				<p>2 ρ has been revealed. It predicts that m a = 1.09GeV . It is well known that a 1 meson has a long history and the present mass of a 1 meson is 1.26 GeV[3]. In this letter we try to see what we can learn if we only apply chiral symmetry, VMD, and current algebra to study the physics of ρ and a 1 mesons. We follow the Ward identity found by Weinberg[1].</p>

				<p>From the formalism of ref.[1] it can be seen that the Weinberg&apos;s first sum rule is the natural result of chiral symmetry, and current algebra. Under VMD, the first sum rule</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∞ 0 {ρ V (µ 2 ) − ρ A (µ 2 )}µ −2 dµ 2 = F 2 π 4 (1) leads to g 2 ρ m 2 ρ − g 2 A m 2 A = F 2 π 4 (2) where &lt; 0|V a µ |ρ λ b &gt;= ǫ λ µ δ ab g ρ , &lt; 0|A a µ |a λ b &gt;= ǫ λ µ δ ab g A ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and F π is pion decay constant, F π = 186MeV . This sum rule(2) can be tested. According to VMD, g ρ is the coupling constant between ρ and γ and it has been determined g ρ = 0.12GeV 2 from Γ(ρ → l + l − ). Using m a = 1.26GeV the first sum rule predicts that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g A = 0.16GeV 2 . (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the other hand, g A can be determined from Γ(τ → a 1 ν).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>By using VMD, we have Γ(τ → a 1 ν) = G 2 8π cos 2 θ c g 2 A m 3 τ m 2 a (1 − m 2 a m 2 τ ) 2 (1 + 2 m 2 a m 2 τ ). (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The experimental data of the decay rate is[3]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.14 × 10 −13 (1 ± 0.32)GeV . g A is determined to be 0.16(1 ± 0.16)GeV 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. This value is in good agreement with theoretical prediction(3).</p>

				<p>By applying the VMD to the second sum rule of ref.[1]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∞ 0 {ρ V (µ 2 ) − ρ A (µ 2 )}dµ 2 = 0 (5) the relationship g A = g ρ has been found. Combining eq.(5) with KSFR sum rule[2]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the mass relation of ρ and a 1</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>mesons m 2 a = 2m 2 ρ (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>has been established. As mentioned above, the relation(6) is not in good agreement with data. Therefore, it is needed to reexamine the second sum rule. From ref.[1] it can be seen that for the second sum rule(5) besides chiral symmetry and current algebra, an extra assumption has been used. It is not our attempt to comment on this assumption. What we want to study is that if we do not use this assumption and insist on chiral symmetry, VMD, and current algebra, what else can be obtained besides Weinberg&apos;s first sum rule(1)? In ref.[1] the following equation (eq.(11) in ref.[1]) has been established by using SU</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(2) L × SU(2) R chiral symmetry and current algebra 1 2 q µ M µνλ (q, p) = ∆ νλ V (q + p) − ∆ νλ A (p), (7) where − iǫ abc M µνλ = d 4 xd 4 y &lt; 0|T {A µ a (x)A ν b (y)V λ c (0)}|0 &gt; exp{−iqx − ipy}, (8) δ ab ∆ νλ V (p) = i d 4 ye −ipy &lt; 0|T {V ν a (y)V λ b (0)}|0 &gt; . (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first sum rule has been derived from this equation[1]. In this letter the study starts from this equation(7). Following ref.[1] setting q µ = 0 in eq.(7), on the left hand of the equation(7) only pion poles survive. In this limit the equation (7)now reads</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−iǫ abc q µ M µνλ | qµ→0 = F π 2k 0 d 4 ye −ipy k · q{ θ(y 0 ) q 0 + k 0 − iε e −i(q 0 +k 0 )y 0 &lt; π a ( k = − q, k 0 )|A ν b (y)V λ c (0)|0 &gt; + θ(−y 0 ) q 0 + k 0 − iε &lt; π a ( k = − q, k 0 )|V λ c (0)|A ν b (y)|0 &gt; − θ(y 0 ) k 0 − q 0 − iε &lt; 0|A ν b (y)V λ c (0)|π a ( k = q, k 0 ) &gt; − θ(−y 0 ) k 0 − q 0 − iε e i(k 0 −q 0 )y 0 &lt; 0|V λ c (0)A ν b (y)|π a ( k = q, k 0 ) &gt;}. (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In eq.(10) the pion is on mass shell and in chiral limit k 0 = | q|. When k = − q there is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>k · q 2k 0 1 q 0 + k 0 − iε = 1 2 , (11) and when k = q there is k · q 2k 0 1 k 0 − q 0 − iε = − 1 2 . (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the limit of q µ → 0, the energy of the pion states in eq.(10) is zero. Considering this fact and substituting the two equations(</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>11,12) into eq.(10), the eq.(7) becomes F π d 4 ye −ipy &lt; π a |T {A ν b (y)V λ c (0)}|0 &gt;= −ǫ abc {∆ νλ V (p) − ∆ νλ A (p)}. (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Comparing with the eq.(18) of ref.[1], there is an additional factor of two in eq.(13). This new factor does not affect the second sum rule(5) of ref.[1] under its assumption. However, this factor is important for the study of this letter.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>In eq.(13) ∆ νλ V (p) has ρ meson pole and ∆ νλ A</trash>

					<figDesc>(p) has both pion pole and a 1 meson pole. The left hand side of the equation(13) should have these three poles. Therefore, multiplying both sides of the equation by p 2 − m 2 and letting q 2 → m 2 the corresponding pole term can be picked out from the equation, where m 2 is pion mass(in chiral limit pion mass is zero) , ρ meson mass, and a 1 meson mass respectively. The poles of the left hand side of the eq.(13) can be obtained in following way</figDesc>
					<trash>F π d 4 ye −ipy &lt; π a |T {A ν b (y)V λ c (0)}|0 &gt;= {θ(y 0 )e −iky iF π k ν &lt; π a π b (k)|V λ c (0)|0 &gt; +θ(y 0 )e iky (−)iF π k ν &lt; π a |V λ c (0)|π a &gt; +θ(y 0 )e −iky g ρ ε σ * λ (k) &lt; π a |A ν b (0)|ρ σ c (k) &gt; +θ(y 0 )e iky g ρ ε σ λ (k) &lt; π a ρ σ c (k)|A ν b (0)|0 &gt; +θ(y 0 )e −iky g A ε σ ν (k) &lt; π a a σ b (k)|V λ c (0)|0 &gt; +θ(y 0 )e iky g A ε σ * ν (k) &lt; π a |V λ c (0)|a σ b (k) &gt;}. (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>After using VMD, the following formulas are obtained</figDesc>
					<trash>&lt; π a |V λ c (0)|π b (k) &gt;= iǫ abc g ρ f ρππ k λ m m 2 ρ , &lt; π a π b (k)|V λ c (0)|0 &gt;= −iǫ abc g ρ f ρππ k λ m m 2 ρ , (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>where f ρππ is the coupling constant of the decay of ρ → 2π in the limit of that the energy of one pion is zero. Using VMD, the other four matrix elements in eq.(14) are related to the decay of a 1 → ρπ. The vertex of this decay has been written as {Ag µν + Bp πµ p πν }ǫ abc a</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>a µ ρ b ν π c , (16)</formula></p>

				<p>where A and B are functions of momenta of a 1 , ρ, and π. In eq.(14), the energy of the state |π a &gt; is zero, therefore only the amplitude A contributes to these matrix elements of eq.(14) and the amplitude A is in the limit of p π = 0. Using eq.(16) and VMD we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>&lt; π a |A ν b (0)|ρ σ c (k) &gt;= −ǫ abc g A A(m 2 ρ )ε σ (k) ν 1 m 2 ρ − m 2 a , &lt; π a ρ σ c (k)|A ν b (0)|0 &gt;= −ǫ abc g A A(m 2 ρ )ε σ * (k) ν 1 m 2 ρ − m 2 a . (17) In eq.(17), due to k 2 = m 2 ρ , we have A(k 2 ) = A(m 2</trash>

					<figDesc>ρ ). In the same way, two other matrix elements of eq.(14) can be written as</figDesc>
					<trash>&lt; π a |V λ c (0)|a σ b (k) &gt;= −ǫ abc g ρ A(m 2 a ) 1 m 2 a − m 2 ρ ǫ σ (k) λ , &lt; π a a σ b (k)|V λ c (0)|0 &gt;= −ǫ abc g ρ A(m 2 a ) 1 m 2 a − m 2 ρ ǫ σ * (k) λ . (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is necessary to point out that due to the limit of p π = 0 in eq.(13), the amplitude A is function of k 2 where k is either the momentum of ρ or a 1 . It has been found that in eq.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(17) k 2 = m 2 ρ and k 2 = m 2</trash>

					<figDesc>a in eq.(18). Substituting the six matrix elements(15,17,18) into eq.(14), the pole terms on the left hand side of the eq.(13) are obtained</figDesc>
					<trash>F π d 4 ye −ipy &lt; π a |T {A ν b (y)V λ c (0)}|0 &gt; | poles = ig ρ f ρππ F 2 π m 2 ρ p ν p λ p 2 −iǫ abc F π g ρ g A 1 m 2 ρ − m 2 a 1 p 2 − m 2 ρ (−g λν + p λ p ν m m 2 ρ ) −iǫ abc F π g ρ g A A(m 2 a ) 1 m 2 a − m 2 ρ 1 p 2 − m 2 a (−g νλ + p ν p λ m 2 a ). (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>By applying the VMD to the right hand side of the equation(13), the pole terms are obtained</figDesc>
					<trash>iF 2 π p ν p λ p 2 + ig 2 ρ 1 p 2 − m 2 ρ (−g νλ + p ν p λ p 2 )ig 2 A 1 p 2 − m 2 a (−g νλ + p ν p λ m 2 a ). (20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Multiply both sides of eq.(13) by p 2 and set p 2 = 0 the pion pole can be picked out and the following relation can be found g ρ f ρππ = m</figDesc>
					<trash>2 ρ . (21) Multiply eq.(13) by p 2 −m 2 ρ and set p 2 = m 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>ρ and the ρ pole can be picked out and the second relation is obtained</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g A F π A(m 2 ρ ) = −g ρ (m 2 a − m 2 ρ ). (22) Multiply eq.(13) by p 2 − m 2 a and set p 2 = m 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>a and the a 1 pole can be picked out and the third relation is found g ρ F π A(m 2 a ) = −g A (m 2 a − m 2 ρ ). (23) Let&apos;s discuss these three relations. The first relation is well known from VMD[4]. In eqs.(22,23), if we assume that A(k 2 ), where k is either the momentum of ρ meson or the momentum of a 1 meson, is independent of k 2 , i.e.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A(m 2 ρ ) = A(m 2 a ), (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>then from eqs.(22,23) it can be obtained that g ρ = g A which is just the consequence of the second sum rule of ref.[1].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>However, based on chiral symmetry, VMD, and current algebra only, we can not reach the conclusion(24). On the other hand, from the discussion of Weinberg&apos;s first sum rule above and the current value of m a , the relation (24) does not have good support theoretically and experimentally. Therefore, in</figDesc>
					<trash>general, A(k 2 ) depends on k 2 . From eqs.(22,23), we determine that A(m 2 ρ ) = −8.14GeV, A(m 2 a ) = −14.05GeV. Therefore, A(k</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>2 ) strongly depends on k 2 . In order to see the deviation of these values from physical ones we can use the experimental data of the ratio of d-wave to s wave[5]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>d/s = −0.11 ± 0.02 to determine the B in the amplitude (16), B = −1.1A.</p>

				<p>Using the values of A and B, the width of a 1 → ρπ calculated is higher than experimental value[3] by one order of magnitude. Of course, the A&apos;s in eqs.(22,23) are determined in an unphysical limit of p π = 0. Unlike the case of ρ → ππ that f ρππ (p π = 0) determined in eq.(21) and KSFR sum rule is very close to physical value, the A&apos;s determined by eqs.(22,23) in the limit of p π = 0 are far away from the physical value of the amplitude. In ref.[6] a chiral theory of mesons including pseudoscalar, vector and axial-vector mesons has been studied and it can be considered as a realization of chiral symmetry, VMD, and current algebra. In this theory Weinberg&apos;s first sum rule and relation (21) are satisfied. It can also be seen that the amplitude A found in this theory satisfies the relations (22,23) in the limit of p π = 0.</p>

				<p>Explanations of why f ρππ in the limit of p π = 0 is very close to the physical value and the amplitude A in the limit of p π = 0 is not, can be found and a new mass relation of ρ and a 1 mesons has been presented.</p>

				<p>To conclude, relations(22,23) do not lead to m 2 a = 2m 2 ρ , therefore, from chiral symmetry, VMD, and current algebra alone this mass relation can not be obtained. In the limit of p π = 0, the amplitude of a 1 → ρπ must satisfy the relations(22,23).</p>

				<p>This research is partially supported by DE-91ER75661.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18507</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kawarabayashi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Suzuki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1071</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>255. ; Riazuddin and Fayyazudin</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Particle Data Group, Phys. Rev. D50 No</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.J.Sakurai, Currents and Mesons</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">53</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Argus</forename>
				<surname>Collaboration</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Albrecht</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">5861</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R Chiral Theory of Mesons, preprint</title>
		<editor>Bing An Li, U(2) L × U</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
