<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">H events in the ZEUS Detector</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1995-03">May 1995 April 10, 1995</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">E</forename>
								<surname>Accomando</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Dipartimento di Fisica</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universita&apos; di Torino</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Italy (</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Iori</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Dipartimento di Fisica</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universita&apos; di Torino</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Italy (</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Mattioli</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Dipartimento di Fisica and I.N.F.N</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universita&apos; di Roma \La Sapienza&quot;</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>sez. di Roma</settlement>
									<country>Italy, Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">H events in the ZEUS Detector</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1995-03">May 1995 April 10, 1995</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The supersymmetric left-right models suggest a production of doubly charged Higgs particles. Still there is no evidence for the existence and only some lower limits for their mass are present from the Z decay. Here we investigate the possibility of observing the doubly electronic Higgs decay assuming a M H = 50 Gev and M H = 100 Gev.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<figure>
					<trash>hep-ph/9505274 10 May 1995 H events in the ZEUS Detector E. Accomando (1;2) ,M. Iori (2) , M. Mattioli (2) (1) Dipartimento di Fisica, Universita&apos; di Torino, Italy (2) Dipartimento di Fisica, Universita&apos; di Roma \La Sapienza&quot;, Italy and I.N.F.N., sez. di Roma, Italy April 10, 1995</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Abstract The supersymmetric left-right models suggest a production of doubly charged Higgs particles. Still there is no evidence for the existence and only some lower limits for their mass are present from the Z decay. Here we investigate the possibility of observing the doubly electronic Higgs decay assuming a M H = 50 Gev and M H = 100 Gev.</p>

			<div>
				<head n="1">Higgs boson at HERA</head>

				<p>The doubly charged Higgs boson, H are the basic particles of a class of model of elettro-weak interaction beyond the Standard Model with spontaneous parity violation 1,2].</p>

				<p>In the recent paper 3] the authors pointed out the possible production of a single double Higgs boson at Hera, in e p collider at Desy with p s = 313 GeV .</p>

				<p>Their calculated the following processes:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e p ! e + p H (1) where H ! e e ( ; ) and e p ! + p H (2) where H ! e (e ; )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>whose diagrams are shown in Fig. 1 2 Study of the topology of the generated events</p>

				<p>In order to investigate the possibility of observing the processes (1,2) in the Zeus detector was written a generator based upon the cross section and the decay rate 2]. In this generator the mass of Higgs may be varied also. The decay mode as well the coupling constant g ee ,g ee . Fig. 2 shows a plot of the calculated cross section as function of Higgs mass. The dashed line refers to the process (1) and the full line to the process (2). The rst step in the analysis was to investigate the topology of the generated events in order to estimate the fraction for which the lepton would visible in the detector. As shown before the Higgs boson can decay in two identical lepton (e e ; ) or in electron-muon (e ). In the rst case according to the leptonic number and charge conservation in the nal state is present a positron in the second case a positive muon. In both situations they follow the electron beam direction (backward respect to the proton beam direction). The processes (1,2) have the caratterisctics to be diiractive ( high Q 2 ) then the proton goes in the beam pipe (forward direction) and no information in the hadronic calorimeter are left.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.1 Study of reaction e p ! p e + H ! p e + e e The Zeus Monte Carlo</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>provides a detailed simulation of the detector geometry and resolution based upon the Geant package. The output is read in Zephyr and recontruction of events is carried out.</p>

				<p>Using this software in the ooine enviroment we have investigated the global properties of the event. For the reason the calorimeter is hermetic we devoted our study to the e e Higgs decays in particular to the following reaction e p ! p e + H where H ! e e As shown in Ref 3] those results exclude an Higgs-boson mass 6:5 &lt; M H &lt; 36:5 GeV as function of the coupling strength of the Higgs boson to lepton pairs,g ll . We have chosen a Higgs mass value of 50 GeV and of 100 GeV with g ee = 0:5 10 4 and g ee = 0:1 respectively. An electromagnetic cluster nding algorithm for Uranium calorimeter 6]and CTD nding software 7] was used to identiied a global track. Figs 3a-b show the energy deposited as electromagnetic cluster in the calorimeter and the distribution of the polar angle, l , of one of the negative leptons in the nal state for M H = 50 GeV respectively. We nd the most of the energy relased by the electron in the calorimeter is greater than 20 GeV and the energy distribution of the electromagnetic cluster (Fig. 3a) is peacked at 25 GeV. In Fig 3b we nd a deleption of events at small l angle due to calorimeter acceptance in forward region. Figs 4a-b show the same distribution as Fig</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>b using M H = 100 GeV . We nd again an excess of events with very low energy deposited in em-calorimeter and the l distribution is shifted to low values as expected. Each time the decay track loses the energy deposited in the calorimeter the track can be identiied by the cone algorithm as pion or muon. After a generation of 1000 events ,using the setup of 1994 data taking, with M H =</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>100 GeV ,by the cluster identiication, we nd the 88% 3% are identiied electron , 8%1 pion and the rest are muons and jets. The misindentiication of the cluster as pion increases to 9:5% 1 when we assume M H = 50 GeV . Fig 5a-b show the ee angle distribution respectively obtained using only the two highest electromagnetic clusters found in the calorimeter with E cal &gt; 20 GeV at least and the Higgs mass reconstructed imposing 150 &lt; ee &lt; 200, l &gt; 30 degrees for the decay leptons. A clear peack at M H = 50 GeV is found. Fig</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>b show the some distribution of Fig 5a-b assuming M H = 100 GeV .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The topology of this sample of events is characterized by a two isolated tracks in the Central Tracking Detector (CTD), back-to-back in the transverse plane leaving large amount of energy in the electromagnetic calorimeter.</p>

				<p>The general conclusion to be drawn from these investigations is that the detector acceptance is able to detect two leptons decaying from Higgs boson and is approximately constant if we assume an Higgs mass of 50 GeV and 100 GeV but we lose electron identiied track by the calorimeter at small l values (15 &lt; l &lt; 40)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Background</head>

				<p>The nature of the Higgs boson signal chosen with two high energy electron seen in the detector makes the physics background rare. The transverse energy, E t and longitudinal energy E z for the decay electrons is plotted in Fig 7-8 rispectively for M H = 50 GeV and M H = 100 GeV and E e &gt; 20 GeV . We nd the E t distribution is peacked at 20 GeV and 45 GeV for M H = 50 GeV and M H = 100 GeV respectively. Appling a cut in tranverse energy , E t &gt; 15 GeV we remove possible contribution from elastic J= where a charge misidentiication is present.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have investigated one of the production processes of Higgs boson at Hera energies in the framework left-right symmetric model proposed by Senjanovic and Mohapatra. The presence of M H &gt; 40 GeV is allowed both theoretically and experimentally assuming g ee &gt; 10 3 . A remarkable signature enables us to search for the Higgs mass. According with this analysis after 100 pb 1 we extimate have 181 events from Higgs with M H = 50 GeV characterized by a two isolated tracks in the Central Tracking Detector (CTD), back-to-back in the transverse plane leaving E Cal &gt; 20 GeV</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Acknowledgments</head>

				<p>We thank to Prof. S. Petrarca for valuable discussions.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>7 Figures 6</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>

					<figDesc>Feynman graphs for single H production at Hera</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 2:</head>

					<figDesc>Plot of the total cross sction at p s = 313 GeV versus M H from Ref 3]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3:</head>

					<figDesc>Energy in the EmCAL a) Electron energy in the electromagnetic cluster b) of electromagnetic cluster of one electron in the nal state both distributions are obtained with M H = 50 GeV</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4:</head>

					<figDesc>Energy in the EmCAL a) Electron energy in the electromagnetic cluster b) of electromagnetic cluster of one electron in the nal state both distributions are obtained with M H = 100 GeV</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 5:</head>

					<figDesc>M H = 50 GeV : a) ee distribution of the electromagnetic cluster for the two highest electron b) Higgs mass evaluated using the electromagnetic clusters; the cuts are discussed in the text</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 6:</head>

					<figDesc>M H = 100 GeV : a) ee distribution of the electromagnetic cluster for the two highest electron b) Higgs mass evaluated using the electromagnetic clusters; the cuts are discussed in the text Figure 7</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>: M H = 50 GeV : Transverse energy, E t and longitudinal energy, E z for the decay electron with E e &gt; 20 GeV Figure 8: M H = 100 GeV : Transverse energy, E t and longitudinal energy, E z for the decay electron with E e &gt; 20 GeV</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">References</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Mohapatra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Senjanovic</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys .Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">912</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Gelmini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Roncadelli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">411</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Accomando</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S. Petrarca</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">323</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">212</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The generator is supported on UNIX stations,the source code of the program can be found in e3rs01.roma.infn.it; The generate input to the Zeus detector simulation programme (Mozart) was obtained by the interface program to ZDIS</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Swartz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="19902877" />
			<biblScope unit="page">24</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">DeJong et al Status of the Calorimeter Reconstruction Programme ZEUS-91-36</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Long at al CTD Reconstruction Programme User&apos;s Guide ZEUS-90-122</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
