<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Flavor and Horizontal Symmetries</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Paul</forename>
								<forename type="middle">H</forename>
								<surname>Frampton</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute of Field Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics and Astronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of North Carolina</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>27599-3255</postCode>
									<settlement>Chapel Hill</settlement>
									<region>NC</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Flavor and Horizontal Symmetries</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-ph/9510260v1 10 Oct 1995 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>§1. Flavor Questions.</p>

				<p>We may identify three issues: (i)Replication.</p>

				<p>Surely the most basic flavor question is why there exists the replication of the quarks: u,d; c,s; t.b and similarly for the leptons: ν e , e; ν µ , µ; ν τ , τ . Why are there three families? Although there are papers about this topic, it will not be my subject here. (ii)Fermion mass hierarchy. If I define λ = sinθ C ≃ 0.22, the Cabibbo angle, as a &quot; small &quot; parameter then for the up-type (Q=+2/3) quarks: m u /m t ∼ λ 8 ; m c /m t ∼ λ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>4 (1 . 1) while for the down-type quarks (Q = -1/3): m d /m b ∼ λ 4 ; m s /m b ∼ λ 2 . (1 . 2) The charged lepton masses approximately satisfy: m e /m τ ∼ λ 4 ; m µ /m τ ∼ λ 2 . (1 . 3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These masses are evaluated at the GUT scale ∼ 2 × 10 16 GeV. Whence do such hierarchies arise? (iii)Mixing Hierarchy. When the quark mass matrices are diagonalized with the usual bi-unitary trans- formations:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>U L M U U † R = diag(m u , m c , m t ) D L M D D † R = diag(m d , m s , m b ) (1 . 4) and the CKM matrix is constucted by V CKM = U L D † L one find that its elements have the hierarchy: * ) Supported in part by the U. S. Department of Energy. typeset using PTPT E X.sty &lt;ver.0.8&gt; P. H. Frampton |V ii ∼ 1| &gt; |V 12 | &gt; |V 23 | &gt; |V 13 | (1 . 5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where these four elements are of order 1, λ, λ 2 , λ 3 respectively. Whence do these hierarchies come? ......is the third and last flavor question. Note that the fermion and mixing hierarchies speak to 12 of the 19 parameters of the Standard Model: the m i and the Θ k . The others 7 are: the three couplings α i ; the two CP parameters δ and θ; and the two scales M W and M H arising in the electroweak symmetry breaking. §2. Horizontal Symmetries Let the horizontal symmetry group be G H . There are choices to be made about G H : whether it is global or gauged, finite or infinite(Lie), abelian or non-abelian. My choices will be: gauged, finite and non-abelian. Finite abelian groups (Z N ) 1) and finite non-abelian groups (S N only) 2) have been studied previously. What I mean by a gauged finite group will be discussed below. First I offer a brief review of all finite groups of order g ≤ 31. [One usually stops at g = 2 n − 1 because of the richness of g = 2 n ]</p>

				<p>In this range there are, according to standard textbooks 4) , 93 inequivalent groups of which 48 are abelian and 45 are non-abelian. g ≥ 32 might be interesting too but lower g is surely more economic. Let me deal quickly with all the abelian cases. The building block is Z p where the elements are the p th roots of unity, e 2πi/p . The only fact one needs is that Z p × Z q is equivalent to Z pq if and only if p,q have no common prime factor. So if I decompose the order g of the group into its prime factors g = i p k i i then the number of inequivalent abelian finite groups at order g is N a (g) = k i P (k i ), where P (ν) is the number of ordered partitions of ν.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>For example, P (1, 2, 3, 4) = 1, 2, 3, 5. For the cases g ≤ 31, one finds N a (g) = 1 except that N a (g) = 2 for g = 4,9,12,18,20,25,28; N a (g) = 3 for 18,24,27; and N a (16) = 5.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Thus, adding these results gives the required answer of 48 abelian groups with g ≤ 31. These will not be considered further here. Now, and for the remainder of the talk, I shall consider non-abelian finite groups.</p>

				<p>The best known are the S N permutation (or symmetric) groups with order g = N! Since g grows so rapidly, only N=3,4 are in our range. Generally, S N ⊂ O(N − 1) and can be interpreted geometrically as the symmetry of a regular N-plex in (N − 1) spatial dimensions. Next come the dihedral groups D N , with order g = 2N, which are subgroups of 0(3). The geometrical interpretation is the symmetry of a 2-sided planar regular N-agon in 3 spatial dimensions where the polygon is treated as a &quot; two-faced &quot; entity. There is the one g = 12 tetrahedral group (T) which is the even-permutation subgroup of S 4 . Spinorial generalizations (doubles) of the D N are the dicyclic groups Q 2N which have order g = 4N and are subgroups of SU(2) rather than O(3). The majority (32) of the non-abelian groups with order g ≤ 31 are made from</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Flavors and Horizontal Symmetries 3 S N , D N , T, Q 2N as follows: g = 6: D 3 (≡ S 3 ). g = 8: D 4 ; Q ≡ Q 4 . g = 10: D 5 . g = 12: D 6 ; Q 6 ; T . g = 14: D 7 . g = 16: D 8 ; Q 8 ; Z 2 × D 4 ; Z 2 × Q. g = 18: D 9 ; Z 3 × D 3 . g = 20: D 10 ; Q 10 . g = 22: D 11 . g = 24: D 12 ; Q 12 ; Z 2 × D 6 ; Z 2 × Q 6 ; Z 2 × T ; Z 3 × D 4 ; D 3 × Q; Z 4 × D 3 ; S 4 . g = 26: D 13 . g = 28: D 14 ; Q 14 . g = 30: D 15 ; D 5 × Z 3 ; D 3 × Z 5 . There are another 13 which are twisted products of Z n : g = 16: Z 2 ˜ ×Z 8 (two); Z 4 ˜ ×Z 4 ; Z 2 ˜ ×(Z 2 × Z 4 )(two). g = 18: Z 2 ˜ ×(Z 3 × Z 3 ). g = 20: Z 4 ˜ ×Z 5 . g = 21: Z 3 ˜ ×Z 7 . g = 24: Z 3 ˜ ×Z q ; Z 3 ˜ ×Z 8 ; Z 3 ˜ ×D 4 . g = 27: Z 3 ˜ ×Z 9 ; Z 3 ˜ ×(Z 3 × Z 3 ). Of these groups Q 2N is of most interest to model-building 3), 4), 5), 6) . The group Q 2N with order g = 4N has 4 singlet representations 1, 1 ′ , 1 ′′ ,1 ′′′ and the (N − 1) doublets 2 (j) , 1 ≤ j ≤ (N − 1). The doublet multiplication is: 2 (j) × 2 (k) = 2 |j−k| + 2 min(j+k,N −j−k) (2 . 1) with the generalized notation: 2 (0) ≡ 1 + 1 ′ 2 (N ) ≡ 1 ′′ + 1 ′′′ (2 . 2) Q 2N</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>has only singlet and doublet reprentations. To obtain a clearer intuitive understanding of Q 2N , it is defined by the algebra:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A 2N = E B 2 = A N ABA = B The elements are E, A, A 2 , A 3 , ........A 2N −1 , B, AB, A 2 B, A 3 B, .........A 2N −1 B A simple matrix representation is: A = cosθ sinθ −sinθ cosθ with θ = π/N because then A = cosN θ sinN θ −sinN θ cosN θ = −1 −1 P. H. Frampton and for B I use the simple matrix B = −i −i</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Q 2N is thus the full SU(2) symmetry of a planar regular N-agon where rotation by 2π gives a sign -1; only rotation by 4π brings back the identity.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.1. Gauging G H = Q 2N</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Gauging G H , a finite group, is subtle as is immediately seen by considering the covariant derivative. In fact, at a local level it is meaningless in a flat spacetime neighborhood. Globally, with respect to topological aspects of the spacetime manifold , it is best done by gauging SU (2) H ⊃ Q 2N then spontaneously breaking to Q 2N .</p>

				<p>If this is at a high scale, the effective theory has no gauge field -but consistency with wormholes is preserved.</p>

				<p>Gauging leads to consistency requirements: (a) Chiral fermions must be in complete representations of SU (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2) H . (b) (SU (2) H ) 2 Y anomalies must cancel. (c) Witten&apos;s global SU (2</trash>

					<figDesc>) H anomaly must cancel. (b) and (c) are straightforward but (a) requires the dictionary for embedding Q 2N ⊂ SU (2). This is actually a simple pattern:</figDesc>
					<trash>SU (2) → Q 2N 1 → 1 2 → 2 1 3 → 1 ′ + 2 2 4 → 2 1 + 2 3 5 → 1 + 2 2 + 2 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>and so on. The infinite sequence is clear from the above. §3. Model Building with Horizontal Q 2N Symmetry</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>There are five &quot; triples &quot; in the standard model for which Q 2N assignments must be made:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1) (t, b) L , (c, s) L , (u, d) L . (2) t R , c R .u R . (3) b R , s R , d R . (4) (ν τ , τ ) L , (ν µ , µ) L , (ν e , e) L . (5) τ R , µ R , e R . These must be assigned to anomaly-free complete representations of SU (2) H ⊃ G H ≡ Q 2N . The technical details depend on the G H breaking scale. I shall consider: A 10 GeV, B 10 TeV, C 10 16 GeV. Flavors and Horizontal Symmetries 5 3.1</trash>

					<figDesc>. Λ H ∼ 10GeV (&gt; m b )</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Assignments are arranged around the top quark such that: t mass is a G H singlet. b, τ masses break G H →</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G ′ . c mass breaks G ′ → G ′′ s, µ masses break G ′′ → G ′′′</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>At the same time, I exclude, or minimize, additional fermions and demand full anomaly cancellation. It is possible to show 4) that of all the 93 finite groups with g ≤ 31, only the dicyclic groups remain as candidates for G H . The simplest model uses Q 6 . Recall that:</p>

				<p><formula>1 → 1 2 → 2 (1) 3 → 1 ′ + 2 (2)</formula></p>

				<p>so for the five triples the only possible assignments are:</p>

				<p><formula>1 + 1 = 1 1 ′ + 2 (2) 1 + 2 (1)</formula></p>

				<p>For the Q 6 model, the assignments are:</p>

				<p><formula>t b L 1 t R 1 b R 1 ′ ν τ τ L 1 τ R 1 ′ c s L u d L            2 S c R 1 u R 1 s R d R 2 ν µ µ L ν e e L            2 S µ R e R      2</formula></p>

				<p>The mass matrix textures are:</p>

				<p><formula>U = &lt; 2 S &gt; &lt; 2 S &gt; &lt; 1 &gt; &lt; 1 &gt; and: D = L = &lt; 1 ′′ + 1 ′′′ + 2 S &gt; &lt; 2 S &gt; &lt; 2 &gt; &lt; 1 ′ &gt; P. H. Frampton</formula></p>

				<p>The symmetry-breaking steps involve a VEV to a Q 6 singlet ⇒ t mass; then a VEV to a 1 ′ breaks Q 6 to Z 6 , providing b, τ masses. A (1, 2 (1) )V EV gives the c mass and finally a (2, 1 ′′ + 1 ′′′ ) VEV gives the s, µ masses. Some remarks on the Q 6 model: (i) The (SU (2) H ) 2 Y anomaly cancellation requires certain extra singlets predicted to lie between 50GeV and 200GeV. (ii) The hierarchy of Yukawa couplings has been removed: they now all lie between 0.1 and 1.0. (iii) It provides a first step to understanding why the top quark mass is so different from the other quark masses.</p>

			<div>
				<head>3.2.</head>

				<p>Breaking of G H at ≥ 1T eV Here we shall use non-abelian horizontal symmetry in connection with derivation of an ansatz for the texture zeros in the quark mass matrices. The horizontal symmetry will be again Q 2N , but now the Froggatt-Nielsen mechanism 7) becomes an essential part of mass generation. This means that additional vector-like pairs of fermions, at high scale, are present -and these must likewise be assigned to representations of G H .</p>

				<p>The quark assignments are:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>t b L c s L            2 (2) t R c R 2 (2) b R s R 2 (1) u d L 1 ′ u R 1 ′ d R 1 The lepton doublets are correspondingly (2 (1) + 1) and the singlets (2 (2) + 1 ′ ).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This assignment is completely anomaly-free. To consider the quark masses I put the SM Higgs doublet in to down quarks. Their VEVs give masses only to the third family. The other elements of the up-quark mass matrix M U arise from Froggatt- Nielsen graphs shown in Fig. 1. There are second graphs, not shown in Fig.1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>, for (M U ) 32 , (M U ) 31 . Similar graphs for (M D ) lead to the textures:</figDesc>
					<trash>M U =    0 0 λ 4 0 λ 4 λ 2 λ 4 λ 2 1    (3 . 1) M D =    0 λ 4 0 λ 4 λ 3 0 0 0 1    (3 . 2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, as before, λ ≃ sinθ C . The expansion parameter is also identified with the ratios:</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Flavors and Horizontal Symmetries</head>

				<p>λ =&lt; S i &gt; /M odd λ 2 =&lt; S i &gt; /M even (3 . 3) where the &quot; odd &quot; Q 6 doublets occur in the SU (2) H spinor representions ; the &quot; even &quot; in the vector ones.</p>

				<p>Another symmetric texture (the only other attainable one with five zeros) is:</p>

				<p><formula>M U =    0 λ 6 0 λ 6 λ 4 λ 2 0 λ 2 1    (3 . 4) M D =    0 λ 4 0 λ 4 λ 3 0 0 0 1    (3 . 5)</formula></p>

				<p>Three other phenomenologically-viable textures 8) which are symmetric with five zeros are not attainable and hence disfavored.</p>

				<p>The postulation of zeros in the mass matrices reduces the number of free parameters in the low energy theory. This now has a dual description in terms of a horizontal symmetry Q 2N ⊂ SU (2) H .</p>

				<p>This SU (2) H could arise from a GUT group or directly from a superstring. My main point is that derivation of the values of the masses in a putative theory of everything may likely involve a horizontal symmetry, probably gauged, as an important intermediate step. The two simple cases given above illustrate how this can happen. 3.3. G H Breaking ≥ M GU T Again the Froggatt-Nielsen mechanism is used, invoking a spectrum of superheavy fermions in vector-like pairs.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The symmetry group 6) is SU (5) × SU (5) × SU (2) H The SU (2) H is broken to Q 12 at M(SU(2)) and the SU (5) × SU (5) is broken to a diagonal SU (5) at M GU T . Supersymmetry is broken near the weak scake. The light, heavy and superheavy fermion contents are in the following list of chiral SU (5) × SU (5) supermultiplets. The third entry denotes the content under</figDesc>
					<trash>S(2) H → Q 12 . (10, 1, 1 → 1(T )) (10, 1, 4 → 2 1 + 2 3 ) (10, 1, 7 → 1 ′ + 2 2 + 2 4 + 2 6 ) (10, 1, 4 → 2 1 + 2 3 ) (10, 1, 7 → 1 ′ + 2 2 + 2 4 + 2 6 ) P. H. Frampton (5, 1, 3 → 1 ′ + 2 2 ) (5, 1, 6 → 2 1 + 2 3 + 2 5 (H d /b)) (5, 1, 1(H u )) (5, 1, 3 → 1 ′ + 2 2 ) (5, 1, 4 → 2 1 + 2 3 ) (1, 10, 1) (1, 10, 2 → 2 1 (Q)) (1, 10, 1) (1, 5, 2 → 2 1 (D))</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This list is seen to be relatively short when one realizes that it includes all the vector-like F-N superheavy fermions and the light chiral fermions.</p>

				<p>The effective theory at the weak scale contains only the fermions of the standard model transforming as follows: (u, d) L , (c, s) L as Q(2 1 ); (t, b) L as T(1); u R , c R as U (2 1 ); d R , s R as D(2 1 ); t R as T(1); b R as H d /b(2 5 ). This gives supersymmetry without R-parity. b − τ /H d are in a horizontal doublet incompatible with the usual R-parity, but matter parity arises here from group properties of G H . The &quot; µ problem &quot; (5.5 term at tree level) is also solved here by G H .</p>

				<p>The mass matrix textures are:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M U =    λ 8 λ 6 0 λ 6 λ 4 0 0 0 1    (3 . 6) M D =    0 λ 5 λ 5 λ 4 λ 3 λ 3 0 λ 3 1    (3 . 7)</trash>

					<figDesc>This is a phenomenologicaly viable SusyGUT for the low energy parameters.</figDesc>
					<trash>Flavors and Horizontal Symmetries 9 §4. Shadow E ′</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="8">Sector</head>

				<p>For the heterotic string, the E 8 × E ′ 8 becomes on Calabi-Yau compactification typically E 6 × E ′ 8 and the E 6 can become SU (3) 3 , for example. In the visible sector one then has unification at M GU T ∼ 2 × 10 16 GeV with α</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>−1</head>

				<p>GU T ∼ 25.</p>

				<p>The SU (3) 3 couplings have β = 0 and consistency dictates an M string = 3.5 × 10 17 GeV . Bridging across to the shadow sector one can choose an SU (N ) gauge subgroup of E ′ 8 such that α N becomes O(1) at a scale where a gluino condensate may break supersymmetry. This suggests e.g. SU (5) × SU (4) × U (1). It is possible that the shadow photino can act as cosmological dark matter 9) . §5. Summary</p>

				<p>The flavor questions for fermion mass and mixing hierarchies may require gauged horizontal symmetries and the above examples illustrate how the dicyclic groups are well-suited. The covering SU (2) H is gauged for consistency. The cases I have described show how this can happen and how it can give phenomenologically acceptable mass matrices and mixings.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P. H. Frampton (a): (M u ) 32 ✲ × ✛ × ✛ t L H u U 6 2 8 c R (b): (M u ) 22 ✲ × ✛ × ✛ c L H u U 6 2 8 c R ✲ × 2 8 Q 10 (c): (M u ) 13 ✲ × ✛ × ✛ × ✛ t L H u U 6 2 8 u R U 14 2 14 Fig. 1</trash>

					<figDesc>. Froggatt-Nielsen tree graphs for Mu. (The symmetric counterparts, (Mu)23, another graph for (Mu)22 and (Mu)31 are not shown)</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Ibanez</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pakvasa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Sugawara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>T. Brown, N. Deshpande, S. Pakvasa and H. Sugawara, ibid 141B</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="95" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Brown</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pakvasa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Sugawara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Yamanaka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">255</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Frampton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Kephart</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D51</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Frampton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Kephart</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Mod. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. press</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Frampton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C W</forename>
				<surname>Kong</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">781</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">UNC-Chapel Hill Report IFP-715-UNC (in prepara- tion)</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Frampton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C W</forename>
				<surname>Kong</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Froggatt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Nielsen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">277</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ramond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Roberts</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">406</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">19</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Frampton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Kephart</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Wright</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
