<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Construction of Solutions to Reflection Equations for Interaction-Round-a-Face Models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Roger</forename>
								<forename type="middle">E</forename>
								<surname>Behrend</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Paul</forename>
								<forename type="middle">A</forename>
								<surname>Pearce</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Mathematics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Physikalische Institut</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Melbourne Parkville</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>3052</postCode>
									<region>Victoria</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitätBonn</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Nußallee12</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-53115</postCode>
									<settlement>Bonn</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">OnleavefromUniversityofMelbourne</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Construction of Solutions to Reflection Equations for Interaction-Round-a-Face Models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9512218v1 29 Dec 1995</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a procedure in which known solutions to reflection equations for interaction-round-a-face lattice models are used to construct new solutions. The procedure is particularly well-suited to models which have a known fusion hierarchy and which are based on graphs containing a node of valency 1. Among such models are the Andrews-Baxter-Forrester models, for which we construct reflection equation solutions for fixed and free boundary conditions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="2">. General Procedure</head>

				<p>We are considering an IRF model on a square lattice, and we assume that there are restrictions on the spins allowed on any adjacent lattice sites, as specified by an adjacency matrix A ab = 0 , spins a and b may not be adjacent 1 , spins a and b may be adjacent</p>

				<p>For such models, we associate a Boltzmann weight with each set of spins a, b, c, d that are allowed to be adjacent around a face—ie for which A ab A bc A cd A da = 1. These weights are</p>

				<p><formula>denoted W d c a b u = d d d d a b c d u (2.1)</formula></p>

				<p>where u is the spectral parameter.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.1">Fixed Boundary Conditions</head>

				<p>We now consider a boundary containing a fixed spin ¯ a.</p>

				<p>In this case we associate a boundary weight with each spin a which is allowed to be adjacent to ¯ a</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>¯ B ¯ a ( a | u ) = a ¯ a u (2.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It can be shown [1] that families of commuting transfer matrices can be obtained if the boundary weights (2.2), together with the face weights (2.1), satisfy the fixed-boundary reflection equations for ¯ a. There is one such equation for each set of spins b, c, d satisfying A ¯ ab A bc A cd A d¯ a = 1,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f W c f b ¯ a u−v W d ¯ a c f µ−u−v ¯ B ¯ a ( f | u ) ¯ B ¯ a ( d | v ) = f W ¯ a f d c u−v W f ¯ a c b µ−u−v ¯ B ¯ a ( f | u ) ¯ B ¯ a ( b | v ) (2.3) d d d d d d d d d u v u−v µ−u−v ¯ a ¯ a ¯ a ¯ a b c d f • = d d d d d d d d d d d d v u u−v µ−u−v ¯ a ¯ a ¯ a ¯ a b c d f •</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, µ is an arbitrary fixed parameter and the sums are over all spins f which are allowed to be adjacent to ¯ a. We note that if the face weights satisfy the symmetry</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>W d c a b u = W b c a d u (2.4) then (2.3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is automatically satisfied whenever b = d. Furthermore, in the case in which there is only one spin a allowed to be adjacent to ¯ a—ie ¯ a has a valency of 1—we must have b = d = f = a in (2.3) implying that the equation is always satisfied and that the single boundary weight ¯ B ¯ a ( a | u ) may be assigned to any function of u.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Free Boundary Conditions</head>

				<p>For the case of free, or at least quasi-free, boundary conditions, we associate a boundary weight with each set of spins a, b, c satisfying A ab A bc =</p>

				<p><formula>1, B b c a u = d d a b c u (2.5)</formula></p>

				<p>In this case, families of commuting transfer matrices can be obtained if the boundary weights (2.5), together with the face weights (2.1), satisfy the free-boundary reflection equations . There is one such equation for each set of spins a, b, c, d, e satisfying A ab A bc A cd A de =</p>

				<p><formula>1, f g W c f b a u−v W d g c f µ−u−v B f g a u B d e g v = f g W e f d c u−v W f g c b µ−u−v B f e g u B b g a v (2.6) d d d d d d d d d d d d u v u−v µ−u−v e d c b a a f g • • = d d d d d d d d d d d d d d v u µ−u−v u−v e e d c b a f g • •</formula></p>

				<p>Here, the sum on the left side is over all spins f , g satisfying A af A cf A f g A gd = 1 and that on the right side is over all spins f , g satisfying A ef A cf A f g A gb = 1.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.3">Construction of New Boundary Weights</head>

				<p>Our construction of new boundary weights requires that there exist an auxiliary adjacency matrix ¯ A and, for each set of spins a, b, c, d satisfying ¯</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A ab A bc ¯ A cd A da = 1, an auxiliary face weight W d c a b u = a b c d u (2.7)</trash>

					<figDesc>These weights, together with the fundamental face weights (2.1), are assumed to satisfy the generalised Yang-Baxter equations. There is one such equation for each set of spins a, b, c, d, e, f satisfying A ab ¯ A bc A cd A de ¯ A ef A f a</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>= 1, g W f g a b u−v W g d b c u W f e g d v = g W a g b c v W f e a g u W e d g c u−v (2.8) d d d d d d u−v u v a b b c d e f f g • = d d d d d d u−v v u a b c c d e e f g •</formula></p>

				<p>Here, the sum on the left side is over all spins g satisfying A bg A f g ¯ A gd = 1 and that on the right side is over all spins g satisfying ¯ A ag A gc A ge = 1.</p>

				<p>In practice, the auxiliary face weights can generally be constructed using fusion with an appropriate row of fundamental face weights. Our construction of new boundary weights takes two forms. In the first form, we obtain new weights for a boundary with fixed spin ¯ a using known weights for a boundary with fixed spin ¯ b, where we assume that, with respect to ¯ A, ¯ a is the only spin allowed to be adjacent to ¯ b. The new weights depend on an arbitrary parameter ¯ χ and, for each spin a allowed to be adjacent to ¯ a, are defined as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>¯ B ′ ¯ a ( a | u ) = b W a b ¯ a ¯ b u+ ¯ χ W ¯ a ¯ b a b µ−u+ ¯ χ ¯ B¯ b ( b | u ) (2.9) = u u+ ¯ χ µ−u+ ¯ χ a ¯ b ¯ b ¯ b ¯ a ¯ a b •</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the sum is over all spins b satisfying ¯ A ab A b ¯ b = 1. We note that we suppress the dependence of these weights on the the spin ¯ b and the parameter ¯ χ. It is straightforward to show that the new weights (2.9) satisfy the fixed boundary reflection equations for ¯ a, using the assumptions that the known weights satisfy the fixed boundary reflection equations for ¯ b, that the auxiliary face weights satisfy (2.8), and that ¯ b has valency 1 with respect to ¯ A.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In the second form of our construction of new boundary weights, we obtain certain weights for free boundary conditions using known weights for a boundary with fixed spin ¯ a. The new weights depend on an arbitrary parameter χ and, for each set of spins a, b, c satisfying ¯ A ¯ aa A ab A bc ¯ A c¯ a = 1, are defined as</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>B b c a u = d W b d a ¯ a u+χ W c ¯ a b d µ−u+χ ¯ B ¯ a ( d | u ) (2.10) = u u+χ µ−u+χ b ¯ a ¯ a ¯ a a c d</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>• where the sum is over all spins d satisfying ¯ A bd A d¯ a = 1. Again we suppress the dependence of these weights on the spin ¯ a and the parameter χ. The new weights (2.10) satisfy the free boundary reflection equations for each set of spins a, b, c, d, e in (2.6) which satisfy ¯ A ¯ aa A ab A bc A cd A de ¯ A e¯ a = 1 . This follows straightforwardly from the assumptions that the known weights satisfy the fixed boundary reflection equations for ¯ a, and that the auxiliary face weights satisfy (2.8).</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">. ABF Models</head>

				<p>We now consider the Andrews-Baxter-Forrester (ABF) models [9]. There is one such model for each integer L ≥ 3, with the spins a in this model taking the values</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a ∈ {1, 2, . . . , L} (3.1)</trash>

					<figDesc>The adjacency matrix is defined by the condition that A ab = 1 if and only if</figDesc>
					<trash>|a − b| = 1 (3.2) There is a fixed crossing parameter λ = π L + 1 (3.3) and the face weights are given by W a±1 a a a∓1 u = θ(λ−u) θ(λ) W a a±1 a∓1 a u = θ((a−1)λ) θ((a+1)λ) θ(aλ) 2 θ(u) θ(λ) (3.4) W a a±1 a±1 a u = θ(aλ±u) θ(aλ)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where θ is the standard elliptic theta-1 function of fixed nome.</p>

				<p>For these models, an auxiliary adjacency matrix and auxiliary face weights which satisfy (2.8) are provided by the level n fused adjacency matrix and the n by 1 fused face weights [10, 11, 12] ¯</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A = A n , W = W n,1 (3.5) where n ∈ {0, 1, . . . , L−1} (3.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The level n fused adjacency matrix is defined by the condition that A n ab = 1 if and only if a − b ∈ {−n, −n+2, .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. . , n−2, n} (3.7) and a + b ∈ {n+2, n+4, . . . , 2L−n−2, 2L−n} (3.8)</trash>

					<figDesc>We note that A 1 = A. The n by 1 fused face weights are defined in terms of rows of n fundamental face weights (3.4) and, after appropriate normalisation and symmetrisation, are given by</figDesc>
					<trash>W n,1 d c a b u = (3.9)                    ǫ b ǫ d θ( a+b∓n 2 λ) θ( c+d±n 2 λ) θ(bλ) θ(dλ) θ(u− n±(a−b) 2 λ) θ(λ) ; c = b±1, d = a±1 ǫ b ǫ d θ( n∓(a−b) 2 λ) θ( n±(d−c) 2 λ) θ(bλ) θ(dλ) θ( a+b±n 2 λ∓u) θ(λ) ; c = b∓1, d = a±1 where ǫ a are factors whose required properties are (ǫ a ) 2 = 1 , ǫ a ǫ a+2 = −1 (3.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We note that the fused weights (3.9) reduce to (3.4) for n = 1.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.1">Weights for Fixed Boundary Conditions</head>

				<p>Since, for the ABF models, the spin 1 has valency 1 with respect to A, and the face weights satisfy the symmetry (2.4), the boundary weight ¯ B 1 ( 2 | u ) can be set to an arbitrary function of u. Furthermore, it follows from (3.7) and (3.8) that the spin 1 has valency 1 with respect to any A ¯ a−1 , the only allowed neighbour being the spin ¯ a. It is therefore possible to construct new weights for a boundary with fixed spin ¯ a using an arbitrary weight for a boundary with fixed spin 1. Accordingly, we apply (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.9) with ¯ A = A ¯ a−1 , W = W ¯ a−1,1 , ¯ b = 1, µ = λ, ¯ χ = −λ− ¯ ξ and ¯ B 1 ( 2 | u ) = ǫ 1 ǫ 2 ǫ ¯ a ǫ ¯ a−1 θ(2λ)/θ(λ) g(u), which gives ¯ B ′ ¯ a ( ¯ a±1 | u ) = g(u) θ((¯ a±1)λ) θ(¯ aλ) θ(u± ¯ ξ) θ(u∓¯ aλ∓ ¯ ξ) θ(λ) 2 (3.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ¯ ξ is an arbitrary constant and g is an arbitrary function.</p>

				<p>It can be seen that these weights exactly match those obtained in [1] by directly solving the reflection equations.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.2">Weights for Free Boundary Conditions</head>

				<p>We now consider the construction of ABF weights for free boundary conditions using (2.10) together with (3.5) and (3.11). We shall associate with any ABF weight B b c a u either odd or even parity, according to the parity of b. Due to (3.2), each free boundary reflection equation (2.6) contains boundary weights all with the same parity. Similarly, due to (3.7) and (3.8), (2.10) generates boundary weights all with the same parity. The requirement in (2.10) that we have A n a¯ a A n c¯ a = 1 also implies that, in general, there might not be a weight B b c a u generated for each b of the appropriate parity. However, by examining (3.7) and (3.8), we find that the unique values</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n =    L−1 2 , L odd L 2 , L even ¯ a = n , odd weights n + 1 , even weights (3.12)</trash>

					<figDesc>do generate a full set of boundary weights of a given parity. We now apply (2.10) with µ = λ, χ = ξ +</figDesc>
					<trash>n−1 2 λ, g(u) → ǫ ¯ a ǫ ¯ a−1 g(u) and ¯ ξ → ¯ ξ − ¯ a 2 λ, which gives B a a±1 a∓1 u = g(u) θ(aλ) θ((a±1)λ) × (3.13) θ( a+¯ a−n−1 2 λ) θ( a+¯ a+n+1 2 λ) θ( n+1−a+¯ a 2 λ) θ( n+1+a−¯ a 2 λ) θ(aλ) 2 θ(λ) 2 θ( a 2 λ− ¯ ξ∓ξ) θ( a 2 λ+ ¯ ξ∓ξ) θ(λ) 2 θ(2u) θ(λ) B a a±1 a±1 u = g(u) θ(aλ) θ((a±1)λ) × (3.14) θ( n+1−a+¯ a 2 λ) θ( n+1+a−¯ a 2 λ) θ(u± a+¯ a 2 λ−ξ) θ(u± a+¯ a 2 λ+ξ) θ(u∓ ¯ a 2 λ− ¯ ξ) θ(u∓ ¯ a 2 λ+ ¯ ξ) θ(aλ) θ(¯ aλ) θ(λ) 4 + θ( a+¯ a−n−1 2 λ) θ( a+¯ a+n+1 2 λ) θ(u± a−¯ a 2 λ−ξ) θ(u± a−¯ a 2 λ+ξ)θ(u± ¯ a 2 λ− ¯ ξ) θ(u± ¯ a 2 λ+ ¯ ξ) θ(aλ) θ(¯ aλ) θ(λ) 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, the two terms which led to (3.13) were combined using a standard elliptic identity, and a common factor ǫ a ǫ a−1 in (3.13) and (3.14) was eliminated since, for a given ¯ a, the allowed values of a must all have the same parity implying that this factor always produces the same sign.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">. Discussion</head>

				<p>We have presented a general procedure for obtaining boundary weights for IRF models and have applied this to the ABF models. Our method should be useful for determining classes of IRF models for which solutions of the reflection equations exist and contain arbitrary parameters. In particular, our method implies the existence of such solutions for the standard A-D-E models, since these are all based on graphs containing a node of valency 1, and have known fusion hierarchies.</p>

				<p>In future work, we plan to construct the weights for the D and E series within the standard A-D-E models, and to study further the weights obtained here for the ABF models, which form the A series. In particular, we intend to investigate the relationship between the ABF weights for free boundary conditions found using our method, and those obtained using intertwiners or by directly solving the reflection equations. We also hope to be able to show that these weights can be used to obtain genuine free boundary conditions at the isotropic point, and that the associated transfer matrices satisfy functional equations with the same form as in the case of fixed and periodic boundary conditions.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> E-mail: reb@maths.mu.oz.au 2 E-mail: pap@maths.mu.oz.au. On leave from University of Melbourne.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>PAP thanks Jean-Marie Maillard and Jean-Bernard Zuber for their kind hospitality at Paris and Saclay, where some of this work was done. PAP also thanks Vladimir Rittenberg for his kind hospitality at Bonn. This work was supported by the Australian Research Council.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preprint hep-th/9507118. Interaction- Round-a-Face Models with Fixed Boundary Conditions: The ABF Fusion Hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Behrend</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Pearce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Brien</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Stat. Phys</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>To. be published in J</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preprint hep-th/9507070. Yang-Baxter Equation and Reflection Equations in Integrable Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Kulish</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Ahn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Koo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Boundary. Yang-Baxter Equation in the RSOS Representation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">General Solution of Reflection Equation for Eight</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Fan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
				<surname>Hou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Shi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Vertex SOS Model</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4743" to="4749" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Vertex SOS Model</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preprint hep-th/9510095. Row Transfer Matrix Functional Relations for Baxter&apos;s Eight-Vertex and Six-Vertex Models with Open Boundaries via More General Reflection Matrices</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Zhou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preprint hep-th/9511008. Surface Critical Phenom- ena in Interaction-Round-a-Face Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Zhou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Batchelor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preprint hep-th/9511081. Surface Free Energies and Surface Critical Behaviour of the ABF Models with Fixed Boundaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O &apos;</forename>
				<surname>Brien</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Pearce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Behrend</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">To be published in Conference Proceedings</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Tianjin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preprint hep-th/9511090. An Ising Model in a Magnetic Field with a Boundary</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Batchelor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Fridkin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Zhou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Andrews</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Baxter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Forrester</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Stat. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Eight-Vertex SOS Model and Generalized Rogers-Ramanujan-Type Identities</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Date</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Jimbo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Miwa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Okado</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Fusion. of the Eight Vertex SOS Model</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Date</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Jimbo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Miwa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Okado</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">97. Erratum and Addendum: Fusion of the Eight Vertex SOS Model</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Date</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Jimbo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kuniba</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Miwa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Okado</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Exactly Solvable SOS Models II: Proof of the Star-Triangle Relation and Combinatorial Identities</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="122" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
