<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SOFT SUPERSYMMETRY BREAKING INDUCED BY HIGHER-DERIVATIVE SUPERGRAVITATION IN THE ELECTROWEAK STANDARD MODEL</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Ahmed</forename>
								<surname>Hindawi</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104-6396</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Burt</forename>
								<forename type="middle">A</forename>
								<surname>Ovrut</surname>
								<roleName>And</roleName>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104-6396</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Daniel</forename>
								<surname>Waldram</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104-6396</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SOFT SUPERSYMMETRY BREAKING INDUCED BY HIGHER-DERIVATIVE SUPERGRAVITATION IN THE ELECTROWEAK STANDARD MODEL</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9602075v2 29 Dec 1996</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term>0450+h</term>
					<term>0465+e</term>
					<term>1130Qc</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We show how spontaneous supersymmetry breaking in the vacuum state of higher-derivative supergravity is transmitted, as explicit soft supersymmetry-breaking terms, to the effective Lagrangian of the standard electroweak model. The general structure of the soft supersymmetry breaking terms is presented and a new scenario for understanding the gauge hierarchy problem, based on the functional form of these terms, is discussed.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>A definitive answer to the question of how supersymmetry is broken in phenomenologically relevant theories of particle physics, be they supergravitational theories or superstrings, remains elusive. One candidate for a mechanism of supersymmetry breaking is the Polonyi model and its many generalizations [1-4]. This approach requires the explicit introduction of new chiral supermultiplets, in addition to those of the standard supersymmetric electroweak model and supergravity. Furthermore, the interactions of such fields with observable matter must be of a specific form; that is, they must form a &quot; hidden &quot; sector. Why such fields should exist, and how they come to be hidden from ordinary matter, is not well understood. A second candidate for a mechanism of supersymmetry breaking is non-perturbative, using gaugino condensation in a strongly interacting sector [5, 6]. Again, this mechanism requires extra superfields in the theory, in this case strongly interacting vector multiplets, and this sector must be sufficiently hidden from observable matter. Generically, it is not well understood why such a mechanism should occur, although in superstring theories this approach seems better motivated.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we will present what we believe to be a very different mechanism for supersymmetry breaking, which seems to overcome at least some of the shortcomings of the afore-mentioned approaches. We begin by considering only the fields of the standard model and the graviton. In the usual way, we will assume that these fields are actually members of four-dimensional, N = 1 supermultiplets: chiral multiplets for quarks, leptons and Higgs fields, vector multiplets for the strong and electroweak gauge fields, and the supergravitational multiplet for the graviton. These are the only superfields we will introduce, which distinguishes our approach from those discussed above. It is traditional, when generalizing the standard supersymmetric model to include supergravity, to admit higher-dimensional interaction terms composed of products of fields suppressed by the Planck mass, but to disallow higher-derivative interactions, be they purely gravitational or involving matter. Generically, there is no justification for this. Higher-derivative terms will appear at the same order when supermatter is coupled to supergravity. It is often said that such terms may indeed be present, but are irrelevant at low momentum since they will be suppressed by powers of momenta over the Planck mass.</p>

				<p>We wish to stress that this statement is naive. The reason is the following. It is well known that, in non-supersymmetric theories, higher-derivative terms in the equations of motion correspond to new degrees of freedom, in addition to the degrees of freedom of the original theory. This situation is amplified in supersymmetric theories where higher-derivative terms not only produce new bosonic and fermionic degrees of freedom, but also cause fields that were auxiliary, and, hence, not physical, in the original theory to become propagating [7]. We want to re-emphasize at this point that one is not introducing new superfields, rather the new degrees of freedom are arising out of derivatives of fields, or auxiliary fields, that have already been introduced. In two recent papers [8, 9], we have shown that these new degrees of freedom can have non-trivial potential energies possessing multiple vacua with vanishing cosmological constant. It is essential to realize that one must first identify the vacuum structure of these new degrees of freedom, and expand around one of the vacua, before taking the low-momentum limit. While it is true that the fluctuations around the vacuum will decouple at low momenta, the effect of the vacuum itself will not. It generically couples to the usual matter fields and survives to low momentum, much as the vacuum state of a grand-unified theory determines the gauge group structure of the low-energy effective theory. It is in this sense that the above statement is naive. This understood, it is important to ask what effect a non-trivial vacuum state can have on the low-energy effective matter Lagrangian. In a previous paper, we have shown that there exist vacua of the new degrees of freedom of pure higher-derivative supergravitation that spontaneously break supersymmetry.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we will couple such theories to the supersymmetric standard model and show that, at low momentum, such a non-trivial vacuum produces soft supersymmetry-breaking terms of fundamental phenomenological importance. Indeed, this mechanism seems sufficient to properly account for supersymmetry breaking in the standard supersymmetric model. There is one further issue that we wish to touch upon before presenting our results. It is well known that higher-derivative theories tend to have at least some extra degrees of freedom whose propagation behavior is ghost-like. This seems to always be the case for matter fields [10] and is frequently the case in the gravitational sector [11-13]. A number of authors have pointed out that, at least in the context of gravity, this apparent ghost-like behavior may be illusory [14-16]. This is a complicated issue that we would like to avoid in this paper. We have shown in a recent publication [9] that there is a consistent and interesting higherderivative extension of supergravity that is, in fact, completely ghost-free. For simplicity, we will, in this paper, take this to be the higher-derivative extension of the standard model coupled to gravity. Hence, the theory discussed in this paper will be ghost-free. Why nature chooses this ghost-free extension of the standard model, or whether generic higher-derivative theories are actually consistent as well, will be left for future research.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Higher-Derivative Supergravity</head>

				<p>In this section we will consider pure supergravitation only.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ordinary N = 1 Einstein supergravity is described by the Lagrangian L = −3M 2 P d 4 θE, (2.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where E is the superdensity and M P the Planck mass. It is well known that the minimal supergravity multiplet contains the graviton e m a , the gravitino ψ m α , a complex scalar M and a real vector b m as component fields. Expressed in terms of these component fields, Lagrangian (2.1) becomes [17]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e −1 L = M 2 P − 1 2 R − 1 3 MM * + 1 3 b m b m + 1 2 ǫ klmn ¯ ψ k ¯ σ l ˜ D m ψ n − ψ k σ l ˜ D m ¯ ψ n , (2.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which describes bosonic Einstein gravitation coupled to a gravitino. The M and b m fields are non-propagating auxiliary fields which can be eliminated from the Lagrangian using their equations of motion M = 0 and b m = 0. It is important to note that it is not supersymmetry that is forcing M and b m to be auxiliary, but rather it is the explicit choice of the Lagrangian (2.1). This Lagrangian was chosen because it describes the simplest supersymmetric extension of ordinary bosonic Einstein gravitation. However, were one to change it to include, for instance, higher-derivative gravitational terms, then it is no longer necessary that M and b m be auxiliary fields. That is, they might begin to propagate and become physical. This is indeed the case, as was first noted at the linearized level in [7] and was established on the non-linear level in [18]. The same phenomenon in new minimal supergravity was discussed in [19, 20]. Recently [9], we constructed the most general class of ghost-free higher-derivative supergravity theories. The Lagrangian for such theories is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = −3M 2 P d 4 θEf R m , R † m , (2.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where f is an arbitrary dimensionless real function and we have chosen to normalize the scalar curvature superfield R by an arbitrary mass m. Expressed in terms of the component</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>fields, this Lagrangian becomes e −1 L = M 2 P − 1 2 (f + Mf M + M * f M * − 4MM * f M M * − 2b m b m f M M * )R − 3 4 f M M * R 2 + 3f M M * ∂ m M∂ m M * − 3f M M * (∇ m b m ) 2 + · · · , (2.4) where f M M * = ∂ 2 f /∂M∂M *</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and we have dropped all fermionic terms and all bosonic terms inessential for this discussion. We see from this expression that Lagrangian (2.3) describes the supersymmetric extension of the higher-derivative bosonic R + R 2 theory. Furthermore, we see explicitly that both the complex M field and the longitudinal part of the b m field are now propagating physical fields, as anticipated. It is well known that, in addition to the helicity-two graviton, R + R 2 bosonic gravitation contains a new propagating scalar field. Therefore, Lagrangian (2.3) contains four new bosonic scalar degrees of freedom in addition to the graviton. The fermionic superpartners of these new degrees of freedom can be identified in the higher-derivative fermionic terms that occur, but were not shown, in component Lagrangian (2.4). These new degrees of freedom must arrange themselves into two new chiral supermultiplets. Written in this higher-derivative form, the physical content of this theory is obscure. However , it can be shown [18, 9] that by performing a super-Legendre transformation, Lagrangian (2.3) can be written in an equivalent form which consists of two chiral supermultiplets, denoted by Φ and Λ, coupled to ordinary Einstein supergravity with a particular Kähler potential and superpotential. Specifically, we showed in [9] that Lagrangian (2.3) is equivalent to the Lagrangian</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = d 4 θE −3M 2 P exp − 1 3 K M 2 P + W 2R + W † 2R † , (2.5) where K = −3M 2 P ln f Φ M P , Φ † M P + Λ + Λ † M P , W = 6mΦΛ. (2.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Written in this form, it is relatively straightforward to determine the vacuum structure of the theory. Using the well-known formula for the potential energy [17], we find that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V = 12 f A M P , A * M P + B + B * M P −2 U(A, B), (2.7) where U = M 2 P |A| 2 f − 2f A A − 2f A * A * + 4f AA * |A| 2 − f −1 AA * B − M P f A A + 2M P f AA * |A| 2 2 (2.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and A and B are the lowest components of chiral superfields Φ and Λ respectively. There is typically a local minimum of the potential at A = B = 0, with vanishing cosmological constant, where supersymmetry remains unbroken. We refer to this minimum as the trivial vacuum. Generically, however, we find that such potentials have other local minima. These non-trivial vacua can be arranged to have zero cosmological constant and, rather remarkably , are found to spontaneously break supersymmetry. It must be kept in mind that we are analyzing a theory of pure higher-derivative supergravitation. This theory involves the gravity supermultiplet only; no new fundamental supermultiplets have been introduced. What these results tell us is that the extra scalar degrees of freedom in such theories can have non-trivial vacua with vanishing cosmological constant which can spontaneously break supersymmetry. There is no need for a Polonyi-type field, gaugino condensates, or any other mechanism. This result seems sufficiently important that we will give a concrete example. Let us consider a function f of the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f R m , R † m = 1 − 2 RR † m 2 + 1 9 (RR † ) 2 m 4 . (2.9)</trash>

					<figDesc>We find that the associated potential energy has precisely two local minima, each with vanishing cosmological constant. The first is the trivial minimum at A = B = 0 which does not break supersymmetry. However, we find a second minimum, actually a ring of minima with zero cosmological constant, at</figDesc>
					<trash>A = M P e iθ , B = 4 3 M P . (2.10) Computing the Kähler covariant derivatives at this vacuum, we find that D A W = 32mM P , D B W = − 15 2 e iθ mM P . (2.11) It follows that supersymmetry is spontaneously broken with strength (mM P ) 1/2 . The associated gravitino mass is found to be m 3/2 = 27 8 m. (2.12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We now proceed to determine the effect of such a non-trivial vacuum on the low-energy effective Lagrangian of the standard model.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Higher-Derivative Supergravity Coupled to Matter</head>

				<p>In this section, we will consider the matter superfields of the supersymmetric standard model and then couple these fields to higher-derivative supergravity. Since the couplings of the vector multiplets are essentially fixed by gauge invariance, we will here only consider the chiral supermultiplets. These we will generically label by Y i , suppressing all gauge indices.</p>

				<p>The supersymmetric standard model Lagrangian can be written in terms of a flat Kähler potential and a specific superpotential g(Y i ) as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L Matter = d 4 θ i Y i Y † i + d 2 θg(Y i ) + h.c. . (3.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The superpotential is trilinear in Y i except for a possible Higgs bilinear term. In the following analysis, however, we do not need to use the exact form of g. It suffices to assume that it leads to a vacuum state where all Y i either vanish, or are of the order of the electroweak scale. We will also take g = 0 without loss of generality. Since supersymmetry is not observed at low-energy, the full model must also include explicit soft supersymmetry-breaking terms. The purpose of this section is to show that, when the standard model is coupled to higher-derivative supergravity, such soft terms are induced naturally when supersymmetry is spontaneously broken in the gravitational sector.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The supergravity extension of Lagrangian (3.1) is usually taken to be L = d 4 θE −3M 2 P exp − 1 3 M −2 P i Y i Y † i + g 2R + g † 2R † . (3.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In addition to Einstein supergravitation, Lagrangian (3.2) introduces a restricted set of higher-dimensional operators suppressed by powers of M P . These operators involve products of the matter fields, but do not contain higher-derivative interactions. However, this is by no means the most general extension of Lagrangian (3.1) to the Planck scale. Generically, in addition to the Planck mass suppressed terms contained in (3.2), one can add higherderivative terms involving both matter superfields and supergravity. There is a general class of such theories, where the higher-derivative terms are associated with the supergravity chiral superfield R, which are ghost-free.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we will restrict the discussion to theories of this type. A natural ghost-free higher-derivative extension of Lagrangian (3.1) is of the</p>

				<p><formula>form L = d 4 θE −3M 2 P F R m , R † m , Y i Y † i M 2 P + g 2R + g † 2R † , (3.3)</formula></p>

				<p>where F is a dimensionless real function and m is some mass-scale which does not have to be related to the Planck mass. We will assume, for the time being, that m is less than M P by at least a few orders of magnitude. Further, we will assume that all the coefficients in the function F are of order unity, so that m and M P are the only two mass scales in the theory. Just as in the case of pure higher-derivative supergravity, we can make a super-Legendre transformation to put Lagrangian (3.3) into an equivalent second-order form. The transformed theory describes Einstein supergravity coupled to matter superfields Y i plus two extra chiral supermultiplets, Φ and Λ. The superfields Φ and Λ represent the new degrees of freedom arising from the higher-derivative supergravitational terms. Making the super- Legendre transformation gives the following Kähler potential and superpotential</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>K = −3M 2 P ln F Φ M P , Φ † M P , Y i Y † i M 2 P + Λ + Λ † M P , W = 6mΦΛ + g(Y i ). (3.4)</trash>

					<figDesc>The associated scalar potential energy is then found to be</figDesc>
					<trash>V = 12e 2K/3M 2 P (U 1 + U 2 + U 3 ) , (3.5) where U 1 = m 2 AA * (F − 2AF A − 2A * F A * + 4AA * F AA * ) , U 2 = − 1 2 m M P (A * g + Ag * ) − m 2 P i (F ij * ) −1 P * j , U 3 = − m 2 M 2 P det F ij * det X B − M P (AF A − 2AA * F AA * − P i (F ij * ) −1 F Aj * ) 2 , (3.6) and we define P i = AF i − 2AA * F iA * − g i 6mM P , X = F AA * F Aj * F iA * F ij * . (3.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>As in the previous section, we write A and B for the lowest components for Φ and Λ respectively, and introduce y i for the lowest component of Y i , while F A = ∂F/∂A and F i = ∂F/∂y i . It is convenient to expand the function F as</figDesc>
					<trash>F Φ M P , Φ † M P , Y i Y † i M 2 P = f Φ M P , Φ † M P + i c i Φ M P , Φ † M P Y i Y † i M 2 P + · · · (3.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and insert this into potential energy (3.5). If we ignore, for the time being, all terms associated with matter superfields Y i , then the potential energy reduces to the pure higherderivative supergravity potential for the function f given in equation (2.7) of the previous section. There we demonstrated, for a wide class of functions f , that the potential energy has a stable, local minimum with non-vanishing vacuum expectation values A and B of the order of M P . Furthermore, the cosmological constant can be chosen to be zero and, generically, supersymmetry is spontaneously broken with strength (mM P ) 1/2 . We, henceforth , assume f is chosen to have these properties. Now let us restore the matter fields Y i .</p>

				<p>We find that potential energy (3.5), although complicated, still possesses a vacuum with zero cosmological constant in which A and B are determined only by f and have the above properties. The y i fields either have y i = 0, or non-zero values of the order of the electroweak scale, depending on the choice of the superpotential g.</p>

				<p>We will now show that, at low-energy, the fluctuations around this vacuum reproduce the standard supersymmetric model described by Lagrangian (3.1) along with a specific set of soft supersymmetry-breaking terms.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we will consider the bosonic part of the Lagrangian only. We write A = A + a and B = B + b but, since y i ≪ M P , leave the y i fields unexpanded. Inserting these expressions into the Lagrangian associated with (3.4) and dropping all terms suppressed by M</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>−1</head>

				<p>P or more, we find that the low-energy theory separates into two pieces: a pure y i part and a separate hidden sector depending on fields a and b, which have masses of order m, but do not interact with the y i fields. We will, henceforth, ignore this hidden sector since, with the possible exception of cosmological consequences, it is physically irrelevant. The low-energy effective Lagrangian for the matter fields y i is found to be</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L eff = 3e 2K/3M 2 P i c i |∂ m y i | 2 − V eff (y i ), (3.9) where V eff (y i ) = V SUSY (y i ) + V Soft (y i ). (3.10) The term V SUSY is given by V SUSY (y i ) = − 1 3 e 2K/3M 2 P i |g i | 2 c i . (3.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Provided that c i &lt; 0, the kinetic energy term and V SUSY can, after appropriate rescaling of the y i fields, be written in the form of Lagrangian (3.1) with a modified superpotential g. Hence, these terms are supersymmetric. The remaining part, V Soft , of the low-energy potential is found to be</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V Soft (y i ) = i m 2 1,i |y i | 2 + m 2 g + i m 3,i y i g i + c.c. , (3.12) where m 2 1,i = 48 m 2 M 2 P AA * 2 e 2K/3M 2 P ∂ 2 c i ∂A∂A * − c −1 i ∂c i ∂A ∂c i ∂A * , m 2 = −6 m M P A * e 2K/3M 2 P , m 3,i = −2 m M P A * e 2K/3M 2 P 2 A ∂ ln c i ∂A − 1 . (3.13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Unlike the previous case, V Soft cannot be written in the form of Lagrangian (3.1) and, therefore , corresponds to genuine soft supersymmetry breaking. Expressions (3.12) and (3.13) are quite general, valid for a wide class of superpotentials g subject to the minor constraints discussed previously. They simplify somewhat if we specialize to the case in which the matter superpotential is a homogeneous polynomial of degree n. We then have i y i g i = ng. (3.14) This is the case in the R-parity invariant, supersymmetric standard model where the Higgs bilinear term is disallowed. Furthermore, since, in this model, the terms in g are trilinear, it follows that n = 3. Therefore, V Soft in (3.12) simplifies to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V Soft = i m 2 1,i |y i | 2 + i m ′ 3,i y i g i + c.c. , (3.15) where m 2 1,i = 48 m 2 M 2 P AA * 2 e 2K/3M 2 P ∂ 2 c i ∂A∂A * − c −1 i ∂c i ∂A ∂c i ∂A * , m ′ 3,i = −4 m M P e 2K/3M P AA * ∂ ln c i ∂A . (3.16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We conclude that for a wide class of theories, including the supersymmetric standard model, spontaneous supersymmetry breaking in the higher-derivative supergravity sector is transmitted to the low-energy effective Lagrangian of observable matter as a specific set of soft, explicit supersymmetry-breaking operators. This result is reminiscent of the Polonyi mechanism with a general Kähler potential [2, 3], but, unlike that mechanism, it arises from pure supergravitation and does not require the introduction of a hidden supersymmetry-breaking sector. The soft supersymmetry-breaking terms will lead, through radiative corrections, to the spontaneous breakdown of electroweak symmetry. If we assume, recalling A ≃ M P , that the c i -dependent coefficients of m or m 2 in (3.13) or (3.16) are of order unity then the scale of the electroweak symmetry breaking will be set by m. In this case, one must take m ≃ 10 2 GeV. The degree of fine-tuning required to do this is exactly the same as in the Polonyi models, and, hence, this is a completely viable approach to electroweak symmetry breaking. However, the higher-derivative supergravity theory described in this paper has a second, and quite novel, possibility for solving the hierarchy problem, in the context of the R-parity invariant, supersymmetric standard model. Note that the coefficients of the soft supersymmetry-breaking terms in (3.15) are explicit combinations of the vacuum expectation values of functions of c i . Above, we assumed that these coefficients were of order unity. This then necessitated taking m to be of the order of the electroweak scale. Note, however, that if, for some reason, these combinations are small, of the order of 10 −16 or so, then the parameter and Polonyi cosmological problems [21] are automatically solved. Very small values for the c i -dependent coefficients are not as unexpected or unnatural as they may first appear to be. For example, suppose that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c i A M P , A * M P = constant, (3.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for all values of i. It is immediately clear from (3.15) that V Soft vanishes for any value of m. This is true despite the fact that supersymmetry is broken with strength (mM P ) 1/2 in the supergravity sector. This breaking is simply not transmitted to the low-energy observable theory. Condition (3.17) is very simple and it is intriguing to speculate whether it could arise naturally as a consequence of a symmetry of the higher-derivative theory. Now suppose the functions c i are not strictly constant, but, instead, are slowly varying. It follows that V Soft no longer vanishes. However, these terms can be very small, conceivably of electroweak strength, independent of the value of m. Such slowly varying functions could arise naturally, for example, from small, perhaps non-perturbative, breaking of the symmetry that enforced condition (3.17). This mechanism opens the possibility of theories involving the Planck mass only, with the gauge hierarchy arising from the structure of the functions c i and not from the fine-tuning of the parameter m. The results of this section all involved approximations in which it was assumed that m ≪ M P . To explore this new mechanism, we will now consider the case where m = M P . 4. Coupling to Matter With m = M P</p>

				<p>We now repeat the analysis of the last section, but here we take m = M P . It follows that we can no longer drop terms proportional to m/M P . As a result, we must keep higher-order terms in the expansion of F . That is, instead of the expansion (3.8), we now consider</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F Φ M P , Φ † M P , Y i Y † i M 2 P = f Φ M P , Φ † M P + i c i Φ M P , Φ † M P Y i Y † i M 2 P + ij e ij Φ M P , Φ † M P Y i Y † i M 2 P Y j Y † j M 2 P + · · · . (4.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For simplicity, we will consider only the R-parity invariant supersymmetric standard model with no Higgs bilinear term. Exactly as in the previous section, the theory has a vacuum state where A and B take the values set by the pure higher-derivative supergravity potential energy associated with the function f , while y i are zero or of the order of the electroweak scale. Again, we assume that f is such that the vacuum spontaneously breaks supersymmetry with zero cosmological constant. However the scale of this breaking is now M P . Furthermore, the masses of the fluctuations in A and B around the vacuum are now generically also of the order of M P and, hence, they completely decouple from the low-energy effective Lagrangian. We find that the low-energy Lagrangian is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L eff = 3e 2K/3M 2 P i c i |∂ m y i | 2 − V eff (y i ), (4.2) where V eff = V SUSY (y i ) + V Soft (y i ) + V Quartic (y i ). (4.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The terms V SUSY and V Soft have exactly the same form as in the previous section, but now with m = M P . What is new here is that the potential energy also contains potentially hard supersymmetry-breaking operators of the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V Quartic (y i ) = ij λ ij |y i | 2 |y j | 2 , (4.4) where λ ij = 12 AA * e 2K/3M 2 P M 2 P 1 − 2A ∂ ln c i c j ∂A 2 e ij + 2 1 − 2A * ∂ ln c i c j ∂A * A ∂e ij ∂A + 2 1 − 2A ∂ ln c i c j ∂A A * ∂e ij ∂A * + 4AA * ∂ 2 e ij ∂A∂A * − e K/3M 2 P M 2 P c i m 2 1,j + c j m 2 1,i − e −2K/3M 2 P 48M 2 P (AA * ) 2 f AA * m 2 1,i m 2 1,j . (4.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In fact, a quartic term of this type, albeit proportional to m/M P , was present in the previous section, as it is in the Polonyi models. Since in these theories m ≪ M P , such terms are automatically suppressed and, hence, are not discussed. In the present case, however, m = M P and these quartic terms are not automatically suppressed.</p>

				<p>In this paper, it will suffice to point out that the λ ij coefficients can always be made to vanish or to be very small, for any choice of c i , by appropriately adjusting the functions e ij in equation (4.1). Once this is done, V Soft can be made to be of the order of the electroweak scale by choosing the functions c i to vary sufficiently slowly, exactly as was discussed in the previous section. To be more concrete, let us suppose that, for some reason,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c i A M P , A * M P = constant, (4.6) for all i and e ij A M P , A * M P = h ij (A/M P ) + (h ij (A/M P )) * |A/M P | , (4.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for all i and j, where h ij are arbitrary functions of A. Putting these expressions into (4.5) immediately yields λ ij = 0, (4.8) for all i and j. Therefore,the quartic terms exactly vanish. Furthermore, since c i = constant, we also have V Soft = 0. In this case then, despite the fact that supersymmetry is spontaneously broken at order M P in the supergravity sector, none of this breaking is transmitted to the low-energy effective Lagrangian. If the conditions (4.6) and (4.7) are now slightly altered, then the quartic terms will remain suppressed whereas an acceptable gauge hierarchy will be generated by the non-vanishing but small V Soft terms. Conditions (4.6) and (4.7) are relatively simple and could arise naturally as the consequence of a symmetry of the higher-derivative theory. Small, perhaps non-perturbative, breaking of these symmetries would then give rise to the observed gauge hierarchy. This intriguing possibility will be discussed elsewhere [22]. We want to emphasize again that since, in these theories, both the gravitino and the supersymmetry-breaking scalar field masses are of order M P , the gravitino and Polonyi cosmological problems [21] are solved. Furthermore, since the new degrees of freedom associated with higher-derivative supergravitation have masses of order M P , this scenario could well arise within the context of superstrings [23]. Finally it is worth noting that the Lagrangian (3.3) is not the most general form of a ghost-free higher-derivative theory of supergravity coupled to matter. In general, one would not separate off the superpotential term g/2R but, rather, include it in the function F , so that F becomes a function of Y i and Y</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>† i separately, giving L = −3M 2 P d 4 θEF (R, R † , Y i , Y † i ). (4.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As we will describe elsewhere [22], extending the analysis of this paper to the general case leads to essentially the same results, with only some minor modifications to the form of the low-energy effective theory.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">Published in Physics Letters B 381 (1996), 154–162.</note>

			<note place="foot">m can be chosen to be large. Thus, although the supersymmetry breaking in the matter sector is of the order of the electroweak scale, the gravitino mass and the masses of the hidden sector fields would be, generically, large. Consequently, in this case the so-called gravitino</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>This work was supported in part by DOE Grant No. DE-FG02-95ER40893 and NATO Grand No. CRG-940784.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Poloyni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Budapest</forename>
				<surname>Preprint</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
			<biblScope unit="page">93</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of the supersymmetry breaking induced by N = 1 supergravity theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Soni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Weldon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supergravity as a messegener of supersymmetry breaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Hall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Lykken</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2359" to="2378" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nilles, Supersymmetry, supergravity and particle physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Breakdown of local supersymmetry through gauge fermion condensates</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Girardello</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Nilles</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="457" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-perturbative aspects in supersym- metric gauge theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Amati</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Konishi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Meurice</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Rossi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Veneziano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">162</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="248" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poincaré and conformal supergravity models with closed algebras</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Grisaru</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Van Nieuwenhuizen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="430" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-dimensional higher-derivative supergravity and a new mechanism for supersymmetry breaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hindawi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Waldram</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">471</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Four-dimensional higher-derivative supergravity and spon- taneous supersymmetry breaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hindawi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Waldram</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">476</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="199" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On field theories with non-localized action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pais</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Uhlenbeck</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Classical gravity with higher derivatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Stelle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Gen. Rel. and Grav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consistent spin-two coupling and quadratic gravitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hindawi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Waldram</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5583" to="5596" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-trivial vacua in higher-derivative gravitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hindawi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Waldram</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5597" to="5608" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Renormalizability and asymptotic freedom in quantum gravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Tomboulis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How&apos;s afraid of (higher-derivative) ghosts?, Quantum Field Theory and Quantum Statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Hawking</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>I. A. Batalin, C. S. Isham, and G. A. Vilkovisky</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="139" />
			<pubPlace>Adam Hilger, Bristol</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exact relation between Einstein and qudratic quantum gravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Tomboulis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9601082</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>UCLA/95</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supersymmetry and supergravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wess</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bagger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd. ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Higher derivative supergravity is equivalent to standard supergravity coupled to matter</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cecotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">190</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New minimal higher derivative supergravity coupled to matter</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Cecotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Porrati</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Sabharwal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="306" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lorentz and U (1) Chern-Simons terms in new minimal supergravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S. Kalyana</forename>
				<surname>Rama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="254" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cosmological problems for the Polonyi potential</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Coughlan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fischler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Kolb</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Raby</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hindawi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Waldram</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Foerger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ovrut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Theisen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Waldram</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Higher derivative gravity in string theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="512" to="520" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
