<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Exact Computations in the Burgers Problem</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1996-09-09">September 9, 1996</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Victor</forename>
								<surname>Gurarie</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Exact Computations in the Burgers Problem</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1996-09-09">September 9, 1996</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9606089v2 9 Sep 1996</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We complete the program outlined in the paper of the author with A. Migdal and sum up exactly all the fluctuations around the instanton solution of the randomly large scale driven Burgers equation. We choose the force correlation function κ to be exactly quadratic function of the coordinate difference. The resulting probability distribution satisfy the differential equation proposed by Polyakov without an anomaly term. The result shows that unless the anomaly term is indeed absent it must come from other possible instanton solutions, and not from the fluctuations. In paper [1] we computed the probability distribution P (δu, r) of observing the velocity difference δu at a distance r for the randomly large scale driven Burgers equation in the WKB approximation. The results obtained there coincided with the one obtained earlier in [2]. Naturally, we were able to derive the probability distribution only for δu ≫ 0, the so-called &quot; right tail &quot; of P. We found P (δu, r) ≈ exp</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>In paper [1] we computed the probability distribution P (δu, r) of observing the velocity difference δu at a distance r for the randomly large scale driven Burgers equation in the WKB approximation. The results obtained there coincided with the one obtained earlier in [2]. Naturally, we were able to derive the probability distribution only for δu ≫ 0, the so-called &quot; right tail &quot; of P . We found</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P (δu, r) ≈ exp − u 3 r 3 (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>At the same time, the left tail, conjectured in [2] to be</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P (δu, r) ≈ r 3 2 |δu| 5 2 , − u 2 ≪ δu ≪ 0 (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>remained to be computed.</p>

				<p>To compute the left tail, we have to go beyond the leading instanton approximation. In this letter we show how to sum up all the fluctuations around the instanton found in [1] in an exact way. We find that the effect of the fluctuations around the instanton is equivalent to a simple quantum mechanics (found previously in [2]) and therefore the summation is reduced to much simpler problem of solving that quantum mechanics.</p>

				<p>As was discussed in [1] the randomly driven Burgers equation is equivalent to the field theory with the action</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = −ı µ(u t + uu x − νu xx ) + 1 2 dxdydt µ(x, t)κ(x − y)µ(y, t) (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with coordinates u(x) and momenta µ(x), the probability distribution of observing the velocity profile u(x) being the wave function in the coordinate representation for (3). In [1] the wave function in the momentum representation was constructed in the WKB, or instanton, approximation. Long range force-force correlation was considered,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f (x, t)f (y, t ′ ) = δ(t − t ′ )κ(x − y) (4) κ is assumed to be a slow varying even function of x which behaves as κ(x) ≈ κ(0) − κ 0 2 x 2 , |x| ≪ κ(0) κ 0 ≡ L (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and quickly turns into zero when |x| ≫ L. While only special wave functions in the momentum representation were considered, let us for completeness give a more general instanton solution. It is rather easy to generalize the instanton found in [1] slightly to see that any correlation function exp ( dxλ(x)u(x)) can be found as long as dxλ(x) = 0. The velocity retains its linear profile and the answer is just</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 exp dxλ(x)u(x) = exp √ 2κ 0 3 dxxλ(x) 3 2 , dxxλ(x) ≫ 0 (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The support of λ(x) must lie within the ±L interval.</p>

				<p>The natural thing to do now would be to consider the fluctuations around the instanton solution, thus computing the corrections to the answer (6). That was the program outlined in [1].</p>

				<p>In principle, the next order correction to (6) is given by the determinant of the operator we derive by expanding the action (3) around the instanton solution. In practice, to compute the determinant directly would be rather inconvenient. So we take a slightly different approach suggested in [1]. Instead of computing the quantity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 Z[λ 0 λ(x)] = exp dxλ 0 λ(x)u(x) (7) we introduce F = d dλ 0 log Z[λ 0 λ(x)] (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This quantity, as was shown in [1], is easy to expand around the instanton solution.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>We choose u = u inst + ˜ u (9) µ = µ inst + ˜ µ u inst and µ inst being the instanton solution, and find F = dxλ(x)u inst (x) + dxλ(x) D˜D µ ˜ u(x) exp − ˜ S D˜D µ exp − ˜ S (10) The actioñ S is the expansion of the action (3), ˜ S = −ı µ(˜ u t − ν ˜ u xx ) + 1 2 dxdydt µ(x, t)κ(x − y)˜ µ(y, t) + (11) +ı µ x ∂ ∂x (˜ uu inst ) − ı µ inst u ˜ u x − ı ˜ µ˜ u x</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The last term of (11) is the interaction. We will refer to the action without the interaction term as S 0 .</p>

				<p>The next step is to define the Green&apos;s functions of small fluctuations around the instanton. These are the Green&apos;s function of the free field theory provided for us by S 0 . For example, if we define</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G(x, t; x ′ , t ′ ) = ı ˜ µ(x, t)˜ u(x ′ , t ′ ) 0 (12) N(x, t; x ′ , t ′ ) = ˜ u(x, t)˜ u(x ′ , t ′ ) 0 M(x, t; x ′ , t ′ ) = −˜ µ(x ′ , t ′ ) 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the brackets 0 signifying the fact that we define these functions with the action S 0 . We can easily find the equations these Green&apos;s functions satisfy, for instance</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N t + ∂ ∂x (u inst N) − νN xx = − dy κ(x − y) G(y, t; x ′ , t ′ ) (13) G t + u inst ∂G ∂x + νG xx = −ı ∂µ inst ∂x N + δ(x − x ′ )δ(t − t ′ )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We could try to solve these equations, find the Green&apos;s functions and then start expanding (10) in powers of the interaction. The perturbation theory (complete with Feynman diagrams) we get in this way is actually a perturbation theory in powers of 1/λ. In that sense, it is much better defined than the perturbation theory we would get if we expanded the action around the zero value of the fields, as in the standard Wyld&apos;s technique (see [7]). Using the perturbation theory around the instanton we could construct F as a function of λ 0 and then we could integrate it to reconstruct the quantity Z. However, to solve the equations (13) in the straightforward way is difficult. If, for instance, we used the expansion (5) we could try to expand the function N in powers of x and x</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>′ as well, N(x, t; x ′ , t ′ ) = a(t, t ′ ) + b(t, t ′ )xx ′ + c(t, t ′ )(x 2 + x ′ 2 ) (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and try to find the functions a, b and c. This approach would not work as a and c will diverge at t → −∞. That shows that the function N is more complicated than just a simple polynomial. That is why we are going to use a certain trick which will allow us to avoid solving (13).</p>

				<p>We begin with writing down the instanton equations of motion again,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>u t + uu x − νu xx = −ı dy κ(x − y)µ(y) (15) µ t + uµ x + νµ xx = 0 (16)</trash>

					<figDesc>These equations, since they follow from the action (3), have at least three conservation laws. The first two are the generalized momentum and energy, the corresponding components of the energy-momentum tensor,</figDesc>
					<trash>E = ı dxµ(uu x − νu xx ) − 1 2 dxdy µ(x)κ(x − y)µ(y) (17) P = dxµu x</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>They were originally found in [4]. In addition to these two, there is another conservation law following from the Galilean invariance of (3). The transformation laws are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>u(x) → u(x − vt) + v (18) µ(x) → µ(x − vt) and the corresponding conserved quantity G = dxµ − tP (19)</trash>

					<figDesc>If the generalized momenum P is zero (and it will be zero for all the solutions of (15) and (16) which fall to zero at t → −∞), then even the quantity ˜ G = dxµ (20) is conserved and zero. The quantity G can be shown to be a canonical momentum conjugate to the constant component of the velocity field. It has an evident meaning of the center of mass of Burgers fluid (moving with the velocity given by the momentum P ). It is important to note that the Galilean symmetry is, in fact, spontaneously broken since</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>u 2 = const (21)</formula></p>

				<p>as was pointed out in [2].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Spontaneous symmetry breaking is, as always, due to the boundary conditions in path integral. The natural boundary condition is u(t = −∞) = 0. If we take u(t = −∞) = v, we obtain another ground state of the system which can be taken to the first one by the symmetry transformation (18). By the way, the instanton found in [1]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>satisfied the boundary condition u(t = −∞) = 0 and therefore it was not invariant under (18); by applying (18) to it we could construct other instantons. We did not need to sum over all those instantons, though, because the symmetry is broken. Fortunately, this spontaneous symmetry breaking does not prevent us from exploring the consequences of the Galilean symmetry.</p>

				<p>We saw that the Galilean symmetry constraints the momentum conjugate to the constant component of the velocity which was the culprit of the unstability in the Green&apos;s functions (compare with (14)). Could we find a way to constraint the integral over the momentum dxµ not only on classical solutions, but also in all the fluctuations? It turns out there is such a way. Following [4], we consider a slight modification of (18) allowing v to depend on time. This is no longer a symmetry of the action (3). Under the proposed transformation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>u(x) → u (x − r(t)) + dr(t) dt (22) µ(x) → µ (x − r(t)) r(0) = 0, dr dt (t = −∞) = 0 the action (3) changes as S → S − ı dt d 2 r dt 2 dxµ (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that the transformation does not change the ground state due to the last condition in (22). It turns out that there is a procedure first proposed in [4] (for a diferent reason) which is similar to the computation of the Faddeev-Popov determinant and which allows to integrate out the degree of freedom associated with r(t). We would like to give here the outline of this procedure. We begin with inserting into the functional integral DuDµ exp(−S) the identity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Drδ u(r) − dr dt J[u] = 1 (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which serves as a definition of the quantity J[u], the Faddeev-Popov determinant. Then we shift the variables of integration according to (22) and integrate out r(t) to obtain the original path integral with the Faddeev-Popov determinant and two constraints.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>DuDµ exp(−S) J[u] δ(u(0)) δ dx d 2 µ dt 2 (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To proceed further we need to compute the Jacobian J[u]. This Jacobian is just J[u]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= det d dt − δu(r) δr (26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We have to understand that the operator whose Jacobian we are computing defines the time propagation backwards; r(0) = 0 and then we find r(t) for t &lt; 0. That allows us to compute the Jacobian using the standard methods (see, for example, [5]) to get J[u]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= exp θ(0) dt u x (0) (27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this form the formula is rather ambiguous and depends on how we define the θ-function at 0. The necessity to define the θ function at 0 is often encountered in path integral formalism. It is related to the way we discretize time in deriving (27). By discretizing time we break Galilean invariance and it is not evident that it will be restored in the limit when we take the discretization time to zero. We have to choose such discretization so as to preserve Galilean invariance in the continuous limit.</p>

				<p>Unfortunately, so far no one has managed to show by a direct computation what the correct choice for θ(0) should be. However, in the paper [6] an indirect procedure was developed which, when applied to the formalism in hand, supports the choice θ(0) = 1. Such a choice would be equivalent to taking the retarded discretization of Burgers equation and was already suggested in [4]. As we will see later, it is also consistent with the Polyakov&apos;s equation. Therefore, the Jacobian must be taken as J[u] = exp dt u x (0)</p>

			<div>
				<head>(28)</head>

				<p>Now note that the two constraints precisely eliminate two unstable modes (compare with (14)). The Jacobian (28) is in fact an effective contribution of the modes we eliminated in this way.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Now we can safely go on and find the Green&apos;s functions. The equations for the Green&apos;s function will be changed slightly to account for the constraints we have. For example, the equations (13) will become (we use u inst = σx)</figDesc>
					<trash>N t + σ ∂ ∂x (xN) − νN xx = − dy κ(x − y) G(y, t; x ′ , t ′ ) + f (t; x ′ , t ′ ) (29) G t + σx ∂G ∂x + νG xx = −ı ∂µ inst ∂x N + [δ(x − x ′ ) − δ(x)]δ(t − t ′ )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the difference of the delta functions being necessary to ensure dx G = 0 and G(x ′ = 0) = 0 and the function f (t; x ′ , t ′ ) being chosen to ensure N(x = 0) = N(x ′ = 0) = 0. It turns out that unlike (13) it is relatively easy to solve (29). We expand the function κ in Taylor series and immediately see that the function N is bilinear in x and x ′ ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N(x, t; x ′ , t ′ ) = b(t, t ′ )xx ′ (30)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the function b(t, t ′ ) coincides exactly with the correlation of fluctuations of the velocity strain. The functions a and c from (14) disappear due to the constraints. Moreover, by a direct computation one can show that the perturbative expansion for the quantity Z defined in (7) coincides term by term with a perturbative expansion of the quantity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z = exp σλ 0 dxxλ(x) (31) defined in a theory with the action S QM = dt ip(σ t + σ 2 ) − κ 0 2 p 2 + σ (32)</trash>

					<figDesc>This action follows from (25) if we formally substitute u = σ(t)x and p = dx xµ(x). The last term σ comes out of the Jacobian (28). S QM defines the motion in the potential</figDesc>
					<trash>3 V (σ) = σ 4 2κ 0 − 2σ (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is the quantum mechanics discussed in [2] without the anomaly term (in the notations of [2] b = 1 4 ).</p>

				<p>This quantum mechanics was shown in [2] not to have a stationary state and gives an asymptotics to the (nonstationary) probability distribution</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P (δu) ≈ 1 |δu| 3 , δu ≪ 0 (34)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is certainly not what is observed in the numerical experiments, [8]. And we note that the viscosity did not contribute to the calculations. This result is physically unsatisfactory. We would have expected to find the anomalous contribution to the Polyakov&apos;s equation due to nonzero viscosity. One possible explanation could be that the instanton found in [1] is not the only possible instanton solution. If this is so, then the further program is to find the instanton solutions for Burgers problem which do not use the Taylor expansion of the force correlation function. Perhaps they will contain the shock waves combined with linear profiles [3] and the fluctuations around them will produce us the anomaly term of [2] and lead to the stationary state.</p>

				<p>This problem notwithstanding, we would like to conclude with saying that we produced an answer for the Burgers problem in the region where the shock waves are absent by summing up exactly the perturbations around the instanton found in [1]. The author is grateful to A. Migdal who was a collaborator in this project at its earlier stages, and to S. Boldyrev, A. Polyakov, E. Balkovsky, V. Lebedev, G. Falkovich and I. Kolokolov for numerous and important discussions which helped to find the correct interpretation to the results obtained in this paper.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>σ 4 2κ0 − (1 + θ(0))σ showing that b = 1+θ(0) 2 . Therefore, a choice θ(0) = 1</trash>

					<figDesc>2 is tempting. Unfortunately, it has not been derived in any way known to the author so far.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The construction of [1] is equivalent to taking λ(x) = λ 0 (δ(x − x 0 /2) − δ(x + x 0 /2)) 2 We introduce an auxiliary parameter λ 0 which we can later set to 1.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We have to put p on the left from σ in the Schrö equation, see [5].</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Gurarie</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Migdal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. E</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Polyakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. E</title>
		<editor>3] A. Polyakov, unpublished [4] E. Balkovsky, G. Falkovich, I. Kolokolov and V. Lebedev</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">529506189</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6183</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9603015</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Field Theory and Critical Phenomena</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Zinn-Justin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Clarendon Press Oxford</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Gotoh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kraichnan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Fluids</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">445</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Wyld</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">143</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Yakhot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Chekhlov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. be submitted to Phys. Rev. E</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
