<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">CP VIOLATION IN W γ and Zγ PRODUCTION</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1996-09">Sep 1996 September 1996</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">S</forename>
								<surname>Dawson</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brookhaven National Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Upton</addrLine>
									<postCode>11973</postCode>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Xiao-Gang</forename>
								<surname>He</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>3052</postCode>
									<settlement>Parkville</settlement>
									<region>Vic</region>
									<country>Australia (</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">G</forename>
								<surname>Valencia</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Astronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>50011</postCode>
									<settlement>Ames</settlement>
									<region>IA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">CP VIOLATION IN W γ and Zγ PRODUCTION</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1996-09">Sep 1996 September 1996</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>* This manuscript has been authored under contract number DE-AC02-76CH00016 with the U.S. Department of Energy. Accordingly, the U.S. Government retains a non-exclusive, royalty-free license to publish or reproduce the published form of this contribution, or allow others to do so, for U.S. Government purposes.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We study the capability of a 2 TeV pp collider with an integrated luminosity of 10 f b −1 to study CP violation in the processes p¯ p → W ± γ and p¯ p → Zγ. We assume the existence of new CP violating interactions beyond the standard model which we describe with an effective Lagrangian. We find that the study of CP-odd observables would allow this machine to place bounds on CP violating anomalous couplings similar to the bounds that the same machine can place on CP conserving anomalous couplings. For example it could place the bound |ãt the 95% confidence level.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>There has been a recent effort to investigate the physics potential of a high-luminosity upgrade of the Fermilab Tevatron collider [1]. One of the directions of this study is the possibility to probe new CP violating interactions in W and Z physics. We have previously studied the issue of searching for CP violation in W and W jet production [2].</p>

				<p>In this paper we extend that study to the case of W γ and Zγ production.</p>

				<p>The motivation for this study is, of course, that the origin of CP violation remains unexplained and the question should be pursued experimentally wherever possible. The reactions p¯ p → W ± γ or Zγ have been studied at the Tevatron and will be studied in further detail at an upgraded machine where samples of a few thousand events are expected [1]. The kinematics of these reactions, unlike that of single W ± or Z production, allows triple-product CP violating correlations to exist.</p>

				<p>It is known that the standard model and minimal extensions (for example multi- Higgs models) do not produce sizable CP violating effects in high-energy processes as the ones we discuss in this paper [3]. We will assume that there are new CP violating interactions at high energy 2 which manifest themselves at energy scales up to a few TeV as CP violating operators in an effective Lagrangian that involves only the fields present in the minimal standard model and respects its symmetries [4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9].</p>

				<p>The CP violating operators that could lead to a CP-odd observable in direct W γ and Zγ production would also contribute to low energy processes where there is no evidence for CP violation beyond that present in the CKM phase of the minimal standard model. However, as we argued in Ref. [2], there are several reasons why the higher energy processes would be more sensitive to certain types of interactions than the lower energy counterparts. Among them, that contributions from the new operators (associated with physics at some high energy scale Λ) to amplitudes at an energy scale µ are suppressed by powers of (µ/Λ) 2 . The effects of these operators in direct W ± γ production are thus enhanced by at least a factor of M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 W /m 2 π ≈ 3.5 × 10 5</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>over their effects in, say, radiative pion decays [2]. It is true that there are stringent indirect bounds on some of the new operators from observables such as the electric dipole moment of the neutron [10]. However, these bounds depend on naturalness assumptions and are, therefore, complementary to the ones that can be placed in direct W ± γ and Zγ production. For our study, we will use CP odd observables already described in the literature or very closely related ones [2, 4, 6, 11]. We present this analysis as a framework for experimental searches for CP violation. Having a specific parameterization of CP violating interactions it is possible to compare different observables and distributions, and in that way distinguish truly CP violating new physics from potential CP biases of the detectors.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 pp → W ± γ → ℓ ±</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>νγ</head>

				<p>This reaction is similar to the process pp → W ± jet that we considered in Ref. [2].</p>

				<p>In fact, the same operator that we considered in that case, Eq. 18 of Ref. [2], would generate CP-odd asymmetries in this process as well. We will focus here on a different operator that generates CP-odd asymmetries in this mode through a CP violating W W γ coupling. The CP violating W W γ couplings have been traditionally parameterized in terms of κ and λ following Ref. [12]. However, within an effective Lagrangian description of the symmetry breaking sector of the standard model, the coupling λ is suppressed with respect tõ κ by a factor µ 2 /Λ 2 for a process with a typical energy scale µ. We denote by Λ the scale of the new CP violating interactions that give rise tõ κ and λ. For this reason we concentrate on the coupling κ using the effective Lagrangian in a notation similar to that of Ref. [9]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = v 2 Λ 2 1 4 α 13 gg ′ ǫ µνρσ B µν Tr(T W ρσ ) + 1 8 α 14 g 2 ǫ µνρσ Tr(T W µν )Tr(T W ρσ ) . (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This differs from Ref. [9] in that we have introduced a factor v 2 /Λ 2 (v ≈ 246 GeV), for consistency with the power counting relevant for this type of new physics [13]. In terms of the conventional notation of Ref. [12] we have [9]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˜ κ γ = − e 2 s 2 θ v 2 Λ 2 (α 13 + α 14 ) ˜ κ Z = v 2 Λ 2 e 2 c 2 θ α 13 − e 2 s 2 θ α 14 , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where c θ = cos θ W , s θ = sin θ W . The process p¯ p → W ± γ is only sensitive tõ κ γ .</p>

				<p>The new physics that generates these anomalous couplings will in general give rise to form factors in the W W γ vertex with imaginary (absorptive) parts that are typically of the same size as the real parts. These absorptive parts combine with the CP violating couplings to generate additional CP odd observables. To study these observables we will assume that there is such an absorptive phase in the W W γ vertex and parameterize it by sin δ(W W γ) which we assume to be a number of order one.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>3</head>

				<p>With all this in mind we proceed to compute the differential cross-section for the process ¯ u(p u )d(p d ) → ℓ − (p ℓ )ν(p ν )γ(p γ ). We find a CP violating term linear iñ κ γ that contains a triple product. After squaring the matrix element, averaging over initial quark color and spin, and summing over the final photon polarization, we find for this term:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|M CP | 2 = 4 3 e 2 g 4 |V ud | 2 ˜ κ γ ǫ(p u , p d , p ℓ , p γ ) (ˆ s − M 2 W )(m 2 ℓν − M 2 W ) 2 · 2p ℓ · p u 3(p γ − p u ) 2 + p ℓ · p u + p ν · p d (ˆ s − M 2 W ) + p ν · p d 3(p γ − p d ) 2 , (3) 2 ℓν = (p ℓ + p ν ) 2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We use the narrow width approximation and, therefore, neglect the contributions to pp → ℓ − νγ from radiative W decays. To justify this approximation we restrict our study to the region of phase space where it works best, given by the cuts described in Ref. [14]. For our numerical results we use set B1 of the Morfin-Tung parton distribution functions [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>evaluated at a scale µ 2 = M 2 W + p 2 T γ and the following cuts: p T γ &gt; 10 GeV, p T ℓ &gt; 20 GeV, p T &gt; 20 GeV, |y γ | &lt; 2.4, |y ℓ | &lt; 3.0, ∆R(ℓγ) &gt; 0.7 and M T (ℓγ, p T ) &gt; 90 GeV.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first and last two cuts, defined as in Ref. [14], suppress the radiative W decays. The other cuts are typical Tevatron acceptance cuts [1]. The correlation in Eq. 3 generates CP-odd and T -odd observables based on the following triple-product in the lab frame: p ℓ · ( p γ × p beam ). We proceed as in Ref. [2] and construct the T -odd observable:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A ± = σ ± [( p γ × p beam ) · p ℓ &gt; 0] − σ ± [( p γ × p beam ) · p ℓ &lt; 0] (4) where A ± refers to the observable for W ± events (or ℓ ± ν events). Using Eq. 4 we construct the following CP odd observables: R 1 ≡ A + − A − σ + + σ − R 2 (y 0 ) ≡ dA + dy | y=y 0 − dA − dy | y=−y 0 dσ + dy | y=y 0 + dσ − dy | y=−y 0 , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where y can be the rapidity of the lepton or the photon (or the W ). Similar observables can be constructed for other distributions [2] but we will not consider them in this paper. When we allow for a non-zero absorptive phase, sin δ(W W γ), there are additional CP violating terms in the differential cross-section. They generate a new set of (T even ) CP-odd asymmetries and following Ref. [2] we construct the following:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˜ R 1 ≡ σ + − σ − σ + + σ − ˜ R 2 (y 0 ) ≡ dσ + dy | y=y 0 − dσ − dy | y=−y 0 dσ + dy | y=y 0 + dσ − dy | y=−y 0 , (6) where σ ± refers to σ(pp → ℓ ± νγ). With the set of cuts discussed above, we find numerically that: σ − ≈ (245 − 36˜in δ(W W γ))f b σ + ≈ (245 + 36˜in δ(W W γ))f b A + = −A − ≈ 119˜ and, therefore, R 1 ≈ 0. 49ãnd R 1 ≈ 0. 15˜in δ(W W γ). For an integrated luminosity of 10f b</trash>

					<figDesc>−1 we thus expect some 2500 W − γ events within the phase space region defined by our cuts and this translates into the 95% confidence level bound:</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>|˜</head>

				<p>Taking Λ ∼ 1 TeV, the bound Eq. 8 translates into |α 13 + α 14 | ≤ 4. In a theory where there is no suppression of CP violating interactions with respect to CP conserving ones 4 these couplings could be of order one and thus this bound could be significant. However, it is more likely that these couplings are much smaller. For example, Ref. [9] finds in generic technicolor models, α 13,14 ∼ 10 −4 (˜ κ γ ∼ 8 × 10 −6 ). It is interesting to compare this bound with the corresponding bound that the same machine could place on similar, but CP conserving, anomalous couplings. For example it has been claimed that a 95% confidence level bound |κ γ | ≤ 0.2 can be achieved [16]. It is possible to place similar constraints on CP violating and CP conserving anomalous couplings. Traditional studies of anomalous couplings [1, 14] have not discussed the coupling κ γ because there is a very strong indirect limit coming from the electric dipole moment of the neutron |˜×10 −4 [10]. This is a very tight indirect bound, and it indicates that it is quite unlikely that a non-zero CP-odd effect will be observed in p¯ p → W ± γ. Nevertheless, in full generality, the electric dipole moment of the neutron and the CP-odd observables that we study here, depend on different combinations of anomalous couplings and, therefore, complement each other. Because of this, and because the origin of CP violation is not understood, we would argue that an experimental search is necessary regardless of the merits of the limits that can be placed on couplings like κ γ .</p>

				<p>Obviously, any experimental search will have to be able to distinguish between truly CP violating effects and possible CP biases of the detector. An important tool for this goal is the simultaneous measurement and comparison of as many observables as possible. With this in mind, we present in Figure [1] the observable R 2 (y e ) as an example. The curve corresponds tõ κ γ = 1, and scales linearly with κ γ . This observable is zero for all values of y e if CP is conserved.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3 pp → Zγ → ℓ ± ℓ ∓ γ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Unlike the reaction which we studied in the previous section, pp → Zγ → ℓ ± ℓ ∓ γ is self-conjugate under a CP transformation. This results in the need for different CPodd observables. Another difference between the two processes is that pp → Zγ → ℓ ± ℓ ∓ γ does not receive contributions from Eq. 1 because the next to leading order effective Lagrangian for the symmetry breaking sector of the standard model does not produce anomalous ZZγ or Zγγ couplings. To generate a non-zero effect in this process we will have to go beyond the next to leading order effective Lagrangian, and we thus expect that any effect in pp → Zγ → ℓ ± ℓ ∓ γ will be smaller than a corresponding effect in pp → W ± γ → ℓνγ.</p>

				<p>In Ref. [12] the anomalous Z(q</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α 1 )γ(q β 2 )V (P</trash>

					<figDesc>µ ) vertices are parameterized in terms of several form factors, (where V = Z, γ). For example, there is a CP violating term</figDesc>
					<trash>-3.0 -2.0 -1.0 0.0 1.0 2.0 3.0 y e -2.0 -1.5 -1.0 -0.5 0.0 R 2 (y e ) Wγ Figure 1: The CP violating observable R 2 (y e )/˜ κ γ for pp → ℓ ± νγ at √ S = 2 TeV. of the form [12]: Γ αβµ ZγV (q 1 , q 2 , P ) = P 2 − M 2 V M 2 Z h V 1 (q µ 2 g αβ − q α 2 g µβ ). (9) The overall factor (P 2 − M 2 V )/M 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Z is required by electromagnetic gauge invariance for V = γ and by Bose symmetry for V = Z [12]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Because of this factor, the contributions from Eq. 9 to q ¯ q → Zγ are equivalent to those of local operators of the forms:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>O γ = 1 Λ 2 eg 2c θ Q q ¯ qγ µ qZ ν F µν O Z = 1 Λ 2 eg 4c θ ¯ qγ µ [R q (1 + γ 5 ) + L q (1 − γ 5 )]qZ ν F µν , (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where F µν is the electromagnetic field strength tensor, L q = τ 3 − 2Q q s 2 θ and R q = −2Q q s 2 θ . We have changed the normalization scale from M Z to Λ, the scale of the new physics responsible for this operator. Since we want to insist on an effective Lagrangian that preserves the symmetries of the standard model we must convert these operators into fully SU(2) L ×U(1) Y gauge invariant versions. There are at least two ways to do this. One way would be to obtain the Z ν field from an SU(2) covariant derivative acting on the fermion field. There are several dimension 6 operators with the desired properties listed in Ref. [5]. One of them is:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = i ˜ α 2Λ 2 (O qB + O uB + O dB ) + h.c. = i ˜ α Λ 2 ¯ qγ µ ∂ ν + ieQ q A ν + ig 4c θ [L q (1 − γ 5 ) + R q (1 + γ 5 )]Z ν qB µν + h.c. (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>With this approach we have an operator that is suppressed by only two powers of the new physics scale. However, as one can see from Eq.11, the fully gauge invariant version of the operator Eq. 10 also generates ¯ qqZ and ¯ qqγ vertices. When all of these new vertices are systematically taken into account, the interference between the lowest order standard model amplitude and the new CP-violating amplitude for the process ¯ qq → ℓ + ℓ − γ vanishes and one is left with no CP-odd effects. This is a rather surprising result that we have checked for all the relevant operators in Ref. [5]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>5</head>

				<p>A second way to make Eq. 10 fully gauge invariant uses a non-linearly realized electroweak symmetry breaking sector. In this case we think of Eq. 10 as the unitary gauge version of fully gauge invariant operators that can be constructed as described in Refs. [8, 13]. This construction generates the CP odd observables which we discuss next. However, the counting rules appropriate for this construction [18], tell us that the operators are suppressed by four inverse powers of the symmetry breaking scale and any effects are, therefore, expected to be extremely small.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Taking the unitary gauge Lagrangian L = v 2 Λ 4 h γ 1 O γ + h Z 1 O Z (12) we find for ¯ qq → ℓ + ℓ − γ a term linear in h V 1 that contains a triple product: |M CP | 2 = 1 12 v 2 h V 1 Λ 4 g 4 c 4 θ e 2 Q q 1 m 2 ℓℓ − M 2 Z 2 ǫ(p q , p ¯ q , p + , p − ) · (L 2 ℓ + R 2 ℓ )C V 1 p q · (p − − p + ) 2p q · p γ − p ¯ q · (p − − p + ) 2p ¯ q · p γ + (L 2 ℓ − R 2 ℓ )C V 2 1 − p q · p ¯ q 2p q · p γ − p q · p ¯ q</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>2p ¯ q · p γ (13) where C γ1 = Q q (L q − R q ), C Z1 = L 2 q − R 2 q , C γ2 = Q q (L q + R q ) and C Z2</p>

				<p><formula>= L 2 q + R 2 q .</formula></p>

				<p>We use the narrow-width approximation again and neglect the contributions from radiative Z decays. As before, we restrict ourselves to the region of phase space where this approximation works best by imposing the cuts: p T γ &gt; 10 GeV, p T ℓ &gt; 20 GeV, |y γ | &lt; 2.4, |y ℓ | &lt; 3.0, ∆R(ℓγ) &gt; 0.7 and M ℓ + ℓ − γ &gt; 100 GeV. As in the case of W ± γ, the first and last two cuts, defined as in Ref. [14], suppress the radiative Z decays and the remainder of the cuts are typical Tevatron acceptance cuts [1].</p>

				<p>In this reaction there can also be an absorptive phase in the form-factor of Eq. 9. If we include this absorptive phase, sin δ(qqZγ), we find additional CP violating contributions to the differential cross-section. As in the case of W ± γ, these new contributions are too cumbersome to write out explicitly but we include them in our numerical work. The reaction p¯ p → ℓ + ℓ − γ is self-conjugate under a CP transformation and this allows us to write fully integrated CP odd observables in the lab-frame such as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A T ≡ sign( p beam · ( p ℓ + × p ℓ − ))dσ sign(E ℓ + − E ℓ − )dσ (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>There will also be observables analogous to those in Eqs. 5, 6. As an illustration we present in Figure 2 the following observable:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∆(y 0 ) ≡ dσ dy ℓ + | y ℓ + =y 0 − dσ dy ℓ − | y ℓ − =−y 0 dσ dy ℓ + | y ℓ + =y 0 + dσ dy ℓ − | y ℓ − =−y 0 . (15) Numerically we use sin δ(qqZγ) = 1 and Λ = 1 TeV. -3.0 -1.0 1.0 3.0 y e - -0.30 -0.20 -0.10 0.00 0.10 ∆(y e ) x 10 4 Zγ h 1 γ h 1 Z Figure 2: ∆(y ℓ ) for pp → ℓ + ℓ − γ at √ S = 2 T eV . These curves are normalized to h V 1 = 1 and scale linearly with h V 1 . We have used Λ = 1 T eV .</trash>

					<figDesc>With the set of cuts that we are using we find numerically that:</figDesc>
					<trash>σ ≈ 348 f b A T ≈ (5.6h γ 1 + 12h Z 1 ) × 10 −3 1 TeV Λ 4 f b A E ≈ (1.3h γ 1 + 0.54h Z 1 ) × 10 −3 1 TeV Λ 4 sin δ(qqZγ) f b (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For an integrated luminosity of 10f b −1 we thus expect about 3500 Zγ events within the phase space region defined by our cuts. This translates into 95% confidence level bounds:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|h γ 1 + 2h Z 1 | ≤ 2700 Λ 1 TeV 4 . (17)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have constructed several CP-odd asymmetries that can be used in the search for CP violation in W ± γ and Zγ events in pp colliders. We have estimated the contributions to these asymmetries from some simple CP violating effective operators that respect the symmetries of the Standard Model. We find that an upgraded</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Tevatron with 10 f b −1 at √ S = 2 TeV can place limits of | α 13 + α 14 |&lt; 4(Λ/1 TeV) 2 and | h γ 1 + 2h Z 1 |&lt; 2700(Λ/1 TeV) 4 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first bound corresponds to | ˜ κ γ |&lt; .1, which is comparable to the bound obtainable for the CP conserving couplings in the next-toleading effective Lagrangian.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* This manuscript has been authored under contract number DE-AC02-76CH00016 with the U.S. Department of Energy. Accordingly, the U.S. Government retains a non-exclusive, royalty-free license to publish or reproduce the published form of this contribution, or allow others to do so, for U.S. Government purposes.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> As it is necessary in order to explain the baryon asymmetry in the universe.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> See Ref. [9] for a calculation of such an absorptive phase within a specific model for CP violation.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Among other things this would be a theory with no custodial SU (2) symmetry.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> Similar observations have been made before in the literature [17].</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>Acknowledgements The work of G.V. was supported in part by the DOE OJI program under contract number DEFG0292ER40730. G. V. thanks the theory group at the University of Melbourne and X-G.H thanks the theory group at BNL for their hospitality while part of this work was performed. The work of X-G.H. was supported by the Australian Research Council. We are grateful to U. Baur, S. Errede, and J.P. Ma for useful conversations.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Future Electroweak Physics at the Fermilab Tevatron Report of the tev-2000 Study Group</title>
		<editor>D. Amidei and R. Brock</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Fermilab-Pub-96/082</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Dawson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Valencia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="2717" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bernabeu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Santamaria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Gavela</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1514</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">and erratum Phys</title>
		<editor>X. G. He and B. McKellar</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1406" to="42" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Barbieri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Georges</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P. Le</forename>
				<surname>Doussal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Buchmü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Wyler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="621" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Brandenburg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Nachtmann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">55</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Burgess</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Robinson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">BNL Summer Study on CP Violation</title>
		<editor>S. Dawson and A. Soni</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>World Scientific</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Peccei</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Zhang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="269" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Appelquist</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G.-H</forename>
				<surname>Wu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">This is an updated number from Ref. [9] that uses the result of W. Marciano and A. Quejeiro</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="3449" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Brandenburg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Munch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Nachtmann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hagiwara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Chanowitz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Golden</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Georgi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="1490" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Baur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Berger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Phys. Rev</title>
		<editor>U. Baur, T. Han and J. Ohnemus</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="1476" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Morfin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W.-K</forename>
				<surname>Tung</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">52</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FERMILAB-Pub-95/031, 1996, to appear in Electroweak Sym- metry Breaking and New Physics at the TeV Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Aihara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>T.Barklow, S. Dawson, H.Haber, and J.Siegrist</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>De Rú</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Traseira and F. Vegas</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="311" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Georgi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">298B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">187</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
