<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A STATISTICAL SUPERFIELD AND ITS OBSERVABLE CONSEQUENCES</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Roland</forename>
								<forename type="middle">E</forename>
								<surname>Allen</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>e-mail: allen@phys.tamu.edu</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Center for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>77843</postCode>
									<settlement>College Station</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A STATISTICAL SUPERFIELD AND ITS OBSERVABLE CONSEQUENCES</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">International Journal of Modern Physics A</title>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2385" to="2412"/>
							<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9612041v5 20 May 1997 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A new kind of fundamental superfield is proposed, with an Ising-like Euclidean action. Near the Planck energy it undergoes its first stage of symmetry-breaking, and the ordered phase is assumed to support specific kinds of topological defects. This picture leads to a low-energy Lagrangian which is similar to that of standard physics, but there are interesting and observable differences. For example, the cosmological constant vanishes, fermions have an extra coupling to gravity, the gravitational interaction of W-bosons is modified, and Higgs bosons have an unconventional equation of motion.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The terms &quot; superfield &quot; and &quot; supersymmetry &quot; are ordinarily used in a context which presupposes local Lorentz invariance. 1−3 It is far from clear, however, that Lorentz invariance is still valid near the Planck scale, fifteen orders of magnitude above the energies where it has been tested. (A century ago, all accepted theories presupposed Galilean invariance.) In this paper the above terms will be used in a broader sense, to mean any field which has both commuting and Grassmann parts and any symmetry which relates these parts. At the same time, the presumption of Lorentz invariance at arbitrarily high energies will be replaced by a less stringent requirement: Lorentz invariance, and the other principles of standard physics, need only emerge at the relatively low energies where they have been tested. One is then free to consider any description which is mathematically consistent and also consistent with experiment and observation.</p>

				<p>It appears, however, that a fundamental theory still needs four central ingredients: a space, a field, an action, and a pattern of symmetry-breaking. The specific versions assumed here are as follows: (1) The space (or base manifold) is R D ; i.e., it is D-dimensional, flat, and initially Euclidean. (2) The classical field Ψ at each point x is an N-dimensional supersymmetric vector. (3) The Euclidean action S has the same basic form as the Hamiltonian for spins on a lattice. 4 (4) Below the Planck energy &lt; Ψ &gt; becomes nonzero. This order parameter can then support topological defects, analogous to those in condensed matter physics. 5−11 Three such defects are postulated in Section 7. The first two of these cause the original symmetry group G 0 to break down locally to a reduced symmetry group U(1) x SU(2) x G. They also produce a local &quot; filamentary &quot; geometry with 4 extended dimensions and (D-4) that are compact. After a reasonable series of approximations, we will find that this relatively simple picture leads to a low-energy Lagrangian (9.4) which closely resembles the conventional Lagrangian of particle physics 12,13 and general relativity. 14,15 There are some interesting and observable differences, however, and these are discussed at the end of the paper.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">The superfield and its Euclidean action</head>

				<p>First consider an analogy from ordinary statistical mechanics: classical spins on a lattice in D dimensions. Each spin s(x) is an N-dimensional vector whose components are real numbers. In the continuum limit, one can obtain a Ginzburg-Landau Hamiltonian</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H = d D x 1 2m ∂ M s † ∂ M s − µs † s + 1 2 b s † s 2 (2.1) where ∂ M = ∂/∂x M . (See, e.g., (3.5.17) of Ref. 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. Summation is implied over repeated indices, and inner products involving vectors are also implied.) The physical properties of this statistical system are determined by H, via the partition function. 4,16−19 At low temperature the order parameter &lt; s &gt; can become nonzero, making the system ferromagnetic.</p>

				<p>The starting point of the present theory is very similar: a classical field Ψ(</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x) having the form Ψ =         z 1 z 2 . . . z N         (2.2) where each z consists of an ordinary complex number z b and a complex Grassmann number z f : z =   z b z f   . (2.3) (Anticommuting Grassmann numbers are required in any classical treatment which includes fermions. 3,4,12,18−26 ) The Euclidean action is postulated to have the Ising-like form S = βH (2.4) H = − J ij Ψ † i Ψ j + 1 2 r ij Ψ † i Ψ j 2 (2.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the summation is over nearest-neighbor lattice sites. The first term represents a tendency for the field to be aligned at neighboring points, and the second ensures that S has a lower bound.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Since Ψ † i Ψ j + Ψ † j Ψ i = − (Ψ i − Ψ j ) † (Ψ i − Ψ j ) + Ψ † i Ψ i + Ψ † j Ψ j (2.6) the continuum version of (2.4) is S = d D x 1 2m ∂ M Ψ † ∂ M Ψ − µΨ † Ψ + 1 2 b Ψ † Ψ 2 (2.7) where Ψ(x) = (a −D β) 1/2 Ψ j , (2m) −1 = a 2 J, µ = 2DJ, b = 2Da D β −1 r, and a is the lattice spacing. We will find below, in (7.28) and (7.34), that m, µ, and b can be related to the Planck energy m P , defined by m −1 P = ℓ P = (16πG) 1/2 (2.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where G is the gravitational constant. (Units with ¯ h = c = 1 are used, so mass and energy are equivalent to inverse length.) The definition (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.8) implies that ℓ P ∼ 10 −32 cm and m P ∼ 10 15 TeV. In the continuum treatment represented by (2.7), the partition function becomes a Euclidean path integral. 4,19,21,24,25,27,28 It initially has the form Z = N 1 D(ReΨ)D(ImΨ)e −S (2.9) but can be rewritten in the equivalent form Z = N 2 DΨDΨ † e −S (2.10) where N 1 and N 2 are constants. In (2.10</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>), and in the following, the functions Ψ and Ψ † are taken to vary independently.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>29</head>

				<p>S can be interpreted as the Euclidean action for interacting Bose and Fermi fields Ψ b and Ψ f :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = S (0) b + S (0) f + S int (2.11) with S (0) b = d D x 1 2m ∂ M Ψ † b ∂ M Ψ b − µΨ † b Ψ b (2.12) S (0) f = d D x 1 2m ∂ M Ψ † f ∂ M Ψ f − µΨ † f Ψ f (2.13) S int = d D x 1 2 b Ψ † b Ψ b + Ψ † f Ψ f 2 . (2.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that S is supersymmetric in an unconventional way: Ψ b and Ψ f have the same number of components and the same form. There is no contradiction with the spin-and-statistics theorem 23 because this theorem is based on Lorentz invariance, a symmetry that will emerge only at low energies, and after a Wick rotation to Lorentzian time. Although Lorentz transformations can be defined only at a later stage, S is already invariant under general coordinate transformations. To make this explicit, we should replace d D x by the invariant volume element d D x h, where</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>h = (det h M N ) 1/2 (2.15) and h M N is the metric tensor for flat Euclidean space, initially given by h M N = δ M N . (2.16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Ψ b and Ψ f are both taken to transform as scalars. This is consistent with the usual convention in general relativity, according to which a spinor transforms as a scalar under general coordinate transformations. 15 After the Lagrangian of (9.4) has been obtained, we will additionally have Lorentz transformations, 14,15 with the usual behavior for spinors and the usual connection between spin and statistics.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">The order parameter</head>

				<p>S has the same form as the grand-canonical Hamiltonian for a conventional superfluid. 5 This Ginzburg-Landau form indicates that &lt; Ψ b &gt; will be nonzero at low temperature, so it is natural to write Ψ b = Ψ s + Φ b (3.1) as in Ref. 5. The classical equations of motion for the order parameter Ψ s , the bosonic excitations Φ b , and the fermionic excitations Ψ f follow from</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δS = 0 (3.2) with Ψ b , Ψ † b , Ψ f , and Ψ † f all varied independently.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We will consider fermionic excitations in the next section and bosonic excitations in Section 8. For the moment, however, let us focus on the order parameter. After integration by parts (with boundary terms assumed to vanish)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(2.11) becomes S 0 = d D x hΨ † s T + 1 2 V − µ Ψ s (3.3) in the absence of excitations, where T = − 1 2m ∂ M ∂ M (3.4) V (x) = bn s (3.5) n s = Ψ † s Ψ s . (3.6) Then (3.2) gives (T + V − µ)Ψ s = 0 (3.7) and Ψ † s (T + V − µ) = 0 (3.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with the operator acting to the left in this last equation.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>For an ordinary superfluid like 4 He, one writes Ψ s = n 1/2 s exp(iθ). The appropriate generalization is Ψ s = n 1/2 s Uη (3.9) Ψ † s = η † U † n 1/2 s (3.10) with U † U = 1 (3.11) η † η = 1. (3.12) U(x) and U † (x</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) are matrices, and η and η † are constant vectors. (Recall that Ψ and Ψ † vary independently, so the quantities in (3.10) are not necessarily the Hermitian conjugates of those in (3.9).) For 4 He, the superfluid velocity is defined by m v = ∇θ.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The generalization is mv M = − iU −1 ∂ M U. (3.13) Notice that (3.11) gives ∂ M U † U = −U † ∂ M U with U † = U −1 , or mv M = i∂ M U † U. (3.14) When (3.9) – (3.14) are used in (3.7), the result is η † n 1/2 s 1 2 mv M v M + V − 1 2m ∂ M ∂ M − µ − i 1 2 ∂ M v M + v M ∂ M n 1/2 s η = 0. (3.15) The Schrödinger -like equations (3.7) and (3.8) also lead to the equation of continuity ∂ M j M = 0 (3.16) with j M = 1 2im Ψ † s (∂ M Ψ s ) − ∂ M Ψ † s Ψ s (3.17) = η † n s v M η. (3.18) Substitution of (3.18) into (3.16) gives η † ∂ M v M + v M ∂ M n s η = 0 (3.19) reducing (3.15) to 1 2 m¯ v 2 + V + P = µ (3.20) where ¯ v 2 = η † v M v M η (3.21) P = − 1 2m n −1/2 s ∂ M ∂ M n 1/2 s . (3.22) Eq. (3.20</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is a quantum version of Bernoulli&apos;s equation, with part of the kinetic energy playing the role of pressure.</p>

				<p>In the next section we will consider an order parameter with the symmetry group U(1) x SU(2). For this case, the &quot; superfluid velocity &quot; v M can be written in terms of the identity matrix σ 0 and the Pauli matrices σ a :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>v M = v α M σ α , α = 0, 1, 2, 3. (3.23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is reasonable to assume that the order parameter has the symmetry η † σ a η = 0 (3.24) which means that the system is not spin-polarized when v M = 0. Then cross terms involving σ a σ 0 vanish, and the relation σ a σ b + σ b σ a = 2δ ab (3.25) further reduces (3.20) to 1 2 mv M α v α M + V + P = µ.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(3.26) 4 Fermionic excitations, U(1) x SU(2) order parameter When fermionic excitations are included, (2.11) becomes S = S 0 + S f , with S f = d D x hΨ † f (T + V − µ) Ψ f . (4.1) The term involving Ψ † f Ψ f 2</trash>

					<figDesc>is neglected in comparison to the one containing V because fermions cannot form a condensate. According to (3.2), Ψ f obeys the same equation of motion as Ψ s , and will share its rapid oscillations in regions where µ–V is large. In order to eliminate these oscillations, it is convenient to write</figDesc>
					<trash>Ψ f = Uψ f = n 1/2 s U ∼ ψ f . (4.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>For simplicity, n s will initially be regarded as slowly varying. Then we will find that lowenergy , long-wavelength excitations ψ f also correspond to low values of the action (4.1), and that it is consistent to identify ψ f with the fermionic fields observed in nature. First consider the case N=2, D=4, with symmetry group U(1) x SU(2) for the order parameter. The coordinates are</figDesc>
					<trash>x µ , µ = 0, 1, 2, 3. (4.3) Substitution of (4.2) into (4.1) gives S f = d 4 x hψ † f 1 2 mv µ v µ + V − 1 2m ∂ µ ∂ µ − µ − i 1 2 ∂ µ v µ + v µ ∂ µ ψ f . (4.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For low-energy (long-wavelength) excitations, ∂ µ ∂ µ ψ f can be neglected in comparison with mv µ ∂ µ ψ f . If n s is slowly varying, P can also be neglected.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Then the Bernoulli equation (3.26), together with (3.23) and (3.25), implies that 1 2 mv µ v µ + V − µ = mv µ 0 v a µ σ a . (4.5) In Section 7, a cosmological picture will be presented in which v a µ is real but v 0 µ is imagi- nary, 1 2 mv µ 0 v 0 µ &lt; 0, (4.6) and the basic texture is given by v 0 k = v a 0 = 0 f or k, a = 1, 2, 3. (4.7) Then (4.4) becomes S f = d 4 x hψ † f − 1 2 i∂ µ v µ − iv µ ∂ µ ψ f (4.8) or S f = d 4 x h 1 2 ψ † f v µ (−i∂ µ ψ f ) + (−i∂ µ ψ f ) † v µ ψ f (4.9) after integration by parts. There is no reason why the texture of (4.7) must be perfectly rigid, however, so we should permit small deformations v 0 k and v a 0 . When second-order terms are neglected, (4.9) is changed to S f = d 4 x ¯ L f (4.10) ¯ L f = − 1 2 ihψ † f v µ α σ α ∼ ∇µ ψ f + conj. (4.11) where ∼ ∇µ = ∂ µ + Γ µ + ia µ + ib µ (4.12) with a 0 = 0, a k = mv 0 k (k = 1, 2, 3) (4.13) b k = 0, b 0 = mv a 0 σ a (a = 1, 2, 3). (4.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here &quot; conj. &quot; represents a second term like that in (4.9). After the transformation to Lorentzian time in Section 9, it can be regarded as the true Hermitian conjugate of the first term, represented by &quot; h.c. &quot; The spin connection Γ µ is initially zero, but must be added to (4.11) to compensate for local transformations of ψ f when frame rotations are permitted.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>15</head>

				<p>Suppose that we now define an effective vierbein e α µ and an effective metric tensor g µν by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e µ α = v µ α , µ, α = 0, 1, 2, 3 (4.15) e α µ e µ β = δ α β (4.16) g µν = η αβ e α µ e β ν . (4.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The Minkowski metric tensor η αβ = diag (-1,1,1,1) is needed because of (4.6) and the requirement that a Euclidean metric tensor g µν should have signature (++++). ¯ L f then has nearly the same form as the standard Euclidean Lagrangian for massless spin 1/2 fermions in the Weyl representation. 13,19,25,30−32 There are two differences: the extra couplings a µ and b µ , and the factor of h rather than</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g = (det g µν ) 1/2 . (4.18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These features will be discussed near the end of the paper, but suppose that we momentarily disregard them. The behavior of massless fermions will then be the same as in a curved spacetime with metric tensor g µν . In the present theory, the geometry of spacetime is defined by the texture of the order parameter, with the &quot; superfluid velocity &quot; v µ α becoming the vierbein e µ α . The origin of spacetime curvature will be discussed in Section 7, and the transformation to Lorentzian time in Section 9.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 Fermionic excitations, U(1) x SU(2) x G order pa- rameter</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The treatment of the preceding section contains only one fermion species and no forces other than gravity. Let us now move to a more realistic description, with N &gt;2 and D &gt;4, which is similar to standard higher-dimensional theories. 3,33−35 The ordered phase described by Ψ s is assumed to locally have a &quot; filamentary &quot; geometry, with 4 extended dimensions and d that are compact. To be more precise, it occupies only a very small volume</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V B = d d x (5.1) in an internal space x B with coordinates x m , m = 4, 5, . . . , 3 + d (5.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>but a very large volume in the 4-dimensional external spacetime x A with coordinates x µ . In the simplest picture, the ordered phase is a d-dimensional ball of condensate in internal space, which can be described by one radial coordinate and (d–1) angular coordinates. To avoid confusion, however, we will retain the original rectangular coordinates x m in the discussion below, so that det h mn = 1 and h = (det h M N ) 1/2 = (det h µν ) 1/2 .</p>

				<p>It is also assumed that the order parameter locally has the form of a product:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ψ s = Ψ A Ψ B (5.3) where Ψ A has the symmetry group U(1) x SU(2) and Ψ B has an unspecified symmetry group G with generators σ c . Then (3.23) must be generalized to v M = v A M σ A = v α M σ α + v c M σ c , c ≥ 4. (5.4)</trash>

					<figDesc>Both the filamentary geometry and the form of the order parameter originate from two topological defects discussed in Section 7, associated respectively with the symmetry groups G and U(1) x SU(2). In generalizing the definition of the effective vierbein e</figDesc>
					<trash>α µ , it will be convenient to choose e c M = v c M (5.5) while retaining (4.15) and (4.16): e M α = v M α (5.6) e α M e M β = δ α β . (5.7) The effective metric tensor is then g M N = η AB e A M e B N = η αβ e α M e β N + e c M e c N . (5.8) Standard Kaluza-Klein theory 33,34 begins with an unperturbed metric tensor having the form g µν = g µν (x A ), g mn = g mn (x B ), g µm = g mµ = 0. The present theory similarly begins with an unperturbed order parameter having the form Ψ s = Ψ A (x A ) Ψ B (x B ) (5.9) which implies the texture v µ α = v µ α (x A ) (5.10) v c µ = 0 (5.11) v c m = v c m (x B ) (5.12) v m α = 0 (5.13) and the effective geometry g µν = g µν (x A ) , g mn = g mn (x B ), g µm = g mµ = 0. The form (5.9) requires that n A = Ψ † A Ψ A and µ A = 1 2 mv µ α v α µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>be regarded as constant in treating the rapid variations of the internal order parameter Ψ B .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Then (3.7) gives − 1 2m ∂ m ∂ m + V Ψ B = µ B Ψ B (5.14) where V (x B ) = bn A n B (x B ) , n B = Ψ † B Ψ B , and µ A = µ − µ B . The internal versions of (3.9) and (3.13) are Ψ B = n 1/2 B U B η B (5.15) and mv m = −iU −1 B ∂ m U B (5.16) with v m = v c m σ c . (5.17)</trash>

					<figDesc>Now let us turn to the fermion field ψ f of (4.2). It can be expanded in a complete set of states ψ</figDesc>
					<trash>B r (x B ) with coefficients ψ r (x A ) : 3,33−35 ψ f (x A , x B ) = r ψ r (x A ) ψ B r (x B ) . (5.18) The boson-fermion symmetry suggests that we should choose each term in (5.18) to have the same form as (5.3). We can also write Ψ B r = U B ψ B r = n 1/2 B U B ∼ ψ B r (5.19) as in (5.15), and choose the Ψ B r to be eigenfunctions of the operator in (5.14): − 1 2m ∂ m ∂ m + V − µ B Ψ B r = ε r Ψ B r . (5.20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We will find, as usual, that only the solutions with ε r = 0 can be retained in the low-energy limit. 3,33−35 The above choices and ideas are similar to those of other higher-dimensional theories, and it will be seen that they lead to consistent results. The internal space x B has an effective geometry determined by the effective metric tensor g mn . One can then define Killing vectors K</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n i , or K i = K n i ∂ n . (5.21) They have an algebra 14,36 K i K j − K j K i = −c k ij K k (5.22) and satisfy Killing&apos;s equation 15,37 K p i ∂ p g mn + g pn ∂ m K p i + g mp ∂ n K p i = 0. (5.23)</trash>

					<figDesc>For a scalar function F which is invariant under the symmetry operation specified by K i , the corresponding equation is</figDesc>
					<trash>K i F = 0. (5.24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We now need two assumptions: First, the condensate density n B is assumed to have the same symmetry as the geometry defined by g mn :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>K i n B (x B ) = 0. (5.25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This will be the case if the velocity v m results from an instanton with spherical symmetry which is &quot; frozen into &quot; internal space, as in the examples of Section 7. Second, the physically significant zero modes of (5.20) are assumed to share this symmetry:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>K i ∼ ψ B r = 0, ε r = 0. (5.26) This assumption is reasonable because ∼ ψ B r , defined in (5.19), satisfies</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the same equation as the constant vector η B of (5.15). It is also plausible that zero modes should reflect the symmetry of the space in which they are defined. A more detailed discussion of these modes is given in Section 8.</p>

				<p>In the simple picture mentioned below (5.2) and (5.25), the K i are associated with rotations in d dimensions, and thus with the symmetry group SO(d).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Since the Ψ B r serve as basis functions, let &lt; r|Q|s &gt;= d d x Ψ B † r QΨ B s (5.27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where Q is any operator. In the next section we will need these functions to be orthogonal,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>&lt; r|s &gt;= δ rs (5.28) and we will also need the result K i Ψ B s = U B (imK n i v c n σ c ) ψ B s (5.29) which follows from (5.16), (5.25), and (5.26). This implies the relation d d x ψ B † r σ i ψ B s =&lt; r|(−iK i )|s &gt; (5.30) where σ i = mK n i v c n σ c (5.31) is a matrix associated with the i th internal symmetry direction. 6 Gauge fields In conventional Kaluza-Klein theories, 33,34 the metric tensor is perturbed by letting g µm (x A , x B ) = A i µ (x A ) K n i (x B ) g nm . (6.1) In the present theory, this corresponds to letting v c µ = A i µ K n i v c n (6.2) since g µm = v c µ v c m (with v α m still zero) and g nm = v c n v c m . It is also equivalent to writing mv c µ σ c = A i µ σ i . (6.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We now need to determine how the gauge fields A i µ are coupled to the fermion fields ψ r .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>When (4.2) and (5.18) are substituted into (4.1), and (5.20) is used (with ε r = 0), the result is S f = rs d D x hψ B † r ψ † r U † − 1 2m ∂ µ ∂ µ − 1 2 mv µ α v α µ Uψ s ψ B s . (6.4) Let us focus on the term involving ∂ µ ∂ µ , and a particular r and s, which becomes S rs = 1 2m d D x hψ B † r [∂ µ (Uψ r )] † ∂ µ (Uψ s )ψ B s (6.5) after integration by parts. Since (3.13) and (5.4) give ∂ µ U = imU v α µ σ α + v c µ σ c (6.6) we need to consider ∂ µ (Uψ s ) = U imv α µ σ α + ∂ µ ψ s + Uimv c µ σ c ψ s . (6.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This expression is multiplied by its conjugate (with s → r). The product of the first term with its conjugate was already treated in Section 4. The product of the second term with its conjugate is second order in v c µ , and can consequently be neglected. The extra contribution to (6.5) thus involves the cross terms (imψ r )</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>† v µ c σ c imv α µ σ α + ∂ µ ψ s + (conj. with r ↔ s). For low-energy excitations, however, ∂ µ ψ s can be neglected in comparison with mv µ ψ s . We are left with m 2 ψ † r v c µ σ c v µ α σ α ψ s (6.8) plus its conjugate. The additional term in (6.5) is then ∆S rs = 1 2 d 4 x hψ † r v µ α σ α d d x ψ B † r mv c µ σ c ψ B s ψ s + conj. (6.9) When (6.3) and (5.30) are employed, the factor in square brackets reduces to a remarkably nice form: ∆S µ rs = d d x ψ B † r mv c µ σ c ψ B s (6.10) = A i µ d d x ψ B † r σ i ψ B s (6.11) = A i µ r| (−iK i ) |s. (6.12) Then (6.9) can be rewritten as ∆S rs = 1 2 d 4 x hψ † r v µ α σ α A i µ t rs i ψ s + conj. (6.13) where t rs i =&lt; r| (−iK i ) |s &gt; . (6.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let t i be the matrix with elements t rs i . Since it corresponds to the operator -iK i , it has the same algebra:</p>

				<p><formula>t i t j − t j t i = ic k ij t k . (6.15)</formula></p>

				<p>This is exactly what is needed for (6.13) to represent a proper gauge interaction. To simplify notation, let ψ be the vector with components ψ r . Then the extra contribution to (</p>

				<p><formula>6.4) is ∆S = 1 2 d 4 x hψ † e µ α σ α A i µ t i ψ + conj. (6.16)</formula></p>

				<p>After (5.28) is used, the other terms in (6.4) can be treated just as in Section 4. The Lagrangian density corresponding to (6.16) can then be added to (</p>

				<p><formula>4.11), giving ¯ L f = − 1 2 ih ψ † e µ α σ α ∼ Dµ ψ + conj. (6.17) where ∼ Dµ = ∼ ∇µ +iA i µ t i . (6.18)</formula></p>

				<p>The present theory thus yields the correct form for initially massless fermions coupled to both gravity and gauge fields.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="7">Instantons</head>

				<p>In an ordinary superfluid, the definition m v = ∇θ implies that ∇ × v = 0. (7.1)</p>

				<p>For the condensate of the present theory, the definition mv M = −iU −1 ∂ M U, together with the condition ∂ M ∂ N U -∂ N ∂ M U = 0, immediately gives the generalization</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G M N = 0 (7.2) where G M N = ∂ M v N − ∂ N v M + im [v M , v N ] . (7.3) If (7.2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) were to hold everywhere, the present theory would be untenable, since there is no such constraint on the vielbein and metric tensor in standard physics. It seems to be a general principle, however, that constraints like (7.2) can be relieved by topological defects, with important physical consequences. Let us consider a few examples. (a) U(1) vortices. Since (7.1) states that v is irrotational, it was originally a mystery how superfluid 4 He could exhibit its observed rotation. Feynman provided an answer by postulating the existence of vortices, 5 which were later seen experimentally. Integration over an area A containing a vortex gives</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A ∇ × v · d S = C v · d ℓ = 2πn/m (7.4)</trash>

					<figDesc>where n is an integer. The singularity at the center of a vortex thus relieves the constraint (7.1), in the sense that the integrated value of ∇ × v in (7.4) is nonzero. This has the important effect of allowing the superfluid to rotate. (b) SU(2) instantons in four dimensions. The velocity field around an n=1 vortex is given by</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>5 m v( r) = r −1 φ (7.5)</formula></p>

				<p>where r = (r, φ) in the xy plane. For an n=1 BPST instanton the corresponding result is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>12,32 m v(x) = σx 0 + σ × x ρ 2 , mv 0 (x) = σ · x ρ 2 (7.6) where ρ 2 = x 2 0 + x 2 . (7.7)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(The replacement</head>

				<p>A µ /i → mv µ has been made in the usual expressions, and the instanton size λ has been set equal to zero.) Even though (7.2) is satisfied at all points except ρ=0, the integrated value of G µν G µν is nonzero:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d 4 x tr (G µν G µν ) = 16π 2 /m 2 . (7.8)</trash>

					<figDesc>(c) Gravitational instantons in four dimensions. The Eguchi-Hanson instanton has a metric which can be written in the form</figDesc>
					<trash>28 ds 2 = 1 − a 4 r −4 −1 dr 2 + 1 − a 4 r −4 r 2 /4 (dψ + cosθ dφ) 2 + r 2 /4 dθ 2 + sin 2 θ dφ 2 . (7.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>As r/a → ∞ this becomes the metric of flat Euclidean space, but the Euler number</figDesc>
					<trash>χ = 128π 2 −1 d 4 x gε τ ω µν R τ ωαβ ε αβ ρσ R µνρσ + boundary terms (7.10) and the signature τ = 96π 2 −1 d 4 x gR µνρσ ε ρστ ω R µν τ ω + boundary terms (7.11) are nonzero: χ=2 and τ =1. Gibbons and Hawking obtained a generalization with the form 28 ds 2 = u −1 (dτ + ω · d x) 2 + u d x · d x (7.12) where u = u 0 + s i=1 q i | x − x i | −1 (7.13) ∇ × ω = ∇u. (7.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>When u 0 = 0 and all the q i are equal, these solutions are also asymptotically locally Euclidean , but with χ=s and τ =s-1. (d) Multidimensional instantons. The above ideas are known to generalize to larger symmetry groups and higher dimensions. 38−40 For example, the Kaluza-Klein monopole in 5 dimensions is given by</p>

				<p><formula>41 ds 2 = dt 2 + u −1 (dτ + ω · d x) 2 + u d x · d x (7.15)</formula></p>

				<p>where the fifth coordinate τ is periodic and u 0 = 1, s = 1 in (7.13). (e) Other topological defects in field theory 12,28,42−48 which play an important role in grand-unified theories, higher-dimensional theories, and cosmological models. (f) Other topological defects in condensed-matter physics, 6−11 which have a pervasive influence on the properties of superfluid 3 He and 4 He, type I and type II superconductors, liquid crystals, crystalline solids, magnetic materials, one-dimensional organic systems, and two-dimensional phase transitions. Given the ubiquity of topological defects, it is not unreasonable to assume that they exist in an ordered phase of the kind proposed here. The vortices postulated by Feynman relaxed the constraint (7.1), permitting the integrated vorticity to be nonzero. The topological defects postulated here will similarly relax the constraint (7.2), permitting integrated curvature scalars like (7.8) to be nonzero. Three distinct kinds of defects are needed: (1) An internal instanton, associated with the symmetry group G, which accounts for the internal velocity field v c m . This topological defect is analogous to the monopoles, instantons, etc. which are postulated in other higher-dimensional theories. Since G is left unspecified in the present paper, so is the detailed nature of this instanton.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The simplest toy models are the following: (a) d → 2 and G → U(1). Then the condensate is bounded by a circle of radius r B in internal space, and V B = πr 2 B . The internal instanton is a vortex, with v φ = (mr) −1 . There is only one Killing vector K = ∂ φ (7.16) and the gauge group is U(1). (b) d → 4 and G → SU(2).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In this case the condensate is enclosed by a 3-sphere of radius r B . The internal instanton has the form (7.6). There are now 6 Killing vectors K i , associated with the 6 rotational degrees of freedom, and the gauge group is SO(4). A more realistic model is provided by d → 10. Then the condensate lies within a 9- sphere of radius r B , and the internal instanton is a hypothetical extension of (7.6) to a larger symmetry group which is contained in G. There are 45 Killing vectors and the gauge group is SO(10), perhaps the most appealing possibility for grand unification.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>49</head>

				<p>A finite internal volume V B is required for this instanton to have finite action: If mv c m ∝ r −1 , as in (7.5) and (7.6), then the kinetic energy contribution</p>

				<p><formula>d d x n B · 1 2 mv m c v c m (7.17)</formula></p>

				<p>will diverge unless n B → 0 for r &gt; r B . Since the natural length scale in (5.14) is the correlation length</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 ξ = (2mµ) −1/2 (7.18) it is plausible that r B ∼ ξ, V B ∼ ξ d . (7.19)</trash>

					<figDesc>Notice that the internal velocity v m has no radial component. The metric tensor g mn is then defined only along the tangential directions, with v c m ∝ (mr) −1 and g mn ∝ (mr) −2 within a (d-1)-sphere of radius r. Let V ′ B be the effective volume of this sphere:</figDesc>
					<trash>V ′ B = d d ′ x g d ′ , d ′ = d − 1 (7.20) where g d ′ = (det g mn ) 1/2 (7.21) and m, n = 4,5, . . ., 3 + d ′ . We can similarly define g D ′ = (det g M N ) 1/2 , (7.22) where D ′ = D-1 and the coordinates are restricted to those describing the manifold R 4 × S d ′ : M,N = 0,1, . . ., D ′ -1 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Since g d ′ ∝ (mr) −d ′ and d d ′ x = r d ′ dΩ, where dΩ is a solid angle, (7.20) implies that V</figDesc>
					<trash>′ B is independent of r and V ′ B ∼ m −d ′ . (7.23) (2) A cosmological instanton, with an SU(2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) velocity field like that of (7.6). If we choose x = 0 at our position in the universe, then the 3-vector v a k σ a has the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>v ∝ σ/mx 0 (7.24) and v a 0 = 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The singularity at x 0 = 0 is interpreted as the big bang. Recall that there is also a U(1) velocity field v 0 µ , which need not be real, and that Ψ and Ψ † vary independently. These features can be exploited in minimizing the action (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3.3), by requiring the U(1) kinetic energy 1 2 mv µ 0 v 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>µ to be negative. Symmetry indicates that v 0 µ is radial, or along the x 0 direction at our position in the universe, giving the texture (4.7). Ψ s then varies as exp(−ωx 0 ) within the present Euclidean picture, with Ψ † s ∝ exp (+ωx 0 ) to keep n s constant. In Section 9 we will transform to a Lorentzian picture by performing a Wick rotation x 0 → ix 0 . The above dependences are then changed to exp(−iωx 0 ) and exp(+iωx 0 ), with the condensate density still constant. The continuity equation (3.16) appears to impose a constraint on the velocity field v 0 µ , but this constraint may also be relieved by topological defects: There can be monopole-like defects which act as sources or sinks for the current j 0 µ = η † n s v 0 µ η, with ∂ µ j 0 µ = 0 everywhere except at the singularities themselves (where n s → 0). These defects are physically allowed because v α µ is not a true superfluid velocity; it instead specifies a field configuration, analogous to the configuration of spins on a lattice. (3) Planck-scale instantons which are dilutely distributed throughout external spacetime, and which give rise to a twisting of the field e A µ . Just as an ordinary gravitational instanton is embedded in a surrounding metric g µν , or vierbein e α µ , the instantons postulated here are embedded in a more general field e A µ which includes both the gravitational field (for A = α ≤ 3) and the gauge fields (for A = c ≥ 4). The effective vielbein e A M and metric tensor g M N of (5.8) are defined on a manifold M of dimension D ′ . (Recall that D ′ = D -1 and M = R 4 × S D ′ −4 in the models above (7.23).) We can then define a Riemannian curvature scalar (D ′ ) R and a scalar density g D ′ = det g M N , with the coordinates M and N restricted to this manifold. Let S in be the action of one instanton, and R in be its contribution to the quantity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− d D ′ x g D ′ (D ′ ) R. (7.25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(It is assumed that each instanton has a core singularity which makes R in nonzero. It is also assumed that instantons of the same kind have the same values of S in and R in .) A comparison of (7.29) with (7.30) shows that R in must be positive. Although it costs an action S in to form an instanton, the action of the matter fields can be lowered by the resulting change in curvature. We will find below that minimization of the total action with respect to g µν and A i µ leads to the Einstein and Maxwell field equations. Since S in is dimensionless and (D ′ ) R has dimension length −2 , we can write</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S in = ℓ −D ′ +2 0 R in . (7.26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To obtain precise values of S in , R in , and ℓ 0 would require detailed calculations for a specific model. We can, however, obtain estimates if the instantons are assumed to have the following general properties: First, the presence of m in (3.13) suggests a &quot; velocity core &quot; of size r v ∼ m −1 , within which v A µ ∼ 1 and ∂ µ v A ν ∼ m. (This behavior can be seen explicitly in (7.5) and (7.6), which become dimensionless if distances are scaled by m −1 .) Second, the presence of a singularity suggests a &quot; density core &quot; of size r n ∼ ξ. One then expects R in ∼ m −4 V</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>′ B m 2 and S in ∼ ξ 4 V B µ 2 /b. (The action (3.3) becomes d D x − 1 2 bn 2 s after (3.7</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is used. If Ψ s is constant, (3.7) also implies that the density is ¯ n s = µ/b. Then in a core region of radius r n , whose density is depleted by a singularity at the center, the change in the action is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∆S = d D x − 1 2 bn 2 s + 1 2 b¯ n 2 s ∼ ξ 4 V B µ 2 /b.) It follows that ℓ D ′ −2 0 ∼ ξ −d V ′ B b ∼ (µ/m) d/2 mb (7.27) where (7.18), (7.19), and (7.23) have been used. Finally, (7.31) relates the Planck length ℓ P to the parameters m, µ, and b of (2.7): ℓ 2 P ∼ (mµ) d/2 b, d = D − 4. (7.28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Since the contributions are additive for dilutely distributed instantons, (7.26) implies that they have a net action</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S D ′ = −ℓ −D ′ +2 0 d D ′ x g D ′ (D ′ ) R in (7.29) where (D ′ )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>R in represents their total contribution to the scalar curvature. This is the Euclidean Einstein-Hilbert action in D ′ dimensions, and the usual Kaluza-Klein reduction gives</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>33,34 S D ′ = −ℓ −2 P d 4 x g (4) R + 1 4 g −2 0 d 4 x gF i µν F i ρσ g µρ g νσ (7.30) where ℓ −2 P = ℓ −D ′ +2 0 V ′ B (7.31) ℓ −2 P &lt; g mn K m i K n j &gt;= g −2 0 δ ij (7.32) and F i µν = ∂ µ A i ν − ∂ ν A i µ + c i jk A j µ A k ν . (7.33) V ′</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>B is the internal volume of (7.20) and &lt; — &gt; represents an average over this volume. (If σ i is constant in (5.31), however, then so is g mn K m i K n j , eliminating the need for an average.)</p>

				<p>As in conventional Kaluza-Klein theories, (4) R is the curvature scalar associated with the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>vierbein e α µ , and g = det e α µ e α ν 1/2 . Suppose that v c m v c n K m i K n j is ∼ m −2 δ ij , as in the models above (7.23). Since g 0 is ∼ 1, 12,13 (7.32) then implies the relationship m ∼ m P . (7.34) The Lagrangian densities corresponding to (7.30) are ¯ L G = −ℓ −2 P g (4) R (7.35) ¯ L g = 1 4 g −2 0 gF i µν F i ρσ g µρ g νσ . (7.36) 8 Bosonic excitations When bosonic excitations Φ b are included, (2.11) becomes S = S b + S f (8.1) S b = d D x hΨ † b T + 1 2 ∼ V −µ Ψ b (8.2) S f = d D x hΨ † f T + ∼ V −µ Ψ f (8.3) where ∼ V = bΨ † b Ψ b (8.4) and Ψ b = Ψ s + Φ b . If we now require that T + ∼ V −µ Ψ s = 0 (8.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the treatment of the order parameter and fermionic excitations in the preceding sections is unchanged, except that V →</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∼ V . The bosonic action (8.2) can be written S b = S 0 + ∆S b + ∆S ′ b (8.6) with ∆S b = d D x hΦ † b T + V − µ + 1 2 bΦ † b Φ b Φ b (8.7) ∆S ′ b = d D x hΦ † b T + 1 2 ∼ V + 1 2 V + 1 2 bΦ † b Φ b − µ Ψ s + conj. (8.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For the excitations considered below, we will find that Φ † b Ψ s = 0, so that (8.8) is unchanged if the interaction terms in parentheses are replaced by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∼ V . But the equation of motion (8.5) then gives ∆S ′ b = 0. (8.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let us expand the boson field Φ b in the complete set of internal states Ψ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B r , with coefficients Φ r : Φ b = r ′ Φ r Ψ B r (8.10) where Ψ B 0 = N −1/2 B Ψ B , (8.11) N B = d</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>d x n B , and the prime means r = 0. Recall that these basis functions are the solutions to (5.20), and are written in the form (5.19). In treating low-energy bosonic excitations, it is necessary to assume the orthogonality condition</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∼ ψ B † r ∼ ψ B s = N −1 B δ rs , ε r = ε s = 0 (8.12) or equivalently Ψ B † r Ψ B s = N −1 B n B δ rs , ε r = ε s = 0. (8.13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Only those functions satisfying this condition and (5.26) are considered to be physically significant in the present context. There is another set of solutions to (5.20) with Ψ B r → Ψ B r * ; since these involve motion counter to that of the condensate, however, it is assumed that radiative corrections will break the degeneracy between these states and those of (8.13), so they are omitted from the sums of (5.18) and (8.10) at low energy. The state with r=0 is already occupied by the order parameter, so it is also omitted from (8.10).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Then (5.9) and (8.10) – (8.13) imply that Φ † b Ψ s = 0 (8.14) and Φ † b Φ b = r ′ Φ † r Φ r Ψ B † r Ψ B r . (8.15) Since T = (2m) −1 (∂ µ ∂ µ + ∂ m ∂ m ), the first term in (8.7) involves ∂ µ Φ b = ∂ µ s ′ Φ s U B ψ B s (8.16) = s ′ U B ψ B s ∂ µ Φ s + imv c µ σ c ψ B s Φ s (8.17) = s ′ Ψ B s ∂ µ Φ s + A i µ K i Ψ B s Φ s (8.18) where (8.10), (5.19), (6.6), (6.3), (5.31), and (5.29) have been used. After integration by parts, the ∂ µ ∂ µ term of (8.7) then has the form ∆S 1 = d 4 x h(2m) −1 rs ′ d d x P µ r Ψ B r † P µs Ψ B s (8.19) where P µs = ∂ µ Φ s + Φ s A i µ K i . (8.20) The integral over the internal coordinates can be written r|P µ † r P µs |s = t r|P µ † r |tt|P µs |s (8.21) = t δ tr ∂ µ Φ r + iA µ i t tr i Φ r † δ ts ∂ µ Φ s + iA j µ t ts j Φ s (8.22) after (6.14) is used. Then (8.19) becomes ∆S 1 = d 4 x h(2m) −1 D µ Φ † D µ Φ (8.23) where Φ is the vector with components Φ r and D µ = ∂ µ + iA i µ t i . (8.24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that the bosons of this section have not been treated in the same way as the fermions of Sections 4–6. This is because the bosons can undergo condensation at low energy. Their equation of motion is then less important than their coupling to the gauge fields A i µ , and it is appropriate to deal directly with the boson field Φ b rather than writing it in the form (4.2) and neglecting terms that are second order in A</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>i µ . With ε r = 0, (5.20) and (8.10) imply that − 1 2m ∂ m ∂ m + V − µ B Φ b = 0 (8.25) so the next term from (8.7) is ∆S 2 = − d 4 x hΦ † µ A Φ. (8.26) Also, (8.15) gives d d x Φ † b Φ b 2 = rs ′ Φ † r Φ r I rs Φ † s Φ s (8.27) where I rs = d d x Ψ B † r Ψ B r Ψ B † s Ψ B s . (8.28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For the solutions of (8.13), however, this expression is independent of r and s: I rs = I. The last term from (8.7) is then</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∆S 3 = 1 2 bI d 4 x h Φ † Φ 2 . (8.29) To obtain a standard form, let φ = (2m) −1/2 Φ (8.30) ¯ µ 2 = 2mµ A . (8.31) The total Lagrangian density resulting from (8.23), (8.26), and (8.29) becomes ¯ L b = h D µ φ † D µ φ − ¯ µ 2 φ † φ + 1 2 ¯ b φ † φ 2 (8.32) where ¯ b = (2m) 2 bI. (8.33) The prefactor in (8.32) is h = (det h µν ) 1/2 rather than g = (det g µν ) 1/2 , and the first term involves D µ φ † D µ φ = h µν D µ φ † D ν φ (8.34) rather than g µν D µ φ † D ν φ. Suppose for simplicity that v k a = λδ k a and v 0 0 = iλ (with v 0 a = v k 0 = 0</trash>

					<figDesc>), since a similar scaling is implied by the cosmological model of Section 7. It follows that</figDesc>
					<trash>g µν = λ 2 δ µν , g = λ −4 . (8.35) Letting φ ′ = λφ (8.36) we can write ¯ L b = g g µν D µ φ ′ † D ν φ ′ − λ 2 ¯ µ 2 φ ′ † φ ′ + 1 2 ¯ b φ ′ † φ ′ 2 . (8.37) We can similarly rescale (6.17): ¯ L f = − 1 2 igψ ′ † e µ α σ α ∼ Dµ ψ ′ + conj. (8.38) where ψ ′ = λ 2 ψ. (8.39)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The specific scaling of the preceding paragraph is simplistic, but it suggests that the second term in (8.37) may be neglected, leaving</p>

				<p><formula>¯ L b = h D µ φ † D µ φ + 1 2 ¯ b φ † φ 2 . (8.40)</formula></p>

				<p>(There is another reason for neglecting this term: If µ B is constant in (5.14), µ A must also be constant, and it is asymptotically equal to zero in the cosmological picture of Section 7. It follows that ¯ µ = 0.) The final Lagrangian for fundamental bosons then has no mass terms or Yukawa couplings. This is consistent with the idea that radiative effects may give rise to such additional interactions at the electroweak scale. On the other hand, symmetry-breaking at a grand-unified scale is attributed to formation of the order parameter itself: The argument that led to (8.23) and (8.29) also implies that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S 0 = d 4 x h (2m) −1 D µ ∼ Φ † D µ ∼ Φ −µN B n A + 1 2 (2m) −2 ¯ b (N B n A ) 2 (8.41) where ∼</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Φ is the vector corresponding to Ψ s , with all its components</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>∼</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Φr equal to zero except</figDesc>
					<trash>∼ Φ0 = N 1/2</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>B Ψ A . The gauge fields A i µ that are coupled to Ψ s , through the term</figDesc>
					<trash>∼ Φ † A µ i t i A j µ t j ∼ Φ in (8.41), will acquire large masses when Ψ s becomes nonzero. According to (8.19) and (5.30), these are the fields for which d d x K i Ψ B 0 † K j Ψ B 0 = N −1 B d d x n B η † B σ i σ j η B (8.42)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is nonzero, where σ i is defined in (5.31). For example, if the σ i were proportional to the SU(3) Gell-Mann matrices λ i , 12 and if η † B were (0,0,1), then the gauge fields corresponding to i = 4,5,6,7,8 would acquire masses at the grand-unified scale, and those corresponding to i = 1,2,3 would not, leaving an unbroken SU(2) gauge group at lower energy. The true internal symmetry group G should, of course, leave an unbroken gauge group SU(3) × SU(2) × U(1). Notice that the Bernoulli equation (3.26) is unchanged when mv c µ σ c = A i µ σ i is introduced at low energy. For those A i µ which do not couple to η B , η † σ i σ j η vanishes in (3.21). But those which do couple have large masses, so they do not appear at low energy. The scaling above (8.35) is also relevant to the extra fields of (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>4.11) – (4.14): If v µ α ∼ λ, (4.16) shows that e α µ ∼ λ −1 , or v α µ ∼ λ 2 e α µ , giving a k ∼ λ 2 me 0 k , b 0 ∼ λ 2 me a 0 σ a . (8.43)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>There is then an extra coupling to gravity for spin-polarized fermions which involves a mass λ 2 m.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>9 Observable consequences The low-energy Lagrangian ¯ L = ¯ L f + ¯ L b + ¯ L g + ¯ L G (9.1) still corresponds to Euclidean spacetime. We now need to perform a Wick rotation 4,12,24−28 x 0 → ix 0 (9.2) to obtain the Lorentzian action S L = iS = d 4 x L (9.3) where L = L f + L b + L g + L G (9.4) L f = 1 2 if ψ † e µ α σ α ∼ Dµ ψ + h.c. (9.5) L b = −f D µ φ † D µ φ + 1 2 ¯ b φ † φ 2 (9.6) L g = − 1 4 g −2 0 eF i µν F i ρσ g µρ g νσ (9.7) L G = ℓ −2 P e (4) R (9.8) e = det e α µ = (−det g µν ) 1/2 (9.9) f = (−det h µν ) 1/2 (9.10) and D µ = ∂ µ + iA i µ t i . (9.11) A i 0 , e α 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, etc. are now real-valued Lorentzian fields (see, e.g., p. 329 of Ref. 28), and the metric tensors h µν and g µν have Lorentzian signature (–+++). L contains four terms, corresponding respectively to spin 1/2 fermions, scalar bosons, gauge fields, and the gravitational field. It has the same form as the Lagrangian postulated in standard fundamental physics, except for several differences that it is now appropriate to discuss.</p>

				<p>For the sake of generality, suppose that radiative effects give rise to additional interaction terms and an effective Lagrangian</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L ef f = L − f u (φ) + L int (9.12) L int = − 1 2 f γψ † φψ + h.c. (9.13) = − 1 2 f rps γ rps ψ † r φ p ψ s + h.c. (9.14) where u(φ) contains terms of the form ±µ 2 p φ † p φ p . The complete matter field Lagrangian is then L m = L f + L B + L int (9.15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with L B = L b − f u (φ). Since the fermions and fundamental bosons described by L m are defined on an initially flat spacetime with metric tensor h µν , this Lagrangian does not contain a conventional factor e = (−det g µν ) 1/2 . Instead it contains the nondynamical factor</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f = (−det h µν ) 1/2 : L m = f ∼ Lm . (9.16) The variational principle (3.2) also holds for the Lorentzian action S L : δS L = 0. (9.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In addition, it holds for variations in g µν , or e µ α = v µ α , since these are equivalent to variations in Ψ s or Ψ b . The Einstein field equations are given as usual by δS L /δg µν = 0. With the present action</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S m = d 4 x f ∼ Lm (9.18) they are R µν − 1 2 g µν (4) R = −ℓ 2 P e −1 f δ ∼ Lm δg µν − ℓ 2 P e −1 δL g δg µν (9.19) since δe/δg µν = − 1 2 g µν e and δ (4) R/δg µν is effectively R µν . 14,15 With the conventional matter field action S ′ m = d 4 x e ∼ L ′ m (9.20) they are instead R µν − 1 2 g µν (4) R = −ℓ 2 P   δ ∼ L ′ m δg µν − 1 2 g µν ∼ L ′ m   − ℓ 2 P e −1 δL g δg µν . (9.21)</trash>

					<figDesc>Let us now consider the consequences of this modification. (i) The cosmological constant. In conventional physics, the vacuum has a Lagrangian</figDesc>
					<trash>density e ∼ L0 due to Higgs fields. 50 If δ ∼ L0 /δg µν is neglected, this density gives a contribution 1 2 ℓ 2 P g µν ∼ L0 in the field equations (9.21), so it corresponds to an effective cosmological constant Λ: 14,15 Λ = − 1 2 ℓ 2 P ∼ L0 . (9.22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This prediction of conventional physics is in error by at least 50 orders of magnitude. 50 In the present theory, however, the Lagrangian density is f ∼ L0 , and there is no contribution involving ∼ L0 directly in the field equations (9.19):</p>

				<p><formula>Λ = 0. (9.23)</formula></p>

				<p>There may be a much weaker term involving δ ∼ L0 /δg µν , but this appears to be consistent with observation. There is also a more poorly defined contribution due to vacuum fluctuations which is not considered here. (ii) Ordinary matter as a gravitational source. Since L B does not contribute in the field equations (9.19), we are left with</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L F = f ∼ LF = L f + L int = 1 2 f ψ † ie µ α σ α ∼ Dµ −γφ ψ + h.c. (9.24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The variational principle (9.17), for arbitrary δψ † , then gives the Dirac equation for initially massless fermions coupled to gauge fields and scalar bosons:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ie µ α σ α ∼ Dµ −γφ ψ = 0. (9.25)</trash>

					<figDesc>But this makes L F = 0. The same reasoning applies to the corresponding action L ′ F in conventional physics, so the conventional field equations (9.21) reduce to</figDesc>
					<trash>R µν − 1 2 g µν (4) R = −ℓ 2 P δ ∼ L ′ F δg µν − ℓ 2 P e −1 δL g δg µν . (9.26) In L ′ F , the fermion field ψ ′ has a normalization d 4 x eψ ′ † ψ ′ = N f (9.27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where N f is the total number of fermions. In L F , on the other hand, ψ has a normalization d 4 x f ψ † ψ = N f . (9.28)</p>

				<p>When this difference is taken into account, the conventional field equations (9.26) and the present field equations (9.19) make nearly the same predictions. It appears that both are in agreement with the classic and more recent tests of general relativity. 14,15,51,52 As mentioned below (8.43), however, there is an extra coupling of fermions to gravity through the fields a k and b 0 , which might be observable. (iii) Massless vector bosons. For photons and gluons the only coupling to gravity is through the Lagrangian L g of (9.7), and this is the same in the present theory as in coventional physics. (iv) Massive vector bosons. For the W and Z particles there is an additional term resulting from (9.6). In the present theory it is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−f h µν A i µ t i φ † (A j ν t j φ) . whereas in conventional physics it would have the form −eg µν A i µ t i φ ′ † (A j ν t j φ ′ ) .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>There is thus a difference in the coupling of these particles to gravity. The resulting violation of the equivalence principle will be small, because virtual W-bosons have large masses, but it is potentially observable.</p>

				<p>In addition to the above gravitational effects, the present theory predicts unconventional behavior of propagators at high energy: For p µ &gt; mv µ , the approximation below (4.4) will fail, and fermion propagators should begin to go as p −2 rather than / p −1 . Also, the equation of motion for scalar bosons involves h µν ∂ µ φ † ∂ ν φ rather than g µν ∂ µ φ ′ † ∂ ν φ ′ . Since the model scaling above (8.35) is not quantitatively correct, there will be a violation of Lorentz invariance which should lead to observable effects for Higgs bosons. Finally, the present theory provides a new cosmological picture, with implications for the Hubble constant 53 and other large-scale properties of the universe.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>I have greatly benefitted from discussions with R.L. Arnowitt, M.J. Duff, C.N. Pope, E.</p>
				<p>Sezgin, S.A. Fulling, C.-R. Hu, and V. Pokrovsky. This work was supported by the Robert A. Welch Foundation.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supersymmetric Gauge Field Theory and String Theory (Insti- tute of Physics Citations of the original papers are given in this and the other books and articles listed below</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Bailin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Love</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<pubPlace>Bristol</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Supergravities in Diverse Dimensions</title>
		<editor>A. Salam and E. Sezgin (North- Holland</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Green</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Schwarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum and Statistical Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Le</forename>
				<surname>Bellac</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<pubPlace>Clarendon, Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Theory of Many-Particle Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Fetter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Walecka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<publisher>McGraw- Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>San Francisco</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Tilley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Tilley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Superconductivity</forename>
				<surname>Superfluidity</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<pubPlace>Adam Hilger, Bristol</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Third. Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Superfluid Phases of Helium 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Vollhardt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wö</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>Taylor and Francis</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Anderson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic Notions of Condensed Matter Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>De Gennes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Superconductivity of Metals and Alloys</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Chaikin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Lubensky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Principles of Condensed Matter Physics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Mermin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">591</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T.-P</forename>
				<surname>Cheng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L.-F</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<pubPlace>Clarendon, Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Introduction to Gauge Theories and Modern Particle Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Leader</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Predazzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<editor>C.W. Misner, K.S. Thorne, and J.A. Wheeler, Gravitation (W.H. Freeman</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
			<pubPlace>San Fran- cisco</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Gravitation and Cosmology</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Statistical Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Parisi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley, Menlo Park</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Amit, Field Theory, the Renormalization Group, and Critical Phenomena</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Scientific</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second. Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Many-Particle Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Negele</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Orland</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley Menlo Park</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Field Theory and Critical Phenomena</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Zinn-Justin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Claren- don</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second. Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Method of Second Quantization</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Berezin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Physics, A Functional Integral Point of View</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Glimm</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Jaffe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second. Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Itzykson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J.-B</forename>
				<surname>Zuber</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Quantum Theory of Fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum Theory of Many-Variable Systems and Fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Sakita</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Scientific</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Path Integral Approach to Quantum Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Roepstorff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Path Integral Methods in Quantum Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Rivers</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Hawking</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Hawking on the Big Bang and Black Holes</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Euclidean</forename>
				<surname>Quantum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Gravity</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Sci- entific</title>
		<editor>G.W. Gibbons and S.W. Hawking</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>See</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Swanson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Path Integrals and Quantum Processes</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Academic, Boston</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page">226</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Field Theory: A Modern Primer</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ramond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley Menlo Park</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second. Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Fields in Curved Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C W</forename>
				<surname>Davies</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>Cambridge Univer- sity Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Aspects of Symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Coleman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Appelquist</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Chodos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G O</forename>
				<surname>Freund</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Modern Kaluza-Klein Theories</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Addison- Wesley Menlo Park</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Addison- Wesley Menlo Park</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physics in Higher DimensionsWorld Scientific</title>
		<editor>T. Piran and S. Weinberg</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Duff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E W</forename>
				<surname>Nilsson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Pope</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ref</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">359</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Nakahara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Geometry</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Physics</forename>
				<surname>Topology</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<pubPlace>Adam Hilger ; Bristol</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Topology of Gauge Fields and Condensed Matter</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Monastyrsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Plenum</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Choquet-Bruhat</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Dewitt-Morette</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dillard-Bleick</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Analysis, Manifolds, and Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>North-Holland</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>North-Holland</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Eguchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Gilkey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Hanson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">213</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Dowker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Gauntlett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Gibbons</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Horowitz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7115</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Rajaraman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Instantons</forename>
				<surname>Solitons</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>North-Holland</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<editor>A.S. Schwarz, Quantum Field Theory and Topology</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gauge Fields and Strings</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Polyakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<pubPlace>Harwood, Chur</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Instantons in Gauge Theories</title>
		<editor>M. Shifman</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gö</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Schü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Differential Geometry, Gauge Theories, and Gravity</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Vilenkin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P S</forename>
				<surname>Shellard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cosmic Strings and Other Topological Defects</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cam- bridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Duff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Khuri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">X</forename>
				<surname>Lu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">259</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">213</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<pubPlace>Benjamin, Menlo Park</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Grand. Unified Theories</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Wald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Relativity</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chicago</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Kenyon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Relativity</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Principles of Physical Cosmology</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Peebles</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press, Prince- ton</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
