<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Non-Supersymmetric Open String Theory and S-Duality</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="97011372-03-18">9701137v2 18 May 1997 January 1997</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Oren</forename>
								<surname>Bergman</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brandeis University Waltham</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02254</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lyman Laboratory of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Matthias</forename>
								<forename type="middle">R</forename>
								<surname>Gaberdiel</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lyman Laboratory of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Non-Supersymmetric Open String Theory and S-Duality</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="97011372-03-18">9701137v2 18 May 1997 January 1997</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>hep-th/9701137 HUTP-97/A003 BRX TH-402 This suggests that the two theories are related by S-duality. *</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A non-supersymmetric ten-dimensional open string theory is constructed as an orbifold of type I string theory, and as an orientifold of the bosonic type B theory. It is purely bosonic, and cancellation of massless tadpoles requires the gauge group to be SO(32) × SO(32). The spectrum of the theory contains a closed string tachyon, and open string tachyons in the (32, 32) multiplet. The D-branes of this theory are analyzed, and it is found that the massless excitations of one of the 1-branes coincide with the world-sheet degrees of freedom of the D = 26 bosonic string theory compactified on the SO(32) lattice.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The past two and a half years have seen a tremendous increase in our understanding of the dynamics of superstring theory [1]. In particular it has become apparent that the five tendimensional theories, together with an eleven-dimensional theory (M-theory), are different limits in moduli space of some unifying description. A guiding principle throughout has been the fact that supersymmetry guarantees that certain perturbative results are protected from corrections, and are therefore exact. Another important insight has been the realization that certain solitonic states admit a fully stringy description in terms of Dirichlet branes [2]. Similar advances have not occurred for non-supersymmetric theories, as they are not known to possess non-renormalization theorems. On the other hand, some of them have D-branes, and therefore should allow for an analogous analysis of their non-perturbative dynamics.</p>

				<p>In ten dimensions, there are a number of closed non-supersymmetric string theories which can be obtained as certain orbifolds of the four closed supersymmetric theories. These include the bosonic type A and type B theories, which are orbifolds by (−1) F S of type IIA and type IIB, where F S is the spacetime fermion number operator [3, 4]. There are furthermore seven non-supersymmetric heterotic string theories, which are obtained as orbifolds by (−1) F S · y from the two heterotic theories, where y is an automorphism of the weight lattice [4] (see also [5, 6, 7]); these theories are uniquely characterized by their gauge group, and the different possible groups are SO</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(32), E 8 × SO(16), SO(24) × SO(8), (E 7 × SU (2)) 2 , SU (16) × U (1), E 8</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and SO(16) × SO(16). All of these theories, except for the last one, have tachyons. By analyzing modular properties it has been shown that these are the only consistent nonsupersymmetric closed string theories in ten dimensions which can be obtained from a free fermionic construction [6]. It is well known that there is also an open supersymmetric theory in ten dimensions, the socalled type I theory with N = 1 supersymmetry and gauge group SO(32). It can be obtained as an orientifold of type IIB [8, 9, 10, 11]. It is therefore natural to ask whether there exists an analogous non-supersymmetric open theory which may be obtained as an orientifold from type B. Furthermore, in view of the diagram,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>• • • • ? ? - type I type O type IIB type B Ω Ω (−1) F S (−1) F S</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the theory in question should also be an orbifold of the type I theory by (−1) F S . It is one of the aims of this paper to exhibit these two constructions, thereby describing this open string theory, which we shall call type O, and its D-branes in detail. This theory was first constructed by Bianchi and Sagnotti [12] from the orientifold point of view. 1 It will turn out that tadpole cancellation conditions require the gauge group of type O to be SO(32) × SO(32). Since type O theory is non-chiral, and actually free of fermions, the low-energy effective theory is trivially anomaly free.</p>

				<p>One of the best established strong/weak coupling dualities of supersymmetric theories is the duality of the heterotic SO(32) closed string theory with the type I theory [13, 14].</p>

				<p>Both theories have the same low-energy effective action, and in particular the same gauge group SO(32). The strongest piece of evidence for this duality is the fact that the type I theory possesses a 1-brane, whose massless excitations coincide with the world-sheet degrees of freedom of the heterotic string [14]. Type O has gauge group SO(32) × SO(32), and if its strong coupling dual is yet another string theory, the analogy to the previous case suggests that this string theory is closed and that it has gauge group SO(32) × SO(32). The only candidate is the D = 26 bosonic string theory compactified to ten dimensions on the SO(32) lattice. Analyzing the branes of type O, we find that the theory has four different 1-branes, and that the massless excitations of one of them indeed reproduce the world-sheet excitations of the bosonic string theory in 26 dimensions compactified on the SO(32) weight lattice. (The degrees of freedom of this 1-brane can be thought of as corresponding to roughly double the excitations of the heterotic string.) Furthermore, the two theories have identical tachyonic spectra, and parts of the massless spectra agree. On the other hand, the D = 26 bosonic theory has additional scalars, and type O has an additional massless 2-form, but as we are considering non-supersymmetric theories, there is a priori no reason why the low-energy effective degrees of freedom should match up. We regard this as evidence for the proposal that the strong coupling limit of the type O theory is the 26 dimensional bosonic theory compactified on the SO(32) weight lattice. To our knowledge this is the first evidence for a duality between non-supersymmetric theories, although the D = 26 bosonic string, together with the superstrings and the supermembrane, has already made an appearance as a possible target of the (2, 1) heterotic string [15]. If true, this duality would indicate that these non-supersymmetric string theories might be nonperturbatively consistent despite having tachyons. It would also suggest that string duality does not necessarily rely on supersymmetry. The paper is organized as follows. In section 2 we explain how the type O theory can be obtained as the orbifold of type I. We analyze the tadpole condition carefully, and explain why the gauge group is SO(32) × SO(32). In section 3 we demonstrate that the theory can also be obtained as an orientifold of type B. In particular, we show that the open strings necessary to cancel the tadpoles can be obtained from boundary states of the type B theory which are invariant under world-sheet parity. In section 4 we analyze the massless excitations of the 1- branes of this theory, and show that for one of them they coincide with the world-sheet degrees of freedom of the bosonic string in 26 dimensions compactified on the SO(32) lattice. We also analyze the tachyonic and massless degrees of freedom of both theories. In section 5 we make some conclusive remarks, and we have included three appendices, where we give details of the various D-brane calculations.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Type O as a Type I Orbifold</head>

				<p>The simplest way to realize type O theory is as an orbifold of type I string theory. Some of the features of the resulting type O string theory, such as the appropriate open string GSO projection, are easy to see from this point of view. Other features, such as the precise D-brane spectrum, are easier to analyze from the orientifold point of view discussed in the next section.</p>

				<p>Let us thus begin by reviewing type I open string theory.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.1">Review of Type I string theory</head>

				<p>Recall that type I string theory consists of unoriented open strings with GSO projection</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 (1 + (−1) F ) in both the Ramond (R) and Neveu-Schwarz (NS) sectors, and unoriented closed strings with GSO projection 1 4 (1 + (−1) F )(1 + (−1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>F ) in the R-R, NS-NS, R-NS and NS-R sectors, resulting in an N = 1 supersymmetric theory. The physical states of the unoriented strings must also be invariant under the action of the world-sheet parity operator Ω, which on the closed string sector is defined by [16]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ωα µ n Ω = α µ n Ωψ µ r Ω = ψ µ r Ω ψ µ r Ω = −ψ µ r , (2.1) so that Ωψ µ r ψ ν r Ω = ψ ν r ψ µ r , (2.2) and Ω|0 N S ⊗ |0 N S = |0 N S ⊗ |0 N S Ω|S α R ⊗ | S β R = −|S β R ⊗ | S α R , (2.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where |S α R and | S β R are states in the spinor representation 8 s ⊕ 8 c . These conventions are chosen so that in the NS-NS (R-R) sector the symmetric (anti-symmetric) combinations are invariant under Ω. Thus the massless closed string sector consists of the metric G µν , dilaton Φ, R-R 2-form A µν , and their super-partners. The massless sector of the unoriented open string consists of the SO(N ) gauge field A a µ and its super-partner. Cancellation of the massless tadpoles requires N = 32, and thus the gauge group to be SO(32) [17, 18, 19]. This can also be understood as an anomaly cancellation condition in the low-energy effective action [20]. Type I string theory contains Dirichlet p-branes for p = 1, 5, 9. This follows, for example, from the fact that type I can be understood as the orientifold of type IIB string theory, together with the transformation properties of the various boundary states in the type IIB theory (see the analogous analysis for type O in section 3.2). From this point of view, tadpole cancellation requires the inclusion of 32 9-branes in the vacuum which give rise to the appropriate Chan- Paton factors for the open strings.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Type O string theory</head>

				<p>Now let us gauge the Z Z 2 symmetry group of the type I theory corresponding to a 2π rotation in space. Because of the spin-statistics theorem, this transformation is equivalently described by (−1) F S . The effect of the corresponding orbifold in string theory is to remove all the fermions from the spectrum, namely the R sector of the open string and the R-NS and NS-R sectors of the closed string, thus completely breaking supersymmetry. The resulting untwisted sector is given by unoriented open strings in the NS sector and unoriented closed strings in the R-R and NS-NS sectors, with the same GSO projections (and Chan-Paton factors) as before. For the closed strings we have to introduce a twisted sector in the standard way, where again the orbifold projection removes all fermions. This twisted sector is most easily described in the Green-Schwarz formulation following [4]. It corresponds to (unoriented) strings which close only up to a transformation by (−1) F S . This means that the spacetime spinors S and S are both anti-periodic. The lowest state in this sector is a tachyon, and the next states are given by the massless states S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α −1/2 |0 ⊗ S β −1/2 |0 . (2.4) Here S α −1/2 |0 and S β −1/2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>|0 are states in the same spinor representation, which is of opposite chirality to the physical spinor representation in the untwisted sector; in the RNS formalism, these states therefore correspond to states in the NS-NS and R-R sectors, where we choose the opposite GSO projection from above, namely</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 4 (1 − (−1) F )(1 − (−1) F ).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The spectrum of the orbifolded theory is thus purely bosonic, and consists of unoriented open strings in the NS sector with GSO projection</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 (1 + (−1) F ), and unoriented closed strings in the R-R and NS-NS sectors with GSO projection 1 2 (1 + (−1) F + F ).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Only states invariant under Ω are physical, so in particular the massless fields are given in the open string sector by vectors A a µ in the adjoint representation of SO(32), and in the closed sector by the metric G µν , dilaton Φ, and two R-R 2-forms A 1 µν , A 2 µν from the anti-symmetric combinations of 8 s ⊗ 8 s and 8 c ⊗ 8 c . In addition there is a closed string tachyon with α ′ O M 2 = −2.</p>

				<p>To analyze whether this is a consistent string theory, we have to check whether the massless tadpoles vanish. Recall that anomalies in the low-energy effective theory are not an issue since there are no chiral fields. However, as pointed out in [18], there are more fundamental reasons to cancel tadpoles; in particular the R-R tadpole must vanish to satisfy the equation of motion of the ten-form gauge field. The NS-NS (dilaton) tadpole is less severe, as it can, in principle, be removed by a shift of the background (Fischler-Susskind mechanism) [21], but this introduces a spacetime-dependent coupling constant; in the following we shall therefore attempt to cancel both the NS-NS and R-R massless tadpoles. Unlike the situation in type I string theory, where the total vacuum amplitude vanishes because of supersymmetry, this will not happen in our case. As a consequence, we have to analyze the tadpoles in the R-R and NS-NS sectors separately. The relevant contributions to the one-loop vacuum amplitude are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A C = ∞ 0 dt 2t Tr open e −2πtL 0 (−1) F S P GSO open 1 2 A M = ∞ 0 dt 2t Tr open e −2πtL 0 (−1) F S P GSO open Ω 2 A K = ∞ 0 dt 2t Tr closed e −2πt(L 0 + L 0 ) (−1) F S P GSO closed Ω 2 , (2.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>corresponding to the cylinder, Möbius strip, and Klein bottle, respectively. In order to extract the massless tadpoles we must perform a modular transformation, relating the loop channel calculation to a tree channel calculation involving the exchange of closed strings between either boundary or crosscap external states. It is useful to summarize the effect of the modular transformation in a &quot; translation table &quot; , relating the contributions in the tree channel to the corresponding contributions in the loop channel. This correspondence depends on which sectors are actually present in the theory, as well as on the GSO projection in each sector. As a consequence, the translation table is different for type O theory, where it is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Type O tree channel loop channel Cylinder R ⊗ R N S; 1 2 (−1) F × 1 2 N S ⊗ N S N S; 1 4 Möbius strip R ⊗ R 0 N S ⊗ N S N S; 1 2 (1 + (−1) F ) × 1 2 Ω Klein bottle R ⊗ R 0 N S ⊗ N S (R ⊗ R + N S ⊗ N S); 1 2 (1 + (−1) F + F ) × 1 2</trash>

					<figDesc>Ω , compared with the corresponding table for type I theory [18]</figDesc>
					<trash>Type I tree channel loop channel Cylinder R ⊗ R N S; 1 2 (−1) F × 1 2 N S ⊗ N S (N S − R); 1 4 Möbius strip R ⊗ R R; − 1 2 × 1 2 Ω N S ⊗ N S N S; 1 2 (1 + (−1) F ) × 1 2 Ω Klein bottle R ⊗ R (R ⊗ R + N S ⊗ N S); 1 4 ((−1) F + (−1) F ) × 1 2 Ω N S ⊗ N S (R ⊗ R + N S ⊗ N S); 1 4 (1 + (−1) F + F ) × 1 2 Ω .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The different factors for the Klein bottle amplitudes for type O theory compared to type I theory deserve some comment. In the type I theory, the GSO projection in the closed string sector is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 4 (1 + (−1) F + (−1) F + (−1) F + F</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>); the NS-NS tree channel contribution corresponds to the first and the last term in the loop channel trace, and the R-R tree channel contribution corresponds to the second and the third term in the loop channel trace. On the other hand, for the type O theory the GSO projection in the closed string sector is just</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 (1 + (−1) F + F ), and</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>therefore there is no R-R tree contribution, and the NS-NS tree contribution is twice as large. In the type O case, only the cylinder has a R-R contribution, and it is therefore clear that it must cancel by itself. The cylinder corresponds to the tree channel amplitude involving two boundary 9-branes. As we have already 32 9-branes in the theory (which now carry only bosonic open string excitations), the only way to cancel the R-R tadpole is to introduce an equal number of anti-9-branes, as branes and anti-branes carry opposite R-R charge. This means, in particular, that the relevant gauge group will be a product group SO(N ) × SO(N ), where N ≥ 32. (As will become apparent from the discussion of the next section, the lowlying excitations of open stings stretching between branes and branes, and anti-branes and anti-branes are massless vectors, whereas open strings stretching between branes and antibranes have an open string tachyon, and no massless excitations. As we are considering an unoriented theory, the vectors give rise to an SO(N ) group.) In order to decide whether there is a solution for N , we have to analyze the various contributions to the massless NS-NS tadpole. From the table above we see that the NS-NS vacuum amplitudes are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A N SN S C = 1 4 ∞ 0 dt 2t Tr N S e −2πtL 0 A N SN S M = 1 4 ∞ 0 dt 2t Tr N S e −2πtL 0 (1 + (−1) F )Ω A N SN S K = 1 4 ∞ 0 dt 2t Tr N SN S+RR e −2πt(L 0 + L 0 ) (1 + (−1) F + F )Ω . (2.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The cylinder trace is a straightforward computation which is similar to the type I case except for the absence of the R sector open strings</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A N SN S C = G C 4 ∞ 0 dt 2t (8π 2 t) −5 f 3 (e −πt ) 8 f 1 (e −πt ) 8 . (2.7)</trash>

					<figDesc>Here G C is the group factor for the cylinder, which for the gauge group SO(N ) × SO(N ) is G C = (2N ) 2 , and the functions f i and their modular properties are given in eqs. (C.1,C.2) of appendix C. The Möbius strip trace is exactly the same as in the type I case</figDesc>
					<trash>A N SN S M = G M 4 ∞ 0 dt 2t (8π 2 t) −5 f 2 (ie −πt ) 8 f 1 (ie −πt ) 8 , (2.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where G M is the group factor for the Möbius strip, which in our case is G M = −2N . The Klein bottle trace is twice what it is in type I; the action of Ω in the closed string trace (2.1,2.3) entails that only states which are left-right symmetric contribute, for which (−1) F + F is automatically +1. Furthermore, because of the relative minus sign in the action of Ω on the R-R and NS-NS ground states, the two sectors appear with opposite sign, and the resulting expression has the structure of the difference of an open string NS trace and an open string R trace, both without any (−1) F insertions. Using the abstruse identity (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C.3), we thus find A N SN S K = 1 2 ∞ 0 dt 2t (4π 2 t) −5 f 4 (e −2πt ) 8 f 1 (e −2πt ) 8 , (2.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and there is no group factor. To extract the singular behavior at t = 0 we substitute in the integrals</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>l =      1/2t cylinder 1/8t Möbius strip 1/4t Klein bottle , (2.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and perform the appropriate modular transformation, thus obtaining the tree channel expression for the NS-NS vacuum amplitude</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A N SN S = −(8π 2 ) −5 dl 2 G C 2 f 3 (e −2πl ) 8 f 1 (e −2πl ) 8 + 32G M f 2 (ie −2πl ) 8 f 1 (ie −2πl ) 8 + 32 2 f 2 (e −2πl ) 8 f 1 (e −2πl ) 8 . (2.11)</trash>

					<figDesc>The l → ∞ behavior of the modular functions is manifest from their definition (C.1). The relevant terms in the expression in brackets are then</figDesc>
					<trash>1 2 G C e 2πl + 4(G C + 4 · 32G M + 4 · 32 2 ) = 2N 2 e 2πl + 16(32 − N ) 2 , (2.12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have inserted the actual values of the group theory factors. The first term is the tachyon tadpole, which we expect in a theory with a closed string tachyon, and the other terms correspond to the massless NS-NS tadpole that we want to cancel. We can see directly that the massless tadpole cancels for N = 32. Type O string theory is thus a theory of unoriented open and closed strings with a gauge group SO(32) × SO(32). Its massless fields consist of a vector transforming in the adjoint representation A a µ , a metric G µν , a dilaton Φ, and a pair of 2-forms A 1,2 µν . The ground state in the closed string sector is a singlet tachyon with α ′ O M 2 = −2. In addition, open strings stretching between 9-branes and anti-9-branes give rise to a (32, 32) multiplet of tachyons with α ′ O M 2 = −1/2. The allowed D-branes appear to be the same as in type I, namely p = 1, 5, 9, except that now they do not carry fermionic modes. We will see in the following section that this is not quite correct, and that the D-brane spectrum of type O string theory is somewhat richer. A first indication of this is the fact that type O has two 2-forms in the R-R sector. This will be important for the 1-brane analysis in section 4.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Type O as an Orientifold of Type B</head>

				<p>In this section we want to discuss how type O theory can also be obtained as an orientifold of type B theory. The construction is in close analogy to the realization of type I as an orientifold of type IIB. As in the previous construction, massless tadpoles will have to be cancelled, and this will require the inclusion of 32 9-branes and 32 anti-9-branes. The actual calculation will be identical to the one we have performed in the previous section, and we shall therefore not repeat it. The point of the analysis of this section is to demonstrate that there exist appropriate branes leading to the correct open string sector in the spectrum of type O theory. Along the way, we shall also, more generally, discuss the different Dirichlet branes of type O and type B theory.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.1">Type B</head>

				<p>string theory and its D-branes Type B string theory is obtained from type IIB just as type O was from type I, namely by a (−1) F S orbifold [4]. It is a purely bosonic theory of oriented closed strings in the R-R and NS-NS sectors with GSO projection 1 2 (1 + (−1) F + F ). The NS-NS sector contains a tachyon with α ′ M 2 = −2. The massless fields consist of a metric G µν , Kalb-Ramond field B µν , and dilaton Φ in the NS-NS sector, and two scalars A 1,2 , two 2-forms A 1,2 µν , and a self-dual and an anti-self-dual 4-form A + µνλρ , A − µνλρ in the R-R sector. The R-R sector of type B is effectively doubled compared to the R-R sector of type IIB, and in the NS-NS sector there is an additional tachyon. We therefore expect that there exist additional boundary states (compared to the boundary states of type IIB) which are charged under the additional R-R fields, and which couple to the tachyon (rather than to the dilaton and the graviton). As we are dealing with a non-supersymmetric theory, the NS-NS and R-R sectors are in essence independent, and we expect that the theory will have four boundary p-branes for each odd p (as well as four anti-p-branes). 2 The explicit construction and analysis of the boundary states can be found in appendix A. A general boundary p-brane state is of the form α + |Bp, + N SN S + α − |Bp, − N SN S + β + |Bp, + RR + β − |Bp, − RR , (3.1) where p is odd, and α ± and β ± are arbitrary normalization constants. (For type IIB, the normalization constants are fixed up to an overall scale, as explained in appendix A.) However, physical D-brane states also have to satisfy another consistency condition. 3 The additional condition comes from the fact that open strings which end on the same boundary state should be able to close, and that the resulting state should already be in the closed-string spectrum of the theory. For the type B theory, this implies, in particular, that the corresponding open string states should only be in the NS sector, as the open R sector excitations are fermions which are absent in the type B theory. We also expect, from the analogy of the situation for type IIB and type I, that the GSO projection of the NS open string sector should agree with the GSO projection in the type O theory. The implications of these two constraints can be easily read off from the analysis of appendix C. The open string sector corresponding to strings beginning and ending on the same boundary state is determined by the loop channel corresponding to the tree channel amplitude of the boundary state with itself. The first constraint implies then that the NS-NS sector contribution is either |Bp, + N SN S or |Bp, − N SN S , but not a linear combination of them. Likewise, the second constraint determines the correct relative normalization of the NS-NS and the R-R boundary states in (3.1) up to a phase. The actual linear combination of |Bp, + RR and |Bp, − RR for the R-R boundary state is not fixed by this consideration, as</p>

				<p>Bp, +|e −lH |Bp, − RR = 0 , (3.2) and so |Bp, + RR and |Bp, − RR do not mix. We can therefore, without loss of generality, restrict ourselves to considering R-R boundary states which are either |Bp, + RR or |Bp, − RR .</p>

				<p>We should mention that the two different R-R boundary states for given p are charged with respect to the two different (p + 1)-forms in the R-R sector. This leaves us with a total of four Dirichlet branes for each odd p in type B string theory, given by |Bp, η N SN S + |Bp, η ′ RR , (3.3) where η and η ′ are independently + or −. We denote these by |Bp, ηη ′ . For anti-D-branes the sign in front of the R-R boundary state is reversed.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.2">Type O string theory and its D-branes</head>

				<p>In taking the orientifold projection of type B string theory we remove the states which are not invariant under Ω, and add 9-branes as necessary to cancel the massless tadpoles arising from the non-orientable world-sheets. Given the Ω transformation conventions of (2.1) and (2.3), the first step leaves us with a massless sector consisting of a metric G µν , dilaton Φ, and two 2-forms A 1,2 µν , and the closed-string tachyon of α ′ O M 2 = −2. The massless tadpole calculation is the same as in the previous section, and requires the addition of 32 9-branes and 32 anti-9-branes for cancellation.</p>

				<p>The spectrum of D-branes in type O string theory consists of those boundary states of the form (3.3) which are invariant under Ω. In the NS-NS sector it follows from the explicit expression for the boundary state (A.3) together with eqs. (2.1-2.3) that Ω|Bp, η N SN S = |Bp, η N SN S .</p>

				<p>To understand the action in the R-R sector, we have to analyze carefully how Ω acts on the boundary ground state |B7, + 0 RR which is defined in appendix A; this is explained in appendix B. We then find that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ω|Bp, η 0 RR = Ω 9 µ=p+3 (ψ µ 0 + iη ψ µ 0 )|B7, η 0 RR = − 9 µ=p+3 (−iη)(ψ µ 0 + iη ψ µ 0 )|B7, η 0 RR = −(−iη) 7−p |Bp, η 0 RR , (3.4) and it follows that Ω|Bp, η RR = −(−iη) 7−p |Bp, η RR . (3.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Thus only Dirichlet p-branes with p = 1, 5 and 9 survive the orientifold projection. (The same analysis also applies to the orientifold of type IIB theory, thus establishing that type I theory has p-branes for p = 1, 5, 9.) For the type O theory, there are four branes of each such p as explained in the previous subsection.</p>

				<p>The theory therefore contains 9-branes and anti-9-branes, and we are able to cancel the massless tadpoles by the same calculation as in section 2. Indeed, as explained before, there are four different Dirichlet 9-branes, and we can cancel the massless tadpoles by including 32 9-branes of a given type, as long as the anti-9-branes are of the same type. To see that this will reproduce the calculation of section 2, we note that the open strings stretching between two 9-branes (3.3) of the same type are in the GSO-projected NS sector (with the GSO projection being 1 2 (1 + (−1) F )), whereas the open strings stretching between a 9-brane and an anti-9- brane of the same type are in the NS sector with projection</p>

				<figure>
					<head>1 2</head>

					<figDesc>(1 − (−1) F ), as follows from the calculations of appendix C. This matches up with the assumed structure of the open string sector in the calculation of section 2. This argument also shows that the open strings stretching between branes and branes or anti-branes and anti-branes give rise to massless vector fields in the adjoint representation of SO(32) × SO(32). On the other hand, the open strings stretching between branes and antibranes do not have massless excitations, but give rise to tachyons of α ′ O M 2 = −1/2 in the (32, 32) multiplet of SO(32) × SO(32). This completes the description of the spectrum of the type O theory. From the point of view of the orientifold, there exist other solutions which cancel the massless tadpoles (but which cannot be obtained as orbifolds of type I). We can consider (32 − n) 9-branes of type |B9, ++ and n 9-branes of type |B9, −−, together with their respective anti-branes. The resulting open string theory then possesses the gauge group SO(32 − n) × SO(n) × SO(32 − n) × SO(n), open</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>string tachyons in the (32 − n, 1, 32 − n, 1) and (1, n, 1, n) representations, and massless fermions in the (32 − n, n, 1, 1), (32 − n, 1, 1, n), (1, n, 32 − n, 1) and (1, 1, 32 − n, n) representations of the gauge group, as well as the same closed string spectrum as type O. The fermions are excitations of open strings stretching between branes or anti-branes of type |B9, ++ and branes or anti-branes of type |B9, −−; in particular these open strings cannot close, and there is no inconsistency with the fact that the closed string sector does not contain fermions. These theories were first constructed by Bianchi and Sagnotti [12]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">A proposal for the strong coupling limit</head>

				<p>In this section we want to analyze the massless excitations of the 1-branes of type O string theory. These are described as in [14] by two different types of open strings: those beginning and ending on the 1-brane, and those beginning on the 1-brane and ending on the background 9-branes. As regards the former, all different 1-branes are alike; it follows from the analysis in appendix C (cf. (C.10,C.11,C.14,C.15)) that the open string corresponding to the tree diagram B1, ηη ′ |e −lH |B1, ηη ′ is in the NS sector with the GSO projection 1 2 (1 + (−1) F ); there are thus no tachyonic modes, and eight massless bosonic modes in 8 v . By the same argument as in [14], there are then eight left-moving and eight right-moving scalars on the world-sheet of the 1-brane. On the other hand, the open string sector relating the 1-branes to the background 9-branes depends on the relation between the 1-brane and the background 9-branes. In defining the type O theory, we have to make a choice, by taking the 9-branes (and anti-branes) to be of a definite type. To fix notation for the following, let us assume, without loss of generality, that these 9-branes are all of type |B9, ++. For the 1-branes of type |B1, ++ there are no additional massless modes, as the contribution from the R-R boundary state vanishes (C.16), and as the contribution from the NS-NS boundary state is purely massive (C.12). The massless excitations of the |B1, ++ 1-brane are then eight left-and right-moving scalars, and therefore do not constitute the world-sheet degrees of freedom of a critical string theory. For the 1-branes of type |B1, −+ there are additional massless modes in the twisted R sector (where all eight transverse bosons and fermions are half-integrally moded), coming from the NS-NS boundary state (C.13). Each twisted R sector has two massless states, which, in a Lorentz-covariant formulation, transform as a spinor of the two longitudinal directions. The two states have opposite chirality, and therefore correspond to a left-moving fermion and a right-moving fermion on the world-sheet of the 1-brane. As there are 32 9-branes and 32 anti-9-branes, we end up with a total of 64 left-moving and 64 right-moving fermions, as well as the eight left-and right-moving scalars. Again, this does not correspond to a critical string theory. For |B1, +−, the situation is similar to the previous case, except that the additional massless modes come from the R-R boundary state, and are in the twisted R sector with (−1) F (C.17). This gives the same number of massless fermions as in the previous case, although the significance of the various minus signs in the trace is unclear. At any rate, this does not give a critical string theory. This leaves us with the |B1, −− 1-brane, for which we have a contribution to the massless states both from the R-R sector, and the NS-NS sector (C.13,C.17). Altogether, we get 32 open strings in the twisted R sector with 1 2 (1 + (−1) F ) (from the 32 9-branes), and 32 open strings in the twisted R sector with 1 2 (1 − (−1) F ) (from the 32 anti-9-branes). Each of these sectors has a single massless fermion of definite chirality, the 9-branes giving rise to fermions of opposite chirality to those coming from the anti-9-branes. We therefore obtain in addition to the eight left-and right-moving scalars, 32 left-and 32 right-moving fermions in the (32, 1) and (1, 32) of SO(32) × SO(32), respectively. These are precisely the world-sheet excitations of the 26-dimensional bosonic string theory compactified on the SO(32) lattice. As we do not have supersymmetry at our disposal to extend tree-level calculations to strong coupling, we do not know how the tension of the different 1-branes behave at strong coupling.</p>

				<p>However, if we are willing to assume that the strong coupling regime of the type O theory is again described by another string theory, the above analysis seems to suggest that at strong coupling the |B1, −− 1-brane becomes light, and that the strong coupling limit of the type O theory is described by the 26 dimensional bosonic theory compactified on the SO(32) lattice. 4 A similar analysis can also be performed for the (SO(32−n)×SO(n)) 2 theories, which were discussed at the end of section 3. In this case, none of the 1-branes have massless excitations which correspond to the world-sheet degrees of freedom of any (known) critical string theory. This is reassuring, as these theories have massless fermions in addition to a rank 32 gauge group. As discussed in sections 2 and 3, type O theory has one singlet tachyon of mass squared α ′ O M 2 = −2, and a (32, 32) multiplet of tachyons of mass squared α ′ O M 2 = −1/2. On the other hand, we can describe the 26 dimensional bosonic theory compactified on the SO(32) lattice in terms of eight (left-moving) bosonic oscillators α µ n , where µ = 2, . . . , 9 and n ∈ Z Z, and 32 (left-moving) fermionic oscillators ψ a r , where a = 1, . . . 32, r ∈ Z Z + 1/2 in the NS sector and r ∈ Z Z in the (purely massive) R sector, together with their corresponding right-movers. It is then easy to see that the theory has one (singlet) tachyon of mass squared α ′ B M 2 = −4 (the ground state |0 ⊗ |0), and a (32, 32) multiplet of tachyons of mass squared α ′ B M 2 = −2, corresponding to the states ψ a</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>−1/2</head>

				<p>ψ b −1/2 |0 ⊗ |0. The tachyons of the two theories therefore appear in the same representations. As regards massless states, both theories have a metric, Kalb-Ramond field and dilaton, and the same gauge fields. (For the 26 dimensional theory, these are the states of the form α</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µ −1 α ν −1 |0⊗|0 and ψ a −1/2 ψ b −1/2 α µ −1 |0⊗|0, α µ −1 ψ a −1/2 ψ b −1/2 |0⊗|0.) In particular, the D = 26</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>bosonic theory is the only known closed string theory which can have a perturbative gauge group of rank 32. Apart from these (rather surprising) coincidences, there are also differences in the massless spectrum. 5 In particular, the 26 dimensional theory has massless scalars in the bi-adjoint representation of SO(32) × SO(32), that are not present in type O; these are the states of the form ψ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a −1/2 ψ b −1/2 ψ c −1/2 ψ d −1/2 |0 ⊗ |0 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the other hand, type O theory has an additional 2-form in the R-R sector, which couples to the two 1-branes |B1, ±+. As regards the former, these scalars are the moduli of the Narain lattice describing the compactification. As has been pointed out by Ginsparg and Vafa [23], the cosmological constant is critical for the points in the moduli space of Narain lattices for which the theory has maximal gauge group (such as SO(32) × SO(32)), and it is therefore conceivable that the theory is frozen at such a point for large coupling. This would imply that these scalars become massive at large coupling. As regards the additional 2-form, the situation is rather less clear.</p>

				<p>coupling limit of type O theory is this D = 26 bosonic theory. We find it surprising that the tachyonic states match. On the other hand, we do not yet have a good understanding of the mismatch of the massless scalars and 2-forms, or the behavior of the 1-branes of type O at strong coupling.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Appendix</head>

				<p>We want to explain a novel way of doing D-brane calculations. In this approach the boundary states are defined as coherent states in the closed string theory (as in [18, 19]), and the physical D-brane states are then identified by certain consistency conditions, rather than by their supersymmetry transformation properties. We shall recover many of the known results for D-branes of the type IIA/IIB/I theories, but we can also apply these techniques to the non-supersymmetric type A/B/O theories.</p>

				<p>A The coherent state approach to D-branes</p>

				<p>In the following we shall work in the RNS formalism in light-cone gauge. This will make the formulae more manageable as there will be no ghost contributions. On the other hand, this approach limits us to considering only D-branes whose dimensions differ at most by eight. Furthermore, the two light-cone directions must have Dirichlet boundary conditions, so that we are really describing (p + 1)-instantons rather than Dirichlet p-branes [26]. Since all boundary states have at least two Dirichlet directions, we will be considering p = −1, . . . , 7. These instantons are related by a double Wick rotation to D-branes, and we shall therefore assume that the results of our calculations apply equally to the corresponding Dirichlet branes [26].</p>

				<p>In the following we shall always refer to the boundary states as D-branes. A boundary state corresponding to a Dirichlet p-brane |Bp, η satisfies</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(α µ n − α µ −n )|Bp, η = 0 (ψ µ r − iη ψ µ −r )|Bp, η = 0 µ = 2, . . . , p + 2 , (A.1) (α µ n + α µ −n )|Bp, η = 0 (ψ µ r + iη ψ µ −r )|Bp, η = 0 µ = p + 3, . . . , 9 , (A.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have chosen µ = 0, 1 as the light-cone directions. Here η = ±1 (the two different signs correspond to different spin structures), the ψ µ r are the half-integrally (integrally) moded fermionic oscillators of the left-moving NS(R) sector, and the tilde denotes the corresponding right-moving mode. The solution to these equations is given by the coherent state</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|Bp, η = N exp    ∞ n=1   − 1 n p+2 µ=2 α µ −n α µ −n + 1 n 9 µ=p+3 α µ −n α µ −n   +iη ∞ r&gt;0   − p+2 µ=2 ψ µ −r ψ µ −r + 9 µ=p+3 ψ µ −r ψ µ −r      |0 ⊗ |0 , (A.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where N is a normalization constant which, for later convenience, we choose to be N = 1 in the NS-NS sector and N = 4i in the R-R sector, and |0 ⊗ |0 is the ground state of either the NS-NS or the R-R sector. In the latter case, this ground state will be denoted by |Bp, η 0 RR ; it satisfies (A.1) and (A.2) with r = 0. The boundary states in the NS-NS sector transform under (−1) F and (−1)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F as (−1) F |Bp, η N SN S = −|Bp, −η N SN S (−1) F |Bp, η N SN S = −|Bp, −η N SN S , (A.4) as (−1) F |0 N S = −|0 N S .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To analyze the situation in the R-R sector, we introduce the modes</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ψ µ ± = 1 √ 2 ψ µ 0 ± i ψ µ 0 , which satisfy the anti-commutation relations {ψ µ ± , ψ ν ± } = 0 and {ψ µ + , ψ ν − } = δ µν , as {ψ µ 0 , ψ ν 0 } = { ψ µ 0 , ψ ν 0 } = δ µν and {ψ µ 0 , ψ ν 0 } = 0. The chirality operators in light-cone gauge are Γ 9 = ψ 2 0 · · · ψ 9 0 and Γ 9 = ψ 2 0 · · · ψ 9 0 , and they satisfy Γ 9 ψ µ ± = −ψ µ ∓ Γ 9 Γ 2 9 = 1 Γ 9 ψ µ ± = ψ µ ∓ Γ 9 Γ 2 9 = 1 . From (A.1) we see that the state |B7, + 0 RR satisfies the equation ψ µ − |B7, + 0 RR = 0 for all µ = 2, . . . , 9. We fix the normalization of |B7, − 0 RR by defining |B7, − 0 RR = Γ 9 |B7, + 0 RR . It then follows that Γ 9 |B7, + 0 RR = i 8 Γ 9 |B7, + 0 RR = |B7, − 0 RR Γ 9 |B7, + 0 RR = |B7, − 0 RR Γ 9 |B7, − 0 RR = |B7, + 0 RR Γ 9 |B7, − 0 RR = |B7, + 0 RR . Next we define |Bp, ± 0 RR = 9 µ=p+3 ψ µ ± |B7, ± 0 RR , and then ψ µ ∓ |Bp, ± 0 RR = 0 for µ = 2, . . . , p + 2, and ψ µ ± |Bp, ± 0 RR = 0 for µ = p + 3, . . . , 9. Furthermore, Γ 9 |Bp, ± 0 RR = |Bp, ∓ 0 RR Γ 9 |Bp, ± 0 RR = (−1) 7−p |Bp, ∓ 0 RR .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This implies that the action of (−1) F Γ 9 and (−1) F Γ 9 on the boundary state is given by (−1) F Γ 9 |Bp, η RR = (−1) 7−p |Bp, −η RR</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(−1) F Γ 9 |Bp, η RR = |Bp, −η RR . (A.5) Taking (A.4) and (A.5</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) together, we can now deduce which boundary states are compatible with the GSO projection. In the type II theories, physical states in the NS-NS (R-R) sector are invariant under (−1) F (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(−1) F Γ 9 ) and (−1) F ((−1) F Γ 9 ) separately; in the NS-NS sector, the only physical state is |Bp N SN S = 1 2 |Bp, + N SN S − |Bp, − N SN S , (A.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is physical for all p, whereas in the R-R sector, the only potentially physical state is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|Bp RR = 1 2 |Bp, + RR + |Bp, − RR , (A.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is physical for even p in the case of type IIA, and odd p in the case of type IIB. By a similar argument to the one following eq. (3.1), the open-closed consistency condition requires the physical D-branes to be sums of NS-NS and R-R boundary states. This then implies that the D-branes of type IIA (type IIB) only exist for even (odd) p. This restriction can also be understood from the fact that these D-branes preserve 1/2 of the spacetime supersymmetry [27].</p>

				<p>In the bosonic type A/B theories, the states only have to be invariant under (−1) F + F ((−1) F + F Γ 9 Γ 9 ). It then follows that in both the NS-NS and the R-R sectors the states |Bp, + and |Bp, − are already GSO-invariant, and thus form allowed boundary states. In each sector there are therefore two independent boundary states; this reflects the fact that the massless fields of the R-R sector are doubled compared to the corresponding type II theories, and that the NS-NS sector contains in addition a tachyon.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B Orientifolded D-branes</head>

				<p>In this short appendix we want to determine how Ω acts on the ground state of the D-brane coherent state |B7, + 0 RR in the R-R sector. (The action on the other ground states follows then easily, as explained in section 3.2.) Let us first introduce a convenient description for the ground states of the R-R sector. Given the oscillators ψ µ 0 , ψ ν 0 , where µ, ν = 2, . . . , 9, satisfying the anti-commutation relations as described in appendix A, we define</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>b j ± = 1 √ 2 ψ 2j 0 ± iψ 2j+1 0 j = 1, 2, 3, 4 b j ± = 1 √ 2 ψ 2j 0 ± i ψ 2j+1 0 j = 1, 2, 3, 4 , (B.1) which satisfy the anti-commutation relations {b i * , b j * } = 0, {b i ± , b j ± } = { b i ± , b j ± } = 0, {b i + , b j − } = { b i + , b j</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>− } = δ ij . We can then consider the space of states created by the action of b i + and b j + from a vacuum state |0 which satisfies b i − |0 = b j − |0 = 0. The R-R ground state space of the type B theory is then the subspace of this space for which the difference between the number of b i + and b j + generators is even.</p>

				<p>Next we introduce the generators</p>

				<p><formula>B i,± = b i + ± i b i + C i,± = b i − ± i b i − . (B.2)</formula></p>

				<p>The generators B i,± anti-commute among themselves, and we can equivalently describe the R-R ground state space of the type B theory as being generated from |0 by the action of an even number of B i,± . (The generators C i,± all annihilate |0.)</p>

				<p>In terms of these generators, the boundary ground state |B7, + 0 RR satisfies the equations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B i,− |B7, + 0 RR = C i,− |B7, + 0 RR = 0 , where i = 1, 2, 3, 4. The unique solution for |B7, + 0 RR is therefore (up to normalization) |B7, + 0 RR = 4 i=1 B i,− |0 , (B.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>as C i,− anti-commutes with B j,− , and annihilates |0. We can now easily read off how Ω acts on this state. First of all, it is clear that Ω|0 = −|0, as |0 is a left-right symmetric state and we have chosen the convention (2.3). (This convention, together with (B.4) below, implies that the anti-symmetric combination of the R-R ground states are invariant under Ω.) Furthermore, because of (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.1), ΩB i,− Ω = iB i,− , (B.4) and thus Ω|B7, + 0 RR = −|B7, + 0 RR .</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C Loop and tree calculations</head>

				<p>In this appendix we collect the relevant formulae for relating the loop-and tree-channel calculations involving the boundary states. Let us start by introducing some notation which will prove convenient for the following. Following Polchinski and Cai [18] (see also [2]), we define</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f 1 (q) = q 1/12 ∞ n=1 (1 − q 2n ) f 2 (q) = √ 2q 1/12 ∞ n=1 (1 + q 2n ) f 3 (q) = q −1/24 ∞ n=1 (1 + q 2n−1 ) f 4 (q) = q −1/24 ∞ n=1 (1 − q 2n−1 ) . (C.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For q = e −πt , the limit t → ∞ corresponds to q → 0, for which the asymptotic expansion of these functions is obvious. The modular transformation which we shall use repeatedly in the following is q → q = e −π/t , and the relevant relations are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f 1 ( q) = √ tf 1 (q) f 2 ( q) = f 4 (q) f 3 ( q) = f 3 (q) f 4 ( q) = f 2 (q) . (C.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(We should mention that these identities only hold up to a root of unity whose eighth power is +1.) The functions also satisfy the so-called &quot; abstruse identity &quot;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f 3 (q) 8 − f 2 (q) 8 − f 4 (q) 8 = 0 . (C.3) The relevant amplitudes are then A(p, η; q, η ′ ) = 1 2 ∞ 0 dl 2 Bp, η|e −lH |Bq, η ′ , (C.4) where H = −2p + p − + (p ⊥ ) 2 + M 2 , M 2 = nN</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>n and N n is the number operator for the oscillators. Using the explicit form for the various boundary states, the inner products can be determined; they take the form of a trace in an open string theory, reflecting the fact that the boundary state relates left-and right-movers. In more detail, we find that in the NS-NS sector</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Bp, η|e −lH |Bq, η ′ N SN S = T r N S   e −2lL 0 (ηη ′ ) F q+2 µ=p+3 (−1) Bµ   , (C.5) where we have assumed (without loss of generality) that p ≤ q, and where (−1) Bµ is defined by (−1) Bµ α ν m (−1) Bµ = α ν m µ = ν −α ν m µ = ν (−1) Bµ ψ ν r (−1) Bµ = ψ ν r µ = ν −ψ ν r µ = ν . (C.6)</trash>

					<figDesc>Here α ν m and ψ ν r are the bosonic and fermionic modes in the open string trace. We shall mainly be interested in the case of p = q, for which the above simplifies to</figDesc>
					<trash>Bp, η|e −lH |Bp, η N SN S = f 3 (e −2πl ) 8 f 1 (e −2πl ) 8 , Bp, η|e −lH |Bp, −η N SN S = f 4 (e −2πl ) 8 f 1 (e −2πl ) 8 . (C.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The other case of interest is q = p + 8, which in our case corresponds to p = −1 and q = 7. In the main body of the paper we mainly use the following results for p = 1, q = 9; this can be deduced from the results for p = −1, q = 7 using appropriate space-time and Wick rotations [26]. In this case we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Bp, η|e −lH |B(p + 8), η N SN S = 16 f 4 (e −2πl ) f 2 (e −2πl ) 8 , (C.8) Bp, η|e −lH |B(p + 8), −η N SN S = 16 f 3 (e −2πl ) f 2 (e −2πl ) 8 . (C.9)</trash>

					<figDesc>The amplitude then becomes in the first case of (C.7)</figDesc>
					<trash>A(p, η; p, η) N SN S = 1 2 ∞ 0 dl 2 f 3 (e −2πl ) f 1 (e −2πl ) 8 = 1 8 ∞ 0 dt t t −5 f 3 (e −πt ) f 1 (e −πt ) 8 , (C.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have made the substitution l = 1/2t, and used the modular transformation properties of the functions f i . We can interpret this as a loop calculation in the (unprojected) NS sector of an open string theory. By similar manipulations we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A(p, η; p, −η) N SN S = 1 8 ∞ 0 dt t t −5 f 2 (e −πt ) f 1 (e −πt ) 8 , (C.11) which corresponds to the R sector of an open string. Similarly, we have A(p, η; p + 8, η) N SN S = 2 ∞ 0 dt t t −1 f 2 (e −πt ) f 4 (e −πt ) 8 , (C.12) and A(p, η; p + 8, −η) N SN S = 2 ∞ 0 dt t t −1 f 3 (e −πt ) f 4 (e −πt ) 8 . (C.13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These correspond in the first case to the NS open string sector, where all eight transverse coordinates are twisted, i.e. the fermionic modes are integral and the bosonic modes are halfintegral . The second case is the R open string sector, where all eight transverse coordinates are twisted. The ground state energy of the first open string is +1/2, and that of the second open string is 0. In the R-R sector, a similar analysis is possible, and the results are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A(p, η; p, η) RR = − 1 8 ∞ 0 dt t t −5 f 4 (e −πt ) f 1 (e −πt ) 8 , (C.14) A(p, η; p, −η) RR = 0 , (C.15) A(p, η; p + 8, η) RR = 0 , (C.16) A(p, η; p + 8, −η) RR = −2 ∞ 0 dt t t −1 , (C.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where, as always, t = 1/2l. These correspond in the first case to the NS open string sector with (−1) F , and in the last case to the R open string sector with (−1) F , where all eight transverse coordinates are twisted. The ground state energy in the first case is −1/2, and in the last case it is 0.</p>

				<p>Finally, we should mention that we can use the above techniques to derive the forces between the various D-branes, thereby recovering the results of [28, 26, 29]. For example, it follows from (C.5) and a similar formula for the R-R sector, that two type II branes whose dimensions differ by 4 do not exert any force in either the NS-NS or R-R sectors onto each other.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We thank Carlo Angelantonj for drawing our attention to this paper.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The corresponding statement also holds for the type A theory for even p. 3 We thank Joe Polchinski for drawing our attention to this problem. (See [22] for related issues.) We also thank Cumrun Vafa and Barton Zwiebach for helpful discussions on this point.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> We should mention that the |B1, −− 1-brane seems to be the only 1-brane for which the massless excitations correspond to any known string theory, even if we relax the open-closed consistency condition and allow arbitrary linear combinations of boundary states. 5 This does not rule out the proposed strong coupling relation, as the theory in question is not supersymmetric; in particular, there is no reason why the masses of the states should not get renormalized.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>We would like to thank Joe Polchinski, Cumrun Vafa and Barton Zwiebach for very helpful discussions. We would also like to thank Wolfgang Eholzer, Michael Green, Albion Lawrence, Zurab Kakushadze and Steve Naculich for helpful comments. O.B. is supported in part by the NSF under grants PHY-93-15811 and PHY-92-18167, and M.R.G. is supported by a NATO- Fellowship and in part by NSF grant PHY-92-18167.</p>
			</div>

		<div type="annex">
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusions</head>

				<p>In this paper we have analyzed an open string theory in ten dimensions which can be obtained as an orbifold of type I, and as an orientifold of type B, which itself is an orbifold of type IIB. This theory is a special case of a class of orientifolds which were first described by Bianchi and Sagnotti [12]. The open string theory, type O, has a closed string tachyon of α ′ O M 2 = −2 and open string tachyons of α ′ O M 2 = −1/2 in the (32, 32) multiplet of the gauge group SO(32) × SO(32). Apart from this gauge group, the other massless states are the dilaton, graviton, and two 2-forms. We have analyzed the D-branes of type B and of type O. These theories have essentially the same D-brane spectrum as type IIB and type I, respectively, apart from the fact that for every (allowed) p, type B and type O possess four distinct Dirichlet p-branes instead of just one. We have explained that there exists an additional consistency condition related to the compatibility of open and closed strings, which singles out certain boundary states as the physical D-branes.</p>

				<p>The relation of the four theories, type IIB, B, I and O, to each other has a natural interpretation in terms of F-theory [24]. By definition, compactification of F-theory on a torus is type IIB, and it has been argued in [25] that compactification of F-theory on a cylinder is type I. We can obtain the cylinder as a Z Z 2 -quotient of the torus, where the Z Z 2 group acts on the coordinates of the torus (x, y), x ∼ x + R x , y ∼ y + R y , as i x : (x, y) → (−x, y). This is consistent with the fact that type I can be obtained as the Z Z 2 orientifold of type IIB. There exist two quotient manifolds of the torus which do not have covariantly constant spinors, and it is natural to assume that compactification of F-theory on these will lead to nonsupersymmetric string theories in ten dimensions. One of them is the (closed) tetrahedron, which is the Z Z 2 quotient of the torus by the action (x, y) → (−x, −y), and the other is the (open) rectangle, which is the Z Z 2 × Z Z 2 quotient of the torus by the action of i x and i y , where i y is defined by (x, y) → (x, −y). Following the above reasoning, it is suggestive to identify the first theory with type B, the Z Z 2 orbifold of type IIB, and the second with type O, the Z Z 2 orientifold of type B or the Z Z 2 orbifold of type I. This picture is consistent as we can obtain the rectangle as a Z Z 2 quotient of the cylinder (by the action of i y ) and of the tetrahedron (by the action of i x ). From this point of view, it is suggestive to associate the gauge group SO(32) to a pair of opposite boundaries. The closed theories, type IIB and B, do not have any gauge fields, the cylinder theory (type I) has one pair of boundaries and gauge group SO(32), and the rectangle theory (type O) has two pairs of boundaries and gauge group SO(32)×SO(32). Obviously, this discussion is rather formal, and much more work is needed to substantiate these suggestions.</p>

				<p>We analyzed the massless excitations of the four 1-branes of type O, and found that for one of them, the excitations agree precisely with the world-sheet excitations of the bosonic string in D = 26 dimensions compactified on the SO(32) lattice. Furthermore, this D = 26 theory and type O have the same gauge group, the same tachyonic representations, and parts of the massless spectrum agree. We regard this as evidence for the proposal that the strong</p>

			</div>
		</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lectures on superstring and M theory dualities, hep-th/9607201; A. Sen, Unification of string dualities, hep-th/9609176</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Dou- glas Superstring dualities, Dirichlet branes and the small scale structure of space</title>
		<editor>J.H. Schwarz</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9610041" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to=" th" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Notes on D-branes, hep-th/9602052; J. Polchinski, TASI lectures on D-branes, hep-th</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Chaudhuri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Johnson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9611050" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spin structures in string theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Seiberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">276</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">272</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">String theories in ten dimensions without spacetime supersym- metry</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Dixon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Harvey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">274</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">93</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Alvarez-Gaumé</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ginsparg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Vafa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">An</forename>
				<forename type="middle">O</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">16) × O(16) heterotic string</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="page">155</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Classification of closed-fermionic-string models</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Kawai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Lewellen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H H</forename>
				<surname>Tye</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3794</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Higher level Kac-Moody representations and rank reduction in string models</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Forgá</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Horvá</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Palla</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Vecsernyé</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">308</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">477</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Open strings and their symmetry groups, in: Carg ese &apos;87 Nonperturbative quantum field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sagnotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>G. Mack et. al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Pergamon Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Background duality of open string models Strings on world-sheet orbifolds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Horava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">231</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">461</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New connections between string theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Dai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Leigh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mod. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2073</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dirichlet-branes and Ramond-Ramond charges</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4724</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the systematics of open-string theories); A. Sagnotti, Some properties of open-string theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Bianchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sagnotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">247</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="9509080" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">String theory dynamics in various dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">443</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9503124</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for heterotic-type I string duality</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">460</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">525</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9510169</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New principles for string/membrane unification</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kutasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Martinec</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">477</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">652</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9602049</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consistency conditions for orientifolds and D manifolds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Gimon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1667</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infinity cancellations in SO(32) superstring theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Green</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Schwarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">151</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consistency of open superstring theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">296</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">91</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loop corrections to superstring equa- tions of motion</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Callan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Lovelace</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Nappi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Yost</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">308</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">221</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anomaly cancellations in supersymmetric D = 10 gauge theory require SO(32)</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Green</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Schwarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">117</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dilaton tadpoles, string condensates and scale invariance, I and II</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Fischler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Susskind</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">171</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">173</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">262</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tensors from K3 orientifolds, hep-th/9606165</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toroidal compactification of nonsupersymmetric heterotic strings</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ginsparg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Vafa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">289</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">414</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for F theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Vafa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">469</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">403</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9602022</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compactifications of F theory on Calabi-Yau threefolds I and II</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Morrison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Vafa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">473</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">476</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="437" to="9603161" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Light-cone supersymmetry and D-branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Green</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gutperle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">476</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">484</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9604091</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Boundary states of D-branes and Dy-strings</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">460</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">351</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9510161</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">D-brane dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Bachas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">374</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9511043</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing D-branes to black branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Lifschytz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">388</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">720</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9604156</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
