<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1997-08">August 1997</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Michael</forename>
								<surname>Kuhlen</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: kuhlen@desy.de</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Max-Planck-Institut fürPhysik</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Werner-Heisenberg-InstitutFöhringerRing6</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-80805</postCode>
									<settlement>München</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1997-08">August 1997</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-ph/9709206v1 1 Sep 1997 MPI-PhE/97-21 hep-ph/9709206 QCD INSTANTONS AT HERA *</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Phenomenological aspects of chirality violating processes induced by QCD in-stantons in deep inelastic scattering are discussed. First instanton searches and the prospects for their experimental discovery at HERA are presented.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Since a long time it has been recognized that the standard model contains processes which cannot be described by perturbation theory, and which violate classical conservation laws like baryon number (B) and lepton number (L) in the case of the electroweak interaction, and chirality (Q 5 ) in the case of the strong interaction 1 . Such anomalous processes are induced by so-called instantons 2 . The name indicates that these are non-perturbative fluctuations that are confined to &quot; an instant &quot; in spacetime , with no corresponding free particle solutions for t → ±∞. The interest in instantons remained somewhat academic, as observable effects were predicted to exist only at extremely high energies of O(10 5 TeV), until it was discovered that their exponential suppression is much reduced by the emission of gauge bosons 3 . In electroweak theory with massive gauge bosons still rather high energies of O( 10 TeV) would be required, but not so in QCD with massless gluons and strong coupling. Instanton effects could play a rôle in QCD reactions already at present day colliders . Deep inelastic ep scattering at HERA is particularly interesting, because the virtuality of the photon probe Q 2 provides a hard scale for the instanton subprocess, which is needed for theoretically sound predictions 4,5,6 . Instanton effects have not yet been observed in nature. Their experimental discovery would be of fundamental significance for particle physics.</p>

				<p>In this report a short introduction to the basic theoretical ideas will be given. Instanton phenomenology in deep inelastic scattering (DIS) will be discussed, covering cross sections and event topologies. Finally, prospects for instanton searches and first results from the analysis of HERA data will be presented.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Instanton theory</head>

				<p>Instantons originate from the non-trivial topological structure of the vacuum in non-Abelian gauge field theories, where the vacuum is degenerate in the Chern-Simons number N CS . N CS is defined as an integral over the gauge fields A</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a µ with coupling g, N CS := g 2 16π 2 d 3 xǫ ijk A a i ∂ j A a k − g 3 ǫ abc A a i A b j A c k . (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Neighbouring vacua have the same (minimal) potential energy, but differ in their topological winding number N CS , and are separated by a potential barrier of height E B (fig. 1</p>

				<p><formula>). CS B E E N -1 tunnelling pert. 2 1 0 Fig. 1.</formula></p>

				<p>The structure of the vacuum. Instanton solutions represent tunnelling transitions between topological inequivalent minima, which cannot be reached perturbatively.</p>

				<p>The usual perturbative expansion of the scattering amplitudes in the coupling constant α around one minimum (fig. 1), conveniently represented by a series of Feynman graphs, does not allow for transitions between neighbouring minima. They may however occur classically when the energy E is large enough E &gt; E B , or by quantum mechanical tunnelling when E &lt; E B , corresponding to so-called instanton solutions of the classical field equations. The transition amplitude for the instanton–induced tunnelling process is exponentially suppressed ∝ exp(−4π/α), a very small number.</p>

				<p><formula>a) t s c c I + gauge bosons d t + µ d e + b u τ ν b) u * c c s g * e&apos; p I d u R R R R R R u d + gluons s R R γ e Fig. 2</formula></p>

				<p>. a) the electroweak interaction with ∆(B + L) = −6 and in b) the strong interaction with ∆Q 5 = 8.</p>

				<p>In the electroweak theory, the minimal barrier height is E B ≈ m W /α w = O(10TeV).</p>

				<p>Instanton transitions between vacua separated by ∆N CS (see fig. 2a for an example)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>would violate baryon (B) and lepton numbers (L = L e + L µ + L τ ) according to ∆(B + L) = −2 n gener. · ∆N CS , (2) but respect ∆(B − L) = 0 ∆L e = ∆L µ = ∆L τ = ∆B/3. (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>n gener. = 3 is the number of fermion generations.</p>

				<p>In instanton induced QCD reactions (see fig. 2b) chirality is violated. The chirality Q 5 is the difference between the number of left-and right-handed fermions, Q 5 = #L − #R. For n f active quark flavours, the selection rule is ∆Q 5 = 2 n f · ∆N CS . (4)</p>

				<p>The minimal barrier height is given by the hard scale of the process, e.g. E B = O(Q) for DIS 5 . The exponential suppression is less severe than in the electroweak case, because α s ≫ α w .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Instantons at HERA</head>

				<p>In recent years, it has been realized 5,6,7,8,9,10 that quantitative calculations are possible for processes induced by QCD instantons in DIS due to the presence of a hard scale, Q 2 . In DIS, events due to QCD instantons I (and anti-instantons I) are predominantly produced in a photon-gluon fusion processes a (Fig. 3</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>)</figDesc>
					<trash>γ * + g I → n f (q R + q R ) + n g g γ * + g I → n f (q L + q L ) + n g g. (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In each event, quarks and antiquarks of all n f active flavours are found, with n g gluons in addition.</p>

				<p>The kinematics is depicted in fig. 3. The DIS variables Bjorken x and Q 2 can be measured from the scattered electron, q = e − e ′ . A measurement of the other variables is more challenging. A measurement of the invariant mass of the hadronic system, excluding the remnant, would determinê s. If the outgoing &quot; current jet &quot; could be identified and measured, it&apos;s 4-momentum q ′′ would determine q ′ = q − q ′′ , and thus the variables x ′ and Q ′2 which characterise the instanton subprocess. In practice, when not all of the five independent invariants (for example x, Q 2 , x ′ , Q ′2 , ˆ s) can be measured, they are being integrated over. The instanton induced cross section is given by a convolution of the probability to find a gluon in the proton P g/p , the probability that the virtual photon splits</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>a</head>

				<p>Quark initiated processes have not yet been considered. Due to the large gluon content of the proton in the HERA domain at small x, they are expected to be of minor importance. In addition, they are expected to be suppressed by O(α</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I q&apos; q q&quot; g= P ξ W 2 P s&apos; s e e&apos; DIS variables: Q 2 := −q 2 x := Q 2 /(2P · q) W 2 := (q + P ) 2 = Q 2 (1 − x)/x ˆ s := (q + g) 2 ξ = x(1 + ˆ s/Q 2 ) Variables of instanton subprocess: Q ′2 := −q ′2 x ′ := Q ′2 /(2 g · q ′ ) s ′ := (q ′ + g) 2 = Q ′2 (1 − x ′ )/x</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>′ Fig. 3</head>

				<p>. Kinematics of instanton induced processes in DIS. The labels denote the 4-vectors of the particles. A virtual photon γ * (4-momentum q = e − e ′ ) emitted from the incoming electron fuses with a gluon (4-momentum g) from the proton (4-momentum P ). The gluon carries a fraction ξ of the proton momentum. The virtual quark q * entering the instanton subprocess has 4-momentum q ′ , and the outgoing quark from the γ * → qq splitting has 4-momentum q ′′ . The invariant masses squared of the γ * g and q * g systems arê s and s ′ . W is the invariant mass of the total hadronic system (the γ * p system). 0 ≤ x ≤ x/ξ ≤ x ′ ≤ 1 holds. For completeness, we note y :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= (P q)/(P e) = Q 2 /(sx), where s = (e + P ) 2 is the ep invariant mass squared. into a quark-antiquark pair in the instanton background P (I) q * /γ * , and the cross section σ (I) q * g (x ′ , Q ′2 ) of the instanton subprocess 6,7 . Multi-gluon emission enhances the cross section 3 σ (I) q * g;ng ∝ 1 n g ! 1 α s ng exp(−4π/α s ). (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The cross section of the instanton induced subprocess is then 6 :</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>σ</head>

				<figure>
					<trash>(I) q * g (x ′ , Q ′2 ) = ∞ ng=0 σ (I) q * g;ng ≈ Σ(x ′ ) Q ′2 4π α s (µ(Q ′ )) 21 2 exp −4π α s (µ(Q ′ )) F (x ′ ) . (7) Instanton-induced processes dominated by multi-gluon production: (I) q g; n g / 1 n g ! 1 s n g expff4== s g Exponentiates in total cross-section: Exponential suppression fa modiied by \Holy-Grail&quot; function F (x 0 ). In intermediate r 0:2::0:3 &lt; x 0 1, total cross-section exponentially growing decreasing x 0 . Due to inherent ambiguities can take result literally only for x 0 x 0 min &apos; 0:2 0:3 : II F(x&apos;) 1 valley 0.5 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 x&apos; ? S EEective renormalization scale (Q 0 ), (Q 0 ) = Q 0 s ((Q 0 ))=( should be large enough in order to have suuciently small coupling ) Q 0 &gt; 5 GeV : Fig. 4. The holy grail function F (x ′ ) 6 . For small s ′ (x</trash>

					<figDesc>′ ≈ 1), instanton perturbation theory is applied. The calculation with the valley method matches smoothly with the perturbative result. It depends critically on the functions F (x ′ ) (called the &quot; holy grail &quot; function ), which modifies the exponent in the suppression factor exp(−4π/α s ), and on Σ(x ′ ), which depends on F (x ′ ). There exists also a scale dependence due to the choice of the renormalization scale µ(Q ′ ). F (x ′ ) can be estimated reasonably well (see fig. 4</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>) for x ′ not too small, x ′ 0.2 6 . The extrapolation to lower values of x ′ is unreliable due to inherent ambiguities. In addition, multiinstanton effects should be avoided by limiting the instanton size ρ I (the spatial region occupied during the interaction)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>to ρ I &lt; 2 GeV −1 with a cut-off Q ′2 25 GeV 2 6,7 . That requirement ensures also that α s (µ(Q ′ )) stays small enough to apply instanton perturbation theory. The resulting instanton induced subprocess cross section σ (I) q * g (x ′ , Q ′2 ) (see fig. 5) is peaked at Q ′ ≈ 5</trash>

					<figDesc>GeV and exponentially grows with decreasing x ′ . The integrated instanton induced ep DIS cross section (see fig. 6</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>) is sizeable; for x &gt; 0.001 and x ′ &gt; 0.2 it is of O(10 pb). The cross section is approximately scaling (depends only on x, not on Q 2 for large Q 2 ) 7 . It grows towards small x, and increases dramatically when the lower x ′ cut-off is relaxed. Eventually higher order instanton effects have to dampen the growth of the cross section.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a) Resulting x 0 dependence: 0 500 1000 1500 2000 2500 0.2 0.25 0.3 0.35 0.4 Λ = 145 MeV q g * σ (I) (x&apos;,Q&apos;=5 GeV) [nb] x&apos; Lower x 0 cut absolutely necessary. x 0 cut can be enforced, for example, by cutting x x Bj =z Q 2 =(Q 2 + s);</trash>

					<figDesc>from below, where z is the momentum fraction of the proton carried by the gluon and s is the</figDesc>
					<trash>g c.m. energy. (dashed: x 0:1; points: x 0:12) 6 b) Resulting Q 0 dependence: 0 500 1000 1500 2000 2500 3000 0 5 10 15 20 Λ = 145 MeV q g * σ (I) (x&apos;=0.2, Q&apos;) [nb]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Q&apos; [GeV]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Lower Q 0 cut not mandatory (thanks to the chosen r scale). { F (I) 2 g infrared insensitive. Do not have to factor out collinear divergenc distributions. { F (I) 2 g (x; Q 2 ) independent of Q 2 for Q 2 ! 1, i.e. sc Check of the Monte Carlo</trash>

					<figDesc>calculation of the inst contribution to the eP cross-section at HERA: { \Theory&quot;: Take gluon distribution at a xed reference scale. Use the asymptotic scaling result for F</figDesc>
					<trash>(I) 2 g (x; Q 2 ). Perform all the necessary integrations analytically. { Monte Carlo: Use same gluon distribution. In order to simulate the scaling limit (Q 2 ! 1), us Carlo very small = 0:2 145 MeV. Take the cross-section from the Monte Carlo output Fig. 5. The instanton subprocess cross section 9 for q * g → hadrons as a function of a) x ′ for Q ′ = 5 GeV and b) Q ′ for x ′ = 0.2.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Two kinematic regions have to be distinguished. For x ′ &gt; 0.2 the predictions are relatively safe, allowing the instanton theory to be tested. Either instantons are discovered at the predicted level – including the substantial theoretical uncertainties, which still need to be quantified –, or the theory has to be revised. For x ′ &lt; 0.2 the cross section presumably continues to grow, but the extrapolation is extremely uncertain. For a discovery, this is the favourable region due to the large cross section. A negative result however cannot be turned against the theory, it would rather restrict the unknown behaviour of F (x ′ ) at small x ′ . Most promising is the kinematic region of small Bjorken-x, because both the total DIS cross section and the predicted fraction of instanton induced events increase towards small x (see fig. 9b).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Experimental signatures</head>

				<p>In the theoretically safe region, x ′ &gt; 0.2, the expected fraction of instanton events in all DIS events is of O(10 −3 − 10 −4 ) (compare fig.9b), too small to be detected in inclusive cross section measurements (i.e. the structure function F 2 ). Instead,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Result: x&apos; = 0.1 min x&apos; = 0.2 min x&apos; = 0.3 min x Bj–min Bj–min σ HERA Bj (x&apos;&gt;x&apos; , x &gt; x , y &gt; 0.1) min Bj [pb]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(</p>

				<p><formula>Inst.) 0.001 0.002 0.005 0.01 0.0001 0.001 0.01 0.1 1 10 100 1000 10000</formula></p>

				<p>Nice agreement between \theory&quot; (lines) and QCDINS 1.4.1 (points). { Very strong dependence on x 0 min . { Thorough investigation of inherent renormalization-and factorizationscale dependencies is presently under way.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="8">Fig. 6</head>

				<p>. The instanton induced DIS cross section 9 ep → e ′ X integrated over Bjorken x &gt; x min , y &gt; 0.1, and over the regions Q ′ &gt; 5 GeV and x ′ &gt; x ′ min as indicated. dedicated searches for the characteristic features of instanton events in the hadronic final state have to be performed. A Monte Carlo generator (QCDINS 11 ) to simulate the hadronic final state of instanton events in DIS is available. In general, the event shape predictions are more stable than the rate predictions, because poorly known factors cancel. The instanton event properties can be contrasted with predictions from event generators for normal DIS events (ARIADNE 12 , LEPTO 13 and HERWIG 14 ) which give an overall satisfactory description of the DIS final state properties 15 .</p>

				<p>In the q * g rest frame 2n f − 1 quark and antiquarks and n g gluons are emitted isotropically from the instanton subprocess. n g is Poisson distributed with</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>7,9 n g ≈ 2π α s x ′ (1 − x ′ ) dF (x ′ ) dx ′ . (8)</trash>

					<figDesc>After hadronization, this leads to a spherical system with a high multiplicity of hadrons, depending mainly on the available centre of mass energy √ s ′ = Q</figDesc>
					<trash>′ 1/x ′ − 1. For a typical situation (x ′ = 0.2, Q ′ = 5 GeV ⇒ √ s ′ = 10 GeV), n g = O(2).</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>About n p = 10 partons and n = 20 hadrons are expected. The expected parton momentum spectrum is semi-hard 5 with transverse momentum p T ≈ (π/4)( √ s ′ /n p ). Hadronic final state properties are conveniently being studied in the centre of mass system (CMS) of the incoming proton and the virtual boson, i.e. the CMS of the hadronic final state. Longitudinal and transverse quantities are calculated with respect to the virtual boson direction (defining the +z direction). The pseudorapidity η is defined as η = − ln tan(θ/2), where θ is the angle with respect to the virtual photon direction. When boosted to the CMS, the hadrons emerging from the instanton subprocess occupy a band in pseudorapidity of half width ∆η ≈ 1, which is homogeneously populated in azimuth 5 .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The characteristics of instanton events by which they can be distinguished from normal DIS events are therefore: high multiplicity with large transverse energy; spherical event configuration (apart from the current jet); and the presence of all flavours (twice!) that are kinematically allowed in each event. One would therefore look for events which in addition to the other characteristics are rich in K 0 s, charm decays , secondary vertices, muons etc.. In general, the strength of instanton signals in the hadronic final state increases somewhat towards low x ′ and large Q ′2 due to the increasing &quot; instanton mass &quot;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>√ s ′ = Q ′ 1/x ′ − 1. a) η 1/N dE T /dη (GeV) &lt;Q 2 &gt;= 13.1 GeV 2 &lt;x&gt;= 0.37 10 -3 INSDIS Q&apos; 2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 x&apos; &gt; 0.2 x&apos; &gt; 0.1 excl. x&apos; &gt; 0.2 H1 Data nDIS 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 b) E T (GeV) 1/N dN/dE T (1/GeV) 0 &lt; η &lt; 2 &lt;x&gt;= 1.1 10 -3 &lt;Q 2 &gt;= 14.3 GeV 2 nDIS INSDIS Q&apos; 2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 x&apos; &gt; 0.2 x&apos; &gt; 0.1 10 -3 10 -2 10 -1 0 10 20 30 40 50 60 70 80 Fig. 7</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. Transverse energy E T in the hadronic CMS 16 . a) The E T flow vs. η. The proton remnant direction is to the left. The standard QCD model (nDIS=ARIADNE) and different instanton scenarios are confronted with the H1 data 17 . The excluded scenario 16 with an instanton fraction f I &gt; 11.8% for x ′ &gt; 0.2 is indicated. b) The E T distribution, where the transverse energy is measured in the CMS rapidity bin 0 &lt; η &lt; 2, for two instanton scenarios, and the standard QCD model (nDIS=ARIADNE). The plots are normalized to the total number of events N that enter the distributions.</p>

				<p>The &quot; instanton band &quot; shows up in the flow of hadronic transverse energy E T as a function of η (fig. 7a). It&apos;s height and position depends on x ′ and Q ′2 (and also on x and Q 2 ). In normal DIS events on average an E T of 2 GeV per η unit is observed.</p>

				<p>In instanton induced events, that number may go up to 10 GeV for low x ′ . A possible search strategy could involve the E T distribution in a selected rapidity band (fig. 7b), looking for high E T events in the tail of the distribution 18,16 .</p>

				<p>Further discrimination can be obtained 18 from the fact that for instanton events the E T should be distributed isotropically, while normal DIS events are jet-like, in particular for large E T .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>One defines E out := min i p i · n E in := i p i · n ′ . (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The sum runs over all final state hadrons i with momentum p i . n is the unit vector perpendicular to the virtual photon axis which minimizes E out and thus defines the event plane. n ′ lies in the event plane and is normal to both n and the virtual photon axis. It is easy to show that for an ideal isotropic &quot; instanton decay &quot; , E out = √ s ′ /2 18 .</p>

				<p>The &quot; instanton mass &quot; √ s ′ can thus be reconstructed experimentally (fig. 8a). Normal DIS events, either &quot; 1+1 &quot; or &quot; 2+1 &quot; jet events (the +1 refers to the unobserved proton remnant) are contained in the event plane, E out ≪ E in , in contrast to instanton events with E out ≈ E in (see fig. 8b).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>event&quot;-basis, E out = min ^ i n X k j ~ p k ^ i j ; by choice of ^ i normal to the P direction. { Standard (2+1) jet events (boson gluon fusion) have small E out = O(jet width), while for I-induced events 2E out p s 0 W I large! (left Fig.) 0 10 20 30 40 50 60 0 10 20 30 40 50 60 0 0.02 0.04 0.06 0.08 0.1 0.12 0.14 -30 -20 -10 0 10 20 30 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 0 5 10 15 20 25 30 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 0 5 10 15 20 25 30 { E out vs. E in distributions in P c.m. system for 0:001 &lt; x &lt; 0:01, 0:1 &lt; y &lt; 0:6 and 20 &lt; Q 2 &lt; 70 GeV 2 . Normal \DIS&quot; events (upper right Fig.)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, I-induced events (lower right Fig.). 12 Fig. 8. a) The correlation between 2 · E ′ out and the &quot; instanton mass &quot; , W I = √ s ′ (top), and the resolution for √ s ′ that can be achieved (bottom) 18 . The primes indicate additional cuts in η to minimize higher order QCD radiation which may wash out the relation between E out and</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>√ s ′ . b) E ′ out vs. E ′ in for normal (top, HERWIG) and instanton induced events (bottom, QCDINS) 18 . Both distributions are taken in the hadronic CMS for events with 0.001 &lt; x &lt; 0.01, 0.1 &lt; y &lt; 0.6 and 20 GeV 2 &lt; Q 2 &lt; 70 GeV 2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Instanton events are characterized by a large particle density localized in rapidity.</p>

				<p>In normal DIS events there are about 2 charged particles per unit of pseudorapidity 19 , rather uniformly distributed in η. For a low x ′ cut-off, that number goes up to 10 in the peak of the instanton band 16 . Very sensitive to instanton events is the charged particle multiplicity distribution 16 , see fig. 9a. A significant fraction of the instanton events would lead to charged multiplicities which are very unlikely to be found in normal DIS events. Furthermore, particle-particle correlation functions should be influenced by instanton effects 20 .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Searches for instanton processes</head>

				<p>The fact that instanton events look very different from the expectation for standard QCD events can be exploited to search for instanton signals in the HERA data. One strategy is to compare the shape of hadronic final state distributions to the expectation from standard QCD events (nDIS) with an admixture of instanton events (INSDIS) of fraction f I . In case the measured distribution agrees with the standard QCD expectation, a limit on the fraction of instanton induced events in DIS f I &lt; f lim can be set. The caveat of this method is that one has to make an</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a) 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 18 20 0 10 20 30 40 n P(n) (%) INSDIS, Q&apos; 2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 x&apos; &gt; 0.2 x&apos; &gt; 0.1 H1 data, corr. nDIS 185 GeV &lt; W &lt; 220 GeV 1&lt; η &lt; 5 b) x f I (%) Instanton Scenario Q&apos; 2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 x&apos; &gt; 0.2 6.8 8.6 15.3 28.6 34.7 Limits from dE T /dη 23 27.9 INSDIS prediction Multiplicity 10 -3 10 -2 10 -1 1 10 10 -4 10 -3 10 -2 Fig. 9</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. a) The probability distribution P (n) of the charged particle multiplicity n from the CMS pseudorapidity range 1 &lt; η &lt; 5 for events with 185 GeV &lt; W &lt; 220 GeV. Shown are the unfolded H1 data 21 , the expectation from a standard DIS model (nDIS=ARIADNE)), and the predictions for instanton events with different cut-off scenarios 16 . b) The maximally allowed fraction f lim of instanton induced events in DIS for Q ′2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 and x ′ &gt; 0.2 from transverse energy flows and the multiplicity distribution as function of x 16 . Regions above the lines are excluded at 95% C.L..</p>

				<p>The numbers give the average Q 2 values in GeV 2 for the x bins. The theory prediction, calculated with QCDINS 11 , for 10 GeV 2 &lt; Q 2 &lt; 80 GeV 2 is superimposed (full line, label INSDIS). tion on what standard QCD looks like. In particular at small x that issue is under debate 22,23,24 . There exists a danger that an instanton effect is tuned or explained away by stretching the standard QCD predictions by generator tuning, introducing for example BFKL effects etc.. A good understanding of standard QCD will be crucial for the positive identification of instanton effects.</p>

				<p>In the first search for instanton events 25 an anomalous K 0 yield has been looked for. For x &gt; 10 −3 about 0.12 K 0 mesons (including K 0 ) have been measured per event and unit pseudorapidity, with a relatively flat η distribution. For instanton events with x ′ &gt; 0.2, a peaked distribution with about 0.55 K 0 per event and unit η is expected. From the comparison with standard QCD event generators 12,13,14 and the instanton generator 11 an upper limit of f I &lt; f lim = 6% at 95% C.L. is obtained 25 .</p>

				<p>The charged particle multiplicity distribution P (n) in high energy reactions can often by described by a negative binominal distribution (NBD). Also the DIS data are relatively well described by NBDs 21 . The multiplicity distribution from the CMS interval 1 &lt; η &lt; 5 for events with W = 80 − 115 GeV (corresponding to x &gt; 0.0007) can be parametrized with an NBD of mean n = 6.90 ± 0.33. Possible deviations from an NBD allow for an instanton fraction of at most f I =2.7% at 95% C.L. 21 .</p>

				<p>Other measured event shapes have been systematically analysed in terms of their</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>10 -4 10 -3 10 -2 6 7 8 9 10 20 30 40 50 60 70 80 90 Q 2 [GeV 2 ] x Instanton scenario Q&apos; 2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 x&apos; &gt; 0.2 Limits from Multiplicity f lim = 0.5 % σ lim = 75 pb f lim = 0.62 % σ lim = 75 pb f lim = 0.43 % σ lim = 43 pb f lim = 0.5 % σ lim = 41 pb E e = 1 2 G e V Θ e =1 73 ο W 2 = 4 4 0 0 G e V 2 Limits from dE T /dη f lim = 12.6 % σ lim = 603 pb f lim = 8.5 % σ lim = 624 pb f lim = 11.8 % σ lim = 868 pb f lim = 8.2 % σ lim = 473 pb f lim = 8.4 % σ lim = 606 pb f lim = 5.6 % σ lim = 398 pb f lim = 5.9 % σ lim = 344 pb f lim = 6.8 % σ lim = 336 pb f lim = 4.7 % σ lim = 213 pb Fig. 10</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. 95% C.L. limits on instanton production with Q ′2 &gt; 25 GeV 2 and x ′ &gt; 0.2 16 . The crosssection limits (σ lim ) together with the maximally allowed instanton fraction f lim are shown in the x –Q 2 plane. They are obtained from the E T flow analysis (open fields), and from the multiplicity analysis (shaded fields) with their numbers at the right edge. The boundaries implied by the analysis cuts of the energy flow analysis in the angle and energy of the scattered electron, θ e &lt; 173 • and E e &gt; 12 GeV , and by the requirement W 2 &gt; 4400 GeV 2 are indicated. sensitivity to instanton events 16 , and their dependence on the kinematic variables x, Q 2 , x ′ , Q ′2 . The most sensitive distributions were the transverse energy flows 17 , the pseudorapidity distribution of charged particles and their p T spectra 19 . For example, the E T flow has been measured over a wide range of x and Q 2 , allowing to extend the search region down to x = 0.0001. From a shape analysis 16 (see fig. 7), instanton fractions f I between 5 and 13 % can be excluded for x ′ &gt; 0.2 (see figs. 9b, 10). For lower x ′ the signal is more prominent, and somewhat better limits are obtained. The fact that H1 21 did not observe any events above a certain multiplicity n max has been exploited 16 to place more stringent limits on instanton production b . A significant fraction of instanton induced events would have multiplicities n &gt; n max b The previous limits from the H1 multiplicity analysis 21 were derived from the shape of the multiplicity distribution for n &lt; n max .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Table 1.</head>

					<figDesc>Limits on QCD instantons in DIS. A fraction f I &gt; f lim of instanton induced events in DIS is excluded at 95% C.L..</figDesc>
					<trash>analysis DIS kinematics covered instanton scenario limit Q 2 (GeV 2 ) x W (GeV) Q ′2 (GeV 2 ) x ′ f lim K 0 25 10 – 70 0.001 – 0.01 95 – 230 1 0.2 6 % multipl. 21 10 – 80 0.0007 – 0.012 80 – 115 1 0.2 2.7 % E T flows 16 5 – 50 0.0001 – 0.01 65 – 230 &gt; 25 &gt; 0.2 5 – 13 % multipl. 16 10 – 80 0.0001 – 0.01 80 – 220 &gt; 25 &gt; 0.2 0.4 – 0.6 % (compare fig. 9a</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). Instanton fractions f I &gt; 0.4 − 0.6% can therefore be excluded for x ′ &gt; 0.2 (see figs. 9b, 10), and somewhat lower f I values for a lower cut-off x ′ &gt; 0.1 16 .</p>

				<p>This search method has the advantage that, in contrast to the previous shape comparisons , it does not rely on assumptions for standard QCD event topologies, since no background needs to be subtracted. Unavoidable of course is the dependence on the expected instanton event shape, which may be even more uncertain than the standard QCD event shapes. The available bounds on instanton production are summarised in tab. 1. The most stringent limits for the theoretically &quot; safe &quot; scenario x ′ &gt; 0.2 are still a factor 20 higher than what is predicted from the instanton theory, see fig. 9b. Limits for other scenarios can be found in 16 . For x ′ &gt; 0.1 they are already below the naive extrapolation into the theoretically uncertain region, providing a constraint for the theory and the holy grail function F (x ′ ).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Conclusion</head>

				<p>Instanton transitions, a yet unexplored facette of non-abelian gauge field theories, have been discussed. While in the electroweak theory the B + L violating effects induced by instantons are expected only at energies 10 TeV , their chirality violating pendant in QCD could lead to striking signatures already at present day colliders.</p>

				<p>In DIS at HERA, these are a high particle multiplicity with large transverse energy localized in rapidity, and s, c and possibly b quarks in the final state. The expected contribution to DIS events is of O(10 −3 − 10 −4 ), with substantial theoretical uncertainties . First analysis of HERA data taken in the years ≤ 1994, corresponding to an integrated luminosity of O(1.3 pb −1 ), are still a factor ≈ 20 above the prediction. With higher statistics data samples (O(25 pb −1 ) up to summer 1997) and improved search strategies, a fundamental discovery at HERA appears to be in reach. It might be possible to exploit also other reactions than DIS, such as photoproduction, where the hard scale needed for reliable instanton calculations could be provided by the p T of a jet.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="7">Acknowledgements</head>

				<p>I would like to thank B. Kniehl and G. Kramer for their invitation to this beautifully set workshop, and I thank T. Carli, A. Ringwald and F. Schrempp for the exciting time we are having with instantons, and for their critical reading of the manuscript.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="8">References</head>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* invited talk at the Ringberg Workshop &quot; New Trends in HERA Physics &quot; , Schloß Ringberg, Tegernsee , May 1997.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> s ) with respect to the gluon initiated processes.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3432</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Belavin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Polyakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Schwarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yu</forename>
				<surname>Tyupkin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<biblScope unit="page">59</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="330" to="343" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Balitskii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Braun</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">314</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DESY 94-197, hep-ph/9411217</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Int. Sem. &quot; Quarks 94</title>
		<meeting>. of Int. Sem. &quot; Quarks 94<address><addrLine>Vladimir, Russia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">170</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DESY 96-203, hep-ph/9610213</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. IXth Int. Sem. &quot; Quarks 96</title>
		<meeting>. IXth Int. Sem. &quot; Quarks 96<address><addrLine>Yaroslavl, Russia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. in prep</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DESY 96-125, hep-ph/9607238</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Workshop DIS 96 on &quot; Deep Inelastic Scattering and Related Phenomena</title>
		<editor>G. D&apos;Agostini and A. Nigro</editor>
		<meeting>. of the Workshop DIS 96 on &quot; Deep Inelastic Scattering and Related Phenomena<address><addrLine>Rome</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page">481</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the DIS97 workshop</title>
		<editor>J. Repond and D. Krakauer</editor>
		<meeting>. of the DIS97 workshop<address><addrLine>Chicago</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="115" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">DESY 97-114, hep-ph/9706400, to appear in the Proc</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>J. Repond and D. Krakauer</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<pubPlace>Chicago</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>of. the DIS97 workshop</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Carli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gibbs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kuhlen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. preparation. version. used: QCDINS 1.4.1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Lö</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Comp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>version. used: 4.08</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Ingelman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Proc</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physics at HERA</title>
		<editor>W. Buchmü and G. Ingelman 1366</editor>
		<editor>G. Ingelman, A. Edin and J. Rathsman</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="057" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Marchesini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comp. Phys. Comm</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">465</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Brook</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Workshop on Future Physics at HERA</title>
		<editor>G. Ingelman, A. DeRoeck and R. Klanner</editor>
		<meeting>. of the Workshop on Future Physics at HERA<address><addrLine>Hamburg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page">613</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DESY 97-151, MPI-PhE/97-18, hep-ex/9708008, to appear in Nucl</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Carli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kuhlen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. B</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H1</forename>
				<surname>Collab</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Aid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">356</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gibbs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Greenshaw</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Milstead</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ringwald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Schrempp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Proc</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Future Physics at HERA</title>
		<editor>G. Ingelman, A. DeRoeck and R. Klanner</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">509</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H1</forename>
				<surname>Collab</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Adloff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">485</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Kuvshinov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Shulyakovsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Acta Physica Polonica B28</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">1629</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H1</forename>
				<surname>Collab</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Aid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">573</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">72</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New Trends in HERA Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Carli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Ringberg Workshop</title>
		<meeting>. of the Ringberg Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New Trends in HERA Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Grindhammer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Ringberg Workshop</title>
		<meeting>. of the Ringberg Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kuhlen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">the Proc. of the Madrid Workshop on low x Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H1</forename>
				<surname>Collab</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Aid</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">480</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
