<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Dirac confinement of a heavy quark-light quark system (Q, ¯ q) in high orbital angular momentum states</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1998-01-04">4 Jan 1998</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<forename type="middle">A</forename>
								<surname>Avila</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Facultad de Ciencias</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UAEM</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>62210</postCode>
									<settlement>Morelos</settlement>
									<region>Cuernavaca</region>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Dirac confinement of a heavy quark-light quark system (Q, ¯ q) in high orbital angular momentum states</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1998-01-04">4 Jan 1998</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The Regge behaviour of the solutions of a Dirac hamiltonian describing a heavy quark-light quark system in high orbital angular momentum states is analyzed. It is found that the solutions of a scalar confining potential are physically admissible while those of a vector confining potential are not. It is concluded that with a Dirac hamiltonian a scalar confining potential is preferred over a vector confining potential for any value of the orbital angular momentum.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>Recently there has been given a discussion about the nature of the confinement potential in a heavy quark -light quark (Q, ¯ q) system [1]-[2]. In Ref. [1] an analysis was performed from a phenomenological point of view using diverse techniques. These were the calculation of the Isgur-Wise (IW) function [3] as predicted by both the Dirac and the no-pair equation, the study of the classical returning points for s-waves (all of the above for low orbital angular momentum states ), and the study of the Regge behavior of the no-pair equation describing the (Q, ¯ q) system in high orbital angular momentum states. In this work the authors found that with a Dirac-like equation only a Lorentz scalar confinement accounts for the unphysical phenomenon of the mixing of negative with positive energy states also called the Klein paradox, while with the no-pair variant of the Dirac equation only a Lorentz vector confinement potentials leads to a normal Regge behaviour. Concerning to the calculation of the IW function they found that the no-pair equation predicts a value of its slope at zero recoil point in better agreement with the heavy-light data than the Dirac equation.</p>

				<p>The authors of [1] conclude arguing against scalar confinement. It is worth it to stress at this stage two points about the work of Ref. [1] that eventually modify the results. The first one is that the analysis of Regge behavior was done partially, since only the the no-pair equation was considered, while the Dirac-like equation was not. The other is that the relativistic corrections to the Dirac hamiltonian were not included. On the other hand, in Ref. [2] a (Q, ¯ q) system was considered as described by a Dirac-like hamiltonian containing all the relativistic corrections. By assuming that this system is in low orbital angular momentum states it was shown that only a scalar confinement leads to a finite norm of the wave function. Also, it was checked that only this potential accounts for the Klein paradox. In [2] the slope of the IW function at zero recoil point including relativistic corrections was also calculated as predicted by scalar confinement. The value found for this quantity agrees very well with heavylight data. In Ref. [2] it was concluded that scalar confinement is favored over vector confinement when the (Q, ¯ q) meson is in low orbital angular momentum states and it is described by a covariant Dirac equation. On the basis of the above remarks, the purpose of this work is then to investigate the nature of the confinement when the (Q, ¯ q) system is described by a Dirac equation in the Regge limit of high orbital angular momentum states.</p>

				<p>In order to do the above we start with a simple model where we are neglecting the relativistic corrections to the hamiltonian. Consequently, the hamiltonian for the c.m. system is [1], [4]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α · p + m β + U(r) + βS(r) + V (r) ψ = E ψ, (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where m (M Q ) is the light (heavy) quark mass, p is the momentum of the light quark,</p>

				<p>U(r) = −ξ/r is a color Coulomb-like potential, S(r) = κ s r and V (r) = κ v r are linear increasing Lorentz scalar and vector potentials, respectively. The non-perturbative potentials S and V in Eq. (1) are dynamically responsible for the confinement of the light quark, while the Lorentz vector potential U describes the perturbative color interaction between the quarks. If one writes (1) as a matrix equation then</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m + S + U + V − E σ · p σ · p −m − S + U + V − E G iσ · ˆ rF χ m κ = 0 0 . (2) By using the identities σ · L χ m κ = −(1 + κ)χ m κ , (3) σ · p χ m κ = i σ · ˆ r − d dr + κ + 1 r χ m κ , (4) where L = r × p is the angular momentum and κ = −(l + 1) j=l+1/2 l j=l-1/2, (5) Eq. (2) leads to the following system of two coupled linear differential equations dG dr = − κ + 1 r G − E + m + S − (U + V ) F, (6) dF dr = E − (m + S + U + V ) G + κ − 1 r F. (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In order to analyze the Regge behavior of the solutions of these equations we make the following two approximations for large values of the orbital angular momentum (l ≫</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1), E = p 2 r + l(l + 1) r 2 + m 2 ∼ l/r, (8) | κ | ± 1 ∼ | κ | ∼ l. (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In order to assure the validity of Eq. (8) for any value of r and not only near the turning points, in this work it is assumed that the Regge objects under study have finite size of radius R.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Consequently from the Uncertainty Principle in the way 1 ≤ p r R &lt; l, it follows that for r ≤ R p 2 r + l(l + 1) r 2 ≃ (p r r) 2 + l 2 r 2 ≤ (p r R) 2 + l 2 r 2 ≃ l 2 r 2 . (10) With which Eq. (8) holds for any value of r. Before of finding the Regge solutions let us find first the Regge slopes 1 as predicted by Eqs. (6)-(9). In order to find these we are assuming | κ |≫ 1 and nearly circular orbits for the light quark. From (6)-(9) it follows that − F G = V − E + S κ r = κ r V − E − S , (11) which is equivalent to (E − V ) 2 − S 2 = κ 2 r 2 . (12) At the lowest energy state, the energy satisfies ∂E ∂r | κ = 0 which implies (E − V )V ′ + SS ′ = κ 2 r 3 . (13) From (12) and (13) we find the general expression for the Regge slope α ′ = | κ | E 2 = 2κ v κ v + κ 2 v + 8κ 2 s + 4κ 2 s 5κ 2 v + 3κ v κ 2 v + 8κ 2 s + 4κ 2 s . (14) For the most interesting particular cases, Eq. (14) yields the following results -Scalar confinement: V = 0 and S = κ s r α ′ = 1 2κ s (15) -Vector confinement: V = κ v r and S = 0 α ′ = 1 4κ v (16) -Vector and Scalar confinement with same strength: V = S = ar 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As it is well known for large orbital angular momentum, the Regge trajectories become linear for linear confinement and have slopes whose values depend on the Lorentz nature of the confinement [1]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>α ′ = 1 3 √ 3a . (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We must note that these Regge slopes coming from the Dirac equation (1) are the same than those previously found in Ref. [5] which were obtained from a general confinement model for a (Q, ¯ q) system. For the description of this system in [5] it was employed a Klein-Gordon equation whith a confinement potential being a linear combination of scalar and time-component vector potentials. The coincidence between the values of the slopes (15)-(17) and those of Ref. [5] reflects the fact that the Dirac equation (1) behaves semi-classically in the limit of a very large orbital angular momentum. Let us turn now to find the Regge solutions.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>From Eqs. (8) and (9), Eqs. (6) and (7) can be written as, dg dr = − r 2κ l + (κ s − κ v ) f, (18) df dr = r −2κ l − (κ s + κ v ) g, (19) where we have assumed E − U ≃ l + ξ r ≃ l r , r 2κ±1 ≃ r 2κ , and f ≡ r −κ F ; g ≡ r κ G. (20) By substituting (18) in (19) it is obtained g ′′ − 2 κ g ′ + (l − κ v ) 2 − κ 2 s g = 0. (21)</trash>

					<figDesc>By solving this equation and substituting the result in (18), we obtain the Regge solutions for a (Q, ¯ q) system</figDesc>
					<trash>G = r −κ e κ r A 1 e √ κ 2 s + 2 l κv − κ 2 v r + A 2 e − √ κ 2 s + 2 l κv − κ 2 v r , (22) F = − r −κ e κ r (l −κv) + κs × A 1 κ + κ 2 s + 2 l κ v − κ 2 v e √ κ 2 s + 2 l κv − κ 2 v r + A 2 κ − κ 2 s + 2 l κ v − κ 2 v e − √ κ 2 s + 2 l κv − κ 2 v r . (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>As can be seen from the above equations a sinusoidal behavior in the quantity in brackets implies that |ψ| 2 behaves as r −k e κ r which means that ψ is not normalizable for κ = l. So in what follows we assume κ</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>2 s + 2 l κ v − κ 2</formula></p>

				<p>v &gt; 0. From this assumption it follows immediately that if we want physically admissible Regge solutions (i.e. lim r→∞ ψ → 0) it is necessary to drop also the term proportional to A 1 . Consequently, in all of the discussions below we are taking A 1 = 0. Another observation concerning Eq. (23) is that the strength of the potentials must be such that l + κ s = κ v in order to avoid an unphysical divergence in the lower component of the solution. Let us consider first the situation where the confinement potential is strictly scalar (κ v = 0). In this case the solutions are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G = r −κ e (κ − κs ) r , (24) F = − κ − κs l + κs r −κ e (κ − κs) r . (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As we may observe from these equations, if the strength of the scalar potential is strong enough to compensate the intense &apos;centrifugal forces&apos; it is possible to find physically admissible solutions for r → ∞ for either κ = l and κ = −l.</p>

				<p>Let us turn now to consider the case when the confining potential is exclusively vectorial (κ s = 0). As can be seen from Eqs. (22) and (23) in this case the solutions are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G = r −κ e [κ − √ (2 l/κv − 1) κv] r , (26) F = − κ − κv √ 2 l/κv − 1 l − κv r −κ e [κ − √ ( 2 l/κv − 1) κv] r . (27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We note from these equation that the condition needed to avoid that the exponentials in (22) and (23) become oscillatory is that κ v &lt; 2 l which restricts the value of κ v . On the other hand, if we ask for values of κ v in the Regge region, κ v ∼ l to compensate for the intense &apos;centrifugal force&apos;, then the lower component of the wave function ψ would diverge strongly. Indeed, if we take the limit κ v → l in</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eq. (27) we find lim κv→l F =      l r −l e 2l r κ = l l r l e − 2 l r lim κv→l 1 l − κv κ = −l (28) From Eq. (28</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) we conclude that for values of the strength of the vector potential in the Regge regions it is not possible to find physically admisible solutions. In the case of a very weak vector potential κ v ≪ l,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eqs. (26) and (27) yield − F ∼ G ∼ r − κ e κ r , (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which shows that the solutions also diverge in this case for κ = l. Equations (28) and (29) indicate that the norm of the wavefunctions of a (Q, ¯ q) system in high orbital angular momentum states confined by a vector potential and described by a Dirac equation is not finite.</p>

				<p>Let us consider the behavior of the Regge solutions when both kinds of potentials V and S contribute to the confining of the light degree of freedom. Suppose first that both potentials compete in strength, that is κ s = κ v , then Eqs. (22) and (23) are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G = r −κ e (1 − √ 2 κv l ) κ r , (30) F = − κ − √ 2 l κv l r −κ e (1 − √ 2 κv l ) κ r . (31)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From these equations it is evident that for κ s = κ v ≪ l, the solutions behave in the same way as (29). Consequently they diverge when κ = l. While for κ s = κ v ∼ l these become</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G ≃ r −κ , (32) F ≃ 0, (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and therefore they diverge for κ = −l. If both potentials are very strong i.e. κ s = κ v ≫ 2 l the solutions (30) and (31) diverge for κ = −l and converge for κ = l. Let us consider now the general situation where both kind of potentials do not have the same intensity. In this case as can be seen from (22) and (23), the solutions are finite only for values of κ 2 s + 2 l κ v − κ 2 v large enough to compensate the intense centrifugal force. Otherwise they would diverge for κ = l.</p>

				<p>Systematic studies of the very different situation where the (Q, ¯ q) system is in states with small values of the orbital angular momentum, were performed in Refs. [1] and [2]. In Ref. [1] it was shown that the slope of the IW function at zero recoil point constitutes a sensitive test for the nature of the confinement. The authors of this work then calculated this quantity according to both approaches: Dirac equation with scalar confinement and no-pair equations with vector confinement obtaining ξ ′ (1) D ≃ − 0.90, and ξ ′ (1) n.p. ≃ − 1.20, respectively. From these values they found that the last quantity was in better agreement with heavy-light data than the first one. Another interesting thing found in [1] was that with a scalar confinement in a Salpeter (no-pair) equation there is not Regge behaviour. Based on the above findings, the authors of [1] concluded that vector confinement is favored over scalar confinement when it is used a Salpeter (no-pair) equation. On the other hand, by using a Dirac equation with scalar confinement in [2] it was calculated the slope of the IW function at zero recoil point. In [2], this quantity was first calculated such as it is defined properly e.g. in the heavy quark symmetry limit (M Q → ∞) and the value found was the same as that of Ref. [1] e. g. ξ D ≃ −0.90. To calculate the relativistic corrections coming from a M Q finite to the slope in [2], it was found ξ ′ (1) D ≃ − 1.01,.</p>

				<p>This value for the slope is in better agreement with data than the one calculated without relativistic corrections. Therefore in Ref. [2] it was concluded that with a Dirac hamiltonian with relativistic corrections describing the (Q, ¯ q) system, a scalar confinement is favored over vector confinement at low orbital angular momentum states. Let us summarize all of the analysis done above. We have considered here a (Q, ¯ q) system described by a Dirac hamiltonian with Lorentz scalar (S) and vector (V ) confinement potentials. In order to analyze the Regge behavior of such a system we found the respective slopes. It was found that their values are exactly the same as those predicted by the general confinement potential model of Ref.[5].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>To find the general Regge solutions of such an excited mesonic system, it was shown that the solutions with scalar confining potential are physically admissible while those coming from a vector potential are not. As a result of all of the above discussed we can conclude in general that if a (Q, ¯</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>q) system is described by a no-pair equation, scalar confinement is not favored. However, if we use a Dirac equation for describing the hydrogenlike system (Q, ¯ q), a scalar confinement is prefered over a vector confinement for any value of the orbital angular momentum. AcknowledgementIwouldliketothanktoM.Olssonforhisinterestingobservations .IthanktoN.A.andtoN.H.withwhompartofthisworkwasdone.I acknowledgesupportfromCONACyTgrant3135.</p>


			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-ph/9711500v2 4 Jan 1998</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Olsson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Veseli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Williams</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5079</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Avila</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9710241" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Isgur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Wise</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<biblScope unit="page">237</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Avila</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">309</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Olsson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5479</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Sucher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5965</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
