<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Gamma Ray Bursts from Baryon Decay in Neutron Stars</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1997-12-15">15 Dec 1997</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Ue-Li</forename>
								<surname>Pen</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>60 Garden St</addrLine>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Abraham</forename>
								<surname>Loeb</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Neil Turok DAMTP</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cambridge University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Gamma Ray Bursts from Baryon Decay in Neutron Stars</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1997-12-15">15 Dec 1997</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Subject headings: cosmology: theory – gamma rays: bursts</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The standard unbroken electroweak theory is known to erase baryon number. The baryon number symmetry can be restored in the core of a neutron star as its density diverges via gravitational instability due to a binary merger event. We argue that for certain double Higgs models with discrete symmetries, this process may result in an expanding self-sustained burning front which would convert the entire neutron matter into radiation. This process would release ∼ 10 54 ergs in electromagnetic radiation over ∼ 10 −4 sec, with negligible baryonic contamination. The resulting fireball would have all the properties necessary to produce a γ-ray burst as a result of its interaction with ambient interstellar gas. The subsequent Higgs decay would produce a millisecond burst of ∼ 10 52 ergs in ∼ 100 GeV neutrinos which might be observable. The above mechanism may have also caused electroweak baryogenesis in the early universe, giving rise to the observed matter-antimatter asymmetry today.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The energy source for γ-ray bursts (GRB) has been enigmatic since their discovery (see Fishman &amp; Meegan 1995, for a recent review). The recent detection of absorption lines at a redshift z = 0.835 in the optical afterglow spectrum of the event GRB970508 (Metzger et al. 1997), established a firm lower bound on its distance, and hence on its total radiation energy ∼ &gt; 10 52 erg (Waxman 1997). The long duration of some GRBs is difficult to reconcile with their millisecond time structure. If the variability is caused by an external shock due to the interaction of the fireball with an ambient medium ( Mészáros &amp; Rees 1993a,b), then the conversion efficiency must be small (Sari &amp; Piran 1997a) and the total – 2 – energy released approaches the rest mass energy of a neutron star. A further challenge to GRB models is the baryon contamination problem. The high Lorentz factors implied by the short variability and non-thermal spectra of GRBs (see, e.g. Woods &amp; Loeb 1995) require that the baryonic fraction be ∼ &lt; 1%, of the total energy. This constraint is particularly difficult to satisfy in stellar environments such as neutron star mergers (Ruffert et al. 1997, and references therein), where a considerable amount of baryonic debris is unavoidable.</p>

				<p>The standard electroweak theory allows for baryon number violating processes (&apos;t Hooft 1976). Through a combination of chirality and topology, baryon and lepton number may be violated. A change in the winding number of the gauge fields results in fermions being pulled out or pushed into the Dirac sea. Normally, in the broken symmetry vacuum, such effects are very strongly suppressed since the gauge fields are massive and difficult to excite. However, in the unbroken phase it is well established that when the electroweak symmetry is restored, the baryon and lepton number violation processes are unsuppressed (for a review, see Rubakov &amp; Shaposhnikov 1996). It is natural to ask whether these intriguing processes could be excited in the Universe today. There are two fundamental barriers which make their appearance rare: (i) a large energy input is required to change the gauge/Higgs winding numbers, and (ii) the energy must be input in a coherent fashion into the long wavelength components of the bosonic fields (and this, for example, does not happen in high energy collisions of single elementary particles).</p>

				<p>In this Letter we argue that baryon number symmetry might be restored in the core of a neutron star if its density is raised to extreme values. Such a process might be triggered during the catastrophic gravitational collapse caused by some cataclysmic event (such as binary coalescence or substantial accretion), which raises the neutron star mass above its stability limit. Once the symmetry is restored in a sufficiently large (macroscopic) volume, a self-sustained burning front would propagate throughout the star and convert the entire neutron matter into radiation, releasing ∼ 1 GeV per baryon in the process. The burning front will be accompanied by an electroweak domain wall in which the barrier to baryon number violation is greatly reduced. The existence of dense nuclear matter allows long wavelength modes of the gauge fields to be naturally excited. Overall, the burning front could release ∼ 10 54 ergs in electromagnetic radiation with negligible baryonic contamination. The resulting fireball would have all the properties necessary to produce a GRB due to its interaction with ambient interstellar gas.</p>

				<p>In §2 we present the hydrodynamic solution for the associated electroweak burning front. We then discuss the trigger mechanism for the explosive process described above, in §3. §4 considers the energetics of electroweak baryon number violation on moving walls. Finally, we examine the implications of our model for cosmological baryogenesis and – 3 – electroweak theory in §5, and summarize its testable predictions for GRBs in §6.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Self-Similar Explosion</head>

				<p>In our model, we consider three regions of the dynamical explosion. In the outer region, the cold neutron star material is at rest. The shock front propagates through this material at some speed λ s c, where c is the speed of light. This burning front is the second region under consideration, which has a characteristic thickness of an electroweak length ∼ 10 −16 cm. The burning front is sustained by the presence of an electroweak domain wall. While the microphysics in this region is complicated, we can describe its hydrodynamic implications as if it were infinitely thin. We will return to its discussion in §4. The global conservation of energy and momentum thus dictate the global dynamics of this burning region. The last region under consideration includes the postshock (burnt) radiation phase. This heated region will initially expand due to the increase in pressure. This pressure is directly exerted against the domain wall, which then propagates further outward. The goal of this section is to quantify the self-sustained dynamics of these regions, assuming that the process has already been triggered. The possible trigger mechanism will be considered in the next section.</p>

				<p>The equations of motion of a relativistic fluid are given by the energy-momentum conservation equations T µν ;µ = 0 where T µν = (ρ + p)u µ u ν + pg µν . We use a metric signature convention of (−, +, +, +). In the rest frame of the star, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∂ ∂t ρ + pβ 2 1 − β 2 + 1 r 2 ∂ ∂r r 2 (ρ + p)β 1 − β 2 = 0, ∂ ∂t (ρ + p)β 1 − β 2 + 1 r 2 ∂ ∂r r 2 (ρ + p)β 2 1 − β 2 + ∂p ∂r = 0, (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where r is the radial coordinate and the speed of light is set to unity. We ignore gravity for now, assuming that the star is initially in static equilibrium, and that the final phase is gravitationally fully unbound.</p>

				<p>We assume that the pre-shocked neutron star material is described by an equation of state p 0 = αρ 0 . The pre-shock density of a neutron star, ρ 0 ∼ 2 × 10 14 g/cm 3 , is slightly above nuclear density. The pressure is typically small, α ∼ 0.1, but can reach relativistic values near the center of the star, where α ∼ 1/3. The burnt phase consists of radiation and electroweak false vacuum energies, ρ burnt = ρ F + ρ V , p burnt = ρ F /3 − ρ V . Typically ρ V ∼ ρ 0 /100, as discussed further in §5. The burning front has a width of order the electroweak scale, ∼ 10 −16 cm, much smaller than the macroscopic scale of the neutron – 4 – star, and can therefore be approximated as a sharp discontinuity. Since the neutron star density is nearly constant (Shapiro &amp; Teukolsky 1983), the explosion should be well approximated by a self-similar solution (see examples in Blandford &amp; McKee 1976; Pen 1994). The amount of energy released per baryon equals to its rest mass and therefore the Lorentz factor of the burning front cannot be much greater than unity. This implies that any self-similar self-sustained burning front (which does not decay as it expands) must propagate at a constant speed through the neutron matter.</p>

				<p>We therefore seek solutions to (1) and (1) which depend on r, t only through the combination λ = r/t. We define the dimensionless densities ρ = ρ/ρ 0 and ρ V = V (φ − )/ρ 0 , where V is defined in §5 below.</p>

				<p>After some algebra, we find that the equation for β(λ) separates from the equation for ρ:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λβ ′ = 2β(1 − β 2 )(1 − βλ) β 2 (3 − λ 2 ) − 4βλ + 3λ 2 − 1 , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the density is given as a simple integral over the fluid velocity,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˜ ρ = ˜ ρ s exp λs λ 8β (λ ′ − β) dλ ′ β 2 (3 − λ ′2 ) − 4βλ ′ + 3λ ′2 − 1 . (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This self-similar scaling imposes a constant shock speed with velocity λ s . The subscript (...) s on a fluid variable denotes its value immediately behind the shock front, e.g. ˜ ρ s ≡ lim λ→λ − s ˜ ρ(λ).</p>

				<p>In order to solve the system of equations (2) and (3), we need to specify the postshock boundary conditions. Equations (1) and (1) provide the postshock velocity in the star rest frame and the postshock density in the fluid frame:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>β s = 2[λ s 2 (1 − ˜ ρ V ) − α − ˜ ρ V ] − −3(1 + α) 2 λ s 2 + 4[α − λ s 2 (−1 + ˜ ρ V ) + ˜ ρ V ] 2 λ s (3 − α − 4˜ ˜ ρ s = 3(1 + α)(1 − β 2 s )λ s 4(λ s − β s )(1 − β s λ s ) . (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Requiring the postshock velocity to be real in the shock frame yields the inequality</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3 + α(3α − 2) + 8˜ ρ V + α − 1) + √ 3(1 + α) ( 4˜˜α − 1) 8(1 − ˜ ρ V ) 2 &lt; λ 2 s &lt; 1 (6) which simplifies to 3/4 &lt; λ 2 s &lt; 1 if α = ˜ ρ V = 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in the idealized case of a low-pressure neutron star and a negligible burning potential. We conclude that the burning front must propagate supersonically in the star frame. In the shock frame, the post-shock velocity – 5 – of the fluid is smaller than its pre-shock value, therefore this solution corresponds to a detonation front. By examining equation (2) we find that all solutions must pass through the point β = 0, λ = 1/ √ 3. The only physical solution in the range 0 ≤ λ ≤ 1/ √ 3 is β = 0, so any solution is matched continuously at the boundary with discontinuous derivatives.</p>

				<p>Normally one specifies a boundary condition away from the shock front, but in our case this boundary condition is automatically satisfied. The shock speed λ s is therefore a free parameter which can lie anywhere in the allowed range. The actual value of λ s is either set by the trigger mechanism (i.e., the initial conditions) or by the viscous forces acting on the domain wall boundary. In the generic case where viscous forces slow down the shock to its minimum velocity, the unique solution is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ 2 s = 3 4 − α 2 − ˜ ρ V 2 , (7) to leading order in α and ρ V . The postshock density is n s ≃ 3 − 4α − 7ãnd the exact postshock velocity β 2 s = 1 − 2(1 + α) 3 − α − 4˜</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>giving the constraint 3α + 4˜ven though the velocity derivative β ′ formally diverges, the solution is well defined.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>By virtue of equation (1), all shock solutions automatically satisfy total energy conservation T 00 ρ 0 t 3 = 4 3 πλ 3 s = 4 3 π ˜ ρ( 1 √ 3 )3 −3/2 + 4 3 πλ 3 s ˜ ρ V + 4π λs 1/ √ 3 1 + β 2 /3 1 − β 2 ˜ ρλ 2 dλ, (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which provides a consistency check for the final numerical solution. Figure 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>shows the numerical solutions for the velocity and density profiles behind the shock for three different choices of λ s , assuming α = 0 and ρ V = 0.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Trigger Mechanism</head>

				<p>We have found that if triggered, a self-sustained burning front would propagate at a constant speed and spontaneously convert baryons at nuclear density into radiation. However, we still need to demonstrate how this process might be spontaneously triggered, and under which conditions the burning front would release sufficient energy to sustain itself.</p>

				<p>The rate of neutron star mergers in the Hubble volume is similar to the observed rate of GRBs (Narayan et al. 1991; Phinney 1991). It is therefore natural to examine the question – 6 – whether an electroweak burning front would be triggered by such mergers. Typically, the combined mass of the two neutron stars would exceed the maximum mass for a stable star at nuclear densities, and the merger product would be gravitationally unstable and tend to collapse to a black hole. An electroweak burning front might be produced if there is an inner region where the density is sufficiently high to restore electroweak symmetry before being engulfed by a black hole horizon. In this region, baryon-number will be strongly violated and most baryons will decay into anti-leptons. Similar conditions might occur in binary systems where a neutron star exceeds the maximum stable mass due to accretion from its companion. However, the formation of black holes by much more massive systems, such as the direct collapse of massive stars, are characterized by much lower densities (at the Schwarzschild radius, ρ ∝ 1/M 2 ) and are not expected to trigger the electroweak transition before their horizon forms.</p>

				<p>The details of the trigger process depend on the equation of state of neutron star matter above nuclear density, which is not yet fully understood. Some nuclear equations of state predict that p &gt; ρ/3 for densities about ten times nuclear (Prakash et al. 1997). The sound speed c 2 s = ∂p/∂ρ then obtains a maximum value above that of a pure radiation fluid. At yet higher densities, the sound speed eventually declines back to the 1/3 value of a locally interacting radiation field due to asymptotic freedom of QCD. If we now consider a neutron star which collapses slowly through phases of hydrostatic equilibrium, then the central equation of state will stiffen until it reaches its maximum sound speed, and then soften again. The region which enters the softened phase will collapse faster than its surroundings, potentially leading to a runaway density. The compression of this region is caused by the weight of the column of matter above it.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The electroweak symmetry would be restored in this region at a density ∼ 10 27 g/cm 3 , some twelve orders of magnitude above the initial density. This region will not be surrounded by a black hole horizon if its radius is ∼ &lt; 1 cm, or its mass is ∼ &lt; 4 × 10 −6 M ⊙ . A lower bound on the radius of the trigger region arises from the requirement that a self-sustained burning front needs to release more energy interior to it than the total energy stored in the domain wall. At nuclear density the energy released is ∼ (200MeV) 4 R 3 while the wall energy is ∼ (250GeV) 3 R 2 , implying a radius ∼ &gt; 10 −3 cm. Higher background densities will only weaken this constraint.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>We have two apparently contradictory requirements. The fluid must collapse to electroweak densities, and then expand again to drive the explosion. In the dense phase, the relative pressure gain from the burning of each nucleon is small. One would expect that the gravitational collapse and the subsequent phase transitions will raise the entropy of the fluid in the central region and cause entropy inversion, therefore resulting in convective flows. A fluid element taken through the electroweak phase transition which would subsequently rise due to buoyancy forces, could trigger the explosion as it cools adiabatically and is trapped – 7 – in the false vacuum.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Kinematics of Baryon Number Violation on Propagating Walls</head>

				<p>In this section we discuss the energetics and timescales of the baryon number violating processes on bubble walls moving through cold neutron matter. We consider the possibility that neutrons are converted into antineutrinos as the bubble wall passes. Our analysis will be extremely schematic, at best a pointer to the key issues involved. At the end of this section we shall comment on the additional work which is needed in order to settle the microphysics of electroweak bubble walls in neutron matter.</p>

				<p>We shall consider particle physics models which include more than one Higgs doublet field. These models are amongst the most plausible extensions of the standard model and occur as sub-models of low energy supersymmetry and attempts to incorporate generational symmetries in the standard model (Gunion et al. 1990). We are particularly interested in these models because they possess stable domain wall solutions within which the Higgs fields may be very small. The domain wall solutions arise as an inevitable consequence of discrete symmetries imposed to prevent phenomenologically unacceptable flavor changing neutral currents. For example, if the field φ U gives mass to up quark and φ D to the down quark, one imposes a symmetry: φ U → −φ U , U R → −U R , with U R being the right-handed up quark. This prevents tree level processes in which neutral Higgs intermediate states allow up type quarks to change into down type quarks (Glashow &amp; Weinberg 1977). Of course these symmetries mean that at least at the classical level the theories possess degenerate vacua, and the domain walls are stable classical field configurations interpolating between them.</p>

				<p>The domain walls are interesting to us because in their interior the gauge field masses may be very small and the barrier to baryon number violating processes is therefore small. Furthermore, as pointed out by Preskill et al. 1991, in these particular theories the domain walls pose no problems for cosmology, since they vacuum degeneracy is actually broken by very small instanton induced effects, the vacuum energy being different by ∼</p>

				<p><formula>1 3 f 2 π m 2 π ∼ (80 MeV) 4 .</formula></p>

				<p>They may in fact be useful for producing a cosmological baryon asymmetry, as we discuss below.</p>

				<p>The electroweak baryon number violating processes violate baryon and lepton number, but conserve their difference. A unit change in the gauge/Higgs winding number destroys 3 baryons and 3 leptons. Since quarks, but not leptons, are allowed to change flavors through Cabibbo-Kobayashi-Maskawa mixing, one can have the processes 3n → ν e + ν µ + ν τ , or – 8 – 2n → n + ν e + ν µ + ν τ . A key prediction of our mechanism is that the high energy neutrinos measured from these processes would exhibit an equal excess of antineutrinos from each generation.</p>

				<p>The basic equation governing the rate of baryon number violation in the standard model reads,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dn B dt = N 8π 2 (g 2 2 E · B − g 2 1 e · b), (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where n B is the baryon number density, N = 3 the number of generations, g 2 and g 1 the SU(2) and U(1) Y gauge coupling constants and E, B, e, b the corresponding electric and magnetic fields. The linear combination occurring on the right hand side of (10) vanishes for electromagnetic fields: baryon number violation requires the W and Z fields. If the wall moves at velocity v w , then the number of neutrons hitting the wall per unit time per unit area is γ w n N v w , where n N is the ambient neutron density.</p>

				<p>Requiring that a sizeable fraction of these neutrons are converted then leads to an estimate of the required electric and magnetic fields.</p>

				<p>Assuming equipartition between electric and magnetic fields, and a semi-relativistic wall velocity, we find the needed fields are:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B required ∼ E required ∼ γ w n N v w m H /α 2 ∼ (1.5GeV) 2 , (11) with α 2 = g 2 2 /4π ∼ 1 30</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the weak fine structure constant. Here we have integrated the anomaly across the wall width, taken to be the inverse Higgs mass m H ∼ 100GeV, and have ignored g 1 since it is much smaller than g 2 . The resulting fields are indeed large, but they are very much smaller than the electroweak scale. We have ignored the Cabibbo-Kobayashi-Maskawa mixing angle suppression. The B violating processes would presumably create heavy quark states which would be trapped upon the wall since they are light on it, which would annihilate with ups and downs via CKM mixing.</p>

				<p>Could the required fields be accreted on the wall? It is clear that the physics of the domain walls is quite complex and there are many possible contributing effects. Fermions are attracted to the wall, since their masses are lower on it, and form bound states which may support currents flowing without resistance on the wall. Since the neutrons carry weak isospin, their presence automatically causes a weak isospin electric fields of order gn 2 3 N on the wall if the gauge fields are massless there. But the most likely mechanism for generating the required ∼ 1 GeV 2 fields is the Meissner effect – W and Z gauge fields would be swept along by the back edge just because they are light on the wall and massive off it. It is also possible that a dynamo mechanism would operate on the wall, building up the magnetic fields to the saturation value B crit ∼ (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>100GeV) 2 . – 9 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>How much energy do the fields in equation (11) cost? And how does this compare with the rate of energy input in the form of neutrons onto the wall? Equating the energies per unit area B 2 required /m H ∼ n N L N m N where L N is the path swept up in the cold neutrons, we find that the required field energy could be accreted in a distance as short as ∼ 3 neutron spacings at nuclear density, or L N ∼ (α 2 m N ) −1 . So there is certainly no shortage of energy input to maintain the fields.</p>

				<p>We require aligned electric and magnetic fields in order to violate baryon number: we may think of the process occurring in two stages. First magnetic fields are established on the wall via some kind of dynamo mechanism coupled to the Meissner effect. In a constant SU(2) magnetic field, the lowest energy levels for the quark consists of left handed particles with positive isospin (up quarks) moving against the field and left handed particles with negative isospin (down quarks) moving along the field. Right handed particles do not couple to the field. A beam of neutrons streaming into such a field would undergo isospin separation, leading to an electric field aligned with the magnetic field. The resulting change in the gauge field winding causes neutrons to disappear.</p>

				<p>Some elementary steps towards establishing the viability of this mechanism would be: (i) finding the energy barrier required for baryon number violation in the presence of a domain wall, (ii) studying the fate of currents on the wall, and whether they can support magnetic fields of the required magnitude, and finally (iii) studying the possibility of a dynamo mechanism that would establish such fields out of a seed magnetic field, that is likely to be present in the neutron star. We shall return to these questions in future work.</p>

				<p>Assuming the electroweak baryon number violation processes are sustained in the bubble wall, the latter will be pushed forward through the neutrons by the excess pressure of the hot medium behind it. Presumably it will reach a terminal speed determined by collisions with the neutron matter. The self-sustained detonation front described in §2 could convert all the nuclear matter mass M tot into neutrinos and photons, releasing ∼ 5 × 10 54 ergs × (M tot /3M ⊙ ) over a time ∼ &lt; (30 km/c) ∼ 10 −4 sec.</p>

				<p>When the electroweak domain wall emerges from the surface of the neutron star, the domain wall will still expand due to the thermal pressure behind it out to R max /R ⋆ ∼ ˜ ρ −1/3 V where R ⋆ is the radius of the neutron star. The lack of additional fuel will prevent it from expanding further; beyond this radius, the radiation fireball will diffuse out and separate from the domain wall. This energy release will be the primary source of energy for the GRB. As discussed in the next section, typically ρ V ∼ 1/100, and the limiting radius would be R max ∼ 10 7 cm. If ρ V = 0 the wall will not expand forever, but rather at R ∼ 10 10 cm it will contract again due to wall tension. Eventually, the wall would lose the radiation pressure support behind it and collapse again. The Higgs energy of the wall and the – 10 – false vacuum behind it will be radiated as high energy (∼ 100 GeV) neutrinos, photons, and particle-antiparticle pairs. In contrast to supernovae, where neutrinos carry 99% of the energy (since photons are trapped by the opaque stellar envelope), there should be comparable energies in neutrinos and photons in the resulting fireball here. In addition to the ∼ 10 54 ergs radiated in neutrinos of energy ∼ 100 MeV, a second sub-millisecond burst carrying ∼ 10 52 ergs of ∼ 100 GeV neutrinos is a generic prediction of our model.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Implications for Electroweak Theory and Cosmological Baryogenesis</head>

				<p>Electroweak domain walls can be cosmologically disastrous. When formed in a first order phase transition, they will come to dominate the matter density of the universe (Zel&apos;dovich et al. 1975). If we assume about one domain wall per horizon volume, electroweak domain walls would dominate the matter density of the Universe if they persist until its temperature is ∼ 1 keV. Thus, there is a cosmological lower bound on the potential difference ∆V ≡ V − − V + ≫ (1 keV) 4 . Preskill et al. (1991) argued that discrete symmetries could be broken anomalously through QCD effects, yielding an energy difference ∆V ∼ (80 MeV) 4 . The vacuum energy admits an equation of state p = −ρ. The energy density of a neutron star is ∼ (200 MeV) 4 .</p>

				<p>Requiring the postshock pressure to be positive, we obtain an upper bound to this energy asymmetry ∆V ∼ &lt; (150 MeV) 4 , in order for the burning front to be self-sustained. This bound is well above the value predicted by Preskill et al. (1991). We also see that such electroweak explosions can only occur in matter which has densities close to nuclear, i.e. only in neutron stars.</p>

				<p>A related enigma in cosmology is baryogenesis. Baryon number is strongly violated above the electroweak phase transition, and in some theories (where baryon number minus lepton number is conserved) baryon asymmetries generated before this transition would be erased. Baryon number is conserved after the electroweak symmetry breaking, so the natural time to create baryon number would be during this phase transition. The Sakharov criteria require that baryon number B, charge conjugation symmetry C, and parity CP be violated, and that the system be out of equilibrium. In the minimal standard model of particle physics, two of these criteria are problematic. The current measurement of the top mass m top ∼ 180 GeV appear to preclude a first order phase transition, which would be the natural way to bring the Universe out of equilibrium. Also, the magnitude of CP violation in the minimal standard model cannot produce the observed baryon-to-photon ratio η ∼ 10 −10 . Moving topological defects such as domain walls restore the out-of-equilibrium requirement (Prokopec et al. 1996), and the extra freedom in selecting the second Higgs field also allows a match for the required CP violation rates. The long persistence of – 11 – the anomalous domain walls will also amplify the net baryon production to become more consistent with the small observed CP violation rates.</p>

				<p>Another consequence of the long persistence of these walls is a coherence length of the baryon production regions which is intermediate to the horizon size at electroweak and the horizon size when the domain walls disappear. This length scale of ∼ 10 15 –10 19 comoving cm, is significantly longer than the diffusion length at nucleosynthesis (Jedamzik and Fuller 1995). The baryon-to-photon ratio would generically fluctuate in different regions, resulting in inhomogeneous nucleosynthesis and affecting the standard predictions for the abundance of light elements.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have argued that the gravitationally unstable core of a neutron star merger might trigger an electroweak burning front which would propagate outwards and convert all the nuclear material into radiation. The associated detonation front would be self-sustained and propagate at a constant semi-relativistic speed ∼ 3/4c). The baryon-number violating reaction is induced by a domain wall, which is naturally predicted in double Higgs models of electroweak interactions. We have shown that the electroweak burning front can only be self-sustained if it propagates into material with nuclear densities. Although our mechanism provides an efficient way for alleviating the baryonic contamination problem, some surrounding stellar debris might remain unburnt and limit the Lorentz Factor of the expanding fireball. Minimal contamination is required to make the emission spectrum from the fireball non-thermal (Goodman 1986; Paczy´ski 1986).</p>

				<p>The electroweak explosion process releases ∼ &gt; 10 54 ergs over ∼ &lt; msec, and produces a fireball which subsequently impacts on the ambient (interstellar) medium. This impact generates an external shock which could produce via synchrotron emission and inverse-Compton scattering of Fermi-accelerated electrons, the observed spectrum of GRBs ( Mészáros &amp; Rees 1993a,b; Mészáros , Laguna, &amp; Rees 1993). In this model, the observed variability of GRBs might be either due to inhomogeneities in the ambient gas density, or due to instabilities at the shock front (e.g. Waxman &amp; Piran 1994). The release of ∼ &gt; 10 54 ergs remedies the energy problem which was previously identified for external shock models (Sari &amp; Piran 1997a,b), and is in fact required if GRBs follow the star formation history of the Universe with the dimmest bursts originating at redshifts as high as z ∼ 6 (Wijers et al. 1997). The integrated light from afterglow observations can set a lower bound on the total energy released, and in principle challenge models which provide too little energy. The release of ∼ 10 54 ergs in more conventional astrophysical settings (see e.g., the – 12 – hypernovae model of Paczy´ski 1997) is likely to be contaminated by baryons at a level which depends on many random parameters, such as the orientation of line-of-sight through the source. Under such circumstances, one would expect a continuous distribution of events with varying levels of baryonic contamination, from the level of ∼ &lt; 10 −2 M ⊙ required for GRBs and up to the level of ∼ 10M ⊙ found in supernovae. Such models would therefore predict the existence of softer events, such as X-ray bursts (which were not observed so far), in addition to GRBs. Our model naturally accounts for the gap between the baryonic contamination levels found in GRBs and supernovae.</p>

				<p>The collapse of the bubble wall could also release a fractioñ ρ V of the neutron star rest mass, i.e. ∼ 10 52 ergs, when some of the Higgs potential energy is converted into non-thermal neutrinos with very high energies ∼ 100 GeV. The number of ∼ 100 GeV neutrinos per unit area from a source at a distance ∼ 3 Gpc would be ∼ 10 6 km −2 . Full timing and directional coincidence with GRB events might allow statistical detection by large area Cherenkov arrays, such as AMANDA. With a typical conversion efficiency of 10 −8 into upward moving muons (Gaisser et al. 1995), a year long cross-correlation with ∼ 300 bursts could yield ∼ 3 events with a km 2 array. This neutrino burst supplements the predicted neutrino flux from standard fireball models (Waxman &amp; Bahcall 1997, Paczy´ski and Xu 1994). A larger amount of energy ∼ 10 54 is released in ∼ 200 MeV neutrinos, remnant of the burnt phase behind the detonation front; however, these lower energy neutrinos would be more difficult to detect.</p>

				<p>Finally, we note that the extended Higgs models are amongst the simplest extensions of the standard model, and the discrete symmetries needed to produce the domain walls are required by particle physics phenomenology. These models may well provide a new solution to the problem of electroweak baryogenesis, with associated inhomogeneous cosmological nucleosynthesis. The quantitative constraints which are placed on the double Higgs theory by our GRB model could be tested with future accelerator experiments. Conversely, if our proposed link between electroweak theory and GRB is established, GRBs might be used to place constraints on parameters of the Higgs sector which go beyond the capabilities of laboratory accelerators.</p>

				<p>We thank Shmulik Balberg and Eli Waxman for useful discussions. This work was supported in part by the NASA ATP grant NAG5-3085 and the Harvard Milton fund (for AL and UP). – 15 – Fig. 1.— Self-Similar explosion solution for α = 0 and ρ V = 0. The different curves correspond to different detonation front speeds, λ s . The solid line is the generic solution in the presence of weak viscosity.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">This preprint was prepared with the AAS L A T E X macros v4.0.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Blandford</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Mckee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Fluids</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1130</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Fishman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Meegan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>ARA&amp; A</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">415</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Goodman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ApJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">308</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">47</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Higgs Hunter&apos;s Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Gunion</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>Addison Wesley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Jedamzik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Fuller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page">33</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 452</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Metzger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IAU Circ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6655</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Mészá</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Rees</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">59</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Mészá</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Laguna</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Rees</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">181</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Narayan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Piran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Shemi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="astro" to="ph" />
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 379, L17 Paczy´ , B. 1986, ApJ, 308, L43 Paczy´ , B</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Paczy´</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Xu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">708</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 427</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Pen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ApJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">429</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">759</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Phinney</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ApJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">380</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Prakash</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Bombaci</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Prakash</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Lattimer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Knorren</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physics Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">280</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Preskill</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Trivedi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Wilczek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Wise</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nuclear Physics, B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">363</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">207</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Prokopec</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Brandenberger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Davis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Trodden</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physics Letters B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">384</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">175</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Rubakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Shaposhnikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Usp. Fiz. Nauk</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">166</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">493</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ruffert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Janka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Th</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Takahashi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Schaefer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>A&amp; A</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">122</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Sari</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Piran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page">270</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 485</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Sari</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Piran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MNRAS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">287</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">110</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">14</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Black Holes, White Dwarfs and Neutron Stars</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Shapiro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Teukolsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New-York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Waxman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 489, L33</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Waxman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Bahcall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2292</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Waxman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Piran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ApJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">433</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">85</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A M J</forename>
				<surname>Wijers</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Bloom</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Bagla</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Natarajan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>MNRAS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">9708183</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>submitted</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Woods</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Loeb</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page">583</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 453</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ya</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Zel &apos;dovich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Kobzarev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Okun</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<biblScope unit="page">40</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
