<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">4-D homogeneous isotropic cosmological models generated by the 5-D vacuum</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Yu</forename>
								<forename type="middle">S</forename>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Moscow State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Kokarev</forename>
								<forename type="middle">S S</forename>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Yaroslavl State Pedagogical University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">4-D homogeneous isotropic cosmological models generated by the 5-D vacuum</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:gr-qc/0210067v1 19 Oct 2002</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>4-dimensional homogeneous isotropic cosmological models obtained from solutions of vacuum 5-dimensional Einstein equations are considered. It is assumed, that the G55–component of the 5-d metric simulates matter in the comoving frame of reference. Observable 4-d metric is defined up to conformal transformations of the metric of 4-d sectioñ gµν, with a conformal factor as a function of the component G55. It is demonstrated, that the form of this function determines the matter equation of state. Possible equations of state are analyzed separately for flat, open and close models.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>There is a number of fundamental problems in multidimensional geometric Kaluza-Klein theories. Among such problems the question of physical meaning of the scalar fields, given by extra components of metric G 55 , G 66 . . . , takes a significant place. One can indicate four viewpoints on the status of scalar fields: 1) Scalar fields are superfluous [1, 2, 3, 23]. In this approach scalar fields are eliminated on the geometric Lagrangian level by additional conditions like G 55 = const. 2) Extra components describe new unknown physical (massless) scalar fields [4, 5, 6]. The problem of their experimental observation is posed. Some researchers connect such fields with the hypothesis of the so-called &quot; fifth &quot; force, others with the hypothesis of variable fundamental constants. To this line adjoin investigations in the context of scalar-tensor gravitation theories of Jordan-Brans-Dicke type [7]. 3) Scalar fields can be understood as a geometric simulation of matter [9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 20, 25], which is substituted arbitrarily to the right-hand side of the Einstein equation through energy-momentum tensor T µν in 4-d GR. 4) In a number of variants of a unified multidimensional theory of the gravitational and electroweak interactions geometric scalar fields describe Higgs particles [18].</p>

				<p>In this paper the third from the above approaches is investigated in the context of the 5-d Kaluza- Klein theory. The possibility of describing matter by a geometric scalar field in homogeneous isotropic cosmological models of Friedmann type is considered.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>Physically meaningful quantities in the 5-D Kaluza-Klein the- ory The problem of the physical meaning of scalar fields is closely related to another question of greater importance: what quantities in multidimensional theory are to be endowed by physical meaning? Recall that the same question appears in 4-d GR. There it has been solved with the help of the monad method of describing reference frames [19, 20], which is often called the 1+3-splitting method. Therewith the metric can be represented as g µν = τ µ τ ν − h µν , (1) where Greek indices take values 0,1,2,3; τ µ is 4-d vector field, oriented along the corresponding observer&apos;s world line, h µν is orthogonal to τ µ and has the meaning of a metric in a local 3-d space section. A physical meaning is ascribed only to quantities projected onto the τ -direction or onto the orthogonal space section. It is convenient to apply the monad method in a special coordinate system, where the coordinate lines x i = const, i = 1, 2, 3 are directed along world lines of the frame of reference. In this case the vector τ µ has the components</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>τ µ = g µ 0 √ g 00 . (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The monad method in such coordinate systems has been called method of chronometric invariants [19].</p>

				<p>In this method the following coordinate transformations are distinguished:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x ′0 = x ′0 (x 0 , x 1 , x 2 , x 3 ); (3) x ′i = x ′i (x 1 , x 2 , x 3 ). (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A physical meaning is possessed by chronometrically invariant quantities, i.e. quantities, which are invariant under the transformations (3) and covariant under the transformations (4). For the description of physically meaningful quantities in 5-d Kaluza-Klein theory one should use a similar method of 1+4-splitting of the 5-dimensional manifold into the fifth direction and the 4-d classical space-time. The 5-d metric tensor G AB has the following form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G AB = −λ A λ B + ˜ g AB , (5) where A, B = 0, 1, 2, 3, 5, λ A is a 5</trash>

					<figDesc>-d unit vector oriented along the fifths direction, ˜ g AB is a metric of the 4-d section orthogonal to λ A . It appears reasonable that only quantities projected onto the λ-direction or orthogonal 4-d directions (by the projector g</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>A B ) have a physical meaning. There is a correspondence between the method of chronometric invariants and that of gauge invariants 1 [20, 21] in 5-d theory, wherein coordinate systems, in which λ A is oriented along the fifths coordinate x 5 are selected. Then the vector λ A is given by the expression</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ A = G A 5 / −G 55 , (6) the 4-d metric has the components ˜ g µν = G µν − G 5µ G 5ν G 55 ; ˜ g µν = G µν , (7) and the following coordinate transformations are distinguished: x ′5 = x ′5 (x 0 , x 1 , x 2 , x 3 , x 5 ); (8) x ′µ = x ′µ (x 0 , x 1 , x 2 , x 3 ). (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Gauge invariant quantities now become physically meaningful, i.e., quantities invariant under transformations (8) and 4-d covariant under the transformations (9). Recall that in such a theory the electromagnetic field tensor F µν is described by a gauge invariant expression, while the gauge-non-invariant components λ µ correspond to components of the electromagnetic vector potential. A new circumstance, which was absent in 4-d GR, appears when describing the &quot; generalized frames of reference &quot; of this kind. It is connected with the fact that if the quantities of a multidimensional theory depend on extra coordinates, then they will have an electric charge and may be other charges (hyphercharge, isospin). Since the gravitational and electromagnetic fields are neutral, the 5-metric should not dependent on x 5 .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Then (8) should be narrowed to x ′5 = x 5 + f (x 0 , x 1 , x 2 , x 3 ), (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which conserves the cylindricity condition of G AB with respect to x 5 . Under this transformations the components of λ µ transform by the law</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ ′ µ = λ µ + ∂f ∂x µ , (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>that corresponds to the well-known gauge transformations of electrodynamics. A new circumstance lies in the fact that the component G 55 is invariant under the transformation (10). It means in turn that any of the conformally corresponding metrics</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g µν = ˜ g µν /F (G 55 ), (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>can be physically meaningful, where the conformal factor F (G 55 ) is an arbitrary function of G 55 . There is an uncertainty in choosing the conformal factor. What factor F should be chosen? — this question has been posed and discussed in the book by one of the authors [20]. A number of works on 5-d theories were there analyzed and the following three most frequently used cases were distinguished: a) F (G 55 ) = 1 (immediate identification of the metric obtained from the 1+4-splitting procedure). This case is used in most works on 5-d theories, in particular, in the papers by Wesson [9, 12, 13]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>. b) The case F (G 55 ) = (−G 55 ) −1/2 ≡ 1/ϕ is of interest because after 1+4-splitting the effective energymomentum tensor of the scalar field has a canonical form (without second derivatives of ϕ = √ −G 55 ). c) The relation F (G 55 ) = −G 55 = ϕ 2 has been used, for example, in our works [21, 24]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. This case is of interest because the gravitational &quot; constant &quot; in the 4-d Einstein equations is a true constant and in the fifteenth Einstein equation the scalar of curvature 4 R appears with the coefficient -1/6, as in the case of a conformally invariant scalar field. Other cases are possible as well. A reasonable question arises: what is hidden behind this arbitrary choice of F (ϕ)? It turns out that, in the context of the approach to the physical meaning of ϕ proposed here, a specific choice of the conformal factor means specifying the equation matter of state.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3 Exact solutions Let us take vacuum (without a right-hand side) 5-d Einstein equation 5 R AB = 0. (13) We shall find its solutions which correspond to 4-d homogeneous isotropic cosmological models dI 2 = dt 2 − e 2λ [dr 2 + Σ(r)(dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] − e 2φ(t) (dx 5 ) 2 , (14) where λ(t) and φ(t) are two so far unknown functions of t and Σ(r) =    r 2 for flat 3-d section; sin 2 r for close 3-d section; sinh 2 r for open 3-d section. Substituting (14) to (13), one can write the Einstein equations in the form    3( ¨ λ + ˙ λ 2 ) + ¨ φ + ˙ φ 2 = 0; ¨ φ + ˙ φ 2 + 3 ˙ φ ˙ λ = 0; ¨ λ + 3 ˙ λ 2 + ˙ λ ˙ φ + 2se −2λ = 0, (15) where s = 0, +1, −1, according to the three outlined cases. The solutions of (15) are exhausted by the following four: 1) The metric of Kasner type with a flat 3-d space section dI 2 = dt 2 − dr 2 − r 2 (dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 ) − t 2 (dx 5 ) 2 , (16) has been considered in [25]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. This solution describes flat 5-d space-time.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2) The metric with a flat 3-d section dI 2 = dt 2 − t[dr 2 + r 2 (dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] − 1 t d(x 5 ) 2 , (t ≥ 0) (17) has been analyzed in [9]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and by others. It is of Kasner type too. 3) The metric with a 3-d space section of positive curvature</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dI 2 = dt 2 − (t 2 0 − t 2 )[dr 2 + sin 2 r(dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] − t 2 t 2 0 − t 2 d(x 5 ) 2 , (18) (0 ≤ |t| ≤ t 0 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>has been obtained in other coordinates in our work [20] and by others [26]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>. 4) The metric with a 3-d space section of negative curvature</figDesc>
					<trash>dI 2 = dt 2 − (t 2 − t 2 0 )[dr 2 + sinh 2 r(dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] − t 2 t 2 − t 2 0 d(x 5 ) 2 , (|t| ≥ t 0 ), (19) has been obtained in [20, 26]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>too. Note that all these solutions will be valid for the case of a timelike 5-th coordinate (after changing the sign).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Conformal transformations and equations of state</head>

				<p>We restrict our attention to conformal factors of the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F (ϕ) = ϕ 2n , (20)</trash>

					<figDesc>Take the metrics of the form g µν = ˜ g µν ϕ −2n . (21) as observable ones. We consider models with flat space sections separately. The metric (16) after the transformation (21) takes the following form:</figDesc>
					<trash>ds 2 n = dτ 2 − τ 2n/n−1 [dr 2 + r 2 (dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] , if n = 1; ds 2 1 = dτ 2 − e ±2τ [dr 2 + r 2 (dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, if n = 1, (22) where τ is the world time. Similarly one can derive an observable metric for the solution (17) ds 2 n = dτ 2 − τ 2(n+1)/(n+2) [dr 2</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>+ r 2 (dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] if n = −2; ds 2 −2 = dτ 2 − e ±τ [dr 2 + r 2 (dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )] if n = −2. (23)</trash>

					<figDesc>Let us use the well known expression for the matter energy-momentum tensor in GR T µν = (p + ε)u µ u ν − pg µν (24) In our case there is no nongeometric matter, however there is the scalar field ϕ, and we shall consider it to be describing external matter. Substituting the metric components from (22)–(23) to the left-hand side of the Einstein equations and T µν from (24) to right-hand side, we can deduce expressions for the energy density ε and the pressure p of the effective simulated matter in comoving reference frame:</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>ε = 3 ˙ λ 2 ; p = −3 ˙ λ 2 − 2 ¨ λ 2 , (25)</formula></p>

				<p>where ˙ λ ≡ dλ/dτ . Let us introduce k which determines the equation of state:</p>

				<p><formula>p = kε. (26)</formula></p>

				<p>For the flat space section k is constant. For the metrics (22) we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>k = −1 + 2 3 · n − 1 n , (27) for instance, if n = 1 → p = −ε −Zeldovich matter; if n = −2 → p = 0 −dust; if n = −1 → p = ε/3 −radiation; if n = −1/2 → p = ε −stiff matter; For the metrics (23) in a similar manner we find k = −1 + 2 3 · n + 2 n + 1 , (28) For instance, if n = −2 → p = −ε −Zeldovich matter; if n = 1 → p = 0 −dust; if n = 0 → p = ε/3 −radiation; if n = −1/2 → p = ε −stiff matter;</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>So, for any equation of state (any k=const) in both solutions one can select an appropriate value of the index n for the conformal factor and vice versa, i.e. the 5-d solutions (16) and (17) describe all cosmological 4-d models of Friedmann type with a flat 3-d space section and the matter equation of state p = kε. This result is in accordance with those, obtained in [17] by another method.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Nonflat cosmological models</head>

				<p>For the solutions (18) and (19), corresponding to cosmological models with nonflat 3-d space sections, the 4-d metrics after the conformal transformation can be written in the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A) ds 2 n = (t 2 0 − t 2 ) n t 2n dt 2 − (t 2 0 − t 2 ) n+1 t 2n [dr 2 + sin 2 r(dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )], (29) where the proper time τ can be found from the expression τ = ± (t 2 0 − t 2 ) n/2 t n dt + τ 0 ; (30) B) ds 2 n = (t 2 − t 2 0 ) n t 2n dt 2 − (t 2 − t 2 0 ) n+1 t 2n [dr 2 + sinh 2 r(dθ 2 + sin 2 θdϕ 2 )], (31) where τ = ± (t 2 − t 2 0 ) n/2 t n dt + τ 0 ; (32)</trash>

					<figDesc>Simple reasoning provides the following expression for the effective ε and p</figDesc>
					<trash>ε = 3 ˙ λ 2 + 3se −2λ ; p = −3 ˙ λ 2 − 2 ¨ λ − se −2λ . (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In both these cases the coefficient k is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>k = (2n + 1)t 2 − (n + 2)nt 2 0 3[(2n + 1)t 2 + n 2 t 2 0</trash>

					<figDesc>]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, (34) i.e. is in general a function of time. There are some special cases, when k = const: ) n = 0 or −1 → k = 1/3 — radiation; b) n = −1/2 → k = 1 — stiff matter. In all other cases k is a function of time. Below we comment on some peculiarities of 8 variants, depending on values of n: a) each variant contains a time interval, when the Universe is expanding; b) for most of the variants matter passes through a dust-like state; c) for n ∈ (0, 1) and n ∈ (−2, −1) in closed models there is an infinite expansion for a finite time; d) there is no variants that could give the sequence matter states: vacuum — radiation — dust. For instance, open models for n ≥ 1 contain the sequence: vacuum — dust — radiation and for n ∈ (0, 1) closed models give the sequence: radiation — dust — vacuum; e) when n ≤ −1/2, for open models the function k(t) acquires vertical asymptotes and has the corresponding peculiar moments of time. At these moments a specific kind of &quot; phase transition &quot; takes place; f) cases with n ≤ −1 contain examples of cosmological models without cosmological singularities.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">General conformal transformation</head>

				<p>Results that have been obtained in the previous section, demonstrate pros and cons of the interpretation, proposed here. As since Big Bang matter has evolved and passed through a number of a different states it would be reasonable to create 4-d cosmological solutions with a variable equation of state that would have in this case a phenomenological nature. The application of a conformal transformation, on the other hand, gives a variable equation of state automatically, but there appears the problem of choosing the conformal factor. Conformally transformed 5-d solutions with nonzero space curvature, as have been shown in previous section, give neither the required sequence of matter states, nor equations of state of the form p = kε with arbitrary k = const.</p>

				<p>To obtain this class of equations of state, it is necessary to abandon the restriction (20) and consider the case of a general conformal transformation F (ϕ):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˜ g µν = 1 F 2 (ϕ 2 ) g µν . (35) Then for close models we have ds 2 = F 2 (ϕ 2 )dt 2 − F 2 (ϕ 2 )(t 2 0 − t 2 )dl 2 + ; ϕ 2 = t 2 t 2 0 − t 2 . (36) In the same way for open models ds 2 = F 2 (ϕ 2 )dt 2 − F 2 (ϕ 2 )(t 2 − t 2 0 )dl 2 − ; ϕ 2 = t 2 t 2 − t 2 0 . (37)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here l + and l − are the 3-d intervals of closed and open models. A calculation, performed in the same way as in section 3, leads to the following expression for k:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>k + = p ε = 4t 4 0 t 2 (F ′2 − 2F F ′′ ) − 4F F ′ t 2 0 (t 4 0 − t 4 ) + t 2 0 F 2 (t 2 0 − t 2 ) 2 12F ′2 t 2 t 4 0 − 12F F ′ t 2 t 2 0 (t 2 0 − t 2 ) + 3F 2 t 2 0 (t 2 0 − t 2 ) 2 . (38) k − for open model can be derived from k + by changing t → it, t 0 → it 0 , ϕ 2 → −ϕ 2 : k − = 4t 4 0 t 2 (F ′2 − 2F F ′′ ) + 4F F ′ t 2 0 (t 4 0 − t 4 ) + t 2 0 F 2 (t 2 0 − t 2 ) 2 12F ′2 t 2 t 4 0 + 12F F ′ t 2 t 2 0 (t 2 0 − t 2 ) + 3F 2 t 2 0 (t 2 0 − t 2 ) 2 . (39) Here F ′ = dF (ϕ 2 )/d(ϕ 2 ). Making a change of the variable and the function, x = t 2 /(t 2 − t 2 0 ), u = F 2−σ 2 , (σ = 1 − 3k = 2) we obtain for open models the hyphergeometric Gauss equation x(x − 1)u ′′ + [(α + β + 1)x − γ]u ′ + αβu = 0, (40) where α + β + 1 = (σ + 1)/2; γ = 1/2</trash>

					<figDesc>; αβ = σ(σ − 2)/16. For closed models x should be changed to −x. The general solution of (40) has the form</figDesc>
					<trash>u = C 1 F (α, β, 1/2, x) + C 2 √ xF (α + 1/2, β + 1/2, 3/2, x) (41)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where F is the hyphergeometric function. So, if geometrized matter has the equation of state p = kε, where k = const, then the conformal factor F should have a form more general then (20) and should satisfy (40). For example, for dust (k = 0) Eq. (40) has the particular solution F = 1 + 1 ± ϕ 2 for closed and open models, respectively. For Zeldovich matter (k = −1) F = 1 ± ϕ 2 . For σ = 2 (k = −1/3) we obtain a linear equation of second order for F and it&apos;s solution can be written in terms of elementary functions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="7">Conclusion</head>

				<p>So, in 5-d Kaluza-Klein theory, matter can be indeed described by a geometric scalar field (ϕ = √ G 55 ), while in 4-d GR it is conventional to substitute an arbitrary through tensor T µν . The freedom in choosing the conformal factor corresponds to different possible equations of state for matter. In the present paper it has been demonstrated that for flat cosmological models the equations of state is prescribed by the index of the conformal factor ϕ n . For nonflat models a number of variants is possible. Variable equations of state with &quot; phase transitions &quot; of matter are obtained automatically. To describe of matter with constant equations of state it is necessary to use conformal factors of a more general form than the exponential function.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* e-mail: vlad@fund.phys.msu.su † e-mail: sergey@yspu.yar.ru</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The appearance of this method can be traced back to the works of Mandel [22], then it was improved in the works of Einstein and Bergmann [23]. It was ultimately formulated in the works by one of the present authors [20]</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Sitzungsber.preuss.Akad.Wiss.Phys.-math.Kl.-1927-s</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Einstein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Physik-1933-bd.18-s.305</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Pauli</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Ann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">337</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Math.Phys.-1978-v</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Pigeaud</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Repts</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="284" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vestnik MGU-Ser.phys.and astron.-1982-N6-p</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vladimirov</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Kislov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Russian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Foundations of Physics-1975-v</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Browne</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="3" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Vladimirov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Miroshnic</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A O</forename>
				<surname>Mishakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Wiss</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">der Phys-1974-1-S219-228. Brans C., Dicke R.H. Phys.Rev.-1961-124-p</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jordan</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Ann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="925" to="935" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
				<surname>Mandel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="136" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">J.-1992-v.394-p</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Astroph</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Astroph</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="420" to="49" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Astroph</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="440" to="1" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Grav.-1994-v.11-p</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Leon</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Ponce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Class</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1341" to="1351" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Leon</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Ponce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Lim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int.J.of Mod.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="170" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Leon</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Ponce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4070" to="4079" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Leon</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J J</forename>
				<surname>Ponce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Math</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3883" to="3887" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kalligas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Everitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Astroph</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="548" to="557" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Kokarev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Grav</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cosm</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="247" to="251" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Itogi nauki i techniki-1991-p</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vladimirov</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Popov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Russian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Zelmanov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Dan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Russian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reference frame in gravitation theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vladimirov</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">M.Energoizdat</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Russian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimension of physical spase-time and unification of interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vladimirov</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">M. Izd.MGU</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Russian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Mandel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Zs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Einstein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Bergmann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Space-time: explicit and hidden dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vladimirov</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">M.Nauka</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Russian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Abstracts of school-ceminar &quot; Multid. grav. and cosm</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Kokarev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page">19</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In. Rus- sian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Ivashchuk</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Let</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
