<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">New Limits to the IR Background: Bounds on Radiative Neutrino Decay and on VMO Contributions to the Dark Matter Problem</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">S</forename>
								<forename type="middle">D</forename>
								<surname>Biller</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Oxford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Buckley</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Washington University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>St. Louis</settlement>
									<region>Mo</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<surname>Burdett</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Leeds</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Leeds</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Bussons</forename>
								<surname>Gordo</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">D</forename>
								<forename type="middle">A</forename>
								<surname>Carter-Lewis</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ames</settlement>
									<region>IA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">D</forename>
								<forename type="middle">J</forename>
								<surname>Fegan</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Finley</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Purdue University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Lafayette</settlement>
									<region>IN</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<forename type="middle">A</forename>
								<surname>Gaidos</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Purdue University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Lafayette</settlement>
									<region>IN</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<forename type="middle">M</forename>
								<surname>Hillas</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Leeds</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Leeds</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">F</forename>
								<surname>Krennrich</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ames</settlement>
									<region>IA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">R</forename>
								<forename type="middle">C</forename>
								<surname>Lamb</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>California</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">R</forename>
								<surname>Lessard</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Purdue University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Lafayette</settlement>
									<region>IN</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<forename type="middle">E</forename>
								<surname>Mcenery</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">G</forename>
								<surname>Mohanty</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ames</settlement>
									<region>IA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Quinn</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<forename type="middle">J</forename>
								<surname>Rodgers</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Leeds</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Leeds</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">H</forename>
								<forename type="middle">J</forename>
								<surname>Rose</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Leeds</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Leeds</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">F</forename>
								<surname>Samuelson</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ames</settlement>
									<region>IA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">G</forename>
								<surname>Sembroski</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Purdue University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Lafayette</settlement>
									<region>IN</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">P</forename>
								<surname>Skelton</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Leeds</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Leeds</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">T</forename>
								<forename type="middle">C</forename>
								<surname>Weekes</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Whipple Observatory</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amado</settlement>
									<region>AZ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Zweerink</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ames</settlement>
									<region>IA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">New Limits to the IR Background: Bounds on Radiative Neutrino Decay and on VMO Contributions to the Dark Matter Problem</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:astro-ph/9802234v1 18 Feb 1998 To Appear In Physical Review Letters 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>From considering the effect of γ-γ interactions on recently observed TeV gamma-ray spectra, improved limits are set to the density of extra-galactic infrared (IR) photons which are robust and essentially model-independent. The resulting limits are up to two orders of magnitude more restrictive than direct observations in the 0.025-0.3 eV regime. These limits are used to improve constraints on radiative neutrino decay in the mass range above 0.05eV and on Very Massive Objects (VMOs) as providing the dark matter needed to explain galaxy rotation curves.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The extragalactic background IR field potentially contains a wealth of information relevant to both cosmology and particle physics (see for example [1]), but has so far eluded any conclusive detection. Direct measurement of the characteristics of this radiation are frustrated by the dominance of local, galactic IR sources. TeV gamma-ray astronomy provides a means to study the IR background indirectly, free of such complications, by looking for modifications to high energy gamma ray spectra due to interactions with this background field via the process γγ −→ e + e − . This idea was first noted by Gould and Schréder [2] and has been more recently restated by Stecker and de Jager [3]. Previous IR studies making use of this phenomenon have generally used spectral data from the active galactic nucleus (AGN) Mrk 421 taken by the EGRET [4] and Whipple [5] experiments at GeV and TeV energies, respectively . These studies have relied on extrapolating flux measurements between these two energy regimes in an effort to determine the inherent shape of the source spectrum [3] [6] [7] [8]. This approach has several difficulties: 1) Since the flux level is known to be highly variable at TeV energies, the relative normalization between EGRET and Whipple flux measurements is not known; 2) The flux of IR photons cannot be assumed to be zero in the intervening energy range; and 3) The shape of the inherent source spectrum is not known and cannot be assumed to necessarily follow a single power law from GeV to TeV energies. Indeed, current best fit values for Mrk 421 at TeV energies indicate a steeper spectrum than is reflected by the EGRET data [10], suggesting that the spectral shape changes in the intervening energy range. In addition, most of the analyses have assumed a particular model to describe the shape of the IR photon spectrum. Even a more recent attempt at a less model-dependent limit using data from Mrk 501 nevertheless assumes a power-law source spectrum , an arbitrary IR flux normalization and constant IR energy densities over energy ranges spanning up to an order of magnitude in extent [11]. Limits derived in this manner may not apply if the background IR spectrum is of a different shape and, in particular, cannot necessarily be used to constrain mechanisms which might produce sharp features in the spectrum on a scale smaller than that of the assumed model. This current paper will attempt to define more robust limits based on recent high energy observations of AGN which do not rely on extrapolation from lower energies or the assumption of a strict power-law source spectrum and are independent of the IR model down to scales corresponding to a factor of 2 change in IR energy. These limits will then be used to constrain significantly the possible contribution of Very Massive Objects (VMOs) to the dark matter problem and also to place improved bounds on the radiative decay of massive neutrinos in the mass range above ∼ 0.05 eV, which is in the regime of interest to the atmospheric neutrino problem.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Derived Upper Limits to the Background IR</head>

				<p>Two active galaxies, Mrk 421 and Mrk 501, have thus far been seen to produce TeV gamma-ray emission by independent experimental groups. These active galaxies are both of the blazar class and are located at redshifts of 0.031 and 0.033, respectively. Both objects have exhibited significant flux variability at TeV energies, changing by an order of magnitude or more with characteristic timescales of less than an hour (in the case of Mrk 421, as short as 15 minutes).</p>

				<p>Recent analyses of data from Mrk 421 by the Whipple group [9] [10] indicate a differential spectrum with an ∼ E −2.6 power law extending to energies beyond 5 TeV, possibly as high as 8 TeV. Similarly, the HEGRA collaboration has measured the &quot; high-state &quot; spectrum of Mrk 501 [12] and has found it to be described by an ∼ E −2.5 power law extending to energies as high as 10 TeV. For the purposes of this paper, the available data on active galaxies at a redshift of ∼ 0.03 will thus be taken to indicate a spectral shape which is bounded at the 90% confidence level between the power laws E −2.3 and E</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>−2.8</head>

				<p>and normalized by an arbitrary flux constant. It will be assumed that the measured spectra continue up to energies of 10 TeV. However, due to possible systematic uncertainties in energy scale of ∼30%, more conservative limits will also be computed assuming a maximum gamma-ray energy of 6 TeV. Finally, it will be assumed that the inherent differential source spectrum is steeper than an E −2 power law, although the specific shape need not be a power law itself. The limits derived are relatively insensitive to this latter choice. For example selecting E −1.5 as a bound was found to change the inferred limits by less than 30%. For ease of computation, the high energy spectrum is taken to consist of differential flux measurements at the following discrete energies:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0.4, 0.75, 1.0, 1.5, 2.0, 3.0, 4.0, 6.0 and 10.0 TeV. The spectrum of IR photons is approximated by a series of separate intervals spanning the energies 0.025-0.042, 0.042-0.083, 0.083-0.167, 0.167-0.33, 0.33-0.625 and 0.625-1.0 eV.</trash>

					<figDesc>Within each interval, the value of ε 2 n(ε) is taken as constant, where ε is the energy of the IR photon and n is the number density of photons (i.e. photons/cm 3 /eV).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The value of ε 2 n(ε) among these intervals can thus be varied to reflect different background IR models, and the corresponding effect of γ-γ absorption on TeV gamma-rays calculated according to the prescription described by previous papers [3], [8]. For these calculations, a conservative value for the Hubble constant of 85 km/s/Mpc is assumed [13]. To calculate upper limits then, the inherent AGN differential spectrum was allowed to assume any shape steeper than E −2 and the values of ε 2 n(ε) among IR intervals were allowed to take on any values subject to the following constraints: 1) that these values are lower than the directly determined upper bounds imposed by other experiments (shown in figure 1); and 2) that the attenuation implied by the IR model would not cause the shape of the observed TeV spectrum to deviate outside of the power-law bounds previously defined based on the data. This approach essentially anchors the lower energy TeV data to the appropriate observational upper bounds and then extends these bounds based on the shape and extent of the AGN spectra at higher energies. From these considerations, the maximum value of energy density permitted in each IR interval was determined. The resulting limits are summarized in table 1 and are also plotted in figure 1 for assumed maximum gamma-ray energies of 6 TeV and 10 TeV. Note that this choice of maximum energy primarily effects only the two lowest energy IR intervals.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Upper Limit to ε 2 n(ε) (eV/cm 3 ) Energy Interval (eV) E max = 10 TeV E max = 6 TeV 0.025-0.042 0.0064 0.042-0.083 0.0027 0.094 0.083-0.167 0.0027 0.0038 0.167-0.33 0.0035 0.0037 0.33-0.625 0.0052 0.0052 0.625-1.0 0.012 0.012</trash>

					<head>Table 1:</head>

					<figDesc>Derived upper limits to ε 2 n(ε)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In the range of 0.025 − 0.33 eV, the limits presented here are up to 2 orders of magnitude more restrictive than those of DIRBE [14]. Note that these limits apply only to models which would produce features in the IR spectrum on a scale comparable to or larger than the interval widths used in the calculation. Monoenergetic line features, for example, are not necessarily constrained by these limits.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Constraints on VMO Abundance</head>

				<p>Under certain cosmological scenarios, density fluctuations in the early universe at a redshift of ∼1000 could give rise to the pregalactic formation of massive stars (200 &lt; M/M ⊙ &lt; 10 5 ) at redshifts in the range of ∼100-300 [15]. Such Very Massive Objects (VMOs) would collapse to black holes after their mainsequence phase without any significant metal ejection. It has been suggested that the remnants of VMOs, which would ultimately cluster with galaxies, might provide an explanation for the dark matter associated with galaxy rotation curves [16], [17]. Such rotation curves indicate that the amount of dark matter is in excess of 5 percent of the critical density, while other studies of galaxy motion and hot gas in clusters of galaxies suggest a value as high as 20 percent [13]. While invisible now, VMOs would have produced a significant flux of IR photons during their burning phase. The peak number density of these photons is given [1] by:</p>

				<p><formula>ε 2 pk n V (ε pk ) ≃ 40 Ω V h 2 1 + z V ε pk ≃ 30 1 + z V</formula></p>

				<p>where ε pk is the IR photon energy (in eV) corresponding to the peak of the VMO contribution, n V is the photon number density due to VMOs in cm −3 eV −1 , Ω V is the mass-density of VMOs expressed as a fraction of the critical density, z V is the formation redshift of the VMOs, and the Hubble constant is given by H 0 = 100h km/s/Mpc. Thus, the IR limits derived previously may be used to place upper bounds on Ω V . These bounds are shown in figure 2 as a function of the assumed VMO formation redshift for h=0.65 (which is conservative for this limit). Note that for either maximum gammaray energy assumed, the limit on Ω V is less than 0.05 for the redshift range of 100-200 and less than 0.065 for the range 200-300. If the maximum gamma-ray energy is taken to be 10 TeV, the limit is less than 0.05 for the the entire 100- 300 range. Hence, assuming minimal reprocessing by dust grains, these limits appear to rule out VMO models as providing the explanation for observed galaxy rotation curves.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Constraints on Radiative Neutrino Decay</head>

				<p>Several experiments have observed an apparent descrepency in the ratio of ν e to ν µ fluxes expected from cosmic ray interactions in the atmosphere [18] [19] [20]. A possible explanation for this effect may involve 2-component neutrino oscillations with ∆m 2 ∼ 0.01eV 2 and, thus, a neutrino mass in the regime of 0.1 eV (provided the mass of the lighter neutrino is comparable to or smaller than this value). If neutrinos have mass and different flavor eigenstates may mix, then massive neutrinos might decay via the process ν H → ν L + γ, where m ν H &gt; m ν L . For neutrino masses in the ∼eV regime, such a radiative decay process would contribute to the infrared background. Although monoenergetic photons would be initially produced from a 2-body decay, the photon spectrum would be broadened for relic neutrinos which decay over a range of redshifts such that the background density can be constrained by the limits presented previously. Some unstable relic neutrinos with a lifetime longer than that of the universe would still be decaying now and would have produced a background photon density given by: n γ (ǫ) ≃ 1.1 × 10 12 B r τ ν hǫ where ǫ is half the rest mass of the unstable neutrino in eV, n γ is the photon number density due to neutrino decay in cm −3 eV −1 , B r is the branching ratio for the radiative decay mode and τ ν is the neutrino lifetime in years [21]. Implied lower bounds for τ ν /B r in the neutrino mass range 0.1eV &lt; m ν &lt; 1eV are shown in figure 3 based on the IR limits presented in this paper for h = 0.85. Previous constraints in this mass range from the work of Ressell and Turner [21] are shown for comparison. This represents an improvement of the constraints in some cases by more than 2 orders of magnitude. Similarly, neutrinos with lifetimes shorter than the age of the universe but longer than the age at which decoupling of matter and radiation occurred will result in a background photon density given by:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n γ (ǫ) ≃ 115 B r ǫ where, in this case, ǫ = 1 2 m ν c 2 eV τ ν √ Ω o h 6.5 × 10 9 yr 2/3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where Ω o is the mass-density of the universe in units of the critical density. IR limits given here have thus been used to define exclusion contours which can be conveniently characterised by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B r &lt; 10 −4 1eV m o for the region defined by m ν = m o 1eV 6.5 × 10 9 yr τ ν √ Ω o h 2/3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where 0.05eV &lt; m o &lt; 2.0eV for an assumed maximum gamma-ray energy of 10 TeV, and 0.1eV &lt; m o &lt; 2.0eV for a maximum energy of 6 TeV. Once again, this represents an improvement in branching ratio sensitivity of approximately two orders of magnitude.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Discussion</head>

				<p>Recent data from very high energy gamma-ray observations of active galaxies has been used to set improved upper limits to the infared background radiation which are robust and relatively model-independent. These limits cast doubt on VMO models as providing the explanation for dark matter in galactic halos and tighten constraints on the radiative decay of relic neutrinos in the mass range near 0.1 eV by approximately two orders of magnitude. Substantial improvement in the ability to study the infrared background via γ-γ interactions is expected with the next generation of instruments which will allow the behavior of more distant sources to be examined. In fact, the procedure used to derive the limits given in Table 1 may also be used to determine lower limits to the maximum distance out to which TeV gamma-ray telescopes can be expected to probe. This has been done for the gamma-ray energy range of 0.4-10 TeV, assuming that a source remains &quot; visible &quot; out to an optical depth of 2 and that the majority of the IR was produced prior to the epoch of the sources under study. IR and UV upper bounds from direct observations in the energy range greater than 2 eV have also been used to calculate this minimum distance for gamma-ray energies of 0.05 and 0.1 TeV. The results are shown in figure 4. The current generation of groundbased , gamma-ray telescopes have a typical lower energy threshold of ∼0.5 TeV and are thus expected to be able to see sources possessing redshifts up to or beyond z=0.1. The next generation of instruments is expected to have an energy threshold in the region of 0.05 to 0.1 TeV, and will therefore be able to see out to a redshift of at least z=0.5. This represents a substantially larger volume of space than has so far been explored at TeV energies. This, and the known preponderance of AGN at larger redshifts, indicates a bright future for ground-based, gamma-ray astronomy and strongly suggests a drive towards higher duty cycles, larger apertures and greater dynamic ranges for such instruments to explore this regime thoroughly. This work has been supported in part by PPARC, Forbairt, the US Department of Energy, NASA and the Smithsonian Institution.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 1:</head>

					<figDesc>Upper limits to the background infrared background: &quot; + &quot; symbols are from Matsumoto et al. [22]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>; the diamond is from Dube et al. [23]; the triangle is from Toller [24]; squares are from Hauser et al. [14]; circles are from Kashlinsky et al. [25]; crosses are from Maucherat-Joubert et al. [26]; the solid lines show the limits derived in this work for a maximum gamma-ray energy of 10 TeV, while the dashed lines correspond to a maximum energy of 6 TeV. Figure 2: Upper limits to the abundance of Very Massive Objects based on bounds to the IR background derived in this work. The limit is expressed as a fraction of the critical density and is plotted as a function of the assumed formation redshift of the VMOs. The solid line corresponds to an assumed maximum gamma-ray energy of 10 TeV and the dashed line to a maximum energy of 6 TeV. Figure 3: Lower bounds to the ratio of the neutrino lifetime to the branching ratio for radiative decay based on this current work for the case where the neutrino lifetime is greater than the current age of the universe. The solid line shows the limits derived here assuming a maximum gamma-ray energy of 10 TeV, while the dashed line coresponds to a maximum energy of 6 TeV. Open squares show the limits derived previously by Ressell and Turner.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4:</head>

					<figDesc>Lower limits to the maximum redshift out to which TeV gamma-ray sources are visible as a function of primary gamma-ray energy, based on limits to the background density of IR/UV photons.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:astro-ph/9802234v1 18 Feb 1998</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Bond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Carr</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">&amp;</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Hogan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">306</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">428</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Gould</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">&amp; G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Schré</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">155</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1408</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Stecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">&amp;</forename>
				<forename type="middle">O C</forename>
				<surname>De Jager</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ap</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">71</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Hartman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2nd Compton Symposium</title>
		<meeting>. 2nd Compton Symposium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Mohanty</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 23rd I</title>
		<meeting>. 23rd I<address><addrLine>Calgary</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Dwek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">&amp;</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Slavin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">436</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">696</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>De</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Jager</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Stecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Salamon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">294</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Biller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">445</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">227</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Krennrich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">481</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">758</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Zweerink</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">490</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">141</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Stanev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Franceschini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ap</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. and Astrophys</title>
		<editor>12] F. Aharonian et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">494</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="5" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Barnett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">After the First Three Minutes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Hauser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AIP Conference Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Bond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Arnett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Carr</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ap</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>16] B.J. Carr, J.R. Bond and W.D. Arnett, Ap. J.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="825" to="445" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Faber</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Gallagher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Rev. Astr. Ap</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">135</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Becker-Szendy</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3720</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Suzuki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Neutrino &apos;96</title>
		<editor>K. Enquist, K. Huitu and J. Maalompi</editor>
		<meeting>. of Neutrino &apos;96<address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>World Scientific</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W M</forename>
				<surname>Allison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">391</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">491</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Comments on Astrophys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Ressell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Turner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page">323</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Matsumoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Akiba</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Murakami</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ap</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page">575</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Dube</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">232</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">333</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Toller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ap</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<biblScope unit="page">79</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kashlinsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ap. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">470</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">681</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Maucherat-Jobert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Ap</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">323</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
