<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Non-abelian gauge theories as a consequence of perturbative quantum gauge invariance *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<surname>Aste</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institut fürTheoretischePhysik</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitätZürich</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Winterthurerstrasse190</addrLine>
									<postCode>CH-8057</postCode>
									<settlement>Zürich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">G</forename>
								<surname>Scharf</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institut fürTheoretischePhysik</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitätZürich</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Winterthurerstrasse190</addrLine>
									<postCode>CH-8057</postCode>
									<settlement>Zürich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Non-abelian gauge theories as a consequence of perturbative quantum gauge invariance *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9803011v2 29 Jan 1999 * Work supported by Swiss National Science Foundation 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term>1110 -Field theory</term>
					<term>1120 -S-matrix theory</term>
					<term>1235 -General properties of quan- 
 tum chromodynamics</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We show for the case of interacting massless vector bosons, how the structure of Yang-Mills theories emerges automatically from a more fundamental concept, namely perturbative quantum gauge invariance. It turns out that the coupling in a non-abelian gauge theory is necessarily of Yang-Mills type plus divergence-and coboundary couplings. The extension of the method to massive gauge theories is briefly discussed.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>It is a well-known fact that gauge theories have many pleasing features. Apart from the beauty of the mathematical structure of the classical theories, it is the renormalizability of their quantum versions which makes them so important for particle physicists. What is less known is that some basic properties of non-abelian quantum gauge theories can be understood as the consequence of a suitable quantum version of gauge invariance. It is the aim of this paper to demonstrate this fact for the case of interacting massless vector bosons. The result will be the usual Yang-Mills plus ghost couplings plus some divengence-and coboundary couplings. The nice feature of this approach is that the Lie algebra structure of the Yang-Mills theory is not put in, but comes out: the antisymmetry of the structure constants follows from first order gauge invariance and the Jacobi identity from second order. This fact has been noticed by R. Stora in a more special setting [1].</p>

				<p>The present method has already been used by us to analyse the abelian Higgs model [2] and the electroweak theory [3, 4].</p>

				<p>The paper is organized as follows: In section 2 we present our general framework and define perturbative quantum gauge invariance on the Fock space of free asymptotic massless vector bosons and scalar fermionic ghosts [5, 6]. In section 3 we investigate how gauge invariance restricts all renormalizable couplings of the gauge fields at first and second order of perturbation theory. In section 4 we give a short outlook how the presented method can be generalized to the case of massive gauge bosons.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 Theoretical Framework 2.1 Construction of the S-Matrix</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this paper, we consider the perturbative S-matrix as a sum of smeared operator-valued distributions of the following form [7, 8]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S(g) = 1 + ∞ n=1 1 n! dx 1 ...dx n T n (x 1 , ...x n )g(x 1 ) · ...g(x n ), (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where g ∈ S, the Schwartz space of functions of rapid decrease. The test function g plays the role of &apos;adiabatic switching&apos; and provides a cutoff in the long-range part of the interaction, without destroying any symmetry. It can be considered as a natural infrared regulator. We work with free asymptotic fields throughout, so that all expressions are well-defined; interacting fields nowhere appear. The T n (x 1 , ...x n ) are well-defined time-ordered products of the first order coupling T 1 (x), they are expressed in terms of Wick monomials of free fields. The construction of the T n requires some care: If the arguments (x 1 , ...x n ) are all time-ordered, i.e. if we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x 0 1 &gt; x 0 2 &gt; ... &gt; x 0 n , (2) then T n is simply given by T n (x 1 , ...x n ) = T 1 (x 1 )T 1 (x 2 )... · T 1 (x n ) (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>According to the definition (1) T n (x 1 , ...x n ) is symmetric in x 1 , ...x n . Using this fact allows us in principle to obtain the operator-valued distribution T n inductively everywhere except for the complete diagonal ∆ n = {x 1 = ... = x n } [9].If T n were a C-number distribution, we could make it a well-defined distribution for all x 1 , ...x n by extending the distribution from R 4n /∆ n to R 4 .</p>

				<p>The problem can be reduced to a C-number problem by the Wick expansion of the operatorvalued distributions. The extension T (x 1 , ...x n ) is, of course, not unique: it is ambiguous up to distributions with local support ∆ n . This ambiguity can be further reduced by the help of symmetries (in particular gauge invariance) and power counting theory. The concrete inductive construction of the T n has also to be performed carefully. Since the behaviour of the distributions in p-space is much better than the very singular one in x-space, it is advantageous to use the original Epstein-Glaser method of splitting causal distributions [8, 10], instead of the above extension method, because the former can be translated to p-space. The well-known ultraviolet divergences are in fact a consequence of &apos;careless&apos; splitting of operator valued distributions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Definition of Perturbative Quantum Gauge Invariance</head>

				<p>We introduce the concept of gauge invariance for the simple case of quantum electrodynamics first, where the coupling of the electron to the photon is given at first order by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T 1 (x) = ie : ¯ Ψ(x)γ µ Ψ(x) : A µ (x) . (4) Let Q def = d 3 x(∂ µ A µ (x) ↔ ∂ 0 u(x)) (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>be the generator of (free) gauge transformations, called gauge charge for brevity. This Q has first been introduced in a paper by T. Kugo and I. Ojima [11]. A µ is the gauge potential in the Feynman gauge, and we choose u as a scalar fermionic field, in order to have Q 2 = 0 (see section 2.3). The free fields satisfy the well-known commutation relations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>[A (±) µ (x), A (∓) ν (y)] = ig µν D (∓) (x − y), (6) {u (±) (x), ˜ u (∓) (y)} = −iD (∓) (x − y), (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and all other commutators vanish. D ∓ are the well-known positive and negative frequency parts of the Pauli-Jordan distribution. All the fields fulfil the Klein-Gordon equation with zero mass, and as already mentioned, we are working in Feynman gauge, but we are not forced to do so.</p>

				<p>The following discussion would go through with some technical changes in other covariant ξgauges as well [12]. In order to see how the infinitesimal gauge tranformation acts on the free fields, we calculate the commutators [5]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>[Q, A µ ] = i∂ µ u , {Q, u} = 0 , {Q, ˜ u} = −i∂ ν A ν , [Q, Ψ] = [Q, ¯ Ψ] = 0 . (8) Then we have [Q, T 1 (x)] = −e : ¯ Ψγ µ Ψ : ∂ µ u = i∂ µ (ie : ¯ Ψγ µ Ψ : u) = i∂ µ T µ 1/1 (x). (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that the free electron field is not affected by the gauge transformation. We will call T µ 1/1 the &apos;Q-vertex&apos; in the sequel. The generalization of (9) to n-th order is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>[Q, T n (x 1 , ...x n )] = i n l=1 ∂ x l µ T µ n/l (x 1 , ...x n ) = (sum of divergences) , (10) where T µ n/l is a mathematically rigorous version of the time-ordered product T µ n/l (x 1 , ..., x n ) &quot; = &quot; T (T 1 (x 1 )...T µ 1/1 (x l )...T 1 (x n )) , (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>constructed by means of the methods described in section 2.1. We define (10) to be the condition of gauge invariance [5]. For a fixed x l we consider from T n all terms with the external field operator A µ (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x l ) T n (x 1 , ...x n ) =: t µ l (x 1 , ...x n )A µ (x l ) : +... (12) (the dots represent terms without A µ (x l )). Then gauge invariance (10) requires ∂ l µ [t µ l (x 1 , ...x n )u(x l )] = t µ l (x 1 , ...x n )∂ µ u(x l ) (13) or ∂ l µ t µ l (x 1 , ...x n ) = 0 , (14) i.e. we obtain the Ward-Takahashi identities [13]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for QED. As a further step, we consider the Yang-Mills theory without fermions now. The first order coupling shall be given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T 1 (x) = igf abc { 1 2 : A µa (x)A νb (x)F νµ c (x) : − : A µa (x)u b (x)∂ µ ˜ u c (x) :} , (15) where F νµ a</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>= ∂ ν A ν a − ∂ µ A ν a is the free field strength tensor, u a , ˜ u a are the (fermionic) ghost fields, and the f abc are the usual SU (N ) structure constants. The asymptotic free fields satisfy the commutation relations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>[A (±) µa (x), A (∓) νb (y)] = iδ ab g µν D (∓) (x − y) (16) and {u (±) a (x), ˜ u (∓) b (y)} = −iδ ab D (∓) (x − y), (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and all other {anti-}commutators vanish. The introduction of ghost couplings is necessary here to preserve perturbative quantum gauge invariance at first order. Defining the gauge charge as in (5) by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Q := d 3 x∂ µ A µ a (x) ↔ ∂ 0 u a (x) , (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where summation over repeated indices is understood, we are led to the following (anti-) commutators with the fields:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>[Q, A µ a ] = i∂ µ u a , [Q, F µν a ] = 0 , {Q, u a } = 0 , {Q, ˜ u a } = −i∂ µ A µ a . (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Obviously, these gauge variations have a &apos;simpler&apos; structure than the well-known BRS transformation , because the non-abelian parts are missing here.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Calculating [Q, T 1 (x)] gives the Q-vertex T µ 1/1 = igf abc {: u a A νb F µν c : + 1 2 : u a u b ∂ µ ˜ u c :} (20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the first order coupling is gauge invariant through the presence of a ghost coupling term in T 1 . The first order coupling given in (15) is in fact not the most general one, and it is also possible to construct a gauge invariant first order coupling with bosonic ghosts [5]; but gauge invariance then breaks down at second order of perturbation theory. Gauge invariance at order n is again defined by (11). Note that the usual 4-gluon term ∼ g 2 is missing in T 1 . This term appears as a necessary local normalization term at second order, as we shall see (67). This stresses the fact that our notion of perturbative gauge invariance is strongly related to the formal expansion of the theory in powers of the coupling constant g, in contrast to the conventional treatment which discusses quantum effects of a local gauge group via formal expansions in powers of ¯ h. In our approach, no local gauge group is assumed from the start. Local gauge groups will rather appear as a consequence of perturbative gauge invariance.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2.3</head>

				<p>Important properties of the gauge charge Q</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Using the Leibnitz rule for graded algebras gives Q 2 = 1 2 {Q, Q} = 1 2 x 0 =const. d 3 x∂ ν A ν a (x){ ↔ ∂ x 0 u a (x), Q} − 1 2 x 0 =const. d 3 x[∂ ν A ν a (x), Q] ↔ ∂ x 0 u a (x) = 0 , (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>i.e. Q is nilpotent. This basic property of Q and the Krein structure on the Fock-Hilbert space [14, 15] allows to prove unitarity of the S-matrix on the physical Hilbert space H phys , which is a subspace of the Fock-Hilbert space F containing also the unphysical ghosts and unphysical degrees of freedom of the vector field [6]. The physical Fock space can be expressed by the kernel and the range of Q [6, 14], namely</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H phys = ker Q/ran Q = ker{Q, Q + } . (22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This can be most easily seen by realizing the various field operators on a positive definite Fock- Hilbert space F as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A 0 (x) = (2π) −3/2 d 3 p 2p 0 [a 0 ( p)e −ipx − a + 0 ( p)e ipx ] , (23) A j (x) = (2π) −3/2 d 3 p 2p 0 [a j ( p)e −ipx + a + j ( p)e ipx ] for j = 1, 2, 3, (24) u(x) = (2π) −3/2 d 3 p 2p 0 c 2 ( p)e −ipx + c + 1 ( p)e ipx , (25) ˜ u(x) = (2π) −3/2 d 3 p 2p 0 −c 1 ( p)e −ipx + c + 2 ( p)e ipx , (26) and [a ν ( p), a + µ ( p)] = δ µν δ( p − q) , µ = 0, 1, 2, 3, (27) {c i ( p), c + j ( q)} = δ ij δ( p − q), i, j = 1, 2, (28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Above, + denotes the adjoint with respect to the positive scalar product so that the operators can be represented in the usual way in the Fock space. The Krein structure is then defined by introducing the conjugation K</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a 0 ( p) K = −a 0 ( p) + , a j ( p) K = a j ( p) + , (29) so that A K µ = A µ , and on the ghost sector c 2 ( p) K = c 1 ( p) + , c 1 ( p) K = c 2 ( p) + , (30) so that u K = u is K-selfadjoint and u K = −˜hen Q is densely defined and becomes Ksymmetric Q ⊂ Q K . The anticommutator in (22) is essentially the number operator for unphysical particles {Q + , Q} = 2 d 3 p p 2 [b + 1 ( p)b 1 ( p) + b + 2 ( p)b 2 ( p) + c + 1 ( p)c 1 ( p) + c + 2 ( p)c 2 ( p)] , (31) with b 1,2 = (a ± a 0 )/ √ 2 , a = p j a j /| p| , (32) which implies (22).</trash>

					<figDesc>The nilpotency of Q allows for standard homological notions [6]: Consider the field algebra F consisting of the polynomials in the (smeared) gauge and ghost fields and their Wick powers. Defining a gauge variation for a Wick monomial F according to</figDesc>
					<trash>d Q F def = QF − (−1) n F F Q , (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>where n F is the number of ghost fields in F, Q becomes a differential operator in the sense of homological algebra, and we have</figDesc>
					<trash>d 2 Q = 0 ⇐⇒ {Q, [Q, F b ]} = [Q, {Q, F f }] = 0 , (34)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>where F b is a bosonic and F f a fermionic operator and d Q (F G) = (d Q F )G + (−1) n F F d Q G. For example, we get d Q : A µa u b ∂ µ ˜ u c :=: [Q, A µa ]u b ∂ µ ˜ u c : + : A µa [Q, u b ]∂ µ ˜ u c : − : A µa u b {Q, ∂ µ ˜ u c } : . (35)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>If F = d Q G, then F is called a coboundary.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Implications of Perturbative Quantum Gauge Invariance 3.1 First Order Gauge Invariance</head>

				<p>A theory with massless fields suffers usually from serious infrared divergences which may have deep relevance to the confinement mechanism. This, however, is of no importance in our context, since perturbative gauge invariance concerns the T n only. We describe the interaction of the massless &apos;gluons&apos; by the most general renormalizable ansatz with zero ghost number (coupling with non-zero ghost number would affect the theory only for unphysical processes)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˜ T 1 (x) = ig f 1 abc : A µa (x)A νb (x)∂ ν A µ c (x) : + ˜ f 2 abc : A µa u b ∂ µ ˜ u c : + ˜ f 3 abc : A µa ∂ µ u b ˜ u c : + ˜ f 4 abc : A µa A µ b ∂ ν A ν c : + ˜ f 5 abc : ∂ ν A ν a u b ˜ u c : , ˜ f 4 abc = ˜ f 4</trash>

					<figDesc>bac , where the f &apos;s are arbitrary real constants. The first order coupling term is then antisymmetric with respect to the conjugation K: ˜ T K 1 = − ˜ T 1 . Adding divergence terms tõ T 1 will not change the physics of the theory (see sect.3.3), so that we always calculate modulo divergences in the following. We can modify T 1 by adding divergences −</figDesc>
					<trash>ig 4 ( ˜ f 1 abc + ˜ f 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>cba )∂ ν : A µa A νb A µ c : and −ig f 3 abc ∂ µ : A µ a u b ˜ u c : and arrive at the equivalent first order coupling</figDesc>
					<trash>T 1 = ig{ f 1 abc : A µa A νb ∂ ν A µ c : + f 2 abc : A µa u b ∂ µ ˜ u c : + f 4 abc : A µa A µ b ∂ ν A ν c : + f 5 abc : ∂ ν A ν a u b ˜ u c :} , (36) where f 1 abc = −f 1 cba f 4 abc = f 4 bac . (37) The gauge variation of T 1 is d Q T 1 = −gf 1 abc : ∂ µ u a A νb ∂ ν A µ c + A µa ∂ ν u b ∂ ν A µ c + A µa A νb ∂ ν ∂ µ u c : + −gf 2 abc</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: ∂ µ u a u b ∂ µ ˜ u c + A µa u b ∂ µ ∂ ν A ν c : + −2gf 4 abc : ∂ µ u a A µ b ∂ ν A</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ν c : + −gf 5 abc : ∂ ν A ν a u b ∂ µ A µ c : . (38)</trash>

					<figDesc>Gauge invariance requires that the gauge variation be a divergence:</figDesc>
					<trash>d Q T 1 = g∂ µ { g 1 abc : ∂ µ u a A νb A ν c : + g 2 abc : u a A µ b ∂ ν A ν c : + g 3 abc : ∂ µ u a u b ˜ u c : + g 4 abc : u a u b ∂ µ ˜ u c : + g 5 abc : ∂ ν u a A ν b A µ c : + g 6 abc : u a ∂ µ A ν b A νc : + g 7 abc : u a ∂ ν A µ b A νc :} , (39) where g 1 abc = g 1 acb , g 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>abc = −g 4 bac . Comparing the terms in (38) and (39), we immediately obtain the following set of constraints for the coupling coefficients:</figDesc>
					<trash>− f 1 cab = 2g 1 abc + g 6 abc from : ∂ µ u∂ µ A ν A ν : (40) g 2 abc + g 5 abc = −2f 4 abc : ∂ µ uA µ ∂ ν A ν : (41) g 2 abc + g 2 acb = −f 5 bac − f 5 cab : u∂ ν A ν ∂ µ A µ : (42) −f 2 abc = g 3 abc + 2g 4 abc : ∂ µ uu∂ µ ˜ u : (43) g 3 abc = g 3 bac : ∂ µ u∂ µ u˜4 ) −f 1 cba − f 1 bca = g 5 abc + g 5 acb : ∂ µ ∂ ν uA ν A µ : (45) −f 1 acb = g 5 abc + g 7 abc : ∂ µ u∂ ν A µ A ν : (46) g 6 abc = −g 6 acb : u∂ µ A ν ∂ µ A ν : (47) −f 2 cab = g 2 acb + g 7 abc : u∂ µ ∂ ν A µ A ν : (48) g 7 abc = −g 7 acb : u∂ ν A µ ∂ µ A ν : . (49) From (45) (46) and (49) we immediately derive f 1 abc + f 1 acb − f 1 bca − f 1 cba = 0 . (50)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Combining this with (37), we obtain the first important result that f 1 abc is totally antisymmetric. g 1 abc is symmetric in b and c; from (47) and (40) we conclude g 1 abc = 0 and g 6 abc = −f 1 abc . The ansatz (39) we used for d Q T 1 is still too general, because it has to fulfill d 2 Q T 1 = 0. Calculating d 2 Q T 1 and setting the coefficients of all Wick monomials equal to zero we get the relations 2g</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 abc − g 5 bac − g 5 bca + g 5 abc + g 6 abc + g 7 abc = 0 . (51) 2g 1 abc − g 5 cba + g 6 abc − g 7 cba = 0 g 2 abc + g 2 bac + g 3 abc + g 3 bac + g 5 abc + g 5 bac = 0 g 2 abc − g 3 bac − g 4 bac + g 4 abc + g 7 acb = 0 g 6 abc + g 6 acb + g 7 abc + g 7 acb = 0.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Combining these equations with the previous ones and taking all symmetry properties of the f &apos;s and g&apos;s into account, we find f 2 abc =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−f 1 abc , f 4 = 0, f 5 abc = −f 5 cba (46) g 1 = 0, g 2 abc = −g 5 abc , g 3 = 0, g 4 abc = 1 2 f 1 abc , g 6 abc = −f 1 abc , g 7 abc = f 1 abc − g 5 abc . (52) Then T 1 assumes the following form T 1 = T Y M 1 + T D 1 , (53) T Y M 1 = igf 1 abc {: 1 2 A µa A νb F νµ c : − : A µa u b ∂ µ ˜ u c :} , (54) T D 1 = igf 5 abc : ∂ ν A ν a u b ˜ u c : , (55)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where &apos;YM&apos; stand tentatively for &apos;Yang-Mills&apos; and &apos;D&apos; for &apos;Deformation&apos;, and f 5 abc = −f 5 cba .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.2">Second Order Gauge Invariance</head>

				<p>In this section we investigate the consequences of second order gauge invariance for the theory given by (54)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T 1 = igf abc {: 1 2 A µa A νb F νµ c</trash>

					<figDesc>: − : A µa u b ∂ µ ˜ u c :} + ig f abc : ∂ ν A ν a u b ˜ u c : , (56) where f is totally antisymmetric and f abc antisymmetric in a and c. If we consider the product</figDesc>
					<trash>T 1 (x)T 1 (y) , (57) then its gauge variation is simply given by d Q [T 1 (x)T 1 (y)] = d Q T 1 (x)T 1 (y) + T 1 (x)d Q T 1 (y) = i∂ x µ T µ 1/1 (x)T 1 (y) + iT 1 (x)∂ y µ T 1/1 (y) . (58) But the analogous result d Q T 2 (x, y) = i∂ x µ T µ 2/1 (x, y) + i∂ y µ T µ 2/2 (x, y) (59) is not automatically true. This can be seen as follows: i∂ x µ T µ 1/1 (x)T 1 (y) + (x ↔ y) (60) contains terms ig 2 ∂ µ f abc f a ′ b ′ c ′ : u a A νb ∂ µ A ν c (x) :: A µ ′ a ′ A ν ′ b ′ ∂ ν ′ A µ ′ c ′ (y) : +(x ↔ y) = −g 2 ∂ x µ { f abc f cb ′ c ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λb ′ (y)∂ λ A ν c ′ (y) : ∂ µ x D + (x − y) + f abc f a ′ cc ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λa ′ (y)∂ ν A λ c ′ (y) : ∂ µ x D + (x − y) + −f abc f a ′ b ′ c : u a (x)A νb (x)A ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : ∂ µ x ∂ λ x D + (x − y)} +(x ↔ y) + ... (61)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>If we replace now the distribution D + (x − y) simply by the Feynman propagator (time ordering of expression (61)), we obtain additional local terms (&apos;anomalies&apos;), because D F satisfies the inhomogeneous wave equation ✷ x D F (x − y) = δ(x − y) A = −g 2 { f abc f cb ′ c ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λb ′ (y)∂ λ A ν c ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + f abc f a ′ cc ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λa ′ (y)∂ ν A λ c ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + −f abc f a ′ b ′ c : u a (x)A νb (x)A</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : ∂ x λ δ(x − y)} +(x ↔ y) + ... (62) Using the distributional identity A(x)B(y)∂ x µ δ(x − y) + A(y)B(x)∂ y µ δ(x − y) = A(x)∂ µ B(x)δ(x − y) − ∂ µ A(x)B(x)δ(x − y) , (63) we can rewrite A</trash>

					<figDesc>A = −g 2 { 2f abc f cb ′ c ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λb ′ (y)∂ λ A ν c ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + 2f abc f a ′ cc ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λa ′ (y)∂ ν A λ c ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + f abc f a ′ b ′ c : u a (x)∂ λ A νb (x)A ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + f abc f a ′ b ′ c : ∂ λ u a (x)A νb (x)A ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + −f abc f a ′ b ′ c : u a (x)A νb (x)∂ λ A ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + −f abc f a ′ b ′ c : u a (x)A νb (x)A</figDesc>
					<trash>ν a ′ (y)∂ λ A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + ... (64) Now we are free to add to ∂ x λ T λ 2/1 (x, y) + (x ↔ y) a normalization term −g 2 f abc f a ′ b ′ c ∂ x λ {: u a (x)A νb (x)A ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y)} + (x ↔ y) = −g 2 f abc f a ′ b ′ c : ∂ λ u a A νb A ν a ′ A λ b ′ + u a ∂ λ A νb A ν a ′ A λ b ′ + + u a A νb ∂ λ A ν a ′ A λ b ′ + ∂ λ u a A νb A ν a ′ ∂ λ A λ b ′ : δ(x − y) . (65)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Then the renormalized anomaly term A ′ is given by A ′ = −g 2 { 2f abc f cb ′ c ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λb ′ (y)∂ λ A ν c ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + 2f abc f a ′ cc ′ : u a (x)A νb (x)A λa ′ (y)∂ ν A λ c ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + 2f abc f a ′ b ′ c : u a (x)∂ λ A νb (x)A</figDesc>
					<trash>ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y) + 2f abc f a ′ b ′ c : ∂ λ u a (x)A νb (x)A ν a ′ (y)A λ b ′ (y) : δ(x − y) . (66) Furthermore, we must add a normalization term N = i g 2 2 f abc f a ′ b ′ c ′ : A λa A νb A ν a ′ A λ b ′ : δ(x − y) (67)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>to the gluon-gluon scattering term in T 2 (x, y) which contains a propagator ∼ ∂ µ ∂ ν D F (x − y).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Then the gauge variation of N d Q N = −2g 2 f abc f a ′ b ′ c : ∂ λ u a A νb A ν a ′ A λ b ′ : δ(x − y) (68)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>cancels the term in (66) containing the operator ∂ λ u a . The remaining anomalies cancel, iff f abc f dec + f adc f ebc + f aec f bdc = 0 , (69) i.e. if the structure constants obey the Jacobi identity. Consequently, the Lie algebra structure is obtained as a consequence of perturbative gauge invariance at first and second order.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.3">Analysis of the Deformation</head>

				<p>Now we want to analyse the physical consequences of the various coupling terms in (56) and (55). The last term in (56) or (54) is a coboundary because f abc is antisymmetric in a and c:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˜ f abc : ∂ ν A ν a u b ˜ u c := i 2 d Q ( ˜ f abc : ˜ u a u b ˜ u c :) . (70)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Summing up we have shown that a gauge invariant coupling of gauge and ghost fields is necessarily equal to the usual Yang-Mills form plus a coboundary term. Now the question arises whether the latter has physical consequences. Here the following result is relevant [16]: Theorem (Conjecture): Let P be the projection operator on the physical subspace (22) and T 0 n (x 1 , . . . , x n ) the n-point distribution for the usual Yang-Mills theory (without divergence-and coboundary couplings). If T n (x 1 , . . . , x n ) is the n-point distribution of the general theory (with divergence-and coboundary couplings), then</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P T n (x 1 , . . . , x n )P = P T 0 n (x 1 , . . . , x n )P + (sum of divergences) . (71)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Unfortunately, the proof is not complete in the case of coboundary couplings for arbitrary n (it has been proven for n ≤ 4). But there is no doubt that the theorem is true in general.</p>

				<p>The sum of divergences in (71) have no physical effect because they would vanish in the formal adiabatic limit. Then (71) means that the physical S-matrix elements are unchanged.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Massive Gauge Theories</head>

				<p>If some asymptotic fields are massive, their contribution to the gauge charge (13) is changed according to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Q := d 3 x(∂ µ A µ a (x) + m a Φ a (x)) ↔ ∂ 0 u a (x) . (72) Here Φ a (x) are scalar bosonic fields which are quantized according to ( + m 2 a )Φ a (x) = 0 , [Φ a (x), Φ b (y)] = −iδ ab D ma (x − y) . (73)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This restores the nilpotency of Q. The gauge variations (20) are altered as follows [Q, Φ a ] = im a u a , {Q, ˜ u a } = −i(∂ µ A µ a + m a Φ a ) . (74)</p>

				<p>The scalar fields Φ a appearing in Q do not belong to the physical subspace (22). The starting point is now a general ansatz of the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T 1 = T A 1 + T u 1 + T Φ 1 , (75) where T A 1 + T u 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is the same as in (36) and T Φ 1 is the most general coupling of Φ a and gauge and ghost fields. The discussion of section 3.1 can be repeated, the only change are mass terms ∼ m a or ∼ m 2 a which come from the Klein-Gordon equation (73) and from (74). The latter must be compensated by means of T Φ 1 . This part of the gauge invariance problem is considered in [3] for the case of the electroweak theory. The discussion of second order gauge invariance in the Yang-Mills part (sect.3.2) remains unchanged because all anomalies of sect.3.2 occur in the bigger theory as well. But there are many more anomalies coming from T Φ 1 . It turns out that it is impossible to remove all those anomalies without enlarging the theory still further by introducing another (now physical) scalar field. In this way the Higgs field enters the scene. For the detailed discussion we refer to [3, 4].</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-th/9803011v2 29 Jan 1999</note>

			<note place="foot">* Work supported by Swiss National Science Foundation</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Stora</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Aste</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Dü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Scharf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. A: Math. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5785</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Scharf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9612091" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Aste</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Scharf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9702053</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Hurth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Krahe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Scharf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nuovo Cimento A106</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="375" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Krahe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Acta Physica Polonica B27</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page">2453</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to the theory of quantized fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Bogoliubov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Shirkov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Epstein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Glaser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ann</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
			<biblScope unit="page">211</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Differential algebras in lagrangean field theory (ETH lectures</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Stora</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<pubPlace>Zü</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Finite quantum electrodynamics, the causal approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Scharf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin, Heidelberg, New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>second. edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Kugo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Ojima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl. . Prog. Theor. Phys.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Aste</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Scharf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. A: Math. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1563</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">182</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Razumov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Rybkin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">332</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">209</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Indefinite inner product spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bognar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. A: Math. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7597</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
