<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Possible Production of High-Energy Gamma Rays from Proton Acceleration in the Extragalactic Radio Source Markarian 501</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1998-03-20">20 Mar 1998</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">K</forename>
								<surname>Mannheim</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>(kmannhe@uni-sw.gwdg.de)</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Universitäts-Sternwarte</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Geismarlandstraße11</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-37083</postCode>
									<settlement>Göttingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Possible Production of High-Energy Gamma Rays from Proton Acceleration in the Extragalactic Radio Source Markarian 501</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1998-03-20">20 Mar 1998</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1 SCIENCE 279, 684 (1998)</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>mechanism responsible for the γ rays could be either inverse-Compton scattering of low-energy photons by accelerated electrons (3) or pion production by accelerated protons. In the latter case, the sources could be among the long-sought sources of cosmic rays, that is the isotropic flux of relativistic particles with differential number density (N) spectrum dN/dE ∝ E −2.7 (for energies E &lt; 10 3 TeV) mainly consisting of protons and ions (4).</p>

				<p>Particle acceleration in astrophysics is typically observed to be associated with (collisionless) shock waves when a supersonic flow of magnetized material hits a surrounding medium. Examples of shock waves are shell-type supernova remnants (explosion of a massive star), plerions (pulsar wind), γ ray bursts (relativistic ejecta from the collapse of a compact stellar object), or the jets ejected from active galactic nuclei (collimated relativistic wind from the accretion disk around a supermassive black hole).</p>

				<p>In the theoretical picture of shock acceleration, relativistic particles (protons , ions, electrons) scatter elastically off turbulent fluctuations in the magnetic field on both sides of the shock and thereby gain energy because of the convergence of the scattering centers (approaching walls). The acceleration time scale for the process can be written as t acc = ξr g c/u 2 where u denotes the velocity of the shock wave (c is the speed of light) and r g ∝ E/B denotes the radius of gyration of a particle with energy E in a magnetic field of strength B. The effects of shock obliquity, turbulence spectrum, and other unknowns are conveniently hidden in an empirical factor ξ ≥ 1. The most rapid (gyrotime scale) particle acceleration for relativistic shocks corresponds to ξ = 1 (5). Balancing the acceleration time scale with the energy loss time scale due to synchrotron radiation t syn ∝ B −2 E −1 one obtains the maximum energy of the electrons E max = 10 (ξ/10)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−0.5 (B/3µG) −0.5 (u/10 8 cm s −1 ) TeV (6).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The observed 10 TeV γ rays from the Crab nebula (7) and the observed synchrotron x-rays in shell-type supernova remnants (8) (corresponding to 10 TeV electrons) require ξ ∼ 1 to 10. Because protons lose less energy, they can reach larger E max &apos;s than electrons and give rise to γ ray emission even above ∼ 10 TeV via pion production and subsequent pion decay. Although shock acceleration theory predicts that most of the cosmic rays are accelerated in supernova remnants (4), no definitive γ ray signature has yet been discovered.</p>

				<p>It is commonly argued that the assumption of electron acceleration also suffices to explain the γ rays from blazar jets such as Mrk 501 (9). Estimates of the magnetic field strength in the γ ray emitting part of the jet in Mrk 501 then yield values in the range B ∼ 0.04 to 0.7 G. This magnetic field is much stronger than the one in supernova remnants and the associated stronger cooling of the relativistic electrons due to synchrotron energy losses reduces E max accordingly. The effect is almost compensated by the high shock wave velocities in extragalactic radio sources which speed up the acceleration rate.</p>

				<p>Using radio interferometry, shock wave velocities close to the speed of light have been inferred corresponding to typical bulk Lorentz factors in the range Γ jet = (1 − β 2 ) −0.5 ∼ 2 to 10 (β = u/c) with a few cases of still higher values (10). Due to the alignment of the jet axis and the line-of-sight in Mrk 501 superluminal motion has not been observed. With u = c, ξ = 10, and taking into account equal synchrotron and inverse-Compton losses, one obtains E max ∼ 4 Γ jet (B/G) −0.5 TeV from the balance between acceleration gains and energy losses. The additional factor Γ jet takes into account the boost in energy due to the relativistic bulk motion. Therefore, electron maximum energies of ∼ 10 TeV as required for Mrk 501 (at least 5-8 TeV are required for the similar blazar Mrk 421 (11)) are formally allowed, but one certainly has to push the theory to its limits and this raises a number of concerns: (i) the multi-TeV spectrum should show considerable curvature due to the (socalled Klein-Nishina) decrease of the scattering cross section when the energy of the scattered photon approaches E max and due to the onset of electronpositron pair production (the observed multi-TeV spectrum is consistent with a smooth power law), (ii) the ratio between the γ ray and synchrotron (simultaneous ) luminosities depends sensitively on the jet Lorentz factor Γ jet and therefore requires fine-tuning (both nearest bright blazars, Mrk 421 and Mrk 501, show a similar γ-to-x-ray luminosity ratio), (iii) the magnetic field pressure turns out to be much lower than the relativistic electron pressure in the electron acceleration models which seems inconsistent with the shock acceleration mechanism (the turbulent magnetic field is responsible for pushing the electrons back and forth across the shock), larger values of B are also expected from the adiabatic expansion of a magnetically collimated jet (the observed B-field at the tips of the jet in Cygnus A is consistent with adiabatic expansion (12)), and (iv) larger values of Γ jet could ameliorate the problem that E max ∼ 10 TeV, however, one would run into a serious problem with unification models of active galaxies if Γ jet &gt; 10 would be the rule rather than the exception (13) (number of required host galaxies would exceed the number of known radio galaxies). A natural solution to the problem is to assume that the 10 TeV γ rays are due to pion production from accelerated protons. The balance equation between energy gains and losses for protons yields maximum energies</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>of ∼ 10 6 TeV and short variability time scales t var ≥ 10 5 (ξ/Γ jet )(B/G) −1 s in Mrk 501 (14).</trash>

					<figDesc>The relativistic proton energy loss is dominated by photoproduction of pions in collisions with low-energy synchrotron photons (originating from accelerated electrons). Collisions of the accelerated protons with matter are negligible due to the low matter density in relativistic jets (unless a high-density target moves across the jet (15)). The γ rays from the decay of the neutral pion (far above the observed range of energies) are subject to pair creation in further collisions with the low-energy synchrotron photons (γ + γ → e + + e − ). This initiates an electromagnetic cascade shifting the average photon energy to the TeV range and below. A model based on the combined acceleration of protons (γ rays) and electrons (radio-to-x-rays) – coined the proton blazar model (16) – was fitted to published data of Mrk 501 in order to obtain a prediction of its multi-TeV spectrum (17). Data from 1995 and earlier was available for the analysis and covered the radio-to-x-ray wavelength range including a flux limit above 100 MeV and an integral flux above 300 GeV (for details see references in (17)). The published flux values</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>showed considerable variability in the optical-to-x-ray range and the model spectrum was therefore fitted to match the time-averaged spectrum (from the fit one obtains B = 37 G and Γ jet = 10). The predicted multi-TeV spectrum is shown in Fig.1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>and compared with the data obtained from recent (1996, 1997</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>) air-Cerenkov observations. The fairly robust spectral slope of the model spectrum fits the observations very well, whereas the absolute flux normalization is somewhat too low.</p>

				<p>Considering that the sub-TeV (350 GeV) flux has been reported to increase from 1995 to 1997 (9), the agreement is actually rather impressive if one scales up the model spectrum accordingly. Contemporaneous multi-wavelength observations of blazars such as Mrk 501 will be important to discriminate between electron-based and proton-based models for the γ ray emission from them. Generally, electron-based models require larger values of Γ jet and lower values of B than proton-based models to obtain high-energy γ rays.</p>

				<p>There is a further hint that proton acceleration might be important. Unresolved blazars are the most probable source population to produce the observed extragalactic γ ray background between 10 MeV and 10 GeV (18).</p>

				<p>The energy density of this γ ray background is ≃ 4 × 10 −6 eV cm −3 . A similar value is found for an extragalactic flux of protons (with dN/dE ∝ E −2 differential spectrum between 10 9 eV and 10 20 eV) providing all of the observed cosmic rays with energies above 10 18.5 eV (the so-called &quot; ankle &quot; above which the very high energy differential cosmic ray spectrum ∝ E −3 flattens) (19). On the assumption that the γ rays are from proton (p) acceleration, the comparable energy densities result from simple decay kinematics: Photoproduction of neutral pions (π 0 ) (p + γ → π • + p) and their subsequent decay gives rise to γ rays (subject to electromagnetic cascading) which carry ∼ 1/5 of the proton energy. Charged pions (p + γ → π + + n) are produced with approximately the same rate and give rise to neutrons (n) which carry ∼ 4/5 of the accelerated proton energy. Since the neutrons do not scatter off the magnetic field fluctuations responsible for the acceleration and storage of the charged particles in the blazar jet, they must escape the accelerator (energy losses are small and modify the neutron spectrum only at the very highest energies). Time dilation allows the most energetic neutrons to leave the host galaxy freely before β-decay occurs (for protons there would be adiabatic losses due to the magnetic field in the host galaxy). Hence the neutron (and after β-decay proton) luminosity is equal to the γ ray luminosity within factors of order unity. An extragalactic origin of the highest energy cosmic rays is indeed suggested by the absence of an enhancement of the cosmic ray flux toward the Galactic disk (20) and by the change in chemical composition from heavy (protons and ions) to light (protons) above 10 18.5 eV (21). The ultimate challenge to the hypothesis is the measurement of the high-energy neutrino (ν) flux associated with the charged pion decay (π ± → e ± + 3ν).</p>

				<p>The energy density in these multi-TeV neutrinos would be of the same order of magnitude as that in extragalactic cosmic rays and γ rays. Their measurement therefore constitutes an experimentum crucis within reach for the planned cubic kilometer underwater(ice) detectors (22).</p>

				<p>Although γ rays are known from laboratory experiments for their penetrating power, propagation over intergalactic distances is not without hurdles.</p>

				<p>A diffuse isotropic infrared background (DIRB) was produced when the first galaxies formed. Massive stars in early galaxies produced large amounts of dust in their winds reprocessing the visual and ultraviolet light from the stars into infrared light. By colliding with these ample infrared photons, γ ray photons can disappear and turn into electron-positron pairs (23-25). The most numerous infrared photons above threshold for pair production with 10 TeV γ rays have wavelengths ∼ 25 µm. The mean free path (λ γγ ) for pair creation at multi-TeV energies is of the order of the distance (d) of Mrk 501. The exact value depends on the DIRB which is difficult to measure directly owing to the presence of zodiacal light and galactic cirrus clouds.</p>

				<p>One can use the observed power law spectrum (2) to put a limit on the maximum allowed pair attenuation assuming that the observed power law is the unattenuated spectrum emitted by the source (consistent with the proton-based model). In general, only very contrived intrinsic spectra would look like a smooth power law after the quasi-exponential attenuation. The maximum allowed deviation from the power law (1 − exp[−d/λ γγ ]) is taken to be the size of the statistical error bar at 10 TeV yielding an optical depth τ γγ = d/λ γγ &lt; 0.7. This limit can be relaxed by a factor not larger than ∼ 2 admitting for weakly absorbed spectra which still approximate a power law (see the dashed line in Fig.1). There is some dependence of the attenuation on the shape of the DIRB spectrum. Useful models for the spectral shape can be found in (23-25) and yield a similar limit for the 25 µm DIRB normalization νI ν (25 µm) &lt; 2 to 4 nW m −2 sr −1 . The absence of γ ray attenuation in Mrk 501 is consistent with no contribution to the DIRB other than from the optically selected galaxies for which one expects ∼ 10% of their optical emission to be reprocessed by warm dust yielding νI ν (25µm) ∼ 1 nW m −2 sr −1 (26), but would also allow a DIRB stronger by a factor 2 to 4. A DIRB of at least ∼ 3 nW m −2 sr −1 is suggested by faint infrared galaxy counts and indicates contributions from dust-enshrouded galaxies at redshifts of z ∼ 3 − 4 (24). Electron-based models for the γ ray emission from Mrk 501 (9) predict deviations from a power law in the multi-TeV range even without external attenuation and therefore impose an upper limit on the DIRB below the lower limit from faint infrared galaxy counts. If both methods to estimate the DIRB (deviations from a power law spectrum in the multi-TeV range, faint infrared galaxy counts) use correct assumptions, a cutoff in the γ ray spectrum of Mrk 501 must be present in the energy range 10 to 30 TeV. Figure captions Fig.1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>: Differential TeV spectrum of Mrk 501. Thin solid line: proton blazar model prediction based on archival data from 1995 and earlier (17) taking into account intergalactic attenuation adopting a DIRB spectrum based on a cold+hot dark matter galaxy formation model from (23) and normalized to</figDesc>
					<trash>νI ν (25µm) = 1.0 nW m −2 sr −1 (a Hubble constant of H • = 75 km s −1 Mpc −1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is assumed throughout the paper). Thin dashed line: same without intergalactic attenuation. Solid thick lines: model spectrum scaled up by factors 2.5 and 20 corresponding to the increase in the mean</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>TeV flux from 1995 to 1996 and spring of 1997, respectively (9). Open circles: HEGRA (High Energy Gamma-Ray Astronomy) CT1 observation March-August 1996 (220h) (27). Solid circles: HEGRA IACT observation March-April 1997 (26.7h) (2) 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 log 10 E [TeV] -4 -3 -2 -1 0 1 log 10 F γ [10 -11 /(TeV cm 2 s)] x 2.5 x 20</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>


				</figure>

		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">and Notes</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Cawley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Weekes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exp. Astron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Aharionan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">HEGRA collaboration) Astron. Astrophys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Dermer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Schlickeiser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">257</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1642</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">O</forename>
				<surname>Lagage</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Cesarsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Astrophys. Astron. Astrophys., in press</title>
		<editor>Wiebel-Sooth, P.L. Biermann, and H. Meyer</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1259709253</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">249</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Jokipii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J. J. Bednartz and M. Ostrowski, Mon. Not. R. Astr. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">313</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">283</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">447</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Reynolds</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">459</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>De</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Jager</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">457</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">253</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Koyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">378</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">255</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Catanese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J. Astrophys. J. Astrophys. J. Lett, in press</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">487</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">456</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Ghisellini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Padovani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Celotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Maraschi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">407</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">65</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Whipple collaboration)</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Krennrich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">481</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">758</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Harris</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Carilli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Perley</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">713</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Urry</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Padovani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pub. Astro. Soc. Pac</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">803</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Biermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Strittmatter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">322</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">643</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Dar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Laor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">478</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Mannheim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Biermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Krü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Astrophys. Astron. Astrophys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">251</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">269</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="723" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Mannheim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Westerhoff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Meyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H.-H</forename>
				<surname>Fink</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Astro- phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">315</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">77</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Kniffen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Astrophys</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>P</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">615</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>P</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl. .</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Padovani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Ghisellini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Fabian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Celotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mon. Not. R</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Astr</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Soc</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. J</title>
		<editor>C. Impey</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">260</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="2667" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Protheroe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Johnson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astropart. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">215</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Stanev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Biermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Lloyd-Evans</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>P. Rachen, and A.A. Wat- son</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3065</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Rachen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Stanev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Biermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Hayashida</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Astrophys. Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">273</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1000</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Gaisser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Halzen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Stanev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">258</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">173</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Macminn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Primack</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sp. Sci. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">413</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Franceschini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astron. Astrophys</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>A</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">285</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>A</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl. .</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Invited Review in ESA FIRST symposium (ESA SP 401), in press (1997) (astro-ph/9707080); T. Stanev and A. Franceschini</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Franceschini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J. Lett., submitted</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9708162</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Stecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Malkan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J., in press</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Madau</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mon. Not. R. Astr. Soc. Astron. J</title>
		<editor>B.T. Soifer and G. Neugebauer</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">283</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1388" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Petry</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International Cosmic Ray Conference</title>
		<editor>P.A. Evanson et al.</editor>
		<meeting>the 25th International Cosmic Ray Conference<address><addrLine>Durban, South Africa</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. press</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Wolfgang Rhode, Frank Rieger, and the referees for their crit- ical reading and suggestions for improvements of the manuscript. This research was generously supported by the Deutsche Forschungsgemein- schaft under travel grant DFG</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Peter</forename>
				<surname>Biermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Arnon</forename>
				<surname>Dar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">John</forename>
				<surname>Kirk</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hinrich</forename>
				<surname>Meyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Joel</forename>
				<surname>Primack</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
