<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Naturalness of nearly degenerate neutrinos</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1999-03">May 1999 April 1999</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<forename type="middle">A</forename>
								<surname>Casas</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Instituto de Estructura de la materia</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>CSIC Serrano 123</addrLine>
									<postCode>28006</postCode>
									<settlement>Madrid</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Theory Division</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CH-1211</postCode>
									<settlement>Geneva 23</settlement>
									<region>CERN</region>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<forename type="middle">R</forename>
								<surname>Espinosa</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Theory Division</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CH-1211</postCode>
									<settlement>Geneva 23</settlement>
									<region>CERN</region>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<surname>Ibarra</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Instituto de Estructura de la materia</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>CSIC Serrano 123</addrLine>
									<postCode>28006</postCode>
									<settlement>Madrid</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">I</forename>
								<surname>Navarro</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Instituto de Estructura de la materia</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>CSIC Serrano 123</addrLine>
									<postCode>28006</postCode>
									<settlement>Madrid</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Naturalness of nearly degenerate neutrinos</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1999-03">May 1999 April 1999</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>IEM-FT-191/99 CERN-TH/99-103 IFT-UAM/CSIC-99-15 hep-ph/9904395 *</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>If neutrinos are to play a relevant cosmological role, they must be essentially degenerate. We study whether radiative corrections can or cannot be responsible for the small mass splittings, in agreement with all the available experimental data. We perform an exhaustive exploration of the bimaximal mixing scenario, finding that (i) the vacuum oscillations solution to the solar neutrino problem is always excluded; (ii) if the mass matrix is produced by a seesaw mechanism, there are large regions of the parameter space consistent with the large angle MSW solution, providing a natural origin for the ∆m 2 sol ≪ ∆m 2 atm hierarchy; (iii) the bimaximal structure becomes then stable under radiative corrections. We also provide analytical expressions for the mass splittings and mixing angles and present a particularly simple seesaw ansatz consistent with all observations.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Standard explanations of the observed atmospheric and solar neutrino anomalies [1] require neutrino oscillations between different species, which imply that neutrinos are massive, with mass-squared differences of at most 10 −2 eV 2 . On the other hand, if neutrinos are to play an essential role in the large scale structure of the universe, the sum of their masses must be a few eV, and therefore they must be almost degenerate.</p>

				<p>This scenario has recently attracted much attention [2]-[5].</p>

				<p>In this paper we will analyze under which circumstances the &quot; observed &quot; mass differences arise naturally (or not), as a radiative effect, in agreement with all the available experimental data.</p>

				<p>Let us briefly review the current relevant experimental constraints on neutrino masses and mixing angles. Observations of atmospheric neutrinos require ν µ − ν τ oscillations driven by a mass splitting and a mixing angle in the range [6]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 × 10 −4 eV 2 &lt; ∆m 2 at &lt; 10 −2 eV 2 , sin 2 2θ at &gt; 0.82 . (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the other hand, there are three main explanations of the solar neutrino flux deficits,</p>

				<p>requiring oscillations of electron neutrinos into other species. The associated mass splittings and mixing angles depend on the type of solution:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Small angle MSW (SAMSW) solution: 3 × 10 −6 eV 2 &lt; ∆m 2 sol &lt; 10 −5 eV 2 , 4 × 10 −3 &lt; sin 2 2θ sol &lt; 1.3 × 10 −2 . (2) Large angle MSW (LAMSW) solution: 10 −5 eV 2 &lt; ∆m 2 sol &lt; 2 × 10 −4 eV 2 , 0.5 &lt; sin 2 2θ sol &lt; 1. (3) Vacuum oscillations (VO) solution: 5 × 10 −11 eV 2 &lt; ∆m 2 sol &lt; 1.1 × 10 −10 eV 2 , sin 2 2θ sol &gt; 0.67 . (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let us remark the hierarchy of mass splittings between the different species of neutrinos , ∆m 2 sol ≪ ∆m 2 at , which is apparent from eqs.(1, 2–4). This hierarchy should be reproduced by any natural explanation of those splittings.</p>

				<p>As it has been shown in ref. [2] the small angle MSW solution is unplausible in a scenario of nearly degenerate neutrinos, so we are left with the LAMSW and VO</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>possibilities.</head>

				<p>An important point concerns the upper limit on sin 2 2θ sol in the LAMSW solution.</p>

				<p>According to ref.[4] the absolute limit sin 2 2θ sol = 1 is forbidden at 99.8%, but with no indication about the tolerable upper limit. In this sense a conservative upper bound sin 2 2θ sol &lt; 0.99 can be adopted. However, recent combined analysis of data, including the day–night effect [7], indicate that even the sin 2 2θ sol = 1 possibility is allowed at</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>99% for 2 × 10 −5 eV 2 &lt; ∆m 2 sol &lt; 1.7 × 10 −4 eV 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, although there may be problems to define the upper limit on sin 2 2θ sol in a precise sense [8]. For the moment we will not adopt an upper bound on sin 2 2θ sol , but later on we will show the effect of such a bound on the results, which turns out to be dramatic.</p>

				<p>Finally, the non-observation of neutrinoless double β-decay puts an upper bound on the ee element of the Majorana neutrino mass matrix, namely [9] M ee &lt; B = 0.2 eV. (5)</p>

				<p>Concerning the cosmological relevance of neutrinos, as mentioned above, we will as- sume m ν i = O(eV). In particular, we will take m ν i = 6 eV as a typical possibility, although as we will see, the results do not depend essentially on the particular value. It should be mentioned here that Tritium β-decay experiments indicate m ν i &lt; 2.5 eV for any mass eigenstate with a significant ν e component [10].</p>

				<p>Using standard notation, we define the effective mass term for the three light (lefthanded ) neutrinos in the flavour basis as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = − 1 2 ν T M ν ν + h.c. (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where M ν is the neutrino mass matrix. This is diagonalized in the usual way</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M ν = V * D V † , (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where V is a unitary &apos;CKM&apos; matrix, relating the flavor eigenstates to the mass</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>states</head>

				<figure>
					<trash>   ν e ν µ ν τ    =    c 2 c 3 c 2 s 3 s 2 e −iδ −c 1 s 3 − s 1 s 2 c 3 e iδ c 1 c 3 − s 1 s 2 s 3 e iδ s 1 c 2 s 1 s 3 − c 1 s 2 c 3 e iδ −s 1 c 3 − c 1 s 2 s 3 e iδ c 1 c 2       ν 1 ν 2 ν 3    , (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where s i and c i denote sin θ i and cos θ i respectively. D may be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>D =    m 1 e iφ 0 0 0 m 2 e iφ ′ 0 0 0 m 3    . (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It should be mentioned here that, for a given mass matrix, the θ i angles are not uniquely defined, unless one gives a criterion to order the mass eigenvectors ν i in eq.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(8) (e.g. m 2 ν 1 &lt; m 2 ν 2 &lt; m 2 ν 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). Of course, the corresponding V matrices differ just in the ordering of the columns, and thus are physically equivalent.</p>

				<p>In this notation, constraint (5) reads</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M ee ≡ |m ν 1 c 2 2 c 2 3 e iφ + m ν 2 c 2 2 s 2 3 e iφ ′ + m ν 3 s 2 2 e i2δ | &lt; B . (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As it has been put forward by Georgi and Glashow in ref. [2], a scenario of nearly degenerate neutrinos plausibly leads to θ 2 ≃ 0. In that case, and for m ν = 2 eV, eq.(10) yields sin 2 2θ 3 ≥ 0.99, which, as discussed above, might be in conflict with the LAMSW solution to the solar neutrino anomaly. However, according to some fits, θ 2 could be as large as 27 0 or even larger [6]. Therefore, although small values of θ 2 are clearly preferred, in some acceptable cases a non-negligible contribution of sin 2 θ 2 in eq.(10) is enough to relax the above mentioned stringent bound on sin 2 2θ 3 , and in fact we will see some examples of this feature later on. Our criterion throughout the paper will be to keep eq.(5) [or the complete eq.(10)] as the neutrinoless double β-decay constraint, without demanding any extra condition on θ 3 , θ 2 [11]. In any case, we will see that in all viable cases sin 2 2θ 3 ≥ 0.99 and θ 2 is very small.</p>

				<p>Let us now discuss the strategy we have followed to analyze if the required mass splittings and mixing angles can or cannot arise in a natural way through radiative corrections.</p>

				<p>Following ref. [2] (some of their arguments have been discussed above), the scenario of nearly degenerate neutrinos should be close to a bimaximal mixing, which constrains the texture of the mass matrix M ν to be [2,3] M b = m ν</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>         0 1 √ 2 1 √ 2 1 √ 2 1 2 − 1 2 1 √ 2 − 1 2 1 2          , (11) where m ν is a general mass scale. M b can be diagonalized by a V matrix V b =          −1 √ 2 1 √ 2 0 1 2 1 2 −1 √ 2 1 2 1 2 1 √ 2          , (12) leading to exactly degenerate neutrinos: D = m ν diag(−1, 1, 1) and θ 2 = 0, sin 2 2θ 3 = sin 2 2θ 1 = 1.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let us remind that in this scenario only the LAMSW and VO solutions to the solar anomaly are acceptable.</p>

				<p>The nice aspect of M b suggests that it could be generated at some scale by interactions obeying appropriate continuous or discrete symmetries. This is an interesting issue [12], which we will not address in this paper. On the other hand, in order to be realistic, the effective matrix M ν at low energy should be certainly close to M b , but it must be slightly different in order to account for the mass splittings given in eqs.(1,3,4). The main goal of this paper is to explore whether the appropriate splittings (and mixing angles) can be generated or not through radiative corrections; more precisely, through the running of the renormalization group equations (RGEs) between the scale at which M ν is generated and low energy. The output of this analysis can be</p>

				<figure>
					<head>of three types:</head>

					<figDesc>i) All the mass splittings and mixing angles obtained from the RG running are in agreement with all experimental limits and constraints.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>ii) Some (or all) mass splittings are much larger than the acceptable ranges.</p>

				<p>iii) Some (or all) mass splittings are smaller than the acceptable ranges, and the rest is within.</p>

				<p>Case (i) is obviously fine. Case (ii) is disastrous. The only way-out would be an extremely artificial fine-tuning between the initial form of M ν and the effect of the RG running. Hence we consider this possibility unacceptable. Finally, case (iii) is not fine, in the sense that the RGEs fail to explain the required modifications of M ν . However, it leaves the door open to the possibility that other (not specified) effects could be responsible for them. In that case, the RGE would not spoil a fine pre-existing structure. Consequently, we consider this possibility as undecidable. We will see along the paper different scenarios corresponding to the three possibilities.</p>

				<p>Concerning the mixing angles, it is worth stressing that, due to the two degenerate eigenvalues of M b , V b is not uniquely defined (V b times any rotation on the plane of degenerate eigenvalues is equally fine). Hence, once the ambiguity is removed thanks to the small splittings coming from the RG running, the mixing angles may be very different from the desired ones. However, if those cases correspond to the previous (iii) possibility, they are still of the &quot; undecidable &quot; type with respect to the mixing angles, since the modifications of M (of non-specified origin) needed to reproduce the correct mass splittings will also change dramatically the mixing angles.</p>

				<p>In section 2, we first examine the general case in which the neutrino masses arise from an effective operator, remnant from new physics entering at a scale Λ. In this framework, we take a low energy point of view, assuming a bimaximal-mixing mass structure at the scale Λ as an initial condition.</p>

				<p>In this section we do not consider possible perturbations of that initial condition coming from high-energy effects. We find this case to be of the undecidable type [possibility (iii) above], except for the VO solution, which is excluded.</p>

				<p>In section 3 we go one step further and consider in detail a particularly well motivated example of the previous case: the see-saw scenario. We include here the high energy effects of the new degrees of freedom above the scale Λ (identified now with the mass of the right-handed neutrinos). We find regions of parameter space where the neutrino spectrum and mixing angles fall naturally in the pattern required to explain solar (LAMSW solution) and atmospheric neutrino anomalies, which we find</p>

				<figure>
					<head>able.</head>

					<figDesc>We complement the numerical results with compact analytical formulas which give a good description of them, and allow to understand the pattern of mass splittings and mixing angles obtained. We also present plausible textures for the neutrino Yukawa couplings leading to a good fit of the oscillation data. Finally we draw some conclusions. 2 M ν as an effective operator</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In this section we consider the simplest possibility that the Majorana mass matrix for the left-handed neutrinos, M ν , is generated at some high energy scale, Λ, by some unspecified mechanism (we allow Λ to vary from M p to M Z ). Assuming that the only light fields below Λ are the Standard Model (SM) ones, the lowest dimension operator producing a mass term of this kind is uniquely given by [14]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− 1 4 κν T νHH + h.c. (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where κ is a matricial coupling and H is the ordinary (neutral) Higgs.</p>

				<p><formula>Obviously, M ν = 1 2 κH 2 .</formula></p>

				<p>The effective coupling κ runs with the scale below Λ, with a RGE given by [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>16π 2 dκ dt = −3g 2 2 + 2λ + 6Y 2 t + 2TrY † e Y e κ − 1 2 κY † e Y e + (Y † e Y e ) T κ , (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where t = log µ, and g 2 , λ, Y t , Y e are the SU(2) gauge coupling, the quartic Higgs coupling, the top Yukawa coupling and the matrix of Yukawa couplings for the charged leptons, respectively. Let us note that the RGE depends on λ, and thus on the value of the Higgs mass, m H . We have taken m H = 150 GeV throughout the paper, but in any case the dependence is very small (it slightly affects the overall neutrino mass scale but not the relative splittings).</p>

				<p>In the scenario in which we are interested (almost degenerate neutrinos), the simplest assumption about the form of κ is that the interactions responsible for it produce the bimaximal mixing texture of eq.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(11). Hence M ν (Λ) = 1 2 κ(Λ)H 2 = M b . (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Clearly, the last term of the RGE (14) will slightly perturb the initial form of M ν , so we expect at low energy small mass splittings, and mixing angles different from the bimaximal case.</p>

				<p>In order to gain intuition on the final (low energy) form of M ν , and the corresponding mass splittings and mixing angles, it is convenient to neglect for a while all the charged lepton Yukawa couplings but Y τ . Then κ maintains its form along the running,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 10 5 10 10 10 15 Λ=M Z Λ (GeV) ∆m 2 (eV 2 ) 5 10 –5 10 –4 1.5 10 –4 0 ∆m 13 2 ∆m 12 2 ∆m 23 2</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>

					<figDesc>Dependence of neutrino mass splittings at low energy (∆m 2 ij in eV 2 ) with the cut-off scale Λ(GeV). except for the third row and column:</figDesc>
					<trash>M ν (µ 0 ) ∝          0 1 √ 2 1 √ 2 (1 + ǫ) 1 √ 2 1 2 − 1 2 (1 + ǫ) 1 √ 2 (1 + ǫ) − 1 2 (1 + ǫ) 1 2 (1 + 2ǫ)          (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where µ 0 is the low-energy scale, which can be identified with M Z and ǫ has positive sign. Therefore, the mass eigenvalues are proportional to 1, −1 − ǫ/2, 1 + 3ǫ/2, and the corresponding splittings (adopting the convention m</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 ν 1 &lt; m 2 ν 2 &lt; m 2 ν 3 ) are ∆m 2 12 = 1 2 ∆m 2 23 = 1 3 ∆m 2 13 ≃ m 2 ν ǫ. (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Clearly, these mass splittings are incompatible with the required hierarchy ∆m</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 sol ≪ ∆m 2 at , of eqs.(1, 3, 4</trash>

					<figDesc>). We will discuss the size of these splittings shortly. Equation (16) is also useful to get an approximate form of the V matrix responsible for the diagonalization of M ν</figDesc>
					<trash>V ≃           1 √ 3 − 1 √ 2 1 √ 6 2 3 1 2 − 1 2 √ 3 0 1 2 √ 3 2           , (18) which leads to mixing angles sin 2 2θ 1 = 9 25 , sin 2 2θ 2 = 5 9 , sin 2 2θ 3 = 24 25 . (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Clearly, these values are far away from the bimaximal mixing ones. In consequence, they are not acceptable.</p>

				<p>The previous failures of the scenario considered in this section in order to reproduce the mass splittings and the mixing angles indicate that we are in one of the two possibilities (ii) or (iii) discussed in the Introduction. To go further, we need a numerical evaluation of the mass splittings, and thus of ǫ.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Solving the RGE (14) at lowest order, we simply find ǫ = Y 2 τ 32π 2 log Λ µ 0 . (20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>So, from eq.(17) the mass splittings are typically of order 10 −5 eV 2 . This is confirmed by the complete numerical evaluation of the RGE , which gives the mass splittings shown in Fig.1. The first conclusion is that for any Λ (even very close to µ 0 ) the mass splittings are much larger than those required for the VO solution to the solar neutrino problem, ∆m 2 sol ∼ 10 −10 eV 2 . Therefore, the effect of the RGE for this scenario is disastrous in the sense discussed in the Introduction for the possibility (ii). In consequence the VO solution to the solar neutrino problem is excluded.</p>

				<p>For the LAMSW solution to the solar neutrino problem, things are a bit different.</p>

				<p>Clearly, the mass splittings obtained from the RGE analysis are within or below the required range, eq.(3), for almost any value of the cut-off scale Λ. In addition, the mass splittings are clearly below the atmospheric range, eq.(1). Therefore, we are in the case (ii) discussed in the Introduction: The radiative corrections fail to provide an origin to the required mass splittings and mixing angles, but they will not destroy a suitable initial modification (from unspecified origin) of M ν at the Λ scale. It is anyway remarkable that the radiative corrections place ∆m 2 just in the right magnitude for the LAMSW solution.</p>

				<p>In the next section we will discuss a natural source for the initial modification of M ν , which leads naturally to completely satisfactory (atmospheric plus LAMSW)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>scenarios.</head>

				<p>3 M ν from the see-saw mechanism A natural way of obtaining small neutrino masses is the so-called see-saw mechanism [16] in which the particle content of the Standard Model is enlarged by one additional neutrino field (not charged under the SM group) per generation, ν α,R (α = e, µ, τ ).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The Lagrangian reads L = −¯ ν R m D ν + 1 2 ¯ ν R M¯ ν T R + h.c. (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here m D is a 3 × 3 Dirac mass matrix with magnitude determined by the electroweak breaking scale, m D = Y ν H, where Y ν is the matrix of neutrino Yukawa couplings and H = 246/ √ 2 GeV; and M is a 3 × 3 Majorana mass matrix which does not break the SM gauge symmetry. Thus, the overall scale of M, which we will denote by M, can be naturally many orders of magnitude higher than the electroweak scale. In that case, the low-energy effective theory, after integrating out the heavy ν α,R fields [whose masses are O(M)], is just the SM with left-handed neutrino masses given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M ν = m T D M −1 m D = Y ν T M −1 Y ν H 2 , (22) suppressed with respect to the typical fermion masses by the inverse power of the large scale M.</trash>

					<figDesc>In this appealing framework, the degeneracy in neutrino masses can come about as a result of some symmetry (at some high energy, e.g. M p ) in the textures of M and Y ν such that M ν (M p ) = M b . Starting from this very symmetric condition at M p</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>we make contact with the low energy neutrino mass matrix using the renormalization group. First we run M and Y ν from M p down to M, where the right-handed neutrinos are decoupled. Below that scale and all the way down to low energy we run M ν as an effective operator, in the same way as in the previous section. We can also think of the first stage of running between M p and M as the high energy effects providing an starting form of M ν for the second stage of running, i.e. the only one considered in the previous section (the role of Λ is played by M). This form, being slightly different from M b , may rescue the previous &quot; undecidable &quot; cases.</p>

				<p>In pursuing this idea, it is natural to assume [13] that the structure leading to the relation M ν (M p ) = M b occurs either in the Dirac matrix m D [while the Majorana matrix M is simply diagonal with equal eigenvalues (up to a sign) 2 ] or in the Majorana matrix [with a simple diagonal Dirac matrix (again with eigenvalues equal up to a sign)]. We cannot expect a conspiracy between both matrices (which come from totally different physics) leading to M ν (M p ) = M b .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>3.1</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Textures of M and Y ν leading to bimaximal mixing In the analysis of what structures for M or Y ν lead to M ν (M p ) = M b for simplicity we only consider real matrices (thus avoiding potential problems with CP violation).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>If we assume that Y ν is proportional to the identity and all the structure arises from the Majorana mass matrix, then we simply need to impose M(M p ) ∝ M b (note that M −1 b ∝ M b ). The alternative case is less trivial but equally simple.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>If M is of the form 3 M = M    −1 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 1    , (23) then it is easy to see that the most general form of Y ν satisfying Y ν T M −1 Y ν ∝ M b is Y ν = Y ν BV T b . (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here Y ν is the overall magnitude of Y ν and B is a combination of two &apos;boosts&apos;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B =    cosh a 0 sinh a 0 1 0 sinh a 0 cosh a       cosh b sinh b 0 sinh b cosh b 0 0 0 1    , (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with two free parameters a, b. Actually, one could also take Y ν = Y ν RBV T b , where R is a rotation in the (µ, τ ) plane, but such rotations can be absorbed into a change of the (ν R ) α basis, ν R → Rν R , with no modification in M and thus give physically equivalent results.</p>

				<p>Let us notice that the former case, where all the structure is in the M matrix, is equivalent to the latter case (all the structure in Y ν ) if we set a = b = 0. To see this, note that a redefinition of the ν R fields as ν R → V b ν R , would leave M ∝ diag(−1, 1, 1) and Y ν = Y ν V T b . In consequence, it is enough to study the case where all the structure is in Y ν , given by eq.(24).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>3.2</head>

				<p>Running M ν from M p to low energy</p>

				<p>From M p to M the evolution of the relevant matrices is governed by the following renormalization group equations [17]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>
					<trash>dY ν dt = − 1 16π 2 Y ν 9 4 g 2 2 + 3 4 g 2 1 − T I 3 − 3 2 Y ν † Y ν − Y † e Y e , (26) dY e dt = − 1 16π 2 Y e 9 4 g 2 2 + 15 4 g 2 1 − T I 3 + 3 2 Y ν † Y ν − Y † e Y e , (27) where T = Tr(3Y † U Y U + 3Y † D Y D + Y † ν Y ν + Y † e Y e ), (28) and dM dt = 1 16π 2 M(Y ν Y ν † ) T + Y ν Y ν † M (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(not yet given in the literature). Here g 2 and g 1 are the SU(2) L and U(1) Y gauge</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>coupling constants, and Y U,D,e are the Yukawa matrices for up quarks, down quarks and charged leptons.</p>

				<p>At M, ν R decouple, and Y e must be diagonalized to redefine the flavour basis of leptons [note that the last term in (27) produces non-diagonal contributions to Y e ]</p>

				<p>affecting the form of the Y ν matrix. Then the effective mass matrix for the light neutrinos is M ν ≃ Y ν T M −1 Y ν H 2 .</p>

				<p>From M to M Z , the effective mass matrix M ν is run down in energy exactly as described in section 2.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The renormalization group equations are integrated with the following boundary conditions: M and Y ν are chosen at M p so as to satisfy M ν (M p ) = M b , (30) with the overall magnitude of Y ν fixed, for a given value of the Majorana mass M, by the requirement m ν ∼ O(eV). The boundary conditions for the other Yukawa couplings are also fixed at the low energy side to give the observed fermion masses.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The free parameters are therefore M, a and b.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.3">Limits on the parameter space</head>

				<p>We discuss here the limits on the parameter space of our study, which is expanded by M, a and b.</p>

				<p>The parameters a and b, which define the texture of the Y ν matrix through eqs.(24, 25), can be in principle any real numbers. However, it is apparent from eqs.(24, 25) that if a or b are large, the entries of Y ν are extremely fine-tuned. Notice that the relative difference between cosh a and sinh a factors is ∼ 2e −2|a| (and the analogue for cosh b and sinh b). Therefore, the Y ν matrix is fine-tuned as ∼ 2e −2(|a|+|b|) parts in one.</p>

				<p>In particular, if |a| or |b| are &gt; 1.5 the matrix elements are fine-tuned at least in a 10%. In consequence, we will demand |a|, |b| ≤ 1.5 . (31)</p>

				<p>Let us remark that the previous limits are based on a criterion of naturality for the Y ν matrix. However, let us mention that if we relax these limits, the final results (to be presented in the next subsection) are basically unchanged, since the allowed regions for a, b remain in the &quot; natural &quot; region (31) in most of the cases.</p>

				<p>Concerning the remaining parameter, M, there is an upper bound on it coming from the fact that for large values of M, the neutrino Yukawa couplings, Y ν , develop</p>

				<p>Landau poles below M p , spoiling the perturbativity of the theory [18]. This occurs for M(M p ) ∼ 4.3 × 10 13 GeV. Actually, there is an additional effect, namely the closing of the allowed Higgs window, which occurs approximately for the same value of M(M p ).</p>

				<p>Consequently, this sets the upper bound on M. It is interesting to note that this effect also restricts the values of a, b: for a given M, the larger a, b, the larger the entries of Y ν , and thus the lower the scale at which the Landau pole appears. In general, this restriction on a, b is less severe than eq.(31).</p>

				<p>Regarding the lower bound on M, there is no physical criterion for it, as the actual origin of the right-handed Majorana matrix is unknown. Since M can be written in terms of m ν and Y ν (roughly speaking M ≃ Y 2 ν H 2 /m ν ), we can adopt the sensible</p>

				<p><formula>-1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 2:</head>

					<figDesc>Left plot: contours of ∆m</figDesc>
					<trash>2 12 /eV 2 in the (b, a) plane from less than 10 −5 (black area), through 2 × 10 −5 and 10 −4 (lines) to more than 2 × 10 −4 (grey). Right plot: same for ∆m 2 23 /eV 2 , from 5 × 10 −4 (black) to 10 −2 (grey). The Majorana mass is 8 × 10 9 GeV.</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>criterion that Y ν is at least as large as the smallest Yukawa coupling so far known, i.e. the electron one. This precisely corresponds to M ∼ 100 GeV, below which is unplausible to descend. In consequence, our limits for M are</figDesc>
					<trash>10 2 GeV &lt; ∼ M &lt; ∼ 4.3 × 10 13 GeV. (32)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>On the other hand, as we will see in the next subsection, there are no physically viable scenarios unless</figDesc>
					<trash>M &gt; ∼ 10 8 GeV, (33) which sets an operating lower limit on M. 3.4 Results</trash>

					<head>Figures 2</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>to 6 present our results for the mass splittings and mixing angles at low energy, after numerical integration of the RGEs from M p to low energy as described in subsection 3.2 (we follow the convention m</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>2 ν 1 &lt; m 2 ν 2 &lt; m 2 ν 3 in all the figures). We have -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3:</head>

					<figDesc>Left plot: Contours of sin 2 2θ 2 in the (b, a) plane.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The grey area marks the sin 2 2θ 2 &gt; 0.64 region. The line singled-out corresponds to sin 2 2θ 2 = 0.36. Right plot: Contours of sin 2 2θ 1 in the (b, a) plane. In the grey area sin 2 2θ 1 is smaller than 0.82, and the line corresponds to sin 2 2θ 1 = 0.9.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The Majorana mass is 8 × 10 9 GeV. chosen M = 8 × 10 9</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>GeV and m ν ≃ 2 eV as a typical example; the dependence of the results with M and m ν is discussed later on. Figure 2, left plot, shows contour lines of constant ∆m 2 12 (the squared mass difference between the lightest neutrinos) in the plane (b, a). The black (grey) region is excluded because there ∆m</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 12 &lt; 10 −5 eV 2 (∆m 2 12 &gt; 2 × 10 −4 eV 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>), which is too small (large) to account for the oscillations of solar neutrinos (LAMSW solution). The white area is thus the allowed region. The lines in it correspond to ∆m</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 12 = 10 −4 eV 2 and 2 × 10 −5 eV 2 . Figure 2, right plot, gives contour lines of constant ∆m 2 23 . The black (grey) region is excluded because there ∆m 2 23 &lt; 5 × 10 −4 eV 2 (∆m 2 23 &gt; 10 −2 eV 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>), which is too small (large) to account for the oscillations of atmospheric neutrinos. Again, the white area is allowed. (The black area corresponds in fact to the &quot; undecidable &quot; case discussed in the Introduction: it might be rescatable by unspecified extra effects.)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>We do not plot ∆m 2 13 because it can always be inferred from ∆m 2 23 and ∆m 2 12 . Moreover, in the -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a</trash>

					<head>Figure 4:</head>

					<figDesc>Left plot: Same as figure 3 for sin 2 2θ 3 .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The grey area corresponds to values above 0.99. The curve gives sin 2 2θ 3 = 0.95. Right plot: The grey area corresponds to cos 2θ 3 &lt; 0</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>interesting case, ∆m 2 12 ≪ ∆m 2 23 , one has ∆m 2 13 ≃ ∆m 2 23 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The intersection of the white areas in both plots is non-zero and would give the allowed area concerning mass splittings. It is always the case that the area surrounding the origin is excluded. There, the mass differences are always of the same order, and follow the same pattern discussed in subsection 2</p>

				<p><formula>(∆m 2 23 = 2∆m 2 12 ).</formula></p>

				<p>In any case we conclude that, away from the origin, there is a non negligible region of parameter space where it is natural to have ∆m 2 23 ≫ ∆m 2 12 and in accordance with the values required to explain the solar and atmospheric neutrino anomalies. In the following subsection we explain the origin of this hierarchy of mass differences.</p>

				<p>Next, we need to ensure that the mixing angles are the correct ones to give a good fit to atmospheric and solar neutrino data (as summarized by the ranges given in the Introduction). Figure 3, left plot, gives contours of constant sin 2 2θ 2 (one of the mixing angles relevant for atmospheric neutrino oscillations). The grey (white) area has sin 2 2θ 2 larger (smaller) than 0.64 and is disfavored (favored) by the data (SK + CHOOZ) at 99% C.L. according to the most recent analysis (last paper of ref. [6]).</p>

				<p>The line singled-out corresponds to sin 2 2θ 2 = 0.36 (maximum allowed value at 90%</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a</trash>

					<head>Figure 5:</head>

					<figDesc>Region (two disconnected parts) in the (b, a) parameter space for M = 8 × 10 9 GeV where all mass splittings and mixing angles satisfy experimental constraints. (See text for qualifications). C.L. according to the same reference). Figure 3</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, right plot, shows contours of constant sin 2 2θ 1 (the other mixing angle relevant for atmospheric neutrinos). The grey (white) area corresponds to sin 2 2θ 1 smaller (larger) than 0.82, and is thus disallowed (allowed). The additional line included has sin 2 2θ 1 = 0.9.</p>

				<p>Finally, figure 4, left plot, presents contours of constant sin 2 2θ 3 which is relevant for oscillations of solar neutrinos. The grey (white) region has sin 2 2θ 3 larger (smaller) than 0.99. If one is willing to interpret the existing data as impliying an upper bound of 0.99 on sin 2 2θ 3 , then the grey region would be excluded. The plotted curve gives sin 2 2θ 3 = 0.95 (sin 2 2θ 3 &gt; 0.8 in all the region shown). Figure 4, right plot, shows the region of the parameter space accomplishing the resonance condition (cos 2θ 3 &gt; 0), which is required for an efficient MSW solution of the solar anomaly (see however the first paper of ref. [6] for caveats on this issue).</p>

				<p>The region of parameter space where all constraints on mixing angles and mass splittings are satisfied is given by the intersection of all white areas in figures 2, 3 and 4 (right plot). If sin 2 2θ 3 &lt; 0.99 is imposed, then that intersection region, including</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 b a</trash>

					<head>Figure 6:</head>

					<figDesc>Same as figure 5 for different values of the Majorana mass: Upper: 10</figDesc>
					<trash>11 GeV; Lower left: 10 10 GeV; Lower right: 10 9 GeV.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>now figure 4 (left plot), is empty and no allowed region remains. It should be noticed that this fact does not come from an incompatibility between the previous constraint and the sin 2 2θ 3 &gt; 0.99 obtained from neutrinoless double β-decay limits, eq. (10), in the θ 2 = 0 approximation. If this were the case, it could be easily solved by decreasing the overall size of the neutrino masses, m ν , in eq.(10), and this is not the case. Indeed, eq.(10) is satisfied in nearly all the parameter space. Even where sin 2 2θ 3 &lt; 0.99, this is still true thanks to the contribution of θ 2 . What actually forbids the whole parameter space if sin 2 2θ 3 &lt; 0.99 is imposed, is the incompatibility between acceptable θ 1 , θ 2 and θ 3 angles to fit simultaneously all the neutrino oscillation data, as can be seen from the figures. This fact remains when m ν is decreased. In fact, the effect of decreasing m ν is essentially an amplification of the figures shown here, which comes from the fact that for a given Majorana mass, the neutrino Yukawa couplings become smaller (the effect is similar to decrease M, which is discussed below).</p>

				<p>If the sin 2 2θ 3 &lt; 0.99 condition is relaxed (as discussed in the Introduction), then the allowed region is given by the two islands in figure 5, which is non-negligible.</p>

				<p>If we now vary M, this allowed region will move in parameter space as indicated in figure 6, where we show the allowed regions for a sequence of Majorana masses that range from 10 9 to 10 11 GeV. As is apparent from the figure, lowering M has the effect of enlarging the allowed region which flies away from the origin, leaving at some point the region of naturalness for a and b. At M = 10 8 GeV there is no allowed region inside the natural range for (a, b). Conversely, increasing M reduces the allowed region, which gets closer to the origin (at M = 10 12 GeV the allowed region becomes extinct). Let us remark again that in the allowed region one fits the observed atmospheric and solar anomalies, while part of the disallowed region corresponds in fact to the undecidable case (more precisely the region near the a = b = 0 origin), in which some additional physics could be invocated to explain the same data. In contrast, the region away from the origin becomes excluded (the mass splittings are too large, even for atmospheric neutrinos). Let us also notice that if the sin 2 2θ 3 &lt; 0.99 condition is imposed, the whole parameter space becomes disallowed for any value of M.</p>

				<p>We also find that, whenever there is a hierarchy in the mass splittings, the two lightest eigenvalues have opposite signs. This is just what is needed to have a cancellation occurring in the neutrinoless double β-decay constraint (10). This constraint is satisfied in almost the whole parameter space for any M.</p>

				<p>This and other features of our results are discussed further in the next subsection.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.5">Analytical understanding of results</head>

				<p>It is simple and very illuminating to derive analytical approximations for the results presented in the previous subsection. The renormalization group equations (14,26,27,29) we integrated numerically can also be integrated analytically in the approximation of constant right hand side. In this approximation (which works very well for our analysis ), the effective neutrino mass matrix at low-energy is simply M b plus some small perturbation. It is straightforward to obtain how the degenerate eigenvalues of M b get split by this perturbation. Neglecting the Y e , Y µ Yukawa couplings, we get the following analytical expressions:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m ν 1 ≃ m ν [−1 + (2c 2 a c 2 b − 1)ǫ ν − 2ǫ τ ] , m ν 2,3 ≃ m ν 1 + 3ǫ τ − c 2 a c 2 b ǫ ν ± [ǫ τ + (c 2 a c 2 b − c 2a )ǫ ν ] 2 + s 2a s b ǫ ν − 2 √ 2ǫ τ 2 1/2 (34) where c a = cosh a, s 2a = sinh 2a, etc, and ǫ τ = Y 2 τ 128π 2 log M M Z + 3 log M p M , (35) ǫ ν = Y 2 ν 16π 2 log M p M . (36)</trash>

					<figDesc>(The labelling of mass eigenvalues in eq.(34) may not always correspond to the</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>tional order m 2 ν 1 &lt; m 2 ν 2 &lt; m 2 ν 3</formula></p>

				<p>.) It can be checked that, for a = b = 0, the Y ν couplings play no role in the mass splittings. This is not surprising since, as was mentioned in subsection 3.1, this case is equivalent to having all the structure in M, while Y ν is proportional to the identity. Then, it can be seen from the RGEs that all the nonuniversal modifications on M ν come from the Y e matrix, and has a form similar to the one found in section 2 [see eq.(16)]. So this scenario gives similar (not satisfactory) results to those found in that section.</p>

				<p>As ǫ ν ≫ ǫ τ (which occurs as soon as Y ν &gt; Y τ , i.e for M &gt; ∼ 10 9 GeV), a further expansion in powers of ǫ τ /ǫ ν of the square root is possible in most of the parameter space (except where the coefficient of ǫ 2 ν inside that square-root becomes very small).</p>

				<p>The mass eigenvalues then read</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m ν 1 ≃ m ν [−1 + (2c 2 a c 2 b − 1)ǫ ν − 2ǫ τ ] , m ν 2 ≃ m ν 1 − (2c 2 a c 2 b − 1)ǫ ν + 2 − 1 − c 2a − 2 √ 2s 2a s b c 2 a c 2 b − 1 ǫ τ , m ν 3 ≃ m ν 1 − ǫ ν + 4 + 1 − c 2a − 2 √ 2s 2a s b c 2 a c 2 b − 1 ǫ τ . (37)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These expressions show clearly the origin of the neutrino mass splittings. The splitting between the first two neutrinos is controlled by the small parameter ǫ τ , proportional to the squared Yukawa couplings of the charged leptons, and is insensitive to the parameter ǫ ν (proportional to the square of the larger Yukawa coupling Y ν ) which is responsible for the mass difference of the third neutrino.</p>

				<p>From the previous expressions we can extract the following remarkable conclusions.</p>

				<p>If the neutrino Yukawa couplings are sizeable (i.e. bigger than Y τ ), we will automatically obtain a hierarchy of mass splittings ∆m</p>

				<p><formula>2 12 ≪ ∆m 2 23 ∼ ∆m 2 13 .</formula></p>

				<p>This is exactly what is needed for a simultaneous solution of the atmospheric and solar neutrino anomalies, and thus represents a natural mechanism for the ∆m 2 sol ≪ ∆m 2 at hierarchy. Thus, if the mixing angle θ 2 is small, as it turns out to be in most of the parameter space, ∆m 2 12 is to be correctly identified with ∆m 2 sol and ∆m 2 23 with ∆m 2 at . The two mass eigenvalues which are more degenerate correspond to the lighter states, i.</p>

				<p><formula>e. m 2 ν 1 ∼ m 2 ν 2 &lt; m 2 ν 3 .</formula></p>

				<p>Moreover, m ν 1 and m ν 2 have opposite signs in the diagonalized mass matrix, which is exactly what is needed to fulfill the neutrinoless double β-decay condition, eq.(10).</p>

				<p>All these nice features are illustrated by the explicit results presented in the previous subsection.</p>

				<p>Concerning the mixing angles, it is straightforward to check that, working in the Y ν &gt; Y τ approximation, the eigenstates of the perturbed M ν matrix, corresponding to the previous eigenvalues, are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V ′ 1 = V 1 , V ′ 2 = 1 √ α 2 + β 2 (αV 2 + βV 3 ), V ′ 3 = 1 √ α 2 + β 2 (−βV 2 + αV 3 ), (38)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where V i are the eigenstates corresponding to the bimaximal mixing matrix, V b [see eq.(12)] V</p>

				<p><formula>1 =          −1 √ 2 1 2 1 2          , V 2 =          1 √ 2 1 2 1 2          , V 3 =         0 −1 √ 2 1 √ 2         , (39)</formula></p>

				<p>and α, β are given by α = c a s b + O(ǫ τ /ǫ ν ), β = s a + O(ǫ τ /ǫ ν ). (40)</p>

				<p>The V ′ i vectors define the new &quot; CKM &quot; matrix V ′ from which the mixing angles are extracted. Clearly, if just one of the two (a, b) parameters is vanishing, then V ′ = V b , i.e. exactly the bimaximal mixing case. Also, whenever c a , c b are sizeable (i.e. away from a = b = 0), |α| ≫ |β|, and thus we are close to the bimaximal case. Therefore, it is not surprising that in most of the parameter space shown in the previous section, this was in fact the case. This is remarkable, because it gives a natural origin for the bimaximal mixing, which was not guaranteed a priori due to the ambiguity in the diagonalization of the initial M ν (M p ) = M b matrix, as was explained in the Introduction.</p>

				<p>On the other hand, the MSW condition cos 2θ 3 &gt; 0 (written using the conventional</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>order m 2 ν 1 &lt; m 2 ν 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) will be clearly satisfied as long as V 1 corresponds to the lightest mass eigenvalue. In other words, this condition requires that the negative mass eigenvalue, see eqs.(34, 37), corresponds to the lightest neutrino.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.6">Examples of acceptable ansätze</head>

				<p>At a generic point in the allowed regions we have found, the form of the matrix Y ν (M p ) would look rather ad-hoc: different elements in that matrix seem to conspire to give the correct neutrino mass texture. However, there are particular cases in which this matrix has a plausible structure. We give an example of such a texture for Y ν (M p ) which for the case M ≃ 8 × 10 9 GeV studied in previous sections, would give mass splittings and mixing angles in agreement with observation:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Y ν (M p ) = Y ν          − 1 2 √ 2 1 1 1 2 √ 2 1 1 0 − 1 √ 2 1 √ 2          . (41) region plotted in figure 5. More precisely, the mass splittings are ∆m 2 12 ≃ 2 × 10 −5 eV 2 , ∆m 2 13 ≃ 1 × 10 −3 eV 2 , ∆m 2 23 ≃ 1 × 10 −3 eV 2 , (42) and the mixing angles sin 2 2θ 2 = 0.04560, sin 2 2θ 1 = 0.95405, sin 2 2θ 3 = 0.99986. (43)</trash>

					<figDesc>Concerning the resonance condition for the MSW mechanism (see Fig.4</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>), this ansatz lies precisely at the border of the allowed area.</p>

				<p>Another examples of working ansätze can be obtained. For instance, the following ansatz (corresponding to a = cosh −1 (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>√ 5/2) ≃ 0.48, b = log( √ 10/2) ≃ 1.15 ) Y ν (M p ) = Y ν           − 1 4 √ 2 3 √ 2 1 2 √ 5 √ 5 2 √ 5 2 − 1 4 √ 5 0 √ 5 2           . (44)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>works correctly for a wider range of right-handed Majorana masses (e.g. for M = 10</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>9</head>

				<p>GeV and M = 10 10 GeV, as can be seen from Figure 6).</p>

				<p>It would be interesting to explore the possibility of finding a symmetry that could be responsible for the form of these ansätze and to analyze their implications for future long baseline experiments [19]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have performed an exhaustive study of the possibility that radiative corrections are responsible for the small mass splittings in the (cosmologically relevant) scenario of nearly degenerate neutrinos. To do that, we assume that the initial form of the neutrino mass matrix (generated at high energy by unspecified interactions) has the bimaximal mixing form, and run down to low energy. We then examine the form of the low-energy neutrino mass matrix, checking its consistency with all the available experimental data, including atmospheric and solar neutrino anomalies.</p>

				<p>We find cases where the radiative corrections produce mass splittings that are i) just fine ii) too large or iii) too small. The vacuum oscillations solution to the solar neutrino problem always falls in the situation (ii), and it is therefore excluded. On the contrary, if the initial bimaximal mass matrix is produced by a see-saw mechanism (a possibility that we analyze in a detailed way), there are large regions of the parameter space consistent with the large angle MSW solution, providing a natural origin for the ∆m 2 sol ≪ ∆m 2 atm hierarchy. Concerning the mixing angles, they are remarkably stable and close to the bimaximal mixing form (something that is not guaranteed a priory, due to an ambiguity in the diagonalization of the initial matrix).</p>

				<p>We have explained analytically the origin of these remarkable features, giving explicit expressions for the mass splittings and the mixing angles. In addition, we have presented particularly simple see-saw ansätze consistent with all the observations.</p>

				<p>Finally, we have noted that the scenario is very sensitive to a possible upper bound on sin 2 2θ 3 (the angle responsible for the solar neutrino oscillations). An upper bound such as sin 2 2θ 3 &lt; 0.99 would disallow completely the scenario of nearly degenerate neutrinos due to the incompatibility between acceptable mixing angles to fit simultaneously all the neutrino oscillation data.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Addendum</head>

				<p>Shortly after completion of this work, a paper by J. Ellis and S. Lola on the same subject appeared [20]. In it, the scenario of our section 2 is also studied and similar (negative) conclusions reached. However, as we show in our section 3, positive results are obtained when the general see-saw scenario as the mechanism responsible for the effective neutrino mass matrix is studied.</p>

				<p>Also, the treatment by these authors of the constraints on mixing angles from neutrinoless double β-decay and LAMSW fits to solar neutrino data is more pessimistic than ours.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Actually, the only condition we are imposing is that the eigenvalues are equal (up to a sign). A suitable transformation will diagonalize M to the form we assume. 3 If M is taken proportional to the identity, the Yukawa matrix Y ν must be chosen complex. Our choice of M avoids that complication and is physically equivalent.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>We thank D. Casper and E. Kearns for clarification of the results of Super-Kamiokande fits. This research was supported in part by the CICYT (contract AEN95-0195) and the European Union (contract CHRX-CT92-0004)</p>
				<figure>
					<figDesc>(JAC). J.R.E. thanks the I.E.M. (CSIC, Spain) and A.I, I.N the CERN Theory Division, for hospitality during the final stages of this work.</figDesc>
				</figure>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Super-Kamiokande Collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Fukuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">433</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kamiokande Collabora- tion</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">;</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Hatakeyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. Lett. MACRO Collaboration, Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Georgi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Vissani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Barger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Pakvasa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Weiler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Whisnant</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page">437</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Giunti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">077301</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">B441 (1998) 299 and [hep-ph</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Carone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Caldwell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Mohapatra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Leon-Taris</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Lola</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>5730 ; R</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Mohapatra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Nussinov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Nomura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yanagida</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Scheich and J.D. Vergados, Phys. Rev. D53</title>
		<editor>83</editor>
		<editor>A.S. Joshipura, Z. Phys. C64 31</editor>
		<editor>A. Ioannisian and J.W.F. Valle, Phys. Lett. B3329806294]</editor>
		<editor>A.J. Baltz, A.S. Goldhaber and M. Goldhaber C. Jarlskog, M. Matsuda and S. Skadhauge S.K. Kang and C.S. Kim S. Davidson and S. King, Phys. Lett. B445 H. Fritzsch and Z. Xing, Phys. Lett. B440</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Tanimoto N</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="420" to="48017303091302" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>6381. ; S. Lola and J.D. Vergados, Prog. Part. Nucl. Phys. 40 (98) 71; B.C. Allanach</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ma, [hep-ph/9812344] and [hep-ph</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Haba</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Rev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Snellman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>M. Lipmanov A.H. Guth, L. Randall and M. SernaC. Branco, M.N. Rebelo and J.I. Silva-Marcos</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">599903464</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">683</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">035011</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Barbieri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98129904465</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">033001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Super-Kamiokande Collaboration, [hep-ex/9812009</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Fukuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Casper</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Kearns</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>private. communications</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Heidelberg-Moscow exp., [hep-ex/9902014</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Baudis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pontecorvo Prize lecture at the JINR</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Lobashev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<editor>A.I. Be- lesev et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">263</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">350</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<editor>See e.g. F. Vissani</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L R</forename>
				<surname>Wu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Barbieri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Hall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Kane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9901228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Altarelli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Feruglio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9811</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="021" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1566</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Babu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Leung</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Pantaleone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gell-Mann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ramond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Slansky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amsterdam Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<editor>P. Van Nieuwenhuizen and D. Freedman (North-Holland A. Sawada and A. Sugamoto, KEK R. Mohapatra and G. Senjanovič</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">912</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">165</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>fied. Theories and Baryon Number in the Universe</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Grzadkowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Lindner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page">193</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Yu.F. Pirogov, O</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Zenin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Haba</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Okamura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sugiura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>18] J.A. Casas, V. Di Clemente, A. Ibarra and M. Quiró</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>De Rú</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Gavela</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Herná</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9811390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Lola</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
