<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Non-renormalizability of a SSB gauge theory induced by a non-linear fermion-Higgs coupling of canonical dimension 4</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2000-03-28">28 Mar 2000 December 18, 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Nistor</forename>
								<surname>Nicolaevici</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">DepartmentofPhysics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University of Timi¸oara</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>P-t¸aHoratiu1</addrLine>
									<postCode>RO-1900</postCode>
									<settlement>Timi¸oara</settlement>
									<country key="RO">Romania</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Non-renormalizability of a SSB gauge theory induced by a non-linear fermion-Higgs coupling of canonical dimension 4</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2000-03-28">28 Mar 2000 December 18, 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/9910257v2</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We consider an abelian gauge theory with spontaneously broken symmetry containing a scalar-fermion coupling which is non-linear in the Higgs field. Although in the unitary gauge it reduces to a pure Yukawa term, suggesting that the theory is renormalizable, the one loop divergence structure in this gauge in the fermion-fermion elastic scattering amplitude shows this is not so. Comparison is made with the theory with a conventional coupling, for which cancellation of the non-renormalizable divergences occurs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>Some years ago it was proposed in Ref. [1] a class of pure left SU(N)⊗U(1) gauge theories with spontaneously broken symmetry, capable of accommodating the Weinberg-Salam model and some of its generalizations a up to the Higgs sector. They exhibit the unfamiliar feature of using a scalar-fermion coupling non-linear in the Higgs fields, specially designed, however, to reduce to a Yukawa term in the unitary gauge. It is natural to ask whether such a construction is generally compatible with renormalizability. We show here, by pointing to a simple abelian model, that renormalizability can be lost. Consider the U(1) theory given by the Lagrangian L = L 1 + L 2 , with the first term corresponding to the Goldstone model (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µ 2 , λ &gt; 0) L 1 = − 1 4 (∂ µ A ν − ∂ ν A µ ) 2 + (D µ Φ) + (D µ Φ) + µ 2 2 Φ + Φ − λ(Φ + Φ) 2 , (1) and L 2 = i ¯ ψγ µ D µ ψ − G ¯ ψψσ, D µ = ∂ µ − igA µ , G &gt; 0, (2) where the σ field is defined by writing Φ = σe iχ , (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with σ, χ real. The fermion-Higgs coupling is of the type mentioned above: it is not linear in Φ, while in the unitary gauge χ = 0 it reduces to a genuine Yukawa term. The non-linearity associated with Φ makes unitary gauge a most convenient choice for writing the Feynman rules. Let m f , M denote the masses (in the tree approximation) acquired by the fermion and vectorial field after symmetry breaking, and let ϕ √ 2 represent the shifted σ field with zero vacuum expectation value. Then the interaction Lagrangian is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L int = −g ¯ ψγ µ ψA µ + gMϕA µ A µ + 1 2 g 2 ϕ 2 A µ A µ (4) −g m f M ¯ ψψϕ + g µ 2 2M ϕ 3 + g 2 µ 2 M 2 ϕ 4 , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the Feynman rules can be read off from the effective interaction Hamiltonian [2]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H ef f = −L int + iδ 4 (0) ln 1 + g ϕ M , (6) using the covariant vector field propagator D µν (k) = (−g µν +k µ k ν /M 2 )/(k 2 − M 2 + iǫ). Now, it is generally accepted [3]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>that despite the bad ultraviolet behaviour of the massive vectorial propagators in unitary gauge, renormalizability should still allow the S matrix divergences to be absorbed into a proper set of counterterms (which is not the case for arbitrary Green functions ). When calculating physical quantities, the hidden gauge symmetry is expected to lead in to the cancellation of the non-renormalizable divergences in individual graphs. It turns out this fails to happen for our theory. Consider the g 4 contribution to the fermion-fermion elastic scattering. The corresponding Feynman graphs are displayed in the Figure. We have not shown (i) diagrams which differ only by an external line permutation, (ii) tadpole and external line self-energy diagrams (as taken care by mass and wave function renormalization), and (iii) diagrams involving only ψ − ϕ interactions. The last ones can be easily seen to contain only renormalizable divergences.</p>

				<p>The result of a straightforward calculation can be summarized as follows.</p>

				<p>The following pairs of diagrams are finite, though each diagram is separately divergent: (a, b), (c, d), (e, f), (g, h), (i, j). Diagrams (k), (l) prove to be individually finite. Vertex diagrams (m), (n) are logarithmically, while (o), (p), (q) and (r) quadratically divergent. The divergences turn out to be momentum-independent, so that in principle they can be cured by coupling constant (eventually m f , M) renormalization. Quadratical divergences in diagrams (s), (t) correspond to vector field mass and wave function renormalization . One is left with the quartically divergent self-energy graph (u).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Its contribution reads f = 2g 4 m 2 f ¯ u(p f )u(p i )¯ u(q f )u(q i ) Σ(k) (k 2 − µ 2 ) 2 , (7) where k = p f − p i = q i − q f and Σ(k) = d 4 q (2π) 4 g µν − q µ q ν /M 2 q 2 − M 2 + iǫ g µν − (k µ − q µ )(k ν − q ν )/M 2 (k − q) 2 − M 2 + iǫ . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Evaluating the integral in n = 4 − ǫ dimensions [4] one gets for the divergent part</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Σ ∞ (k) = i 32π 2 ǫ (k 2 ) 2 M 4 + 3i 8π 2 ǫ , (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which leads, along with mass and wave function renormalization terms, to the non-renormalizable four-fermion interaction</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f N R ∞ = ig 4 16π 2 ǫ m f M 2 2 ¯ u(p f )u(p i )¯ u(q f )u(q i ). (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This suffices to prove our point. It is interesting to consider the same process in the theory modified to allow a conventional coupling. It is not hard to see that the only way to do this without changing the particle spectrum (or destroying relativistic invariance) is to resort to the familiar choice with chiral components of ψ behaving differently under gauge transformations. One can set, without loss of generality, ψ L → e −igΛ ψ L , ψ R → ψ R , (11) where ψ L , ψ R are the left and right handed projections, respectively. This does not affect L 1 , but maintaining U(1) gauge invariance requests replacing</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L 2 with L ′ 2 = i ¯ ψγ µ (∂ µ − ig 1 − γ 5 2 A µ )ψ − G (( ¯ ψ L Φ)ψ R + ¯ ψ R (Φ + ψ L )). (12) The resulting L ′ = L 1 + L ′ 2 theory is just the Appelquist and Quinn model [5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>used in the early days of electroweak theory to test divergence cancellations in unitary gauge calculations. In this gauge, the S matrix still follows from the effective Hamiltonian (6) with the sole modification in L int concerning the spinor-vector coupling</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>¯ ψγ µ ψA µ → ¯ ψγ µ 1 − γ 5 2 ψA µ . (13)</trash>

					<figDesc>This proves essential for divergence cancellations. Situation now presents as follows (the contributing Feynamn graphs in both theories are obviously the same). Diagrams (a) and (b) summed yield a logarithmic divergence which equals f N R ∞ . Diagrams (k) and (l) produce logarithmic and quadratically divergences which added yield, for each diagram, −f</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>N R ∞ . These four diagrams thus exactly cancel the divergence in diagram (u). The rest of diagrams prove to contain either renormalizable infinities, or non-renormalizable ones corresponding to a pseudoscalar-pseudoscalar four-fermion interaction, which again cancel among themselves</p>

			<div>
				<head>b</head>

				<p>In conclusion, our example shows one should be cautious in extending the renormalizability result [7] concerning SSB gauge theories when including in the fermion-scalar terms non-linearities in the Higgs sector, even though by formal power counting this might look justified.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-th/9910257v2 28 Mar 2000</note>

			<note place="foot">a See discussions in Ref. 1.</note>

			<note place="foot">b See Ref. 5. Cancellation of the one-loop non-renormalizable divergences was also checked in Ref. 6, though not by a direct evaluation of individual graphs.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>I am indebted to Ion I. Cot˘ aescu and Geza Ghemes for stimulating discussions and criticisms. I also thank Atilla Farkas for reading the manuscript.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Cot˘</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Mod. P hys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1483</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1068</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Fujikawa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Sanda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>T. W. Appelquist, J. R. Primack, and H. R. Quinn</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1701" to="2923" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Veltman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. P hys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">189</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Appelquist</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Quinn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">229</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Kummer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Lane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1910</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nucl</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
