<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1999-11-25">25 Nov 1999</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Yohanes</forename>
								<surname>Surya</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Kam</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Chan</forename>
								<surname>Hin</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">T</forename>
								<forename type="middle">C</forename>
								<surname>Au</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Yeung</forename>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">W</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
								<surname>Shangguan</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Dept. College of William</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Mary</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Wirawan</forename>
								<surname>Purwanto</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Dept</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Eddy</forename>
								<surname>Yusuf</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Dept</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Florida State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Darmadi</forename>
								<surname>Kusno</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Oki</forename>
								<surname>Gunawan</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Universitas Pelita Harapan</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1999-11-25">25 Nov 1999</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>The role of S 11 resonance in πN Scattering 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We analyze Pion Nucleon Scattering up to 700 MeV using a simple, rela-tivistic, unitary model. 1 The kernel of the integral equation includes nucleon, roper, delta, D 13 as well as S 11 poles with their corresponding crossed pole terms approximated by contact interactions. The sand p-wave phase shifts are calculated from the model and shown to agree very well with the values derived from πN scattering data. 2 All parameters which involve S 11 are presented. 1</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>

				<p>The role of S 11 resonance in πN Scattering</p>

			<div>
				<head>1</head>

				<figure>
					<trash>Yohanes Surya, 2 Kam Chan Hin, 2 T.C Au Yeung, 2 W.Z. Shangguan, 3 Wirawan Purwanto, 4 Eddy Yusuf , 5 Darmadi Kusno, 2 Oki Gunawan 1 Universitas Pelita Harapan, Indonesia 2 Nanyang Technological University, Singapore 3 Physics Dept. College of William and Mary 4 Physics Dept University of Indonesia 5 Physics Dept. Florida State University</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Abstract</head>

				<p>We analyze Pion Nucleon Scattering up to 700 MeV using a simple, relativistic , unitary model. 1 The kernel of the integral equation includes nucleon, roper, delta, D 13 as well as S 11 poles with their corresponding crossed pole terms approximated by contact interactions. The s-and p-wave phase shifts are calculated from the model and shown to agree very well with the values derived from πN scattering data. 2 All parameters which involve S 11 are presented.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>I. Introduction</head>

				<p>Even though pion-nucleon scattering has been extensively studied for many years, there still remains a number of interesting problems to be explored , especially with the construction of powerful new facilities such as TJNAF (Thomas Jefferson National Lab) in Virginia, USA. In this brief paper we analyze pion nucleon scattering up to 700 MeV laboratory kinetic energy of pion using a simple, covariant and unitary model of πN scattering.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1</head>

				<p>In this work, the πN scattering amplitude is obtained as a solution of a relativistic wave equation in which the pion and eta is restricted to their mass shell in all intermediate states. The rationale for this approach has been</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>cussed by Gross and Surya. 1 The kernel of the relativistic integral equation includes undressed delta (∆),roper(N * ), D 13</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and S 11 poles in addition to the undressed nucleon (N) pole. The kernel also includes contributions derived from crossed N, ∆, N * , D 13 ,and S 11 diagrams, as well as from σ-and ρ-like exchange terms. To keep the model simple the crossed terms are approximated by contact interactions as described in reference [1]. The πNN coupling is taken to be the superposition of both pseudoscalar and pseudovector coupling and the πNS 11 coupling is taken as a superposition of both scalar and vector coupling. However for simplicity we take only scalar coupling for the ηNS 11 coupling (the results obtained also show this tendency). The Feynman rule for the πNN and πNS 11 vertex are given as follows,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>πNN vertex : Γ 0N = g πN N λ + 1 − λ 2m γ µ k µ γ 5 τ i πNS 11 vertex : Γ 0S = i g 1 + g 2 m γ µ k µ τ i ηNS 11</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>vertex : Γ 0η = ig η τ 0 k is the pion momentum, λ is a mixing parameter that is determined by the requirement that the nucleon mass be unshifted by the interaction, 1 g 1 , g 2 and g η are the coupling constants adjusted to fit data and m is the nucleon mass. The πNN coupling g πN N is chosen to be equal to 13.5 the same as in the reference [1]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. The model</head>

				<p>The model has been described in detail in reference [1] except for the S 11 resonance. Figure (1) shows additional kernels that one needed to describe</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 1: Figure 2:</head>

					<figDesc>the S 11 resonance. Consistent with the previous model, the crossed diagram is approximated as a contact interaction. Figure (2) shows the self energy of S 11 . M c is the infinite sum of iterated the contact diagrams. The M</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>ππ c , M πη c , M ηπ c and M ηη</formula></p>

				<p>c are treated as a coupled channel.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. Results</head>

				<p>Due to the contact interactions approximation, the model allows us to fit the spin</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 and spin 3 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>phase shifts separately. Our fit to S 11 , S 31 , P 11 and P 31 phase shifts are given in Figures 3 and 4. The fit is good. The S 11 phase shifts are particularly interesting. Figure 5 shows how the total is built up from individual contributions, the curves in the figures show the result when the kernel (i) includes only the direct nucleon pole term and the contact term derived from crossed nucleon exchange plus the combined σ-and ρ-like contact terms (the dot line), (ii) the terms in (i) plus the additional ρ-like ππNN contact term (the dot-dashed line), (iii) the terms in (ii) plus roper driving terms (dashed line) and finally (iv) the total result, which includes the terms in (iii) plus S 11 driving terms (solid line). From our calculation the contribution from S 11 (including ηN channel) plays an important role to pion nucleon interaction at energies above 600 MeV as shown in Figure 5. Table 1 shows parameters that are used to fit the data (column 2). The table includes effective masses (m) and widths (Γ) of the resonances (column 3) . In the table, Λ represents the baryon cut off mass, g′ is the inelastic coupling in the roper channel. We found the S 11 width is smaller compared to Particle data group (∼100 to 250 MeV). 3 This maybe is related to our smaller value of g ηN S 11 = 1.19 as compared to effective models results 3 or QCD sum rules using interpolating field results 4 which is around 2.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>parameter value effective value Λ 1205.8 Λ(N * ) 1961.3 g πN N * 6.924 m N * 1458.0 1463.5 Γ N * 244.3 C ρ 0.911 g′ 0.793 g 2 1.910 g 1 1.222 Λ s11 2666.3 m s11 1540.6 1567.0 Γ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>s11 57.4 g ηN S 11 1.19 IV. Conclusions We have successfully extended the relativistic, simple and unitary model of pion nucleon scattering 1 to analyze the pion nucleon scattering up to 700 MeV which includes the S 11 resonance. We find that the model works well despite of our meson on-shell approximation in all intermediate states. We also find that the inclusion of ηN channel tends to give the correct high energy behavior. The coupling of pion and eta to the nucleon and S 11 is smaller than expected. This would be clarified by some quark model calculations.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. Acknowledgment</head>

				<p>YS would like to thank School of Electrical &amp; Electronic Engineering Nanyang Technological University for their support and for kind hospitality during the visit.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3:</head>

					<figDesc>S 11 phase-shifts</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4:</head>

					<figDesc>P -wave phase shifts</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 5:</head>

					<figDesc>S -wave phase shifts</figDesc>
					<trash>0 10 20 30 40 50 60 70 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 δ T lab (MeV) S 11 S 11 S 11 S 11 S 11 -20 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 δ T lab (MeV) P 11 P 31 -40 -30 -20 -10 0 10 20 30 40 50 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 δ T lab (MeV) S 11 S 11 S 31 S 11 S 31 S 11 S 31</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Franz</forename>
				<surname>Gross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yohanes</forename>
				<surname>Surya</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">703</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">http:\\said.phys.vt.edu\analysis\pin analysis.html. 3 Particle Data Group</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nimai</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Benmerrouche</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Mukhopadhyay</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Kaiser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Siegel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Weiss</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. D Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>Ch. Sauermann, B. L. Friman, and W. Norenberg M. Benmerrouche, Nimai C. Mukhopadhyay, and J. F. Zhang</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Zhenping Li</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3237</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1070" />
			<publisher>Zhenping Li</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lee Los Alamos Preprint nucl-th/9704035</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Chong</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Su</forename>
				<surname>Houng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Oka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Jido</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hosaka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>A. Hosaka, D. Jido and M. Oka</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9702294" />
			<publisher>D</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Los Alamos Preprint hepph ; Los Alamos Preprint hepph</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Jido</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Oka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Hosaka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9610520" />
			<pubPlace>Los Alamos Preprint hepph</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
