<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Atomic Parity Violation, Leptoquarks, and Contact Interactions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2000-03-18">18 Mar 2000 Date: June 26, 2011</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">V</forename>
								<surname>Barger</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1150 University Ave</addrLine>
									<postCode>53706</postCode>
									<settlement>Madison</settlement>
									<region>WI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Kingman</forename>
								<surname>Cheung</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>95616</postCode>
									<settlement>Davis</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Atomic Parity Violation, Leptoquarks, and Contact Interactions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2000-03-18">18 Mar 2000 Date: June 26, 2011</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The recent measurement of atomic parity violation in cesium atoms shows a 2.3σ deviation from the standard model prediction. We show that such an effect can be explained by four-fermion contact interactions with specific chiralities or by scalar leptoquarks which couple to the left-handed quarks. For a coupling of electromagnetic strength, the leptoquark mass is inferred to be 1.1 to 1.3 TeV. We also show that these solutions are consistent with all other low-energy and high-energy neutral-current data.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>1.</head>

				<p>Parity violation in the standard model (SM) results from exchanges of weak gauge bosons. In electronhadron neutral-current processes parity violation is due to the vector axial-vector interaction terms in the</p>

				<p>Lagrangian. These interactions have been tested to a high accuracy in atomic parity violation (APV) measurements. A very recent measurement in cesium (Cs) atoms has been reported [1] by measuring a parity-odd transition between the 6S and 7S energy levels of the Cs atoms. The measurement is stated in terms of the weak charge Q W , which parameterizes the parity violating Hamiltonian.</p>

				<p>The new measurement of the atomic parity violation in cesium atoms is [1] Q W (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>133 55 Cs) = −72.06 ± 0.28(expt) ± 0.34(theo) . (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This result represents a substantial improvement over the previously reported value [2], because of a more precise calculation of the atomic wavefunctions [3]. Compared to the standard model prediction Q SM W = −73.09 ± 0.03 [4], the deviation ∆Q W is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∆Q W ≡ Q W (Cs) − Q SM W (Cs) = 1.03 ± 0.44 , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is 2.3σ away from the SM prediction.</p>

				<p>In this Letter, we propose leptoquark solutions to this APV measurement and also solutions with fourfermion contact interactions. We find that the weak-isospin-doublet leptoquark S R 1/2 , which couples to the right-handed electron and left-handed u and d quarks, and the weak-isospin-triplet leptoquark S L 1 , which couples to left-handed electron and left-handed u, d quarks, can explain the measurement with the couplingto-mass ratio λ/M ∼ 0.29 and 0.24 TeV −1 , respectively, where λ is the coupling and M is the leptoquark mass. For a coupling of electromagnetic strength the leptoquark masses are 1.1 to 1.3 TeV. We verify that these leptoquark explanations are comfortably consistent with all existing experimental constraints. We also find that contact interactions with η eu RL = η ed RL = −0.043 TeV −2 and others can alternatively explain the APV measurement and are consistent with a global fit to data on ℓℓqq interactions.</p>

				<p>Another possible explanation for the APV measurement is extra Z bosons [5], which can come from a number of grand-unified theories. Previous work on constraining new physics using the atomic parity violation measurements can be found in Ref. [6]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2.</head>

				<p>The parity-violating part of the Lagrangian describing electron-nucleon scattering is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L eq = G F √ 2 q=u,d C 1q (¯ eγ µ γ 5 e)(¯ qγ µ q) + C 2q (¯ eγ µ e)(¯ qγ µ γ 5 q) (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where in the SM the coefficients C 1q and C 2q at tree level are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C SM 1q = −T 3q + 2Q q sin 2 θ w , C SM 2q = −T 3q (1 − 4 sin 2 θ w ) .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here T 3q is the third component of the isospin of the quark q and θ w is the weak mixing angle. In terms of the C 1q , the weak charge Q W for Cs is Q W = −376C 1u − 422C 1d . Since we are interested in the deviation of Q W from its SM value, we write ∆Q W (Cs) = −376∆C 1u − 422∆C 1d . (4)</p>

				<p>A convenient form [7] for four-fermion eeqq contact interactions is [8] L Λ = q=u,d {η LL e L γ µ e L q L γ µ q L + η LR e L γ µ e L q R γ µ q R + η RL e R γ µ e R q L γ µ q L + η RR e R γ µ e R q R γ µ q R }</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, (5) where η αβ = 4πǫ/(Λ eq αβ ) 2 and ǫ = ±1. The contact interaction contributions to the ∆C 1q &apos;s are ∆C 1q = 1 2 √ 2G F [−η eq LL + η eq RR − η eq LR + η eq RL ] , (6) and the corresponding contributions to ∆Q W are ∆Q W = (−11.4 TeV 2 ) [−η eu LL + η eu RR − η eu LR + η eu RL ] + (−12.8 TeV 2 ) −η ed LL + η ed RR − η ed LR + η ed RL . (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In order to explain the data in Eq. (2) using contact interactions, we can apply Eq. (7) with nonzero η&apos;s. However, from Eq. (7) we see that there could be cancellations among the η-terms. When we assume one nonzero η at a time, the values required to fit the APV data are tabulated in Table 1. The value of Λ</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Table 1:</head>

					<figDesc>The values of η eu,ed αβ required to fit the ∆QW data of Eq. (2). We assume one nonzero η at a time.</figDesc>
					<trash>η fitted value (TeV −2 ) η fitted value (TeV −2 ) η eu LL 0.090 η ed LL 0.081 η eu RR −0.090 η ed RR −0.081 η eu LR 0.090 η ed LR 0.081 η eu RL −0.090 η ed RL −0.081 corresponding to η = 0.090(0.081) TeV −2 is 11.8(12.5) TeV. If we further assume a SU(2) L symmetry, then η eu RL equals η ed RL and the value to fit the APV data is η eu RL = η ed RL = −0.043 TeV −2 , (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which corresponds to a Λ ∼ 17 TeV. Equation (8) is relevant to one of the leptoquark solutions that we present in the next section.</p>

				<p>The next question to ask is whether the above solutions are in conflict with other existing data. To answer this, we performed an analysis [7] of the neutral-current lepton-quark contact interactions using a global set of ℓℓqq data, which includes (i) the neutral-current (NC) deep-inelastic scattering at HERA, (ii)</p>

				<p>Drell-Yan production at the Tevatron, (iii) the hadronic production cross sections at LEPII, (iv) the parity violation measurements in e-(D, Be, C) scattering at SLAC, Mainz, and Bates, (v) the ν-nucleon scattering measurements by CCFR and NuTeV, and (vi) the lepton-hadron universality of weak charged-currents. This is an update of the analysis in Ref. [7] with new data from LEPII, finalized and published data from H1 and ZEUS [9], and including DØ data on Drell-Yan production [10]. The 95% C.L. one-sided limits on η&apos;s and the corresponding limits on Λ are given in Table 2.</p>

				<p>In obtaining these limits, we do not include the data on atomic parity violation, which is the new physics data that we want to describe in this paper.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>In Table 2</head>

				<p>, the most tightly constrained are η eu LL and η ed LL , mainly due to the constraint of lepton-hadron universality of weak charged currents. In general, the constraints on eu parameters are stronger than those on ed parameters, because of Drell-Yan production, in which the u¯ u-initial-state channel is considerably more important than the d ¯ d-initial-state channel. From Table 2 the 95% C.L. one-sided limits on η RL are 0.30 TeV −2 and −0.64 TeV −2 for ǫ = + and ǫ = −, respectively. Thus, the fit to the APV data in Eq. (8) lies comfortably within the limits and so are the solutions with η LR and η RR . On the other hand, the solution using η eu LL is ruled out while the solution using η ed LL is marginal. Table 2: The 95% C.L. one-sided limits on η eq αβ , α, β = L, R, q = u, d. The &quot; + &quot; and &quot; − &quot; signs correspond to the ǫ in the definition of η&apos;s. The corresponding limits on Λ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>eq αβ are also shown. The SU(2)L implied relation η eu RL = η ed RL is included. η fitted value (TeV −2 ) η 95 (TeV −2 ) Λ (TeV) + − + − η eu LL −0.057 ± 0.030 0.034 −0.11 19.4 10.8 η eu LR −0.024 ± 0.15 0.28 −0.32 6.6 6.3 η eu RL = η ed RL −0.38 +0.20 −0.17 0.30 −0.64 6.4 4.4 η eu RR −0.23 +0.15 −0.14 0.20 −0.46 7.9 5.2 η ed LL 0.059 ± 0.033 0.11 −0.037 10.5 18.6 η ed LR −0.048 +0.33 −0.31 0.62 −0.60 4.5 4.6 η ed RR 0.32 +0.26 −0.30 0.73 −0.61 4.1 4.5 η eu LL = η ed LL /2 0.058 ± 0.034 0.11 −0.040 10.5 17.8 3.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The Lagrangians representing the interactions of the F = 0 and F = −2 (F is the fermion number) scalar leptoquarks are [11, 12] L F =0 = λ L ℓ L u R S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L 1/2 + λ R q L e R (iτ 2 S R * 1/2 ) + ˜ λ L ℓ L d R ˜ S L 1/2 + h.c. , (9) L F =−2 = g L q (c) L iτ 2 ℓ L S L 0 + g R u (c) R e R S R 0 + ˜ g R d (c) R e R ˜ S R 0 + g 3L q (c) L iτ 2 τ ℓ L · S L 1 + h.c. (10) where q L , ℓ L denote the left-handed quark and lepton doublets, u R , d R , e R denote the right-handed up quark, down quark, and electron singlet, and q (c) L , u (c) R , d (c)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>R denote the charge-conjugated fields. The subscript on leptoquark fields denotes the weak-isospin of the leptoquark, while the superscript (L, R) denotes the handedness of the lepton that the leptoquark couples to. The components of the F = 0 leptoquark fields are</p>

				<p><formula>S L,R 1/2 =   S L,R 1/2 (−2/3) S L,R 1/2 (−5/3)   , ˜ S L 1/2 =   ˜ S L(1/3) 1/2 − ˜ S L(−2/3) 1/2   , (11)</formula></p>

				<p>where the electric charge of the component fields is given in the parentheses, and the corresponding</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>charges are Y (S L 1/2 ) = Y (S R 1/2 ) = −7/3 and Y ( ˜ S L 1/2 ) = −1/3. The F = −2 leptoquarks S L 0 , S R 0 , ˜ S R 0 are isospin singlets with hypercharges 2/3, 2/3, 8/3, respectively, while S L 1 is a triplet with hypercharge 2/3: S L 1 =      S L 1 (4/3) S L 1 (1/3) S L 1 (−2/3)      . (12)</trash>

					<figDesc>The SU(2) L × U(1) Y symmetry is assumed in the Lagrangians of Eqs. (9) and (10).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>We have verified that the contributions of leptoquarks S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L 1/2 , ˜ S L 1/2 , S R 0 , and S R 0</trash>

					<figDesc>, that couple to the righthanded quarks, only give a negative ∆Q W , which cannot explain the measurement in Eq. (1). The only viable choices are the leptoquarks S</figDesc>
					<trash>R 1/2 , S L 0 , and S L 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>that couple to the left-handed quarks. Let us first examine the contribution from the F = 0 leptoquark S R 1/2 . The effective interaction of electron-quark scattering via this leptoquark is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = − λ 2 R M 2 S R 1/2 d L e R e R d L + u L e R e R u L , (13) where we have assumed M 2 S R 1/2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>≫ s, |t|, |u| and the overall negative sign is due to the ordering of the fermion fields relative to the γ, Z diagrams. After a Fierz transformation, the above amplitude can be transformed</p>

				<p><formula>to L = − λ 2 R 2M 2 S R 1/2 e R γ µ e R d L γ µ d L + e R γ µ e R u L γ µ u L . (14)</formula></p>

				<p>Comparing with the contact interaction terms, we can relate the above equation to η RL as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>η eu RL = η ed RL = − λ 2 R 2M 2 S R 1/2 . (15)</trash>

					<figDesc>Using the result on contact terms in Eq. (8) and the above equation, we obtain the value for λ R /M S R</figDesc>
					<trash>1/2 to be λ R M S R 1/2 = 0.29 TeV −1 . (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>This result cannot specifically indicate the value for the mass or the coupling of the leptoquark, because the APV is a low-energy atomic process that only probes the λ R /M S R</figDesc>
					<trash>1/2 ratio.</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Similarly, the effective interaction of electron-quark scattering involving S</figDesc>
					<trash>L 0 is L = g 2 L 2M 2 S L 0 e L γ µ e L u L γ µ u L . (17) Therefore, the contribution from S L 0 , in terms of contact interaction, is η eu LL = g 2 L 2M 2 S L 0 . (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Matching with the results in Table 1 the coupling-to-mass ratio of the leptoquark is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g L M S L 0 = 0.43 TeV −1 . (19) However, this leptoquark S L 0 contributes η eu LL = 0.09 TeV −2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and that is ruled out by the limit in Table 2.</p>

				<p>The interaction of the F</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= −2 leptoquark S L 1 is given by L = g 3L − u (c) L e L + d (c) L ν L S L(1/3) 1 − √ 2 d (c) L e L S L(4/3) 1 + √ 2 u (c) L ν L S L(−2/3) 1 + h.c. . (20) The effective interaction of electron-quark scattering involving S L 1 is L = g 2 3L 2M 2 S L 1 e L γ µ e L u L γ µ u L + g 2 3L M 2 S L 1 e L γ µ e L d L γ µ d L . (21) Therefore, the contributions from S L 1 , in terms of contact interaction, are η eu LL = η ed LL 2 = g 2 3L 2M 2 S L 1 . (22) Fitting to ∆Q W using Eq. (7), we obtain the coupling-to-mass ratio of S L 1 to be g 3L M S L 1 = 0.24 TeV −1 , (23) which gives η eu LL = 0.028 TeV −2 and η ed LL = 0.056 TeV −2 .</trash>

					<figDesc>We recalculate the limit from the global set of neutral-current ℓℓqq data for the case of nonzero η</figDesc>
					<trash>eu LL and η ed LL with η eu LL = η ed LL /2. We obtain the 95% C.L. one-sided limits on η eu LL = η ed LL /2 as 0.11 TeV −2 and −0.04 TeV −2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for ǫ = + and ǫ = −, respectively (this result is listed in the last row of Table 2.) Therefore, this leptoquark S L 1 solution is also consistent with all other data.</p>

				<p>As discussed above, there are two leptoquark solutions that are consistent with the limits in Table 2. The one with the F = 0 leptoquark S R 1/2 requires the coupling-to-mass ratio equal 0.29 TeV −1 . With a coupling strength about the same as e = 0.31, the inferred leptoquark mass is about 1.1 TeV for S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R 1/2 . Similarly, the coupling-to-mass ratio for the F = −2 leptoquark S L 1 is required to be 0.24 TeV −1 , which corresponds to a mass of 1.3 TeV. 4.</trash>

					<figDesc>In the following we discuss the above leptoquarks that describe the APV measurement in the context of the limits from various collider experiments.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The model-independent search for the first generation scalar leptoquark at the Tevatron by CDF and DØ puts a lower bound of 242 GeV on the mass of the leptoquark [13]. The direct search for the first generation scalar leptoquark at HERA, on the other hand, depends on the coupling constants and the type of the leptoquark. ZEUS [14] excluded the first generation scalar leptoquark (fermion number F = 0) with electromagnetic coupling strength up to a mass of 280 GeV while H1 [15] excluded a mass up to 275 GeV in e + p collisions. In the most recent searches in e − p collisions, ZEUS excluded F = −2 scalar leptoquarks up to about 290 GeV mass [14]. In general, e ± p colliders can search for leptoquarks up to mass almost equal to the center-of-mass energy of the machine.</p>

				<p>The LEP collaborations performed both direct searches for leptoquarks and indirect searches for virtual effects of leptoquarks in fermion-pair production. OPAL [16] searched for real leptoquarks in pair production and excluded scalar leptoquarks up to about 88 GeV; DELPHI [17] searched for leptoquarks in single production and excluded scalar leptoquarks up to about 161 GeV. Various LEP Collaborations [18] analyzed fermion-pair production and were able to rule out some leptoquark coupling and mass ranges, which depend sensitively on the leptoquark type and couplings. The best mass limit is around 300 GeV for electromagnetic coupling strength. The virtual effects in fermion-pair production have already been included in our global analysis presented in Sec. 2. If we take λ R and g 3L of electromagnetic strength, the leptoquark masses are inferred to be 1.1 and 1.3 TeV, respectively, as already noted above. Therefore, the solutions in Eqs. (16) and (23) lie comfortably with both the direct search limits and the virtual effects in neutral-current ℓℓqq data.</p>

				<p>An important low-energy constraint to leptoquarks or contact interactions is lepton-hadron universality of weak charged-currents (CC), which we have already included in the global analysis in Sec. 2. Since it is particularly important to leptoquark interactions, we would like to explain it briefly. Because of the SU(2) L symmetry, the η eu LL and η ed LL are related to the CC contact interaction η CC ν L γ µ e L d L γ µ u L by η ed LL −η eu LL = η CC .</p>

				<p>Thus, the NC contact interactions and leptoquarks are subject to the constraint on η CC . The leptoquarks that are constrained by this η CC are S L 0 and S L 1 , which couple to the left-handed leptons and quarks.</p>

				<p>The CC contact interaction η CC ν L γ µ e L d L γ µ u L could upset two important experimental constraints: (i) lepton-hadron universality in weak CC, and (ii) e-µ universality in pion decay, of which the former gives a stronger constraint. Using the values for the CKM matrix elements the constraint on η CC is 2η CC = (0.102 ± 0.073) TeV −2 [7]. It is mainly because of this constraint that the leptoquark S L 0 is ruled out while S L 1 remains consistent in our global analysis. Studies of a future scalar leptoquark search at the LHC [19] show that with a luminosity of 100 fb −1 the LHC can probe leptoquark mass up to 1.5 TeV in the pair production channel (which does not depend on the Yukawa coupling) and up to about 3 TeV (with the Yukawa coupling the same as e) in the single production channel. Thus, the leptoquarks in our solutions can be observed or ruled out at the LHC. On the other hand, Run II at the Tevatron can only probe leptoquarks up to a mass of 425 GeV [20].</p>

				<p>Comments about the origin of these leptoquarks are in order.</p>

				<p>(i) The R-parity violating (RPV) squarks, which arise from the supersymmetry framework without the R parity, are special leptoquarks. The natural question to ask is whether the leptoquarks that are used to explain the APV measurement can be the RPV squarks. First, since the RPV squarks couple to leptons via the LQD c term in the superpotential, they only couple to the left-handed leptons. Therefore, S R 1/2 , which couples to the right-handed electron, cannot be a RPV squark. Also, the leptoquark S L 1 , which is an isospin-triplet, is not a RPV squark. On the other hand, the leptoquark S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L 0 has the interactions g L (u (c) L e L − d (c) L ν L ) S L 0 , which is exactly the same as the RPV squark d * R , while the isospin-doublet leptoquark S L 1/2 , which has the interactions λ L ℓ L d R ˜ S L 1/2 , is equivalent to the left-handed RPV squark doublet iτ 2 (˜ u * L , ˜ d * L ) T .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The natural question to ask is whether the coexistence of S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L 0 and S L 1/2 can help S L 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>to evade the constraint of lepton-hadron universality of weak charged currents, and at the same time still gives a positive ∆Q W .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>In Sec. 3, we have shown that S L 0 gives a positive ∆Q W while S L 1/2</trash>

					<figDesc>gives a negative ∆Q W , so that their contributions to ∆Q W cancel. In fitting to the Q W measurement, the coexistence of S</figDesc>
					<trash>L 0 and S L 1/2 would give a lower S L 0 mass or a higher Yukawa coupling. However, S L 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>induces η CC as it couples to both left-handed leptons and quarks, while S L 1/2 does not because it couples to left-handed leptons and right-handed quarks. Therefore, the simultaneous existence of S</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L 0 and S L 1/2 would not help S L 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>to evade the constraint from lepton-hadron universality of weak charged-currents. (ii) The F = −2 leptoquark S L 0 is one of the leptoquarks of E 6 [12]. The F = 0 leptoquark S R 1/2 can be embedded [12] in the flipped SU(5)×U(1) X model [21], in which the SM fermion content is extended by right-handed neutrinos. The associated right-handed neutrinos could be used to generate the neutrino masses by the see-saw mechanism. The S R 1/2 can be placed into 10 + 10, which would also contain the F = −2 leptoquark S R 0 . The simultaneous existence of these two leptoquarks with similar masses and couplings would give cancelling contributions to ∆Q W . Thus, from the view point of fitting to the Q W data, this is not favorable.</p>

				<p>In summary, we have found leptoquark and contact interaction solutions to the atomic parity violation measurement, which stands at a 2.3σ deviation from the SM prediction. In addition, we have shown that these solutions are consistent with all other data.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>This research was supported in part by the U.S. Department of Energy under Grants No. DE-FG03- 91ER40674 and No. DE-FG02-95ER40896 and in part by the Davis Institute for High Energy Physics and the University of Wisconsin Research Committee with funds granted by the Wisconsin Alumni Research</p>
				<p>Foundation.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Bennett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Wieman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2484</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Wood</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">275</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1759</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Dzuba</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Flambaum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Sushkov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4357</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The most recent value for Q W (Cs) is found in 1999 off- year partial update for the 2000 edition available on the PDG WWW site Electroweak Model and Constraints on New Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Caso</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C3</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Cho</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Casalbuoni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>De</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Curtis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Rosner, Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">016006</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Dominici</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Gatto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>J. Erler and P. Langacker</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">460</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">212</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Langacker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Luo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Mann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Leurer, Phys. Rev. D49</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>A. Deandrea, Phys</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page">277</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cheung, e-Print Archive: hep-ph/9807483; D. Zeppenfeld and K. Cheung, MADPH-98-1081, e-Print Archive</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Barger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Cheung</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hagiwara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Zeppenfeld</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Phys. Rev. D57</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Eichten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Lane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Peskin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">811</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">hep-ex/9905032; H1 Coll</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Zeus</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9908059</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Dø</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4769</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Buchmü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Rü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Wyler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page">442</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hewett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Rizzo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5709</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Dø</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Abbott</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>CDF Coll. (F. Abe et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2051</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined limits on first generation leptoquarks from the CDF and DØ experiments</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CDF Coll. and DØ Coll., e-Print Archive</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page">9810015</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DESY-00-023, hep-ex/0002038 Study of High Mass e − -jet Systems in Electron-Proton Scattering at HERA &quot; , submission to Int</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Zeus</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Euro. Conf. on High Energy Physics 99</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Tampere, Finland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H1</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Euro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">447</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Opal</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Abbiendi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CERN-EP-99-091</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9908007</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Delphi</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Abreu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Phys. Lett. B446</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page">62</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Aleph</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Coll</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Barate</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">L3 Coll. (M. Acciarri et al.), Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">183</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>B433</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Abbiendi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eur. Phys. J. C6</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Abdullin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Charles</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Dion</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Marleau</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Simon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Eur</forename>
				<forename type="middle">O</forename>
				<surname>De Montigny</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Eboli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Funchal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lungov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. J. Phys. Rev. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="1715" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Eboli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Lungov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9911292</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Antoniadis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hagelin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Nanopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page">231</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
