<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Acceleration time scale in an ultrarelativistic shock</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2000-03-23">May 2000 Printed 23 January 2014 23 January 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Janusz</forename>
								<surname>Bednarz</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Obserwatorium Astronomiczne</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Uniwersytet Jagiello´ski</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>ul.Orla171</addrLine>
									<postCode>30-244</postCode>
									<settlement>Kraków</settlement>
									<country key="PL">Poland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Acceleration time scale in an ultrarelativistic shock</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">Mon. Not. R. Astron. Soc</title>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="volume">000</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="issue">0000</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="0" to="0"/>
							<date type="published" when="2000-03-23">May 2000 Printed 23 January 2014 23 January 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>(MN L A T E X style file v1.4)</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>acceleration of particles – shock waves – cosmic rays – gamma-rays: 
 bursts</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The acceleration mechanism at ultrarelativistic shocks is investigated using the Monte Carlo simulations. We apply a method of discrete small amplitude particle momentum scattering to reproduce highly anisotropic conditions at the shock and carefully describe the acceleration mechanism. The obtained acceleration times equal 1.0 r g /c if the spectral index reach the value of 2.2, independent of physical conditions in the shock. Some other parameters of the acceleration process are also provided.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>Observations carried out by the Burst and Transient Source Experiment show that GRBs originate from cosmological sources (Meegan et al. 1992 and Dermer 1992). Identification of the host galaxy for the GRB 971214 (Kulkarni et al. 1998) and several other bursts causes there is little doubt now that some, and most likely all GRBs are cosmological. These phenomena are surely related to ultrarelativistic shocks with the Lorentz factors γ &gt; 10 2 .</p>

				<p>Several papers suggested that ultrarelativistic shocks in GRBs could be sources of high energy cosmic rays (cf. Waxman 1995, Vietri 1995), and simulations done by Bednarz &amp; Ostrowski (1998) showed that such shocks are able to accelerate charged particles and values of their energy spectral indices converge to σ = 2.2 when γ → ∞ and/or magnetic turbulence amplitudes grow. Because the acceleration mechanism is quite different from that in the non-relativistic and mildly relativistic regime we distinguish a class of ultrarelativistic shocks if their Lorentz factors γ ≫ 1.</p>

				<p>Observations seem to confirm this mechanism. Waxman (1997) used a fireball model of GRBs and showed from the functional dependence of the flux on time and frequency that σ = 2.3 ± 0.1 in the afterglow of GRB 970228. Galama et al. (1998) made two independent measurements of the electron spectrum index in the afterglow of GRB 970508 which was very close to 2.2.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">ACCELERATION MECHANISM</head>

				<p>A particle crossing the shock to upstream medium has a momentum vector nearly parallel to the shock normal. Then the particle momentum changes its inclination in two ways by: 1) scattering in an inhomogeneous magnetic field and 2) smooth variation in a homogeneous field component. Hereafter , the mean deflection angle in these two cases will be denoted by ∆ΩS and ∆ΩH , respectively. The first process is a diffusive one and the second depends on time linearly. That means that with increasing shock velocity, keeping other parameters constant, ∆ΩS decreases slower as a square root of time in comparison with ∆ΩH . The Lorentz transformation shows that with γ ≫ 1 even a tiny angular deviation in the upstream plasma rest frame can lead to a large angular deviation in the downstream plasma rest frame. Let us denote a particle phase by φ and the angle between momentum and a magnetic field vector by θ both measured in the downstream plasma rest frame. Values of these parameters at the moment when a particle crosses the shock downstream determine if it is able to reach the shock again in the case of neglected magnetic field fluctuations downstream of the shock. In fact a motion in the homogeneous magnetic field carries a particle in such a way that it cannot reach the shock again. The magnetic field fluctuations upstream of the shock perturbing the momentum direction lead to broadening the (φ, θ) range that allows particles to reach the shock again. Thus, as we show below for efficient scattering, when ∆ΩH becomes unimportant in comparison to ∆ΩS, the spectral index and the acceleration time reach their asymptotic values. The discussed relation between ∆ΩH and ∆ΩS is reproduced in our simulations and presented in Fig. 1. There are shown 11 points from γ = 100 to 320 and three additional for γ = 640, 1280, 2560. The expected linear dependence of these quantities can be noticed.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">NUMERICAL SIMULATIONS</head>

				<p>In simulations we follow the procedure used by Bednarz &amp; Ostrowski (1996) with a hybrid approach used in Bednarz &amp; Ostrowski (1998). Monoenergetic seed particles are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 0000 RAS 0.0E+0 4.0E-5 8.0E-5 1.2E-4 ∆Ω 5 0.0E+0 4.0E-3 8.0E-3 1.2E-2 ∆Ω 0 ψ = 45° γ = 320, σ = 2.8 γ = 100, σ = 7.1 τ 7 = 4.31E-05 τ , = 0</trash>

					<head>Figure 1.</head>

					<figDesc>The relation between the mean deflection angle upstream of the shock caused by the scattering in an inhomogeneous magnetic field (∆Ω S ) and by smooth variation in a homogeneous magnetic field (∆Ω H ). Last three points for ∆Ω H below 1 ·</figDesc>
					<trash>10 −3 represent γ = 640, 1280, 2560 and yield σ = 2.5, 2.3 and 2.2 respectively. -2.5 -2.0 -1.5 -1.0 -0.5 log τ 7 2.1 2.2 2.3 2.4 2.5 σ ψ = 45° γ = 80 τ , = 0 Figure 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. Simulated spectral indices as a function of magnetic field fluctuations upstream of the shock. Fluctuations downstream of the shock are neglected. The chosen τ U value for γ = 80 and ψ = 45 • is pointed by a dashed line. A second-degree polynomial fit is also marked by a dashed line. jected at the shock and then their trajectories are derived in the perturbed magnetic field. The inhomogeneities are simulated by small amplitude particle momentum scattering within a cone with angular opening ∆ϑ less than the particle anisotropy ∼ 1/γ (cf. Ostrowski 1991). A particle is excluded from simulations if it escapes through the free-escape boundary placed far off the shock or reaches the energy larger than the assumed upper limit. These particles are replaced with the ones arising from splitting the remaining high-weight particles, preserving their physical parameters. Particles that exist longer than the time upper limit for simulations are excluded from simulations without replacing. All computations are performed in the respective upstream or downstream plasma rest frame. When particles cross the shock their parameters are transformed to the current plasma rest frame and the weighted contribution divided by the particle velocity component normal to the shock (≡ particle density) is added to the time and momentum bin depending on particle parameters, as measured in the shock normal rest frame. For the considered continuous injection after initial time, the energy cut-off of the formed spectrum shifts toward higher energies with time. The resulting spectra allows one to fit spectral indices and derive acceleration time in the shock normal rest frame in units of downstream rg/c ( rg -particle gyroradius in the homogeneous magnetic field component, c -speed of light; for details see Bednarz &amp; Ostrowski 1996). We transform the acceleration time tacc to the downstream plasma rest frame. Hereafter, subscripts U or D mean that a parameter is measured in the upstream or downstream plasma rest frame respectively. We will use downstream rg as a distance and rg/c as a time units. The magnetic field inclination to the shock normal upstream of the shock, ψ, is measured in the upstream plasma rest frame. Let us denote the ratio of the cross-field diffusion coefficient κ ⊥ to the parallel diffusion coefficient κ as τ (the value is measured in the plasma rest frame). Simulations prove that fluctuations upstream of the shock (measured by τ U ) and downstream of the shock (measured by τ D ) influence the acceleration process independently. The minimum fluctuations upstream of the shock needed to run the acceleration process efficiently tend to zero when γ → ∞. We checked by simulations with different τ D that its value does not influence the spectral index considerably for a given τ U .</p>

				<p>Our scattering model is very simple but also universal. In the model we are not able to discuss gyroresonat scattering . Upstream of the shock particles have not enough time to interact resonantly with low-frequency waves and the rough relation τ ∼ (δB/B) 4 (cf. Blandford &amp; Eichler 1987) cannot be deduce from the interaction there. However, for growing τ U and fixed ∆ϑ the time between scattering acts decreases what is equivalent to increasing the magnetic field fluctua- tions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">RESULTS</head>

				<p>In the following simulations we consider shocks with γ =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>20, 40, 80, 160, 320, magnetic field inclinations ψ = 15 • , 30 • , 45 • , 60 • , 75 • , 90 • and downstream values of magnetic field fluctuations τ D = 0, 1.0·10 −3 , 1.1·10 −2 , 0.11, 0.69.</trash>

					<figDesc>Thus, as a first case we consider downstream conditions without magnetic field fluctuations. By simple data inspection (cf. Fig. 2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>) we look for minimum τ U where the spectral index reaches its limit of 2.2 and we apply this value in further simulations. The relation between τ U , γ and ψ can be roughly fitted with the equation τ U = 0.25 γ −1.2 ψ in the considered range of shock parameters. We repeated simulations for a number of cases with different γ and ψ and τ D = 0. The obtained results are in good agreement with the ones derived from the above equation up to τ D = 0.11. Values of the acceleration time tacc for three amplitudes of magnetic field fluctuations downstream of the shock are presented in Fig. 3</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>. In the figure one can see the lack of change of tacc with ψ, but it slowly decreases to the asymptotic value with γ. In the simulations we have observed tendency of tacc to grow when σ increases up to 2.3-2.4 and no further change if magnetic field fluctuations upstream of the shock grow. For τ D ≤ 0.11 the asymptotic value of the ac- Acceleration time scale in an ultrarelativistic shock 3</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>celeration time is close to rg/c. It occurs that rg/c is a good unit provided that the homogeneous magnetic field dominates the randomly component. Unfortunately, when this condition fails the meaning of tacc becomes unclear in the simulations then. For this reason we will not discuss further the case of τ D = 0.69 any more.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Approximate calculations of Gallant &amp; Achterberg (1999) showed that t U U /t D U ≃ 1, where t</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>U U is the particle mean residence time upstream of the shock (upper index) as measured in the upstream plasma rest frame (lower index), and D in t D U stands for the downstream residence time. However, they were not able to consider the anisotropic particle momentum distribution and our results in Fig. 4 transformed to the upstream plasma rest frame with t U U /t D U within the range 0.01 − 0.1 are more adequate for real situations. Additionally , the above authors applied an extremely irregular magnetic field upstream of the shock represented by randomly oriented magnetic cells with field amplitude B and they measured time in the upstream unit of rg(B)/c. As a result they obtained that t U U /t D U could be much larger than 1 in the case. Just before the spectral index reaches its minimal value (cf. Fig. 2) ∆ΩS stabilizes near the limit which value does not further depend on the magnetic field inclination as is seen in Fig. 5. Momentum vectors of particles crossing downstream of the shock have similar distributions as measured in the downstream plasma rest frame if ∆ΩS approaches the maximum value. Then, it follows that parameters we consider below depend only on τ D .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>For growing τ D (τ D = 0, 1.0 · 10 −3 , 1.1 · 10 −2 , 0.11) ⋆ the acceleration</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>time is constant and accompanied by a slow increase of the mean energy gain in one cycle downstreamupstream-downstream ∆E/ED = 0.89, 0.94, 1.0, 1.1, and a slight decrease of the fraction of particles that reach the shock again after crossing it downstream ∆n/n = 0.51, 0.50, 0.48, 0.44. Simultaneously the mean time a particle spends downstream of the shock grows as t D D = 0.96, 1.0, 1.2, 1.35. Time that a particle spends upstream of the shock can be neglected in this rest frame as is visible in Fig. 4. It implies, approximately, tacc = t</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>D</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>D /∆E/ED if one neglects correlations between these quantities (cf. Bednarz &amp; Ostrowski 1996). Similarly we can roughly estimate the value of the energy spectral index of accelerated particles as σ ≃ 1 − ln(∆n/n)/ ln(∆E/ED + 1).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The simulated maximum distance in downstream medium the particle is able to depart from the shock and reach it again is, respectively, d M D = 0.84, 1.5, 2.5, 4.0 (the values were derived from ∼ 10 5 events). We calculated the average values of sin 2 θ for returning particles wandering downstream of the shock and found, respectively, sin 2 θ = 0.676, 0.658, 0.650, 0.651.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">DISCUSSION</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Because of newly found acceleration mechanism in ultrarelativistic shock waves we propose that some part of GRBs radiation could arise due to synchrotron radiation of electrons or electron pairs accelerated across the mechanism. ⋆ Below, we provide the respective series of simulated parameter for this sequence of τ D</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>0.4 0.6 0.8 ⊕ -15° × -30° ∆ -45° o -60° ¶ -75° ∇ -90° 1.0 1.5 t = ? ? [ r C / c ] 1.0 1.5 γ 20 40 80 160 320 τ , = 0 τ , = 0.11 τ , = 0.69 = &gt; ? Figure 3</formula></p>

				<p>. The simulated acceleration time as a function of the shock Lorentz factor: a) without fluctuations downstream of the shock, b) with fluctuations downstream of the shock, c) fluctuations downstream of the shock dominate homogeneous magnetic field. Results for a given upstream magnetic field inclinations, given in a panel a), are joined with dashed lines.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1E-7 1E-6 1E-5 1E-4 1E-3 J , 7 \ t , , γ &quot; &amp; $ ! ψ = 15°, 30°, 45°, 60°, 75°, 90° 15° 90° τ , = 0</trash>

					<head>Figure 4.</head>


				</figure>

				<p>The ratio of the mean time a particle spends upstream of the shock between shock crossings to the time it spends downstream of the shock as a function of the shock Lorentz factor. It slightly decreases with growing upstream magnetic field inclination . Dashed lines join points with a constant ψ. Apparent deviation of the point with γ = 320, ψ = 15 • is real.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c 0000 RAS, MNRAS 000, 000–000 1E-3 1E-2 1E-1 ∆Ω 5 γ &quot; &amp; $ ! ψ = 15°, 30°, 45°, 60°, 75°, 90° τ , = 0</trash>

					<head>Figure 5.</head>

					<figDesc>The mean deflection angle resulting from scattering in an inhomogeneous magnetic field upstream of the shock as a function of the shock Lorentz factor γ with τ U chosen in a way as illustrated in Fig. 2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Six dashed lines for different ψ are identical.</p>

				<p>We follow the internal shocks model of GRBs (cf. Kobayashi et al. 1997 for example). In the model two different shells have different Lorentz factors. The inner shell overtakes a slower outer shell and form a shock. The Lorentz factor of the shock as measured in the frame at rest with respect to the outer shell is assumed to be ∼ 2. With only a part of kinetic energy converted into the internal energy the particle energy distribution downstream of the shock will be nonthermal with, possibly, a substantial fraction of relativistic particles. As a result an amount of relativistic particles will be present in the shock. The particles can be accelerated across the mechanism presented in the paper and could be observed in the afterglow (cf. Waxman 1997, Galama et al. 1998).</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>We derived some parameters of the process that could be used in GRBs models. The acceleration time tacc = 1.0 rg/c, measured in the downstream plasma rest frame in the unit of particle gyroradius in the homogeneous magnetic field component divided by the speed of light is the second important parameter besides the spectral index σ = 2.2. The values of d M D and t</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>D D define the dimensions of the shock that allow the process to be effective, and the values of sin 2 θ shows how the synchrotron radiation can influence the pro- cess.</p>

				<p>In the ejecta of the relativistic matter in the GRB model the outer shells can be faster than the following ones. In this case separated shocks with Lorentz factors reaching γ ∼ 10 3 will be generated. The leading shock could produce seed protons with energies of 10 14 − 10 16 eV. These protons downstream of the first shock can interact with the following one to be reflected with energy gains ∼ γ 2 (cf. Gallant &amp; Achterberg 1999, Bednarz &amp; Ostrowski 1999). For a constant reflection probability the spectrum of these reflected highest energy particles, above 10 20 eV, will be only the shifted in energy spectrum of seed particles with the universal spectral index ∼ 2.2.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head>

				<p>The author is grateful to Micha l Ostrowski for valuable discussions and the referee for comments that was helpful in clarifying the contents of this paper. The presented computations were partly done on the HP Exemplar S2000 in ACK &apos;CYFRONET&apos; in Kraków .</p>

				<p>The present work was supported by Komitet Bada´aukowych through the grant PB 179/P03/96/11 and PB 258/P03/99/17.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">c 0000 RAS, MNRAS 000, 000–000</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bednarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ostrowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>MNRAS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">447</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bednarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ostrowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3911</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bednarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ostrowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MNRAS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">310</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">154 1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>MNRAS</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>L11. Blandford R., Eichler D.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Dermer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1799</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Galama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 500, L101 Gallant Y. A., Achterberg A., 1999, MNRAS</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Kobayashi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Piran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Sari</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Apj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">92</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Kulkarni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">393</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">35</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Meegan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">355</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">143</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Ostrowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>MNRAS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">551</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Vietri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>ApJ</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">883</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Waxman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">386</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Waxman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="000" to="000" />
			<pubPlace>ApJ, 485, L5 c 0000 RAS, MNRAS 000</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
