<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Test of CPT and Lorentz Invariance from Muonium Spectroscopy</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2001-06-29">29 Jun 2001</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">V</forename>
								<forename type="middle">W</forename>
								<surname>Hughes</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06520-8121</postCode>
									<settlement>New Haven</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Grosse Perdekamp</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06520-8121</postCode>
									<settlement>New Haven</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">D</forename>
								<surname>Kawall</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06520-8121</postCode>
									<settlement>New Haven</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">W</forename>
								<surname>Liu</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06520-8121</postCode>
									<settlement>New Haven</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">K</forename>
								<surname>Jungmann</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitätHeidelberg</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>PhysikalischesInstitut</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-69120</postCode>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">G</forename>
								<surname>Zu Putlitz</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitätHeidelberg</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>PhysikalischesInstitut</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-69120</postCode>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Test of CPT and Lorentz Invariance from Muonium Spectroscopy</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2001-06-29">29 Jun 2001</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>

				<p>Test of CPT and Lorentz Invariance from Muonium Spectroscopy V.W. Hughes, M. Grosse Perdekamp † , D. Kawall and W. Liu Yale University, Department of Physics, New Haven, CT 06520-8121, USA K. Jungmann and G. zu Putlitz Universität Heidelberg, Physikalisches Institut, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany</p>

				<p>Following a suggestion of Kosteleckét al. we have evaluated a test of CPT and Lorentz invariance from the microwave spectroscopy of muonium. Hamiltonian terms beyond the standard model violating CPT and Lorentz invariance would contribute frequency shifts δν12 and δν34 to ν12 and ν34, the two transitions involving muon spin flip, which were precisely measured in ground state muonium in a strong magnetic field of 1.7 T. The shifts would be indicated by anti-correlated oscillations in ν12 and ν34 at the earth&apos;s sidereal frequency. No time dependence was found in ν12 or ν34 at the level of 20 Hz, limiting the size of some CPT and Lorentz violating parameters at the level of 2 × 10 −23 GeV, representing Planck scale sensitivity and an order of magnitude improvement in sensitivity over previous limits for the muon.</p>

				<p><formula>11.30.Er, 11.30.Cp, 12.20.Fv, 36.10.Dr</formula></p>

				<p>Much current theoretical work is devoted to finding a more fundamental and general underlying theory from which the standard model of particle physics could be deduced as the low energy limit.</p>

				<p>String theory is a central candidate, with the feature that the assumptions underlying the CPT theorem are invalid for strings, which are extended objects. CPT violation then becomes a possible signature of more fundamental underlying theories, which can be probed by sensitive experimental tests of CPT invariance. Some years ago Kosteleckánd coworkers [1–3] developed a plausible extension of the standard model based on spontaneous breaking of Lorentz and CPT symmetry in an underlying theory without gravity. Their low energy effective theory provides a theoretical basis for establishing quantitative bounds on CPT invariance. The analysis was done in the context of conventional relativistic quantum mechanics and quantum field theory in four dimensions, retaining the usual gauge structure and renormalizability. The Lorentz and CPT violating additions to the standard model Lagrangian are highly suppressed to remain compatible with established experimental bounds. As applied to muonium (µ + e − bound state), the most relevant terms in the extension to the standard model are those in the QED limit, involving only muons, electrons and photons. The additional terms in the Lorentzviolating Lagrangian lead to a modified Dirac equation and are given by [2]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = −a l α ¯ ψ l γ α ψ l − b l α ¯ ψ l γ 5 γ α ψ l (1) − 1 2 H αβ ¯ ψ l σ αβ ψ l + 1 2 ic αβ ¯ ψ l γ α ↔ D β ψ l (2) + 1 2 id αβ ¯ ψ l γ 5 γ α ↔ D β ψ l . (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The lepton fields are denoted by l = e − , µ − , and iD α = i∂ α − qA α where q = −|e|. All terms are Lorentzviolating , while a and b are CPT odd, and H, c and d are CPT even. The lepton number violating terms allowed in the extension are not relevant here and have been omitted.</p>

				<p>To predict the perturbations to muonium, we consider the energy level diagram of the ground state of muonium in a magnetic field (Fig. 1). The transition frequencies ν 12 and ν 34 have been measured [4] with high precision and are used to determine the hyperfine structure interval ∆ν and the ratio µ µ /µ p of the muon magnetic moment to the proton magnetic moment. Leading-order Lorentz violating energy shifts δν 12 and δν 34 due to the new terms in the Lagrangian can be calculated using perturbation theory and relativistic twofermion techniques. For our observed transitions at the strong magnetic field of 1.7 T, dominantly only muon spin flip occurs so these energy shifts are characterized by the muon parameters alone of the extended theory. This approach results in :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δν 12 ≈ − δν 34 ≈ ˜ b µ 3 /π, (4) where b µ 3 ≡ b µ 3 + d µ 30 m µ + H µ 12 [5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are laboratory frame parameters. High precision experiments on muonium (M ) can measure or set limits on the parameters of these symmetry violating terms, which are sensitive at the Planck scale level [5]. Predictions of the values of ν 12 and ν 34 from standard theory -dominantly the QED terms -requires values for many atomic constants including m µ , µ µ , and ∆ν as well as the calculation of higher order QED radiative corrections . The relevant constants and calculations are not known to as high accuracy as the experimental determinations of ν 12 and ν 34 . Indeed several of these constants -∆ν and µ µ /µ p -are obtained from the muonium ex- periment.</p>

				<p>Comparing predictions for ν 12 and ν 34 (based on independent determinations of the required atomic constants) with the experimental results results in poor sensitivity to the non-standard model energy shifts δν 12 and δν 34 .</p>

				<p>However, the theory with CPT and Lorentz violation involves spatial components in a celestial frame of reference , and since the laboratory rotates with the earth, these spatial components vary with time, and consequently the experimentally observed ν 12 and ν 34 may oscillate about a mean value at the earth&apos;s sidereal frequency Ω = 2π/23 hr 56 m with amplitudes δν 12 and δν 34 . No such signal would be obtained from the standard model. In the non-rotating celestial frame of reference with equatorial axes X, ˆ Y , ˆ Z wherê Z is oriented along the earth&apos;s rotational North Pole, an experimental constraint on δν 12 implies [5]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 π |sinχ| b µ X 2 + ˜ b µ Y 2 ≤ δν 12 (5) in which χ ∼ 90</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>• is the angle between Z and the quantization axis defined by the laboratory magnetic field at Los Alamos where the muonium experiment was performed . The transformation from the lab frame quantity b µ 3 to the non-rotating celestial frame quantities b</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µ J (where J = X, Y, Z) is given by ˜ b µ 3 = ˜ b µ Z cos χ + ˜ b µ X cos Ωt + ˜ b µ Y sin Ωt sin χ. (6) The non-rotating frame quantities, ˜ b µ J are defined by b µ J ≡ b µ J + m µ d µ J0 + 1 2 ǫ JKL H µ KL [5]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The experiment has poor sensitivity to the celestial frame parameter b µ Z , but ideal sensitivity to the pair b µ X and b µ Y . The sum of the transition frequencies, ν 12 + ν 34 , is equal to the ground state hyperfine splitting, ∆ν, and since we expect (see Eqn.4) δν 12 + δν 34 ≈ 0, no sidereal variation is expected in the hyperfine interval. At the high field strengths of this experiment, the difference in transition frequencies ν 12 − ν 34 is almost proportional to the magnetic moment of the muon. By looking for a sidereal variation in the difference δν 12 − δν 34 ≈ 2 ˜ b µ 3 /π, we are essentially probing a possible sidereal variation of the magnetic moment of the muon (while the g factor remains constant). The accurate measurements of ν 12 and ν 34 were done in a microwave magnetic resonance experiment [4]. Muonium was formed by electron capture by muons stopping in a krypton gas target. Resonance lines were observed by varying the magnetic field with fixed microwave frequency and by varying the microwave frequency with fixed magnetic field.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>A line narrowing technique was used involving observation of a transition signal only from M atoms which have lived considerably longer than τ µ ∼ 2.2 µs (Fig. 2). The values reported for ν 12 and ν 34 at a magnetic field strength corresponding to a free proton precession frequency of 72.320 000 MHz were</figDesc>
					<trash>ν 12 (exp) = 1 897 539 800 (35) Hz (18 ppb), (7) ν 34 (exp) = 2 565 762 965 (43) Hz (17 ppb) (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>in which one standard deviation errors include both statistical and systematic errors. To search for a time dependence of ν 12 and ν 34 , we have employed the following algorithm. Data from each resonance line run (each lasting about half an hour) are fit at the measured magnetic field strength and Kr pressure to determine provisional line centers for ν 12 and ν 34 . These line centers were then transformed to their values in a magnetic field strength corresponding to a free proton precession frequency of 72.320 000 MHz. The data were taken at Kr pressures of 0.8 and 1.5 atm, so the line centers were corrected for a small quadratic pressure shift, and then were extrapolated linearly to their values at zero pressure, using a pressure shift coefficient determined from the data. Line centers for ν 12 and ν 34 obtained in this way were then grouped as a function of sidereal time, where time zero has been set as the time in 1995 when we obtained our first data. Non-zero values for δν 12 and δν 34 could arise from systematic effects which lead to variations in the parameters affecting the line centers -particularly variations having a period of ≈ 24 hr. Principal concerns are possible daynight variations of the magnetic field strength, and of the density and temperature of the Kr gas. Day-night variations of several • C in the temperature of the experimental hall lead to oscillations in the magnetic field strength of the persistent-mode superconducting solenoid of ≤ 1 ppm. Changes of 0.05 ppm in the field strength were easily resolved, and the oscillation&apos;s effects on the line centers were accounted for in extracting the line centers. Temperature changes also affected the diamagnetic shielding constant of the water in the NMR probes used to monitor the field (the probes were not temperature-stabilized, but were in good thermal contact with the microwave cavity which was temperaturestabilized to 0.1 • C). The maximum conceivable 2 • C</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>day-night changes in water temperature would change the NMR frequencies by 0.02 ppm, leading to errors in the line centers of about 2.5 Hz; of opposite sign for ν 12 and ν 34 . This potential effect is well below the statistical sensitivity for sidereal variations of 12 to 15 Hz. The effect on these data of the variation of Kr pressure with time has been evaluated. The front end window to the Kr stopping target was of 3 mil mylar, and flexed with day-night variations of the external atmospheric pressure. This induced fractional day-night oscillations in the Kr gas target pressure which were measured to be about 2.5 × 10 −4 . Through pressure shift coefficients of about -16.5 kHz/atm for ν 12 and -19.5 kHz/atm for ν 34 , the resulting shifts in the line centers (typically 7.5 Hz in ν 34 and 6 Hz in ν 12 ) were automatically accounted for in performing the linear extrapolation to zero pressure, and should not contribute any significant time variation to ν ij . The pressure shift coefficients depend on the average velocities of the atoms, and so are functions of temperature . The fractional changes in the transition frequencies with temperature (measured in hydrogen and its isotopes [6]) are roughly 1×10 −11 • C −1 Torr −1 . Given the temperature stability of the Kr gas of about 0.1 • C, temperature dependent errors in the extrapolation of the line centers to their vacuum values would be limited to a few Hz, well below the statistical sensitivity of our test. Other potential concerns involve the two frequency references used in the experiment -the proton precession frequency forming the basis of the magnetic field determination , and the Loran-C 10 MHz frequency reference used for the NMR and microwave frequency synthesizers . The Loran-C standard is based on hyperfine transitions in Cs with m F =0, and so is insensitive to any preferred spatial orientation, and would not introduce a signature for Lorentz violation into the spectroscopic measurements. Time dependent gravitational red or blue shifts of the frequency standard, caused by tidal distortions of the earth, are below the 10 −16 level and too small to be seen. Finally, bounds on clock comparisons of 199 Hg and 133 Cs [7,8] place limits on the Lorentz violating energy shifts in the precession frequency of a proton of 10 −27 GeV, which imply the NMR measurements are free of shifts well below the Hz level.</p>

				<p>All the data obtained in 1995 and 1996 are plotted as a function of time measured as a function of a sidereal day in Fig. 3, where twelve points at ≈ 2 hr. intervals are plotted, and the vertical scale is in Hz. The data for ν 12 and ν 34 were fit separately by the functions ν ij (t) = ν ij + δν ij sin (2πt + φ ij ) (9) where t is the time in sidereal days, and the fit parameters are ν ij , the amplitude of the possible time variation δν ij , and the phase φ ij (where no phase relation was assumed between ν 12 and ν 34 ). The amplitudes for δν 12 and δν 34 are consistent with zero, −4±13 Hz and −13±15 Hz respectively. As stated above, the theory being tested requires δν 12 ≈ − δν 34 . A plot of ν 12 − ν 34 versus sidereal time is shown in Figure 4, and fit for a sinusoidal variation (as in Eqn.9) where a common phase is assumed between ν 12 and ν 34 . The data exhibit no variation with time within ± 20 Hz, which corresponds to a 68% confidence level (one sigma) limit on the non-rotating frame components (see</p>

				<p><formula>Eqn. 4) ˜ b µ X 2 + ˜ b µ Y 2 ≤ 2 × 10 −23 GeV. (10)</formula></p>

				<p>The figure of merit of these results as a test of CPT violation is taken as</p>

				<p><formula>2 ˜ b µ X 2 + ˜ b µ Y 2 /m µ &lt; ∼ 2π | δν 12 | m µ ≈ 5 × 10 −22 . (11)</formula></p>

				<p>The limits on δν 34 and δ(ν 34 − ν 12 ) yield similar values. Other choices for the denominator in the figure of merit such as ν ij or ∆ν are inappropriate since the former are B field dependent, and the latter is not a fundamental property of the muon. It is natural to take the muon mass as the basic energy scale since it is an input parameter of the standard model from which the atomic properties are derivable. The ratio of Lorentz and CPT violating deviations of muonium energy levels to the muon mass might be expected to be suppressed by the ratio of the low-energy (standard model) scale to the Planck scale of the underlying theory [9]. In this context the result achieved here, 5 × 10 −22 , is comparable to the dimensionless scaling factor m µ /M P ∼ 10 −20 . Bounds on a different linear combination of the muon parameters b µ J , d µ J0 , and H µ KL than from muonium can also be obtained from precision measurements of the anomalous magnetic moment of the muon a µ = (g µ −2)/2 [5], where one can search for sidereal variations of the anomalous precession frequency ω µ a (the difference between spin and cyclotron frequencies). Also, the parameter b µ Z , which is not tested in the latest muonium experiment , is bound at the level of 10 −22 GeV by the measurements of the anomalous precession frequencies ω µ a of µ + and µ − measured at CERN and BNL [5,10]. Further improvements in the Lorentz and CPT violating parameters for the muon, coming from muonium, will require higher intensity muon sources, as the uncertainties are predominantly statistical.</p>

				<p>In conclusion, no unambiguous violation of CPT or Lorentz invariance has been observed although tests have been done on many systems since 1960 [11]. The results presented here represent Planck scale sensitivity, and are an order of magnitude improvement in sensitivity over previous limits on the muon parameters of the theory. They also represent the first test for sidereal variations in the 2nd generation of leptons, where Lorentz and CPT violating effects may be enhanced [5]. Higher sensitivity tests as well as tests on different physical systems will surely be made [3,12].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>We thank V.A. Kosteleck´or helpful discussions, and the U.S. DOE and BMBF (Germany) for supporting this research. †</figDesc>
					<trash>Current Address : Riken-BNL Research Center, Upton, NY 11973, USA [ 1 ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>V. A . Kosteleckánd R FIG. 1 . Breit - Rabi energy level diagram of ground state muonium . At high fields , the indicated transitions , ν12 and ν34 are essentially muon spin flip transitions .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 20 40 3 . 09¡4 . 04µs Signal ( % ) 200 300 400 0 25 50 6 . 89¡7 . 84µs ν p - 72000 ( kHz ) 0 10 20 30 3 . 12¡4 . 07µs 400 500 600 700 0 10 20 6 . 92¡7 . 87µs ν - 1897000 ( kHz ) FIG . 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. Muonium resonance lines ( data and fit ) for ν12 taken using magnetic field sweep on the left , and microwave frequency sweep on the right , for muonium atoms which have decayed in selected time intervals after formation . FIG . 3 . Two years of data on ν12 and ν34 are shown binned versus sidereal time and fit for a possible sinusoidal variation . The amplitudes are consistent with zero . FIG . 4 . Two years of data on ν12 - ν34 and ν12 + ν34 = ∆ν are shown binned versus sidereal time and fit for a possible sinusoidal variation . The amplitudes are consistent with zero .</p>

		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A R</forename>
				<surname>Kosteleck´kostelecká</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Potting</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">359</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Colladay</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Kosteleck´ . Rev. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">116002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CPT and Lorentz Symmetry</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">711</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Bluhm</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Kosteleck´kostelecká</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Lane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1098</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Morgan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Ensberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1494</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Kosteleck´kostelecká</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Lane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">116010</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Prestage</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2387" to="1879" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Bluhm</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A N</forename>
				<surname>Kosteleck´kostelecká</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Russell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1432</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Brown</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Nucl. Phys</title>
		<editor>J. Bailey et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">150</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2227" to="1" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Hughes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Robinson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Beltran-Lopez</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>R.W.P. Drever</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="683" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Coleman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">116008</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
