<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Non-Linear / Non-Commutative Non-Abelian Monopoles</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2001-07-26">26 Jul 2001</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Koji</forename>
								<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>93106-4030</postCode>
									<settlement>Santa Barbara</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Non-Linear / Non-Commutative Non-Abelian Monopoles</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2001-07-26">26 Jul 2001</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Using recently proposed non-linearly realized supersymmetry in non-Abelian gauge theory corrected to O(α ′ 2), we derive the non-linear BPS equations in the background B-field for the U(2) monopoles and instantons. We show that these non-Abelian non-linear BPS equations coincide with the non-commutative anti-self-dual equations via the Seiberg-Witten map. * koji@itp.ucsb.edu</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>It has been known that there are α ′ corrections to the super Yang-Mills theory as a low energy effective action of superstring theories [1][2]. The low energy effective theories have been a very strong tool for analyzing the full string theory to find dualities and nonperturbative properties. However, the entire structure of the α ′ corrections is still beyond our reach, although much elaborated work has been devoted to this subject [3]–[19]. To be concrete, a stack of parallel Dp-branes has a low energy effective description which is the p+1-dimensional super Yang-Mills theory accompanied with the α ′ corrections, but even in the slowly-varying field approximation the complete form of the effective action has not been obtained yet. To fix this problem, recently there appeared several attempts to constrain the action by supersymmetries [17], or the equivalence [20] to non-commutative theories [10][11]. Especially the paper [17] fixed all the ambiguity of the ordering and coefficients up to O(α ′ 2 ).</p>

				<p>In this paper, we give an evidence supporting both of these arguments of supersymmetries and non-commutative geometries, by analyzing the BPS equations. Solitons and instantons as solutions of the BPS equations in the low energy effective theory of D-branes have brane interpretations. For example, a BPS monopole in U(2) Yang-Mills-Higgs theory corresponds to a D-string suspended between two parallel D3-branes. We consider these brane configurations in the background B-field, and explicitly construct U(2) non-linear BPS equations for the monopoles and the instantons. For the construction we need an explicit form of the linearly/non-linearly realized supersymmetry transformations in the effective theory which was obtained in [3] and [17]. According to the equivalence observed in [20], these equations should be equivalent with the U(2) non-commutative BPS equations [21]–[26].</p>

				<p>In this paper we shall explicitly show this equivalence * . This fact is a supporting evidence of the supersymmetry transformation in the effective action determined in [17]. Then we shall proceed to obtain the explicit solutions to these equations and discuss the brane interpretation of them.</p>

				<p>The low energy effective action of open superstring theory with U(N) Chan-Paton factor is given by the super Yang-Mills action corrected by α ′ [1][2]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = str − 1 4 (F ij ) 2 + 1 2 π 2 α ′2 F ij F jk F kl F li − 1 4 (F ij ) 2 (F kl ) 2 + (fermions) + O(α ′ 3 ). (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The recent argument [17][18] on the ordering of the gauge fields and the fermions shows that up to the order of α ′ 2 all the terms can be arranged by the symmetrized trace (str), which is compatible with the string scattering amplitudes and also the supersymmetries. We use the action in the Euclidean four-dimensional space to treat the anti-self-duality equation for both the monopoles and instantons simultaneously. This action is obtained via dimensional reduction with A µ = 0 (µ = 0, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9). The normalization for the gauge symmetry generators is given by tr[T A T B ] = δ AB , which follows the convention of [18].</p>

				<p>The action (1) has a linearly realized supersymmetry for the gaugino [3]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δ ǫ χ A = 1 2 Γ ij F A ij ǫ − 1 8 π 2 α ′ 2 str(T A T B T C T D ) F B ij F C ji F D kl Γ kl − 4F B ij F C jk F D kl Γ il ǫ, (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which includes the α ′ corrections to the first nontrivial order. The recent paper [17] shows that this system has another supersymmetry, non-linearly realized supersymmetry, as is expected from the fact that the action (1) describes a stuck of N D-branes which breaks half of the bulk supersymmetries. This non-linearly realized supersymmetry is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δ η χ A = η A − 1 2 π 2 (α ′ ) 2 str(T A T B T C T D ) 1 2 F B ij F C ij + 1 4 F B ij F C kl Γ ijkl η D , (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the transformation parameter η has its value only for a U(1) subgroup of U(N) [17]. We have already neglected the fermions in the right hand sides of (2) and (3).</p>

				<p>In order to compare our results with the previous literatures [23]–[25][27] we will consider only the gauge group U(2). The normalized generators are defined as T a =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 √ 2 σ a for a = 1, 2, 3 and T 4 = 1 √ 2 . Therefore especially the symmetrized trace of the four generators appearing in the above supersymmetry transformations (2) and (3) is given by str(T A T A T A T A ) = str(T a T a T 4 T 4 ) = 1 2 , str(T a T a T b T b ) = 1 6 (a = b), (4) where the upper case A runs all the generators of U(2): A = 1, 2, 3, 4. We turn on the background B-field which induces the non-commutativity on the worldvolume of the D-branes. This B-field is appearing in the action (1) as F 4 ij → F 4 ij = F 4 ij +2B ij , due</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>to the bulk gauge invariance of the B-field.</p>

				<p>For simplicity, we put πα ′ = 1, which can be restored on the dimensional ground anytime.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The action (1) and its symmetries (2) (3) are obtained in string theory in the approximation F ≪ 1 and the slowly-varying field approximation. We keep this in mind, and in the following we shall obtain the non-linearly-modified BPS equations, perturbatively in small B. The basic BPS equations around whose solutions we expand the fields are the anti-self-duality equations F (0)a ij + * F (0)a ij = 0, F (0)4 ij = 0, (5) where we have expanded the fields as F A ij = F (0)A ij + O(B),</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the Hodge * is defined as * F ij ≡ ǫ ijkl F kl /2. These equations are obtained by considering the lowest order in α ′ in (2) by requiring a half of the linearly-realized supersymmetries are preserved. The transformation parameters of the preserved supersymemtries then obey the chirality condition</p>

				<p><formula>(1 + Γ 5 )ǫ = 0 (6) where Γ 5 = Γ 1234 .</formula></p>

				<p>In the following, we assume that this chirality condition for ǫ persists also to the higher order in α ′ and even with the inclusion of B. This assumption will be checked by the explicit existence of the solutions.</p>

				<p>Along the argument given in [20][27]–[31], first we consider a combination of the two supersymmetries (2) and (3) which remains unbroken at the spatial infinity where F = 0.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The vanishing of F gives δ ǫ χ A = B ij Γ ij ǫ + O(B 3 ), δ η χ 4 = η 4 + O(B 2 ). (7) Thus (δ ǫ + δ η )χ 4 = 0 at the infinity is equivalent with η 4 = −B ij Γ ij ǫ + O(B 3 ). (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Using this relation between two supersymmetry transformations, the vanishing of the supersymmetry transform of the gaugino in all the four-dimensional space leads to BPS conditions</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 F a ij Γ ij ǫ = 0, (9) 1 2 F 4 ij Γ ij ǫ − B ij Γ ij ǫ − 1 4 str(T 4 T B T C T 4 ) 1 2 F B ij F C ij + 1 4 F B ij F C kl Γ ijkl B ij Γ ij ǫ − 1 8 str(T 4 T B T C T D ) F B ij F C ji F D kl Γ kl − 4F B ij F C jk F D kl Γ il ǫ = 0. (10)</trash>

					<figDesc>The first one (9) gives usual anti-self-duality equation † without any correction of B. In the analysis up to this order, only the U(1) part of the gauge field obtains the first nontrivial correction of B as F</figDesc>

				</figure>

			<div>
				<head>4</head>

				<p>ij = O(B). Let us calculate the third and the fourth terms in (10).</p>

				<p>Keeping in mind that we neglect the terms of the higher order, the third term can be arranged as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− 1 4 (F (0)B ij ) 2 B kl Γ kl ǫ + O(B 2 ), (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have used the anti-self-duality of F (5) and the chirality of ǫ (6). After a straightforward calculation, the fourth term in (10) can be evaluated in the same manner and turns out to be the same as (11) ‡ . The term (F (0) ) 3 is negligible because it is of the higher order.</p>

				<p>These evaluation simplifies the BPS condition (10) to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F 4 ij Γ ij ǫ − (F (0)A kl ) 2 B ij Γ ij ǫ = 0. (12) † The α ′</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>corrections in the linearly-realized transformation (2) are actually factored-out when the lowest order relations (5) are substituted. ‡ These calculations are easily performed with the use of the block-diagonal form of the matrix B which is obtained by the space rotation without losing generality.</p>

				<p>Decomposing this condition into the components, we obtain the non-linear BPS equations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F 4 ij + * F 4 ij − π 2 α ′ 2 (B ij + * B ij )(F (0)A kl ) 2 = 0, (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have restored the dimensionality.</p>

				<p>The important is to check whether the equations (13) are equivalent with the noncommutative BPS equations via the Seiberg-Witten map [20]. The non-commutative U(2) monopoles/instantons [21]–[26] satisfy the following BPS equations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ˆ F A ij + * ˆ F A kl = 0, (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where fields with the hat indicate the ones in the non-commutative space. Substituting the Seiberg-Witten map [20]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ˆ F ij = F ij + 1 2 θ kl 2{F ik , F jk } − {A k , (D l + ∂ l )F ij } + O(θ 2 ) (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>into the above non-commutative BPS equation (14) and noting that the last gauge-variant terms in (15) vanish with the use of the lowest level anti-self-duality (5), then we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F 4 ij + * F 4 ij + 1 4 (θ ij + * θ ij )(F (0) kl ) 2 = 0. (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Now we can use the relation [20, 27] θ ij = −(2πα ′ ) 2 B ij (17) which has been deduced from the worldsheet propagator for an open string in the approximation α ′ B ≪ 1, then we can see the equivalence between the non-commutative BPS equations (14) and the non-linear BPS equations (13).</p>

				<p>Let us consider the specific brane configurations. (1) U(2) non-commutative monopole. In this case we perform the dimensional reduction further down to the three-dimensional space and regard the fourth gauge field A 4 as a scalar field Φ. We turn on only one component of the B-field, B 12 = 0. Since we have a solution to the U(2) non-commutative BPS equation for a monopole [23][24][26], and we know the Seiberg-Witten transform of that solution to an appropreate order in α ′ [27], then from the above equivalence, that transform is actually a corresponding solution to the non-linear BPS equation (13). After diagonalization of the scalar field, the eigenvalues exhibits the configuration in which the single D-string suspended between the two parallel D3-branes is tilted [21] so that they preserve 1/4 supersymmetries in the bulk with the B-field, as shown in [27]. (2) U(2) instanton. It is known that the small instanton singularity of the anti-self-dual instanton moduli space is resolved if we introduce self-dual background θ [20, 32]. However, this resolution does not occur in the case of anti-self-dual θ. This fact may be observed from the non-linear BPS equations and their solutions. First let us analyze the anti-self-dual B-field (note the relation (17)) B 12 + B 34 = 0. Since the equation B ij Γ ij ǫ = 0 (18) holds for ǫ which is involved with the preserved supersymmetries for the anti-self-dual gauge field configuration, the whole η terms vanish. Thus the linear BPS equation is not corrected, and so the configuration is not affected by the B-field:</p>

				<p><formula>F + * F = 0. (19)</formula></p>

				<p>This is consistent with the observation that the linear BPS equation F + * F = 0 may solve fully α ′ -corrected non-Abelian effective theory, as it is true in the case of Abelian theory [33].</p>

				<p>Since now the self-duality is the same as the B-field orientation, we can subtract the B-field from the both sides of the above equation and then obtain (19). This result may be related to the observation in [34] that for the large instanton radius the commutative description of the non-commutative U(2) instanton [25] does not seem to have θ dependence § . From the non-commutative side, we substitute the Seiberg-Witten map to the non-commutative BPS equation (14), but then the order θ terms cancel with each other and we found the usual anti-self-dual equation (19).</p>

				<p>On the other hand, for the self-dual B-field background B 12 = B 34 , there exists a correction , which is expected from the resolution of the small instanton singularity. One can solve the non-linear BPS equation (13) using the general ansatz [20] in this background</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A 4 i = B ij x j h(r) (20) for a radial function h(r). Substituting the lowest order solution F (0)a ij = 4ρ 2 (r 2 + ρ 2 ) 2 η aij , (21) we obtain a differential equation for h(r) and the solution is h(r) = 16π 2 ρ 4 (3r 2 + ρ 2 ) r 4 (r 2 + ρ 2 ) 3 . (22) § For the</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>small value of ρ the gauge fields is not slowly-varying, the D-instanton charge distribution is corrected due to the derivative corrections to the Wess-Zumino term [35], thus we may not see any relation with [34].</p>

				<p>This is the first nontrivial correction to the anti-self-dual instanton. Since in this case the small instanton singularity must be resolved, we might be able to see it by computing the instanton charge distribution with this correction, but it turns out to be very small as ∼ B 2 ρ 8 /r 16 compared to the original instanton density ∼ ρ 4 /r 8 . Therefore unfortunately we cannot see the change of the instanton radius caused by the introduction of the B-field.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* koji@itp.ucsb.edu</note>

			<note place="foot">* In the Abelian case, this equivalence was shown in [27].</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>Acknowledgments: The author would like to thank T. Hirayama and W. Taylor for useful comments. This research was supported in part by Japan Society for the Promotion of Science under the Postdoctoral Research Program (# 02482), and the National Science Foundation under Grant No. PHY99-07949.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Superstring Modification of Einstein Equations</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Gross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">277</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vector Field Effective Action in the Open Superstring Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Tseytlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. Erratum – ibid</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">276</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">879</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">291</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Higher Derivative Super Yang-Mills theo- ries</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Bergshoeff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Rakowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Sezgin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effective Lagrangian for Open Superstring from Five Point Function</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Kitazawa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="599" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On non-abelian generalization of Born-Infeld action in string theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Tseytlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">501</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9701125</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fluctuation Spectra of Tilted and Intersecting D- branes from the Born-Infeld Action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Taylor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Iv</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">503</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">193</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9703217</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supersymmetric Non-Abelian Born- Infeld Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Gonorazky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Schaposnik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Silva</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">449</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">187</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9812094</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-Abelian Born-Infeld versus String Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Denef</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sevrin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Troost</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">581</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">N = 1 and N = 2 supersymmetric non-abelian Born-Infeld actions from superspace</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Ketov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">207</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="491" to="0005265" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the General Structure of the Non-Abelian Born-Infeld Action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Cornalba</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0006018</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Non-Abelian Born-Infeld Action and Noncommutative gauge the- ory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Terashima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0007</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">033</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0006058</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non abelian N=2 supersymmetric Born Infeld action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Refolli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Terzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Zanon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">486</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">337</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0006067</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Non-abelian Born-Infeld and kappa- symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bergshoeff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>De Roo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sevrin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="11018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The non-abelian Born-Infeld action at order F 6</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sevrin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Troost</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Troost</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">603</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">389</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0101192</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The structure of maximally supersym- metric Yang-Mills theory: constraining higher-order corrections</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Cederwall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E W</forename>
				<surname>Nilsson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Tsimpis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">034</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">F 5 contributions to the non- abelian Born Infeld action from a supersymmetric Yang-Mills five-point function</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Refolli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Santambrogio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Terzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Zanon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0105277</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">D = 10 Super-Yang-Mills at O(α ′2 )</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Cederwall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E W</forename>
				<surname>Nilsson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Tsimpis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0104236</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supersymmetric non-abelian Born-Infeld revisited</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bergshoeff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bilal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>De Roo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sevrin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0105274</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Higher-Derivative Corrections to the Non-Abelian Born-Infeld Action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0106062</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">String theory and noncommutative geometry</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Seiberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9909</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">032</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9908142</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Monopoles and Dyons in Non-Commutative Geom- etry</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9911</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">005</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9909202</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deformed Nahm Equation and a Noncommutative BPS Monopole</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Bak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="471" to="9910135" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brane Configuration from Monopole Solution in Non-Commutative Super Yang-Mills Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Hata</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moriyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9912</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">021</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9910196</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noncommutative Monopole at the Second Order in θ</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Goto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Hata</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">085022</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0005101</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dp-D(p+4) in Noncommutative Yang-Mills</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Furuuchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">033</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0010119</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solitons in Noncommutative Gauge Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Gross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Nekrasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">044</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Branes and BPS Configurations of Non-Commutative /Commutative Gauge Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Hirayama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">587</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">207</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear Instantons from Supersymmetric p-Branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Marino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Minasian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0001</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">005</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9911206</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instantons in the U(1) Born-Infeld Theory and Noncommutative Gauge Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Terashima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">477</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">292</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9911245</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noncommutative Monopole from Nonlinear Monopole</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moriyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">485</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">278</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0003231</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noncommutative/Nonlinear BPS Equations without Zero Slope Limit</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moriyama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0008</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">014</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0006056</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instantons on noncommutative R 4 , and (2,0) superconfor- mal six dimensional theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Nekrasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Schwarz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">198</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">689</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Born-Infeld String as a Boundary Conformal Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Thorlacius</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1588</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9710181</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Seiberg-Witten Transforms of Noncommutative Soli- tons &quot; , hep-th/0105311, to be published in Phys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Ooguri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. D</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Derivative corrections to D-brane actions with constant background fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Wyllard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">598</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">247</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
