<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Neutrino oscillations and Big Bang Nucleosynthesis ⋆</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2001-08-15">15 Aug 2001</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Nicole</forename>
								<forename type="middle">F</forename>
								<surname>Bell</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Research Centre for High Energy Physics</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>3010</postCode>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Neutrino oscillations and Big Bang Nucleosynthesis ⋆</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2001-08-15">15 Aug 2001</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We outline how relic neutrino asymmetries may be generated in the early universe via active-sterile neutrino oscillations. We discuss possible consequences for big bang nucleosynthesis, within the context of a particular 4-neutrino model.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The implications of neutrino masses in cosmology and astrophysics are numerous . One fascinating effect, is that of relic neutrino asymmetries, which may be produced if there is mixing between active and sterile neutrino species [1].</p>

				<p>Neutrino asymmetries are interesting since they affect big bang nucleosynthesis (BBN), altering the primordial helium yield. BBN is particularly sensitive to an asymmetry between the ν e and ν e . Additionally, since the matter potential arising from forward scattering is proportional to the asymmetry, a large asymmetry will suppress active-sterile oscillation modes which could otherwise equilibrate sterile neutrino species around the time of BBN. ⋆ Invited talk at the NUFACT&apos;01 workshop in Tsukuba, Japan 24-30 May 2001. Email address: n.bell@physics.unimelb.edu.au (Nicole F. Bell).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Preprint submitted to Elsevier Science 7 February 2008</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>First consider two-flavour mixing between an active neutrino, ν α , and a sterile neutrino, ν s . For each neutrino flavour we define an asymmetry</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L α = n να − n ¯ να n γ , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where n ν and n γ are the neutrino and photon number densities, respectively. The neutrino momentum distributions, N(p), are such that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n = N(p)dp, (2) and in thermal equilibrium are just given by Fermi-Dirac distributions N eq (p) = 1 2π 2 p 2 1 + exp p T + ˜ µ . (3) Here T is the temperature and µ ≡ µ/T , with µ being the neutrino chemical potential. In equilibrium, L α is related to µ as per L α ≃ − 1 24ζ(3) π 2 (˜ µ ν − ˜ µ ¯ ν ) − 6(˜ µ 2 ν − ˜ µ 2 ¯ ν ) ln 2 + (˜ µ 3 ν − ˜ µ 3 ¯ ν ) . (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We wish to track L α as the universe evolves, with the period of interest being the epoch between T ∼ 100MeV and T ∼ 1MeV. The evolution of the neutrino ensemble will be controlled by (i) oscillations, (ii) collisions of the neutrinos with other particles, resulting in decoherence of the oscillations, and (iii) the expansion of the universe, which redshifts energies and momenta.</p>

				<p>The matter affected mixing angle, θ m ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>is sin 2 2θ m = sin 2 2θ 0 sin 2 2θ 0 + (b ± a − cos 2θ 0 ) 2 , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where θ 0 is the mixing angle in vacuum. The term (b ± a) arises from the effective matter potential V = (b ± a)δm 2 /2p, where -/+ corresponds to ν/¯ ν and δm 2 is the mass squared difference of the two neutrino mass eigenstates. The functions a and b are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a(p) = − 4 √ 2ζ(3)G F T 3 L (α) p π 2 δm 2 , b(p) = − 4 √ 2ζ(3)G F T 4 A α p 2 π 2 δm 2 M 2 W , (6) where A e (A τ,µ ) ≃ 17(4.9) [2]. The function L (α) is defined as L (α) = L α + L τ + L µ + L e + η, (7) where η ∼ 10</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>−10 is due to the baryon asymmetry. Note that the mixing angle is dependent on the size of the asymmetry, which makes the evolution of the asymmetry non-linear.</p>

				<p>There are two distinct phases in the growth of a neutrino asymmetry. The first is a collision dominated stage, which occurs at high temperature. The total collision rate of a ν e (ν µ or ν τ ) of momentum p with particles in the background plasma is approximately</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ(p) ≃ 4.0(2.9) p 3.15T T 5 . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These collisions tend to destroy the coherent superposition of flavour states.</p>

				<p>In this regime, it can be shown that the growth of the neutrino asymmetry is governed by the equation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dL α dt ≃ π 2 2ζ(3)T 3 dp N + α − N + s s 2 Γa(c − b) [x + (c − b + a) 2 ][x + (c − b − a) 2 ] , (9) where c ≡ cos 2θ 0 , s ≡ sin 2θ 0 , x ≡ pΓ(p) ∆m 2 2 , N + = 1 2 (N ν + N ν ). (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Eq.(9) can be derived either from a heuristic picture [1] that views collisions as measurement-like interactions, or can be extracted from the exact Quantum Kinetic Equations [3]. It is valid when the collision rate is large and the evolution is adiabatic -see [3] for details.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Note that dL α /dt ∝ a ∝ L</head>

					<figDesc>(α) , which can lead to runaway positive feedback and thus rapid growth of L α . The mixing parameters for which this occurs are specified by |δm 2 |</figDesc>
					<trash>&gt; ∼ 10 −4 eV 2 and sin 2 2θ 0 &gt; ∼ 10 −10 , and</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>we require lighter of the two mass eigenstates to approximately coincide with the ν s . Typically, the asymmetry will reach values L α ∼ O(10 −5 ) in this phase. Note that the sign of the asymmetry, which depends on the initial conditions, can be ambiguous [6].</p>

				<p>The second phase is that lower temperature. Here the collisions are less important , and coherent MSW transitions drive the asymmetry to values L α ∼ O(0.1) [7]. 1 If, for example, the asymmetry is positive, the neutrino MSW resonance occurs at a much higher momentum value than that of the antineutrinos and may be neglected. The rate at which the asymmetry grows is then</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dL να dT = −X d dT p res T , (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where X is the difference between the number of ¯ ν α and ¯ ν s at the resonance. Eq.(11) quantifies the rate at which the resonance moves through the momentum distribution, and holds when transitions are adiabatic and the resonance width is small.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Big bang nucleosynthesis and a four neutrino model</head>

				<p>We wish to determine the impact of such asymmetry production on the BBN light element abundances, and in particular, on the helium yield. In general, the results are somewhat model dependent (compare, say, [7] with [8].)</p>

				<p>The results are particularly sensitive to the size of the ν e asymmetry, which directly affects the neutron/proton ratio through the reaction rates λ(n → p) ≃ λ(nν e → pe − ) + λ(ne + → p¯ ν e ), λ(p → n) ≃ λ(pe − → nν e ) + λ(p¯ ν e → ne + ). (12)</p>

				<p>The n/p ratio determines the helium mass fraction Y P via the equation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dY P dt = −λ(n → p)Y P + λ(p → n)(2 − Y P ). (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For typical values of δm 2 , one must compute the growth of the asymmetry and the effect on BBN simultaneously, as the asymmetries will not have reached their final values before the BBN epoch commences.</p>

				<p>Momentum modes which are depleted due to the oscillations, are refilled by scattering and annihilation processes as per</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d dt N actual N 0 = Γ(p) N eq N 0 − N actual N 0 , (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where N eq is the equilibrium distribution in Eq.(3), and N 0 ≡ N eq | ˜ µ=0 .</p>

				<p>The example we consider is a particular &quot; 2+2 &quot; style 4-neutrino model, consisting of a maximally mixed ν µ − ν τ pair, separated by a mass gap from ν e − ν s .</p>

				<p>The oscillations modes most important in the evolution of the various flavour neutrino asymmetries will be the ones with the largest δm 2 . Specifically, the ν µ,τ − ν s oscillation modes will create large L µ and L τ asymmetries, and the ν µ,τ − ν e oscillation modes will transfer a small amount of this asymmetry to the electron neutrinos. See [8] for further details.</p>

				<p>Numerically integrating the appropriate generalisations of eq.(11), we find that the magnitude of the final lepton asymmetries generated are |L µ |/h = |L τ |/h ≃ 0.16,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|L e |/h ≃ 6.7 × 10 −3 , (15) for δm 2 &gt; ∼ 4eV, where h = T 3 ν /T 3 γ .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Integrating the BBN reaction rates, eq. (12), the direct effect of the ν e asymmetry on the n/p ratio, and hence Y P , is determined. We obtain δY P ≃ ±0.0023, corresponding to an effective change in the number of neutrinos of δN ef f ν ≃ ±0.19. In addition, there is a small direct change to the energy density, leading overall to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δN eff ν ≃ −0.3, positive asymmetry, δN eff ν ≃ +0.1, negative asymmetry, (16) for δm 2 &gt; ∼ 3eV 2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The value of N eff ν obtained in this way must then be compared with that calculated from the observed light abundances [9]. It is not yet clear whether the observed helium and deuterium abundances can be accommodated within the standard BBN scenario with N eff ν = 3, and it is possible that a small ν e asymmetry such as that discussed here would help to provide a better fit [10].</p>

				<p>Recent measurement of the cosmic microwave background radiation (CMBR) anisotropy also provides a determination of the number of neutrinos in the early universe [11], although the constraints are, as yet, not as strong as those arising from BBN. 2 However, future measurements are expected to pin down 2 Note, however, that the effective number of neutrinos extracted from the CMBR the effective neutrino number very precisely [12] and thus will be of great use in constraining models which feature the mixing of active and sterile neutrinos.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Ref.[4] disputed the production of large asymmetries. However, this issue has been resolved, with [4] shown to be in error due to the use of an approximation outside its region of validity [5].</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Foot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Thomson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Volkas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5349</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Notzold</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Raffelt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">307</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">924</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Bell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Volkas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y Y</forename>
				<surname>Wong</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Phys. Rev. Phys. Rev</title>
		<editor>R. R. Volkas and Y. Y. Y. Wong K. S. M. Lee, R. R. Volkas and Y. Y. Y. Wong</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113001" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Dolgov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Hansen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pastor</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Semikoz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astropart. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">79</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">See also R</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Di</forename>
				<surname>Bari</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astropart. Phys. Phys. Rev</title>
		<editor>A. D. Dolgov</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="017302" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Di</forename>
				<surname>Bari</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Foot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105012</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Foot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Volkas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6653</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Bell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Foot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Volkas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="105010" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">astro-ph/0105397. [10] For a recent analysis of BBN and CMBR constraints on neutrino degeneracy, see</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>For A</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Review</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Bbn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cyburt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hannestad</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="105220" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hannestad</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Raffelt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">043001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">and BBN data are not necessarily the same parameter. The two determinations are complementary, since the BBN quantity depends on flavour through its sensitivity to the ν e asymmetry, while the CMBR measures the total energy density residing in neutrinos</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>at. a much later epoch of the universe</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
