<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">On Relation between Two Models of Gauge Field Localization on a Brane</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2001-08-29">29 Aug 2001</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Motoi</forename>
								<surname>Tachibana</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail:motoi@lns.mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Center for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">JSPS Research Fellow on leave from Yukawa Institute for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>606-8502</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">On Relation between Two Models of Gauge Field Localization on a Brane</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2001-08-29">29 Aug 2001</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/0108164v2 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We discuss the relation between two different models which are recently proposed as the model of localizing bulk gauge fields on a brane. In the former model, the localization of gauge field is achieved by adding both bulk and boundary mass terms while in the latter, it is done by taking into consideration the coupling between the gauge field and the dilaton field (this model is also regarded as the gauge theory with nontrivial dielectric &quot; constant &quot;). We make a certain transformation for the gauge field in the latter Lagrangian. As the result, we find those two models are closely related to each other.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Since</head>

				<p>Randall and Sundrum proposed a new solution to the hierarchy problem[1, 2], theories with (infinite) extra spatial dimensions have received much attention. Many people have tried to extend the Randall-Sundrum model in different fashions. One of what they have attempted is to put the standard model into the bulk, i.e., they considered bulk fields(scalar, fermion and gauge fields) as well as gravitons. Bulk scalar field was originally introduced by Goldberger and Wise to stabilize the size of the extra dimension[3]. Bulk fermion fields in the Randall-Sundrum model have been considered as well[4] and it has been shown that they could be localized on both positive and negative tension branes by intoducing the kink-like mass term[5].</p>

				<p>On the other hand, bulk gauge field in the Randall-Sundrum model has a very different story 2 . Unlike the scalar and fermion fields, it has been wellknown that the zero mode of the bulk gauge field is not localized on a brane[7]. Actually it is flat in the extra dimension. The reason consists in the rescaling property of the gauge field action as has already been addressed by several authors[8]. The 4-dimensional kinetic term of the gauge field is not warped.</p>

				<p>However there have more recently appeared several models of gauge field localization in the</p>

				<p>Randall-Sundrum geometry with infinite extra space dimension.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we shall restrict our consideration into the following two different models. One is introduced by the authors of [9, 10] where the localization is achived by adding both bulk and boundary mass terms of the gauge field. The other one is introduced by [11] where the localization is achieved by taking into account the coupling between the gauge field and the dilaton field. Both models have the gauge field zero mode localized on a brane whose wave function has the peak just on the brane.</p>

				<p>In the light of these situations, it is interesting to investigate the relation between these two models of gauge field localization. In fact, it is the purpose of this paper.</p>

				<p>Let us start with introducing Lagrangians of the two models. The action with both bulk and boundary mass terms is given by[9, 10] S massive =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d 5 X √ −G − 1 4 G M N G P Q F M P F N Q − 1 2 (M 2 + cδ(y))G M N A M A N , (1) where M, N, P, Q = 0, 1, 2, 3</trash>

					<figDesc>, y and F M N = ∂ M A N − ∂ N A M . A M (x µ , y) is the bulk U(1) gauge field. G M N is the 5-dimensional metric defined by</figDesc>
					<trash>ds 2 = e −2|y|/L η µν dx µ dx ν + dy 2 . (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here the parameters M and c denote the bulk and the boundary masses, respectively. They are supposed to appear through spontaneous breaking of the gauge invariance in the bulk[10].</p>

				<p>On the other hand, the action with the coupling between the gauge field and the dilaton field is given by[11]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S dilaton = d 5 X √ −G − 1 4 e −λπ/2 √ 3M 3 P l G M N G P Q F M P F N Q + 1 2 (∂φ) 2 + 1 2 (∂π) 2 −V (φ, π) , (3) 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first field theory example of gauge field localization on a brane was suggested in Ref.[6] where λ is a dimensionless coupling depending on the underlying theory. The scalar field φ is the stuff the domain wall is made off while the another scalar field π is nothing but the dilaton field. V (φ, π) is supposed to be usual Higgs-type potential. In the absence of the U(1) gauge field, under the assumption of the following form of the metric,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = e −2A(y) η µν dx µ dx ν + dy 2 , (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>we find the solutions of the equations of motion(we assume both φ and π depend on only the fifth dimensional coordinate y):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ(y) = v tanh(ay), A(y) = −β ln cosh 2 (ay) − β 2 tanh 2 (ay), π(y) = β 3M 3 P l ln cosh 2 (ay) + 1 2 tanh 2 (ay) , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where a −1 is the &quot; width &quot; of the domain wall which is given in terms of some parameters appearing in the original action. β is given by v 2 /36M 3 P l where v is the expectation value of the scalar field. M P l is the 5-dimensional Planck scale.</p>

				<p>Obviously we have to take the brane limit, i.e., a → ∞ to compare these two models appropriately. This limit is taken with the quantity ξ ≡ 3βa fixed. As the result, we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ(y) = vθ(y) + · · · , A(y) = − 2ξ 2 3 |y| − ξ 2 6a (1 − 4 ln 2) + · · · , π(y) = 3M 3 P l 2ξ 2 3 |y| + ξ 2 6a (1 − 4 ln 2) + · · · , (6) where θ(y) is the step function defined by θ(y) = +1 for y &gt; 0 −1 for y &lt; 0 (7) We are ready to go further. As has been suggested, we expect that there is some relation between two models described by the Lagrangians (1) and (3). Here we shall give the following conjecture; e −λπ/4 √ 3M 3 P l A (dilaton) M = A (massive) M , (8) where A (massive) M and A (dilaton) M denote the gauge fields appearing in the Lagrangians (1) and (3), respectively. Now we shall examine the above conjecture by direct computation. Let us first define the function ǫ(π) as e −λπ/4 √ 3M 3 P l ≡ ǫ 2 (π). (9)</trash>

					<figDesc>It is interesting to note here that the function ǫ(π) (correctly speaking, ǫ 2 ) can be regarded as the dielectric &quot; constant &quot; . In Ref.[12]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, a similar model has been discussed to show confinement in the bulk via the dielectric effect proposed in [13] with an appropriate choice for ǫ and V .</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>It is straightforward to see that ǫ(π)F M P = ǫ(∂ M A P − ∂ P A M ), = ∂ M (ǫA P ) − ∂ P (ǫA M ) − (∂ M ǫ · A P − ∂ P ǫ · A M ). (10) Here we put ǫ(π)A P (x, y) = ˜ A P (x, y). It is clear that</figDesc>
					<trash>ǫ(π)F M P (A) = F M P ( ˜ A) − ∂ M ǫ ǫ ˜ A P − ∂ P ǫ ǫ ˜ A M . (11) Therefore we have ǫ 2 (π)G M N G P Q F M P (A)F N Q (A) = G M N G P Q F M P ( ˜ A)F N Q ( ˜ A) −2G M N G P Q F M P ( ˜ A) ∂ N ǫ ǫ ˜ A Q − ∂ Q ǫ ǫ ˜ A N +2G M N G P Q ∂ M ǫ ǫ ∂ N ǫ ǫ ˜ A P ˜ A Q − ∂ M ǫ ǫ ∂ Q ǫ ǫ ˜ A P ˜ A N .(12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>From below, we work with the gauge condition</figDesc>
					<trash>A y (x µ , y) = 0, (13) where µ = 0, 1, 2, 3. Then it is simple to show the following equation ǫ 2 (π)G M N G P Q F M P (A)F N Q (A) = G M N G P Q F M P ( ˜ A)F N Q ( ˜ A) −4G µν ∂ y ǫ ǫ ˜ A µ ∂ y ˜ A ν + 2G µν ∂ y ǫ ǫ 2 ˜ A µ ˜ A ν . (14) Plugging (14) into the Lagrangian (3), we are led to the following expression (the scalar parts are dropped); S dilaton = d 5 X √ −G − 1 4 G M N G P Q F M P ( ˜ A)F N Q ( ˜ A) +G µν ∂ y ǫ ǫ ˜ A µ ∂ y ˜ A ν − 1 2 G µν ∂ y ǫ ǫ 2 ˜ A µ ˜ A ν . (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>By combining the equation (9) with the asymptotic form of π(y) at a → ∞, we can evaluate the term ∂ y ǫ/ǫ ≡ d ln ǫ(π)/dy as follows;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d ln ǫ(π) dy = − λ 4 3M 3 P l dπ dy , = − λξ 2 6 θ(y) + O(1/a). (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Again, θ(y) is the step function defined through eq.(7).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Thus we obtain S dilaton = d 5 X √ −G − 1 4 G M N G P Q F M P ( ˜ A)F N Q ( ˜ A) − 1 2 M ′ 2 G µν A µ ˜ A ν − λξ 2 6 G µν θ(y) ˜ A µ ∂ y ˜ A ν , (17) where M ′ 2 = λ 2 ξ 4 36 , (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which plays a role of the bulk mass of the gauge field.</p>

				<p>Here we make partial integration for the third term in the action (17). The result is that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S dilaton [ ˜ A] = d 5 X √ −G − 1 4 G M N G P Q F M P ( ˜ A)F N Q ( ˜ A) − 1 2 (M ′ 2 + c ′ δ(y))G µν A µ ˜ A ν + λξ 2 6 1 √ −G θ(y)∂ y ( √ −GG µν A µ ) ˜ A ν , (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the coefficient in front of the delta function of the second term is defined by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c ′ = − 2λξ 2 3 , (20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which corresponds to the mass parameter of the gauge field on the brane at y = 0. This is also interpreted as the interaction one between the bulk gauge field and the brane. Note here that the sign of c ′ is negative as long as λ is positive. So we have tachyonic mass term on the brane in this case.</p>

				<p>Eq.(19) has the same form as eq.(1) except the third term of the right hand side when we choose A y = 0 gauge in eq.(1). As has been wellknown, the field transformation such as eq.(8) is used to generate the mass term via the kinetic term. That was one of our original motivations against the conjecture (8). As we see from the process of deriving eq.(19), the origin of the boundary mass term, which is proportional to the delta function, consists in the orbifold geometry of the Randall-Sundrum model.</p>

				<p>Finally let us consider the parameters appearing in both Lagrangians in detail. As we see from eq.(18) and eq.(20) immediately,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M ′ ≈ |c ′ |. (21)</trash>

					<figDesc>On the other hand, The parameters appearing in the action (1), M and c, are related through the boundary condition on the brane at y = 0 as follows;</figDesc>
					<trash>|c| = 2 L ( 1 + M 2 L 2 − 1) ≈ M 2 L, (22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>where L denotes the radius of 5-dimensional AdS space. In the Randall-Sundrum model, L −1 is of the order of the 5-dimensional Planck scale, i.e., L −1 ≈ M P l . Therefore we find |c| ≈ M M P l in this case. From the viewpoint of solving the hierarchy problem, the bulk mass parameter M should be of the order of M P l . If it is applied, the boundary mass parameter |c| is of the order of M P l as well and is given as |c| ≈ M . As the result, we obtain the same relation between the bulk and the boundary mass parameters shown in eq.(21).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>To conclude, in this paper, we discussed the relation between recently proposed two models of gauge field localization on a brane in the Randall-Sundrum model. We made a certain transformation of the gauge field and it was shown that those two models are closely (not exactly) related by direct computation. One important property to derive the mass term on the brane was the orbifold geometry of the Randall-Sundrum model. We examined the parameters</p>

				<p>appearing in Lagrangians of the two models. As the result, we obtained the equivalent relations between the bulk and the boundary mass parameters in both models, which was done through a natural requirement to solve the hierarchy problem. The physical meaning of the conjecture (8) is, however, still less clear even if it generates both bulk and boundary mass terms. This will be a future issue.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> E-mail:motoi@lns.mit.edu JSPS Research Fellow on leave from Yukawa Institute for Theoretical Physics, Kyoto University, Kyoto 606-8502, Japan</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>This work was supported in part by a Grant-in-Aid for Scientific Research from Ministry of Education, Science, Sports and Culture of Japan (No. 3666).</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Large Mass Hierarchy from a Small Extra Dimension</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Randall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Sundrum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9905221</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Alternative to Compactification</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Randall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Sundrum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4690</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9906064</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bulk Fields in the Randall-Sundrum Scenario</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Goldberger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Wise</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">107505</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modulus Stabilization with Bulk Fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Goldberger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Wise</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4922</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9907447</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bulk Standard Model in the Randall-Sundrum Background</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Chang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">084025</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bulk Fields and Supersymmetry in a Slice of AdS</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Gherghetta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pomarol</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>B586</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">0003129</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain Walls in Strongly Coupled Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Dvali</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Shifman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. Erratum-ibid</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">396</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">452</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bulk Gauge Fields in the Randall-Sundrum Model Gauge Bosons in a Five-dimensional Theory with Localized Gravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Davoudiasl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Hewett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Rizzo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>A. Pomarol</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2080</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>A. Pomarol</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>B486</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Chang</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ref</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Extra Dimensions as an Alternative to Higgs Mecha- nism? Comment on Kaluza-Klein Spectrum of Gauge Fields in the Bigravity Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Shaposhnikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Tinyakov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Tachibana</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">0107</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Massive Vector Trapping as a Gauge Boson on a Brane</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Ghoroku</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Nakamura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="106145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multi-Localization in Multi- Brane Worlds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Kogan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Mouslopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Papazoglou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="107307" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Localized Gravitons, Gauge Bosons and Chiral Fermions in Smooth Spaces Generated by a Bounce</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kehagias</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Tamvakis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">504</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0010112</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strings as Flux Tube and Deconfinement on Branes in Gauge Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Kawai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Kuroki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="106103" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cern</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vacuum Polarization and the Absence of Free Quarks in Four Dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kogut</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Susskind</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3501</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
