<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Higher-Dimensional QCD without the Strong CP Problem</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2002-03-28">28 Mar 2002</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Izawa</forename>
								<forename type="middle">K</forename>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">.-I</forename>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">T</forename>
								<surname>Watari</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tokyo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>113-0033</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Research Center for the Early Universe</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tokyo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>113-0033</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">T</forename>
								<surname>Yanagida</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tokyo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>113-0033</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Research Center for the Early Universe</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tokyo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>113-0033</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Higher-Dimensional QCD without the Strong CP Problem</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2002-03-28">28 Mar 2002</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>QCD in a five-dimensional sliced bulk with chiral extra-quarks on the boundaries is generically free from the strong CP problem. Accidental axial symmetry is naturally present except for suppressed breaking interactions, which plays a role of the Peccei-Quinn symmetry to make the strong CP phase sufficiently small.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The standard model of elementary particles has two apparent fine-tuning problems which are hard to be undertaken directly by additional (gauge) symmetries: the cosmological constant and the strong CP [1] problems. The presence of extra dimensions might serve as an alternative to symmetry in obtaining such fine-tuned parameters in a natural way.</p>

				<p>In this paper, as a concrete example, we consider QCD in a five-dimensional sliced bulk with chiral extra-quarks on the boundaries and point out that it is generically free from the strong CP problem.</p>

				<p>For definiteness, let us suppose that there is a pair of extra-quarks in addition to the standard-model quarks: a left-handed colored fermion ψ L and a right-handed one ψ R . We assume an extra-dimensional space which separates them from each other along the extra dimension. If the distance between them is sufficiently large, the theory possesses an axial</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>U(1) symmetry ψ L → e iα ψ L , ψ R → e −iα ψ R (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>approximately, whose breaking is suppressed at a fundamental scale. This accidental global symmetry, which is actually broken by a QCD anomaly, plays a role of the Peccei- Quinn symmetry [2], making the effective strong CP phase to be sufficiently small.</p>

				<p>The point is that the presence of such an approximate symmetry is not an artificial requirement, but a natural result stemming from the higher-dimensional space, which might well be stable even against possible quantum gravitational corrections. Note that axion models in the four-dimensional spacetime suffer from a fine-tuning problem: operators that break the axial symmetry should be highly suppressed without any dynamical reasons. The present model provides a solution to this problem.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Bulk color gauge theory</head>

				<p>Let us consider a four-dimensional Minkowski spacetime M 4 along with one-dimensional extra-space S 1 , whose coordinate y extends form −l to l (that is, two points at y = l and y = −l are identified). The SU(3) C gauge field is assumed to propagate on the whole spacetime M 4 × S 1 . The action of the five-dimensional gauge field is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S A = d 4 x l −l dy M * 4g 2 (y) tr(F M N F M N ) + h(y) tr AF 2 − 1 2 A 3 F + 1 10 A 5 , (2) where F M N = ∂ M A N − ∂ N A M + [A M , A N ] (M, N = 0, · · · , 4; x 4 ≡ y), A = A M dx M , and F = dA + A 2 = (1/2)F M N dx M dx N . Here, M * is supposed to be a cutoff scale in the higher-dimensional gauge theory and g(y) and h(y) are gauge and Chern-Simons coupling functions, respectively.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Kaluza-Klein reduction to the four-dimensional spacetime, however, yields a massless color-octet scalar which is undesirable in the low-energy spectrum. Hence we consider an</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S 1 /Z 2 orbifold instead of the S 1 . The five-dimensional gauge field A M (x, y) is now under a constraint A µ (x, y) = A µ (x, −y), A 4 (x, y) = −A 4 (x, −y), (3) where µ = 0, · · · , 3.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Then, we have only a vector field at low energies without the scalar field after the Kaluza-Klein reduction. In order to define the theory on the orbifold consistently, the action eq.(2) on the S 1 should be invariant under the Z 2 transformation.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>This invariance is achieved as long as g(y) = g(−y) and h(y) = −h(−y). We take the g(y) to be y-independent and the h(y) as h(y) = c y |y| , (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where c is a constant to be determined in the next section. The gauge symmetries are left unbroken with the infinitesimal SU(3) C gauge transformation parameter restricted to satisfy ε(x, y) = ε(x, −y).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Boundary extra-quarks</head>

				<p>There are two fixed points in the S 1 /Z 2 orbifold: y = 0 and y = l. Let us put chiral extra-quarks 1 on the fixed-point boundaries: 2 a left-handed extra-quark ψ L at y = 0 and a right-handed extra-quark ψ R at y = l. The action of the extra-quarks contains</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S ψ = y=0 d 4 x ¯ ψ L iD / ψ L + y=l d 4 x ¯ ψ R iD / ψ R . (5) Under an infinitesimal gauge transformation, this fermionic sector provides a gauge anomaly δS ef f = i 24π 2 y=0 tr εd(AdA + 1 2 A 3 ) − i 24π 2 y=l tr εd(AdA + 1 2 A 3 ) (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>due to its chirality, though the fermion content is vector-like from a four-dimensional</p>

				<figure>
					<head>perspective.</head>

					<figDesc>On the other hand, the bulk action yields</figDesc>
					<trash>δS A = h(y) tr (dε)d(AdA + 1 2 A 3 ) = − (dh(y)) tr εd(AdA + 1 2 A 3 ) (7) under the gauge transformation. Gauge anomaly cancellation with the fermionic sector implies c = i 48π 2 . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Anomalous quasi-symmetry</head>

				<p>The gauge-invariant theory is given by the total action S = S A + S ψ . Then, there is an approximate axial U(1) symmetry given by eq.(1). Indeed, interactions between the chiral extra-quarks (in the four-dimensional effective theory) such as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M * ψ L ψ † R + h.c. (9)</trash>

					<figDesc>are suppressed by e −M * l /(M * l) with M * as the cutoff scale at which new particles and interactions may arise (see also the discussion in the final section).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The extra-quarks should be decoupled from the low-energy spectrum to escape from detection. Thus, we introduce hypercolor gauge interactions in the bulk to confine the extra-quarks at high energies. Such new gauge interactions at the same time induce a chiral condensate ψ L ψ † R , break down the axial U(1) symmetry [1] and provide a corresponding Nambu-Goldstone (NG) boson called an axion [3]. Non-vanishing anomaly U(1)[SU(3) C ] 2 induces a potential of the axion field.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Let us adopt SU(3) H as the hypercolor gauge group and assume that the chiral fermions on each boundary transform as ψ L (3, 3 * ) and ψ R (3, 3 * ) under the SU(3) C ×SU(3) H gauge group. 3 The SU(3) H interactions are supposed to be strong and confining at an intermediate scale F a , and a chiral condensate</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>ψ L ψ † R ≃ F 3</formula></p>

				<p>a develops. Note that the [SU(3) H ] 3 anomaly due to the fermionic sector can also be canceled by bulk Chern-Simons terms in a similar way as in the previous section.</p>

				<p>SU(3) H -charged particles are confined and what is left at low energies are only massless NG bosons. When one switches off the SU(3) C gauge interactions (to concentrate on the strong dynamics of the SU(3) H interactions), then there is U(3) L ×U(3) R flavor symmetry that acts on ψ L and ψ † R , where the SU(3) subgroup of the diagonal U(3) symmetry is actually gauged as SU(3) C . The flavor symmetry U(3) L ×U(3) R is spontaneously broken down to the diagonal U(3) symmetry. The NG bosons due to this chiral symmetry breaking transform as 3 × 3 * = adj. + 1 under the SU(3) C . However, there is not U(3) L ×U(3) R symmetry actually since the diagonal SU(3) is gauged as the SU(3) C gauge group, and hence the adjoint-part of the NG bosons acquires masses due to the SU(3) C radiative corrections. What remains massless is only the color-singlet NG boson, which corresponds to the axial U(1) symmetry in eq.(1).</p>

				<p>The axial symmetry discussed above, however, also has U(1) [ SU(3) H ] 2 anomaly.</p>

				<p>Therefore, the color-singlet NG boson obtains a large mass and it cannot play a role of the axion for the color SU(3) C . Hence we further introduce an additional pair of chiral fermions on each boundary: χ L (1, 3 * ) at y = 0 and χ R (1, 3</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>* ) at y = l. The global symmetry is now U(4) L × U(4) R if the SU(3) C gauge interactions are neglected. The strong dynamics of the SU(3) H gauge interactions leads to spontaneous breakdown of the chiral symmetry,</figDesc>
					<trash>ψ L ψ † R ≃ F 3 a and χ L χ † R ≃ F 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>a . Two color-singlets would remain massless if it were not for anomalies. In this case, one of them does play a role of the axion that makes the effective strong CP phase to be sufficiently small.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Discussion</head>

				<p>The accidental chiral symmetry discussed above is broken by effective operators of the chiral fermions. The operators involving both &apos;ψ L or χ L &apos; and &apos;ψ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>† R or χ † R &apos;, such as eq.(9), are highly suppressed. 4 However, the operators involving either &apos;ψ L and χ L &apos; or &apos;ψ † R and χ †</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>R &apos; are expected to be suppressed only by powers of 1/M * . Thus, such operators induce an additional potential of the axion, but this correction is not too large to render the</p>

				<p>Peccei-Quinn mechanism ineffective: Axial-symmetry breaking on each boundary may have coupling coefficients of order one. Such operators of the lowest mass dimension</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5 are given by y=0 d 4 x 1 M 5 * (ψ L ) 3 (ψ L ) 3 + y=l d 4 x 1 M 5 * (ψ † R ) 3 (ψ † R ) 3 + h.c. (10)</trash>

					<figDesc>Integration of heavy particles of masses of order F a induces an additional potential of the axion field a as</figDesc>
					<trash>V (a) ≃ F 14 a M 10 * f ( a F a ), (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where f (a/F a ) is a function of a/F a , whose minimum is generically different from that of the potential induced exclusively by the QCD effects. The resulting shift in the θ eff parameter of the QCD is expected to be of order</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>θ eff ≃ F a M * 14 M * Λ QCD 4 = 10 −10 F a 10 5 M * 14 M * Λ QCD 10 15 4 . (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The present experimental bound θ eff &lt; 10 −9 is satisfied, for instance, with M * ≃ 10 18 GeV and F a ≤ 10 12 GeV, which is phenomenologically viable.</p>

				<p>We note that the axial-symmetry breaking operators on each boundary can be made to have higher mass dimensions if we adopt a larger hypercolor gauge group instead of the SU(3) H . Then, the θ eff will be more suppressed.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>acknowledgment</head>

				<p>T.W. would like to thank the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science for financial support. This work was partially supported by &quot; Priority Area: Supersymmetry and</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Unified Theory of Elementary Particles (# 707) &quot; (T.Y.).</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-ph/0202171v2 28 Mar 2002</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Instead of boundary extra-quarks, we may introduce vector-like extra-quarks in the bulk with a domain wall background, which results in a similar separation of chiral extra-quarks along the extra dimension. 2 The standard-model quarks may be put on one of the fixed points, which does not alter the point in the following discussion.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Extensions to larger gauge groups and fermion representations are straightforward, which are touched upon in the final section.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> M * l ≃ 150 + 3 ln(F a /10 12 GeV) is sufficient. 5 Discussion here assumes that the extra-quarks are not charged under the SU(2) L or U(1) Y gauge group of the standard model, though we can also consider a model where they are charged under the SU(2) L or U(1) Y .</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep. Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cheng</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">150</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Cheng</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Peccei</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Quinn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="1791" />
			<date type="published" when="1440" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="279" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>223. ; F. Wilczek</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
