<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Strong and Electroweak Interactions, and Their Unification with Noncommutative Space-Time</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Xiao-Gang</forename>
								<surname>He</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute of Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Academia Sinica</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100080</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10764</postCode>
									<settlement>Taipei</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Strong and Electroweak Interactions, and Their Unification with Noncommutative Space-Time</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-ph/0202223v3 3 Apr 2003 Typeset using REVT E X 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term>2220-z</term>
					<term>1115-q</term>
					<term>1210</term>
					<term>1260-i</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Quantum field theories based on noncommutative space-time (NCQFT) have been extensively studied recently. However no NCQFT model, which can uniquely describe the strong and electroweak interactions, has been constructed. This prevents consistent and systematic study of noncommutative space-time. In this work we construct a NCQFT model based on the trini-fication gauge group SU (3) C × SU (3) L × SU (3) R. A unique feature of this model, that all matter fields (fermions and Higgses) are assigned to (anti-)fundamental representations of the factor SU (3) groups, allows us to construct a NCQFT model for strong and electroweak interactions and their unification without ambiguities. This model provides an example which allows consistent and systematic study of noncommutative space-time phenomenol-ogy. We also comment on some related issues regarding extensions to E 6 and U (3) C × U (3) L × U (3) R models.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>Noncommutative quantum field theory (NCQFT), based on modification of the spacetime commutation relations, provides an alternative to the ordinary quantum field theory. A simple way to modify the space-time properties is to change the usual space-time coordinate x to noncommutative coordinatê X such that [1] [ ˆ X µ , ˆ X ν ] = iθ µν , (1) where θ µν is a real anti-symmetric matrix. We will consider the case where θ µν is a constant and commutes with X µ .</p>

				<p>NCQFT based on the above commutation relation can be easily studied using the Weyl- Moyal correspondence replacing the product of two fields A( ˆ X) and B( ˆ X) with noncommutative coordinates by product of the same fields but ordinary coordinate x through the star &quot; * &quot; product, A( ˆ X)B( ˆ X) → A(x) * B(x) = Exp[i 1 2 θ µν ∂ x,µ ∂ y,ν ]A(x)B(y)| x=y . (2)</p>

				<p>Properties related to NCQFT have been studied extensively recently [2–11,13,14]. NC- QFT for a pure U(1) group is easy to study. Related phenomenology have been studied recently [2]. But it is more complicated for non-abelian groups. Due to the &quot; * &quot; product nature, there are fundamental differences between ordinary and noncommutative gauge theories and cause many difficulties to construct a unique and consistent model for strong and electroweak interactions based on SU(3) C × SU(2) L × U(1) Y gauge group [3–11,13,14]. One of the main problems is that SU(N) group can not be simply gauged with &quot; * &quot; product as will be explain in the following. Another problem is that, naively, the charges of any U(1) gauge group with &quot; * &quot; product are quantized to only three possible values, 1, 0, -1 which cannot accommodate all the hypercharges for matter fields in the SM.</p>

				<p>In this work we construct a NCQFT model based on the trinification gauge group</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We show that NCQFT model for strong and electroweak interactions and their unification can be consistently constructed. This model therefore provides an example which allows a consistent and systematic study of noncommutative space-time phenomenology.</p>

				<p>With noncommutative space-time there are modifications to the fields compared with the ordinary ones. We indicate the fields in NCQFT with a hat and the ordinary ones without hat. The definition of gauge transformation α of a gauge field A µ for a SU(N) is similar to the ordinary one but with usual product replaced by the &quot; * &quot; product. For example</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δ α ˆ φ = iˆ φ, (3) wherê φ is a fundamental representation of SU(N). We use the notation A µ = ˆ A a µ T a , ˆ α = α a T a with T a being the SU(N) generator normalized as T r(T a T b ) = δ ab /2.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Due to the noncommutativity of the space-time, two consecutive local transformations ˆ α and β of the type in the above,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(δ α δ β − δ β δ α ) = ( ˆ α * ˆ β − ˆ β * ˆ α), (4) cannot be reduced to the matrix commutator of the generators of the Lie algebra due to the noncommutativity of the space-time. They have to be in the enveloping algebra ˆ α = α + α 1 ab : T a T b : +... + α n−1 a 1 ...an : T a 1 ...T an : +... (5) where : T a 1 ...T</trash>

					<figDesc>an : is totally symmetric under exchange of a i . This poses a difficulty in constructing non-abelian SU(N) gauge theories [3]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<p>Seiberg and Witten have shown [5] that the fields defined in noncommutative coordinate can be mapped on to the ordinary fields, the Seiberg-Witten mapping. In Ref. [6] it was shown that this mapping actually can be applied to the &quot; * &quot; product with any gauge groups.</p>

				<p>It is possible to study non-abelian gauge group theories. Using the above enveloping algebra, one can obtain the noncommutative fields in terms of the ordinary fields with corrections in powers of the noncommutative parameter, θ µν , order by order. To the first order in θ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µν noncommutative fields can be expressed as ˆ α = α + 1 4 θ µν {∂ µ α, A ν } + cθ µν [∂ µ α, A ν ], A µ = − 1 4 θ αβ {A α , ∂ β A µ + F βµ } + cθ αβ ([A α , ∂ µ A β ] + i[A α A β , A µ ]), ˆ φ = aθ µν F µν φ − 1 2 θ µν A µ ∂ ν φ + i( 1 4 + c)θ µν A µ A ν φ, (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where F µν = ∂ µ A ν − ∂ ν A µ − ig N [A µ , A ν ]. The term proportional to a can be absorbed into the redefinition of the matter field φ. The parameter c can not be removed by redefinition of the gauge field. It must be a purely imaginary number from the requirement that the gauge field be self conjugate.</p>

				<p>Using the above noncommutative fields, one can construct a gauge theory for SU(N) group. The action S of a SU(N) NCQFT, to the leading order in θ, is given by [6,7],</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = Ld 4 x, L = − 1 2 T r(F µν F µν ) + 1 4 g N θ µν T r(F µν F ρσ F ρσ − 4F µρ F νσ F ρσ ) + ¯ φ(iγ µ D µ − m)φ − 1 4 θ αβ ¯ φF αβ (iγ µ D µ − m)φ − 1 2 θ αβ ¯ φγ µ F µα iD β φ, (7) where D µ = ∂ µ −ig N T a A a µ .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We note that the parameter c does not appear in the Lagrangian. The Lagrangian is uniquely determined to order θ. We will therefore work with a simple choice c = 0 from now on. In the above, if φ is a chiral field, m = 0.</p>

				<p>To obtain a theory which can describe the strong and electroweak interactions such as the Standard Model (SM), one also needs to solve the U(1) charge quantization problem, namely only three possible values, 1, 0, -1 for U(1) charges, as mentioned earlier. It has been shown that this difficulty can also be overcome with the use of the Seiberg-Witten mapping [5] .</p>

				<p>To solve the U(1) charge quantization problem, one associates each charge gq</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(n) of the nth matter field a gauge field A (n) µ [8]. In the commutative limit, θ µν → 0, ˆ A (n) µ becomes the single gauge field A µ of the ordinary commuting space-time U(1) gauge theory. But at nonzero orders in θ µν , ˆ A (n) µ receives corrections [8]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. In doing so, the kinetic energy of the gauge boson will, however, be affected. Depending on how the kinetic energy is defined (weight over different field strength of A (n) µ ), the resulting kinetic energy will be different even though the proper normalization to obtain the correct kinetic energy in the commutative limit is imposed [8].</p>

				<p>In the SM there are six different matter field multiplets for each generation, i.e. u R , d R , (u, d) L , e R , (ν, e) L and (H 0 , H − ), a priori one can choose a different g i for each of them.</p>

				<p>After identifying three combinations with the usual g 3 , g 2 and g 1 couplings for the SM gauge groups, there is still a freedom to choose different gauge boson self interaction couplings at non-zero orders in θ µν . This leads to ambiguities in self interactions of gauge bosons when non-zero order terms in θ µν are included [8]. This problem needs to be resolved. A way to solve this problem is to have a theory without the use of U(1) factor group.</p>

				<p>There are many groups without U(1) factor group which contain the SM gauge group and may be used to describe the strong and electroweak interactions. However not all of them can be easily extended to a full NCQFT using the formulation described above. For example one can easily obtain unique gauge boson self interactions in SU(5) theory [9]. But the matter fields require more than one representations 5 and 10 which causes additional complications [10] and will reintroduce the uniqueness problem for kinetic energy. One way of obtaining a consistent NCQFT is to have a theory in which all matter and Higgs fields are in the same representation such that once Seiberg-Witten mapping is used to solve the problem of gauging a SU(N) group, there is no problem with unique determination of kinetic energy.</p>

				<p>To this end we propose to use the trinification gauge group [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R with a Z 3 symmetry.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This theory leads to unification of strong and electroweak interactions. An important feature of this theory is that the matter and Higgs fields are assigned to (anti-)fundamental representations of the factor SU(3) groups and therefore the formalism described earlier can be readily used.</p>

				<p>In the trinification model, the gauge fields are in the adjoint representation,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>24 = A C + A L + A R = (8, 1, 1) + (1, 8, 1) + (1, 1, 8), (8</trash>

					<figDesc>) which contains 24 gauge bosons. A C contains the color gluon bosons, a linear combination of component fields of A L and A R forms the U(1) Y gauge boson, and A L contains the SU(2) L gauge bosons. The rest are integrally charged heavy gauge bosons which do not mediate proton decays [15]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<p>Each generation of fermions is assigned to a</p>

				<p><formula>27, ψ = ψ LR + ψ RC + ψ CL = (1, 3, ¯ 3) + ( ¯ 3, 1, 3) + (3, ¯ 3, 1), ψ LR =         E 0 E − e − E + ¯ E 0 ν e + N 1 N 2         , ψ RC =         ¯ u 1 ¯ u 2 ¯ u 3 ¯ d 1 ¯ d 2 ¯ d 3 ¯ B 2 ¯ B 2 ¯ B 2         , ψ CL =         u 1 d 1 B 1 u 2 d 2 B 2 u 3 d 3 B 3         . (9)</formula></p>

				<p>In the above we have written the fermions in left-handed chiral fields. The B field is a heavy particle.</p>

				<p>The Higgs fields which break the trinification to the SM gauge group are also assigned to 27 representations. In order to have correct mass patterns, at least two 27 Higgs representations are needed [15]. We indicate them by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ i = φ LR i + φ RC i + φ CL i = (1, 3, ¯ 3) i + ( ¯ 3, 1, 3) i + (3, ¯ 3, 1) i . (10)</trash>

					<figDesc>The Z 3 symmetry operates in the following way. If (C, L, R) is a representation under the SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R , the effect of Z 3 is to symmetrize it to Z 3 (C, L, R) = (C, L, R) + (R, C, L) + (L, R, C). (11) Requirement of the Lagrangian to be invariant under Z 3 relates the gauge couplings g C,L,R of the gauge groups to be equal, g C = g L = g R = g U , at a scale which is the unification scale of the model. The vacuum expectation values of the Higgs scalars break the symmetry to SU(3) C ×</figDesc>
					<trash>SU(2) L × U(1) Y have the following form &lt; φ LR 1 &gt;=         ˆ 0 0 0 0 ˆ 0 0 0 0 v 1         , &lt; φ LR 2 &gt;=         ˆ 0 0 0 0 ˆ 0 ˆ 0 0 v 2 ˆ 0         . (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Non-zero values of v 1,2 break the symmetry to the SM group. The scale of v 1,2 are at the unification scale. At this stage 12 of the gauge bosons, and B, E i and N i particles receive masses. They are therefore very heavy. The entries indicated by 0 can develop VEV&apos;s of order m W . These VEV&apos;s break the SM group to SU(3) C × U(1) em and provide masses for the ordinary quarks and leptons.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In this model sin 2 θ W = 3/8 at the unification scale. Using the present electroweak precision test data for sin 2 θ W , α s and α em at the Z mass pole, the unification scale is determined to be 10 14 GeV [16]. A unification scale as low as 10 14 GeV in a SU(5) theory, for example, would induce rapid proton decays and be ruled out. However, as have been mentioned previously that in the trinification theory, gauge bosons do not mediate proton decays. Therefore the theory would not have problem with proton decays. Mediation of heavy Higgs particles can produce proton decays [15]. However in this case, there are many free parameters in the Yukawa and the Higgs potential couplings to make the theory to be consistent with data [15].</p>

				<p>It is clear that the trinification model can provides an easy framework for building a phenomenologically acceptable and consistent NCQFT model for strong and electroweak interactions. To the first order in θ µν , the noncommutative gauge fields are the same form for the gauge fields as in eq. (6). The fermion and Higgs fields are in the same representation and are all (anti-)fundamental representations φ of the type (3, ¯ 3) under the subgroups SU(3) × SU(3). The noncommutative fields expressed in the ordinary fields are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ˆ φ = φ − 1 2 θ µν (A µ ∂ ν φ − i 2 A µ A ν φ + ∂ ν φA ′ µ + i 2 φA ′ ν A ′ µ ), (13) where A µ and A ′</trash>

					<figDesc>µ are the gauge fields of the first SU(3) and the second SU(3) gauge groups, respectively. The first order in θ µν corrections to the Lagrangiañ L for gauge and fermion kinetic energy terms are given by</figDesc>
					<trash>˜ L = [ 1 4 g C θ µν T r(F C µν F C αβ F Cαβ − 4F C αµ F C βν F Cαβ ) + (C → L) + (C → R)] − [ i 4 θ µν T r( ¯ ψ LR F L µν γ α D α ψ LR + F R µν ¯ ψ LR γ α D α ψ LR + 2 ¯ ψ LR F L αµ γ α D ν ψ LR + 2F R αµ ¯ ψ LR γ α D ν ψ LR ) + (LR → LC) + (LR → CR)], (14) where D µ ψ LR = ∂ µ ψ LR − ig L A L µ ψ LR + ig R φ LR A R µ .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The above Lagrangian uniquely determine interactions due to noncommutative spacetime correction to the first order in θ µν without the problems pointed out earlier. We emphasis that although the resulting theory at low energies appears to have U(1) factor group(s), the corresponding gauge self-interactions are fixed because of the choice of trinification group which dictates how gauge bosons interact. From the above Lagrangian one can easily study new interactions due to noncommutative space-time and test the model by experimental data. For illustration, we present the neutral gauge boson self interactions and its interactions with the SM fermions. Expanding the above Lagrangian we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L int = 1 4 g C θ µν T r(G µν G αβ G αβ − 4G αµ G βν G αβ ) + 1 16 θ µν g Y [c W ( 7 15 c 2 W + s 2 W )(F µν F αβ F αβ − 4F αµ F βν F αβ ) − s W ( 7 15 s 2 W + c 2 W )(Z µν Z αβ Z αβ − 4Z αµ Z βν Z αβ ) + c W (c 2 W − 23 15 s 2 W )(F µν Z αβ Z αβ + 2Z µν Z αβ F αβ − 4(Z αµ Z βν F αβ + 2F αµ Z βν Z αβ )) − s W (s 2 W − 23 15 c 2 W )(Z µν F αβ F αβ + 2F µν Z αβ F αβ − 4(F αµ F βν Z αβ + 2Z αµ F βν F αβ ))] (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where c w = cos θ W , s W = sin θ W . G µν , F µν , Z µν = ∂ µ Z ν −∂ ν Z µ are the field strengths for the gluon, photon and Z particles, respectively. Note that the above interactions are obtained at the unification scale where g Y =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3/5g U and sin 2 θ W = 3/8, and g C = g L = g R = g U .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From the above we see that the triple neutral gauge boson interactions are uniquely determined unlike the case with SM gauge group studied in Ref. [8]. These interactions are also different from those predicted by SU(5) model [9]. This can be used to test the model [11].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The fermion-gauge boson interactions can readily be obtained by expanding eq. (14). The Yukawa coupling terms and Higgs potential terms can also be obtained using results in eqs. (6) and (13). We have constructed a NCQFT unification model of strong and electroweak interactions based on SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R × Z 3 group. In this model all interactions are determined. New gauge boson self-and fermion-gauge interactions are predicted. If the noncommutative scale turns out to be low, the model can be tested experimentally. This model provides an example which can consistently describe the strong and electroweak interactions and their unification, and allows a systematic investigation of the hypothesis of noncommutative space-time.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Before closing we would like to make two comments on some possible extensions of the model discussed here. One of them concerns about E 6 extension of the model. The SU(3) C × SU(3) L × SU(3) R group can be embedded into E 6 group. One therefore can try to construct a NCQFT based on E 6 . With this group the gauge bosons are in the 78 adjoint representation and the fermions and Higgses are in the 27 fundamental representations [12].</p>

				<p>A NCQFT model can be constructed following the procedures discussed earlier. This model is very similar to the trinification model with the advantage that no additional Z 3 symmetry is needed. There are however differences and complications. In addition to the gauge bosons in the trinification model, there are also 54 colored gauge bosons. These particles mediate proton decays. Therefore they have to be made heavy. To achieve this more Higgs representations will have to be introduced which complicate the theory [12]. The trinification model is simpler in terms of particle contents.</p>

				<p>The other comment concerns another approach to construct trinification model with noncommutative space-time without the use of Seiberg-Witten mapping adopted in Ref. [13]. In this approach one first constructs fields in U(N) product groups and then break the symmetry spontaneously to SU(N) product group. For the trinification model, one can extend the group to U</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(3) C × U(3) L × U(3) R . The gauge field representation is 27 = (9, 1, 1) + (1, 9, 1) + (1, 1, 9).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In Ref. [13] the symmetry breaking of U(N) to SU(N) is assumed to be achieved by nonzero VEV&apos;s of representations S i which transform as singlets under the SU(N) but with non-zero charge for U(1) subgroup of U(N). Following Ref. [13] one can introduce three S i fields for each of the factor U(N) group. The VEV&apos;s of these fields break the group to the trinification group discussed earlier producing three heavy gauge bosons. However it has been shown that models based on such approach violates unitarity [17]. This approach may not lead to a realistic model.</p>


			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-ph/0202223v3 3 Apr 2003</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">work was supported in part by National Science Council under grants NSC 89- 2112-M-002-058 and NSC 89-2112-M-002-065, and in part by the Ministry of Education Academic Excellence Project 89-N-FA01-1-4-3. I would like to thank hospitality provided by the</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Note Added: Another consistent noncommutative grand unified model based on SO(10) has been constructed by P. Aschieri et al. (hep-th/0205214), three months after this work</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">REFERENCES</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Snyder</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Connes, Noncommutative Geometry Douglas and N. Nekrasov</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1947" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hewett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Petriello</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Rizzo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Baek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mathews, ibid D63</title>
		<editor>H. Grosse and Y. Liao S. Godfrey and M. Doncheski</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="075012" to="075007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Hayakawa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">417</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Matsubara, ibid B482</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Armoni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">229</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Seiberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page">032</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Madore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">161</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">521</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Jurco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Schupp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Wess</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>et. al., Eur</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">383</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Carlson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Carone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Lebed</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Calmet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">363</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Deshpande</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X.-G</forename>
				<surname>He</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page">116</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P.-M</forename>
				<surname>Ho</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H.-C</forename>
				<surname>Kao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">151602</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Behr</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0202121</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Gursey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Ramond</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Sikive</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Achiman and B. Stech, Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">389</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Chaichian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Chaichian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0107037</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>De Rujula</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Georgi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Fifth Workshop on Grand Unification</title>
		<editor>K.Kang, H. Fred, and P. Frampton</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<biblScope unit="page">88</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Babu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X.-G</forename>
				<surname>He</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pakvasa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">763</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Willenbrock</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hewett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Petriello</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Rizzo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">036001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
