<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Quantum Universe</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2002-03-05">5 Mar 2002</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Jon</forename>
								<surname>Eakins</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Mathematical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">George</forename>
								<surname>Jaroszkiewicz</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Mathematical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Quantum Universe</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2002-03-05">5 Mar 2002</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>On the basis that the universe is a closed quantum system with no external observers, we propose a paradigm in which the universe jumps through a series of stages. Each stage is defined by a quantum state, an information content, and rules governing temporal evolution. Only some of these rules are currently understood; we can calculate answers to quantum questions, but we do not know why those questions have been asked in the first place. In this paradigm, time is synonymous with the quantum process of information extraction, rather than a label associated with a temporal dimension. We discuss the implications for cosmology.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>On the basis that the universe is a closed quantum system with no external observers, we propose a paradigm in which the universe jumps through a series of stages. Each stage is defined by a quantum state, an information content, and rules governing temporal evolution.</p>

				<p>Only some of these rules are currently understood; we can calculate answers to quantum questions, but we do not know why those questions have been asked in the first place. In this paradigm, time is synonymous with the quantum process of information extraction, rather than a label associated with a temporal dimension. We discuss the implications for cosmology.</p>

				<p>The exact nature of the universe is still uncertain at this time, with a variety of incompatible paradigms, and models based on them, being assumed. We believe that a unique paradigm for the universe can be found once certain specific and reasonable answers to some standard questions are ac- cepted.</p>

				<p>The first important question is this: is the universe a complete quantum system or not? By complete we mean that there are no external observers or classical agencies not subject to the laws of quantum mechanics.</p>

				<p>The observation of Bell-type correlations and violations of Bell-type inequalities together with a vast amount of empirical evidence for the universal correctness of quantum principles strongly suggests that the answer to the first question is yes. This answer excludes from further discussion all paradigms and models based on any sort of classical hidden variables. We assume henceforth that the entire universe is a vast, selfcontained quantum automaton [1].</p>

				<p>An immediate and unavoidable corollary following from this assumption is that there are no semi-classical observers standing outside the universe or any part of it. This seems at odds with the notion of observer in the traditional formulation of quantum mechanics (also associated with the so-called measurement problem), but should be reconciled with it in terms of emergence, i.e., the appearance of classicity from a fully quantum universe.</p>

				<p>From this corollary follows another unavoidable corollary, which is that the universe must always be in a pure state, there being no global meaning to the concept of a mixed state when discussing the entire universe . There can be no intrinsic classical uncertainty as to which state the universe is in at a given time. Mixed states can be discussed in our paradigm but only under certain circumstances to do with emergence, when the notion of a semi-classical observer can be invoked. This will be discussed else- where.</p>

				<p>In a fully quantum universe, physicists who perform experiments and act as observers with free will must themselves be quantum processes and part of the very systems they appear to be monitoring. Accounting for them within a pure state formulation is another aspect of emergence. Given that there are no external observers, the conclusion is that somehow the universe organizes its own observation. This is not as strange as it may seem at first sight. Sophisticated computers, for example, can run diagnostic checks on themselves and repair problems in their software. In the case of the universe, the question is: what does this observation mean? The concepts of observation and measurement are meaningless without the concept of time, which is intrinsically associated with the process of information extraction, and it is only in these terms that we understand the dynamics of the universe. In the standard formulation of quantum mechanics, Schrödinger evolution occurs precisely in the absence of information extraction, and it is only when information about a system is extracted that state reduction occurs. Therefore, we are driven to the conclusion that time is no more nor less than a marker of a constant process of state reduction in the universe which accompanies information extraction. We differ from the multiverse paradigm on a number of counts, the principal one being that we take state reduction as a physically relevant pro- cess. Given that time is a reflection of discontinuous quantum processes, then it is at root a discrete phenomenon and not continuous. Therefore we may use integers to represent time. According to our paradigm, at any given time n the universe will be in a unique state Ψ n , the state of the universe. This state cannot be regarded as either a Schrödinger picture state or a Heisenberg picture state. Exactly what it is is bound up with the concept of a stage, discussed below. The state Ψ n of the universe at a given time n cannot by itself represent the universe at that time in a complete way. In the conventional formulation of quantum mechanics, for example, we would need to add to our knowledge of the wave-function a statement of what the Hamiltonian was and also, what sort of experiment or measurement we were going to perform. All of this represents information I and rules R (laws of physics), effectively telling us how the wave-function evolves. This leads us to define the concept of a stage as follows. To a given time n we associate a unique stage Ω n of the universe, representing all possible attributes of the universe at that time.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>A stage consists of three things: the current state of the universe Ψ n , the current information content I n of the universe, and the current rules R n governing what happens next.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>We may write Ω n = Ω (Ψ n , I n , R n ) and assume that Ψ n is a vector in some fundamental Hilbert space H. We refer now to Peres&apos; discussion of the concept of quantum state preparation, test and outcome [2] as the template for how the quantum universe runs, meaning, how stages evolve. First of all, contrary to Schrödinger evolution , there can be no deterministic sequence of stages. Given stage Ω n , we cannot in general say with certainty what stage Ω n+1 will be. This is a fundamental feature of our paradigm and marks the difference between the notion of process time and block universe (or manifold) time. The principles of quantum mechanics should apply at the level of the universe as well as for subsystems. It is not that we cannot extract information about the future. The future is not there until it happens and this is the correct way to understand the uncertainty principle. The Kochen-Specker theorem [2] supports Bohr&apos;s view that we are not interfering with a preexisting momentum when we measure particle position, and vice-versa. Neither attribute of a particle system exists before we have specified the experiment testing the state of the particle. This is perhaps the hardest implication of quantum mechanics to accept.</p>

				<p>The quantum dynamics of the universe runs as follows. At time n, the current stage of the universe Ω n contains enough information I n for the rules R n to imply a generalized test (in the sense discussed by Peres [2]) Σ n+1 . This test is represented by some selfadjoint operator Σ n+1 in H. It is not clear at this time whether the rules should determine Σ n+1 classically, that is, in an algorithmic , deterministic way, or whether Σ n+1 is determined by (say) a form of quantum test itself. If Σ n+1 is determined classically then it is some function Σ of Ω n and we may write Σ n+1 = Σ (Ω n ) . The state of the universe Ψ n+1 in the next stage is now postulated to be one of the eigenstates of Σ n+1 with some eigenvalue λ n+1 (or set of eigenvalues if Σ n+1 factorizes into parts or if Σ n+1 is represented by more than one operator). The tests associated with stages will be extremely complex in principle, because the Hilbert space H is expected to be vast. A simple estimate of the minimum dimensionality of H may be based on the idea of associating one qubit with each Planck volume in the visible universe. This gives dim H 2 2×10 180 for three spatial dimensions and we expect it to be much bigger, if not infinite. In principle the number of potential tests will be of the order (dim H) 2 [2], which is where the rules R n come in. These will effectively pick out of this vast number of potential tests just one, Σ n+1 , and then the universe will jump into one if its eigenstates. The number of potential eigenstates may be vast, but one and only one of these occurs when the Universe jumps from stage Ω n to stage Ω n+1 , and this eigenstate is denoted by Ψ n+1 . The eigenvalues λ n+1 , test Σ n+1 , state Ψ n+1 and indeed Ω n are then convoluted with the old information content I n to form the new information content I n+1 . Likewise, the outcome Ψ n+1 and new information content I n+1 are convoluted with the old rules R n to give a new set of rules R n+1 , and then the new stage Ω n+1 becomes the new reality. The old stage Ω n now becomes unphysical and not even a memory. Any form of memory associated with the past resides in the new information content I n+1 alone. This may include discrete topological information relating various factor states in Ψ n+1 and how they orig- inated. Which one of the possible eigenstates of Σ n+1 occurs cannot be predicted, as this is the nature of the quantum process at work. However , a probability estimate can be given, assuming that the computational principles of quantum mechanics apply to the universe as well as to subsystems. The conditional probability P (Ψ n+1 = Θ|Ψ n ) that the state of the universe Ψ n+1 at time n + 1 is eigenstate Θ of Σ n+1 , given that the state at time n is Ψ n , is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P (Ψ n+1 = Θ|Ψ n ) = |(Θ, Ψ n )| 2 , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>assuming that all potential outcome states are normalized to unity. This probability estimate is valid only at time n, i.e. before the jump, and we may use it to discuss the potential future in terms of mixed states. Once the universe has jumped from Ω n to Ω n+1 , however, all probabilities alter and have to be revised.</p>

				<p>The dynamics is such that total probability always sums to unity, but it is not reversible.</p>

				<p>The apparent time reversal symmetry in (1) is more readily seen to be an artefact of the traditional Hilbert space notation if instead we write P (Ω n+1 |Ω n ) ≡ |(Ψ n+1 , Ψ n )| 2 . The direction of time is from Ω n to Ω n+1 and not vice-versa. Ω n+1 is an outcome of test Σ n+1 , which is determined by Ω n , whereas Ω n cannot be an outcome of any test determined by Ω n+1 . In fact, Ω n was an outcome of some test Σ n , which was determined by Ω n−1 .</p>

				<p>The direction of time is intrinsically that of information acquisition and information loss. Stage Ω n+1 has information content I n+1 which need not contain I n , and there is no algorithm which guarantees that Ω n+1 could be used to deduce what Ω n was, except in the exceptional circumstance that the universe were reversible, which is believed not to be the case on account of the second law of thermodynamics.</p>

				<p>The stages paradigm permits further refinement relevant to cosmology. There has been much speculation over the years concerning the discretization of space and time on Planck scales. It has been pointed out by various authors [3] that starting from discrete set models, the dimensions of emergent space in a continuum limit may be dynamically determined by, for example, the scale chosen.</p>

				<p>This raises the possibility that current speculations concerning brane universe dynamics are consistent with the stages paradigm, in that strings and branes, higher dimensional space and indeed general relativity are but emergent approximations to a completely quantum universe. The programme of quantizing gravity is from our perspective the wrong direction to come, as has been suggested recently [4]. In the stages paradigm, the quantum process of test and outcome gives a natural reason why time should be discrete. We might expect space also to be discrete, but a straightforward discretization of emergent continuous space would logically be the wrong thing to do without an analogous quantum mechanism. In fact, a natural &quot; lattice &quot; structure does exist within the stages paradigm. In any quantum theory, states in the Hilbert space may be either fully entangled or products of factor states. In standard quantum mechanics, factorization is a measure of classicity. To describe a state ψ combining an identifiable apparatus and an identifiable system under observation, we write ψ = Θ ⊗ ϕ, where Θ is the state of the apparatus and ϕ is the state of the system. Without such a factorization, a classical distinction between apparatus and system cannot be made. The origin of spatial discreteness may be indirectly associated with the degree of factorization of the state Ψ n of the universe at any given time. Information relating factor states in successive stages gives a mechanism for the generation of &quot; family trees &quot; , from which causal set structures can arise, and ultimately, emergent space. We propose the following schema for the cosmological history of the universe. Assume that the Hilbert space H of the universe has some enormous dimensionality, consisting of a direct product of a vast number of fundamental qubits. Qubits are reasonable to assume because fermions can be constructed from systems of qubits in the manner of Jordan and Wigner [5] and fermions can be used to build up all types of particles. In addition , qubits represent the most elementary yes/no kind of quantum information, and information processing is at the heart of our paradigm. Suppose further that the stages paradigm holds, and that the universe jumps from stage to stage in the quantum way discussed above. Imagine now that the state of the universe had once been completely entangled , i.e., consisted of one factor, and had stayed like that over an enormous number of jumps. During this epoch, which may be regarded as pre-big bang, there would have been no possibility whatsoever of any classical structures such as space emerging, and would truly have been a time of chaos in the original, ancient world sense of the word. It is not unreasonable to imagine that a non-zero probability existed that the universe would sooner or later jump into a state which was the product of two or more factors. Factorizable states belong to a subset of measure zero in the set of all states, and therefore, a jump from complete entanglement to a factorizable state would be highly improbable, except if the rules R n at a given stage made it more likely. The empirical fact is that the current state of the universe does appear to be factorizable, and so we may assume that this process occurred. Moreover, it is possible to imagine that the rules and information content would then change in such a way as to make the number of factors in succeeding stages increase monotonically. This would signal the start of a quantum big bang, and indirectly, the expansion of space.</p>

				<p>In such a scenario, we may imagine that the onset of factorization was followed by an epoch in which the number of factors in successive states Ψ n of the universe increased exponentially with jump time n, which would be a period analogous to inflation. However, there need not be any notion of Planck scale in this picture. The conventional Big Bang has to be understood as something associated with emergence, which would occur only long after the original quantum big bang. The individual factor states in the factorizable state of the universe during inflation could themselves be perhaps highly entangled states of vast numbers of qubits. Further, entangled states can exhibit nonlocal correlations, the EPR paradox being a good example. Such correlations within states in the early universe might resolve the horizon problem in cosmology, accounting for the observed isotropy and homogeneity of the current epoch. A feature of this paradigm is that there is never any singularity associated with the quantum big bang. The possibility arises of having many quantum big bangs and quantum big crunches (a return to total entanglement ), and also many separate expanding universes, each regarded as an isolated set of factors in the state of the universe. Each of these sub-universes would be associated with its own emergent spacetime and there might be no reason to link them. If indeed the current information content I n contained no information linking sub-universes at time n then they would remain separate ever after, there being no mechanism (by definition) for re-entangling them at any future time. This is the quantum analogue of the heat death of the universe. The variable number of factors in the state Ψ n of the universe at time n gives a time dependent lattice Λ n called the factor lattice.</p>

				<p>An element Ψ i n of this lattice should not be identified with any discrete point in physical space, as might be thought. The relationship between the factor lattice and conventional spacetime is more subtle on a number of counts, which we will discuss elsewhere. An important feature here is that the factor lattice can easily encode the sort of quantum non-locality observed in violations of Bell inequalities , and this should manifest itself in the emergent limit in such a way that it did not appear ubiquitous in classical spacetime, but only evident when looked for in careful and sophisticated experiments. Given that Ψ n</p>

				<p><formula>= Ψ 1 n ⊗Ψ 2 n ⊗. . .⊗Ψ Nn n , where</formula></p>

				<p>N n is the current number of factors, one way of defining the current classicity κ n of the universe would be κ n ≡ ln N n / ln N, where N is the number of qubits, assumed finite. Then clearly 0 κ n 1. The lower bound zero corresponds to a fully entangled, nonclassical universe, whilst κ n = 1 corresponds to total classicity with no quantum entanglements whatsoever. The current epoch of the universe appears to be one for which κ n is close to, but not yet, unity. The evidence for this is the existence of a stable (and expanding ) classical emergent space, but with a residuum of quantum processes and correlations still active in the universe. Given a high level of classicity, we may discuss quantum fields in terms analogous to those used by Jordan and Wigner to construct fermions. Consider some vast but finite subspace H ′ ≡ {H 1 ⊗ H 2 ⊗ . . . ⊗ H Nn } of factor qubit spaces in stage Ω n , which are not linked via the information content I n to other factor qubit spaces in H at time n. Then to all intents and purposes H ′ represents some isolated sub-universe within the total universe associated with H. We may now construct fully anticommuting (fermionic) quantum field operators acting on states in H ′ in the fashion of Jordan and Wigner [5], and thence construct relativistic quantum field operators on the emergent energy-momentum space and emergent spacetime associated with H ′ . The details will be given in forthcoming papers. Some final comments: the stages paradigm presupposes the existence of a cosmic time in the universe, because quantum information acquisition is inherently incompatible with closed timelike curves. However, this time is &quot; multi-fingered &quot; , in that different factors in a given state Ψ n may jump to new factors in Ψ n+1 which are uncorrelated with each other, and indeed, some factor states might not change from one stage to the next. The overall picture is one of a quantum cellular automaton network structure with ever changing topology predicated on quantum outcomes [1], leading to a causal set structure [3]. The information content I n is a form of memory which tracks over time the possibility of correlations between various factor states, from which emergent structures such as continuous space with a metric can be generated . The rules R n are currently not understood in any significant way. How they might change in time is related to the question of how the laws of physics might change in time, and understanding them is a challenge for the future, as is the difficult problem of emergence.</p>

				<p>Finally, the stages paradigm is based on the notion of process time. Therefore, only one stage (known as the present) can be assumed certain in any discussion. Relative to a given present, both the past and future do not exist.</p>


			<note place="foot">arXiv:quant-ph/0203020v1 5 Mar 2002</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>Acknowledgement: J.E. thanks the EP- SRC (UK) for a research studentship.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Jaroszkiewicz, arXiv:quant- ph/0105013 v2</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum Theory: Concepts and Methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Peres</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publish- ers</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Meyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">M. Requardt</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="524260" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Barcelo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Visser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Jordan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Wigner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Physik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>J. D. Bjorken and S.D. Drell</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1928" />
			<publisher>Relativistic Quantum Fields McGraw-Hill Inc</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">631</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
