<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Comment on &quot; Vector and axial-vector mesons at finite temperature &quot;</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-01-13">13 Jan 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Dey</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Presidency College</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700 073</postCode>
									<settlement>Calcutta</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">V</forename>
								<forename type="middle">L</forename>
								<surname>Eletsky</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Theoretical and Experimental Physics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>B.Cheremushkinskaya 25</addrLine>
									<postCode>117218</postCode>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">B</forename>
								<forename type="middle">L</forename>
								<surname>Ioffe</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Theoretical and Experimental Physics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>B.Cheremushkinskaya 25</addrLine>
									<postCode>117218</postCode>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Comment on &quot; Vector and axial-vector mesons at finite temperature &quot;</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-01-13">13 Jan 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>It is shown, that the correlators of vector and axial-vector currents at finite temperature T in order T 2 reduce to mixing of vacuum V V and AA correlators with universal mixing coefficient given by the parameter ε = T 2 /6F 2 π , unlike the claim in the recent paper by Mallik and Sarkar [1].</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>In a recent paper [1] Mallik and Sarkar considered vector and axial-vector correlators at finite temperature in order T 2 . Earlier, the same problem was treated in our paper [2]. Mallik and Sarkar criticize the calculation method used in [2] and claim, that the results obtained in that paper are wrong. In this comment we show that this is not true. Let us remind shortly the basic results of [2].</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The thermal correlators (J = V, A) C J µν (q, T ) = i d 4 xe iqx n n|T {J a µ (0 ) , J a ν (x)}exp[(Ω − H)/T ]|n (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>were considered at low T in order T 2 . Here e −Ω = n n|exp(−H/T )|n and the sum is over the full set of eigenstates of Hamiltonian H. The currents V a µ and A a µ are isovector vector and axial currents. The validity of the chiral effective theory (CET) – a low energy consequence of QCD – was taken as granted. The explicit form of the Hamiltonian was not specified. It was assumed, that pions are massless and current algebra relations were exploited. In the sum over n in order T 2 it is sufficient to account for the contribution of two lowest states – vacuum and one-pion. Then the factor T 2 arises simply from the one-pion phase space.</p>

				<p>The contributions of higher excited states are suppressed as T k , k &gt; 2 or exponentially, ∼ e −m h /T . It was found [2] that in order T</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 (at q 2 = −Q 2 , Q 2 ≫ T 2 ) C V µν (q, T ) = (1 − ε)C V µν (q, 0) + εC A µν (q, 0) (2) C A µν (q, T ) = (1 − ε)C A µν (q, 0) + εC V µν (q, 0), (3) a) b)</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>


				</figure>

				<p>energy correction to correlator. Solid lines -mean vacuum correlator, dashed lines – pion propagator. a) Pion is virtual; b) pion is from thermal bath. where ε = T 2 /6F 2 π , F π = 91MeV is the pion decay constant. Therefore, in order T 2 the thermal V and A correlators reduce to their vacuum values, but in the vector correlator there appears the admixture of the axial one and vice versa. The positions of the poles (and other singularities) of thermal correlators are the same as at T = 0 (up to appearance of A poles in V channel and vice versa). The residues of the poles are shifted in a universal way given by the parameter ε. In ref.[3] more detailed arguments were presented and the results were generalized to correlators of other currents (baryon, etc.).</p>

				<p>In their consideration of the same problem, Mallik and Sarkar obtained the equation, equivalent to (2) with a difference, that mixing coefficients are not universal and depend on the form of low-energy Lagrangian. They assumed that the terms containing ρ, a 1 , ω and f 1 fields are added to the standard CET Lagrangian. Then, in their calculation of C V µν (q, T ) (2), besides the factor 1 − ε in front of C V µν (q, 0) there appears a term proportional to g 2 1 , where g 1 is the ρwπ coupling constant. However, embedding of the ρwπ interaction term into effective low-energy Lagrangian is not legitimate. As can be easily proved (using eq.(2.22) of [1]) this term violates SU(2) × SU(2) chiral symmetry, leads to appearance of additionaal term in the expression for axial current and, consequently, violates current algebra relations. Moreover, famous low-energy theorems, which follow from current algebra (Goldberger-Treiman, Adler, Gross-Lelwellyn-Smith,</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Weinberg sum rules etc.) would also be violated if such a term persists. Therefore, the disagreement of the Mallik and Sarkar results with eq.2 comes entirely from illegitimate form of the low-energy Lagrangian used in [1]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. If the ρwπ interaction term in the Lagrangian is omitted, then the results of [1] exactly coincide with eq.2, found in [2]. Now, a few words about the criticizm of our paper [2], given in [1]. It was claimed in [1], that the self-energy diagrams on Fig.1 (Fig.1b in [1], Fig.1c,d in [2]) were ignored in [2]. In fact, there are two types of such diagrams: 1) Fig.1a, where the pion is virtual. Such diagram corresponds to vacuum correlator, is T -independent and is accounted in C µν (q, 0) in (2),(3); 2) Fig.1b, where pion comes from thermal bath and is on the mass shell. For a pion on mass shell its interaction vertex is proportional to momentum (Adler theorem). Therefore, the contribution of the Fig.1b diagram is ∼ T 4 and may be omitted. (We repeat here the arguments of ref.[2] for clarity).</p>

				<p>To conclude: the results, no correlator mixing, obtained in [1] are valid only for the model Lagrangian used in [1], but not for QCD and its consequense -low energy chiral effective theory (CET). On the other hand our paper [2] based on QCD and CET shows correlator mixing at low temperature, The thermal V and A correlators mixing in order T 2 -eq. (2),(3) was confirmed in recent paper [4]. Hence the claim of the authors in [1] that our paper [2] is &quot; incorrect &quot; is not correct.</p>


			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-ph/0212288v2 13 Jan 2003</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Mallik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Sarkar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur.Phys.J.C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">445</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Dey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Eletsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Ioffe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Eletsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Ioffe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">620</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="252" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Urban</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Buballa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Wambach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">042002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
