<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">CUBIC FREE FIELD THEORY</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Boris</forename>
								<surname>Pioline</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>pioline@lpthe.jussieu.fr</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">LPTHE</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>UniversitésParis6et7, 4placeJussieu</addrLine>
									<postCode>75252</postCode>
									<settlement>Pariscedex</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">CUBIC FREE FIELD THEORY</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>arXiv:hep-th/0302043v2 27 Feb 2003</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We point out the existence of a class of non-Gaussian yet free &quot; quantum field theories &quot; in 0+0 dimensions, based on a cubic action classified by simple Lie groups. A &quot; three-pronged &quot; version of the Wick theorem applies. (LPTHE-P03-01, hep-th/0302043)</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>With the exception of a few integrable models in low dimension, much of what we know of quantum field theory relies on perturbation around a free theory with a Gaussian action S = φ t Qφ/2. Such a theory is free in the sense that the generating functional of connected diagrams</p>

				<p><formula>e iW (J ) ¯ h = [dφ i ] exp i ¯ h S(φ) + φ t J (1.1)</formula></p>

				<p>is given exactly by the semiclassical, or saddle point, approximation to the integral above,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e iW (J ) ¯ h = 1 det(Q) exp − i 2¯ h J t Q −1 J (1.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The quantum effective action, defined as the Legendre transform of W (J), is therefore identical to the classical action. Interactions can then be introduced by perturbing this Gaussian point by higher powers of the field φ; their effects are computed efficiently by use of Wick&apos;s theorem, which follows immediatly from Eq. (1.2). One may think that the exactness of the semiclassical approximation be a defining property of Gaussian theories. Our goal in this gong-note is to point out that there exist non-Gaussian theories which satisfy the same property. Indeed, consider the simple &quot; action &quot; of four variables, S = C φ 1 φ 2 φ 3 /φ 0 . As first observed by Kazhdan in [1], the Legendre transform of S(φ) in all variables reproduces a similar function again,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C φ 1 φ 2 φ 3 φ 0 + φ t J {φ i } = J 1 J 2 J 3 C J 0 (1.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The &quot; path &quot; integral (1.1) has therefore a single saddle point whose value is the same as the classical action up to an inversion of C. Furthermore, an elementary computation using the Fourier transform of Dirac&apos;s delta function repetitively shows that, for an appropriate choice of the integration measure, the exact generating functional W is equal to its saddle point approximation, [dφ 0123 ]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ 0 exp i ¯ h C φ 1 φ 2 φ 3 ¯ hφ 0 + φ t J = ¯ h 2 J 0 C exp i ¯ h J 1 J 2 J 3 C J 0 (1.4) After a further Legendre transform, the quantum effective action is therefore equal to the classical action, as in the case of a Gaussian action.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In view of this small miracle, one may ask whether other non-Gaussian actions give rise to free quantum theories as well 1 . A necessary requirement is that there should exist exactly one saddle point for any current J, hence the differential dS should be of index one. A possible choice is to take S(φ i ) to be an homogeneous polynomial of degree 3, divided by an extra variable φ 0 so that the total degree is 2. One is thus led to the classification of cubic forms I 3 (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ i=1...n ) = C ijk φ i φ j φ k /6 such that the Fourier transform of exp(iI 3 (φ)/φ 0 ) be equal to exp(iI 3 (J)/J 0 ), possibly up to a one-loop measure factor. In particular, the Legendre transform of I 3 (φ)/φ 0 should be equal to I 3 (J)/J 0 , as in our example (1.3) above.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This problem has been solved recently in a more general context by Etingof, Kazhdan and Polishchuk [2]. They found that the cubic forms I 3 (φ) satisfying the property above fall into one of six cases, labeled by simple Lie groups,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(i) D n≥4 : I 3 = φ 1 (φ 2 φ 3 + φ 4 φ 5 + . . . + φ n−2 φ n−1 ) ; (ii) E 6 : I 3 = det(φ), with φ a 3 × 3 matrix; (iii) E 7 : I 3 = Pfaffian(φ), with φ an antisymmetric 6 × 6 matrix;</trash>

					<figDesc>(iv) E 8 : I 3 = φ 3 | 1 , with φ a 27 representation of E 6 and I 3 the singlet in the cubic power of 27;</figDesc>
					<trash>(v) F 4 : I 3 = det(φ)/2, with φ a symmetric 3 × 3 matrix; (vi) G 2 : I 3 = φ 3 /(3</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>√ 3), with φ a single real number.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Furthermore, for each of these cases, one can find a measure factor µ such that the Fourier transform of µ exp(iI 3 (φ)/φ 0 ) in all φ 0 , φ i variables is exactly given by its one-loop saddle point approximation, and again of the type above (see [2] for details).</p>

				<p>The assignment of a simple Lie group to each cubic form in the list above may seem arbitrary, yet it stems from standard relations between Jordan algebras, Jordan triple systems and the Tits-Kantor-Koecher construction of Lie algebras (physicists may read e.g. [3]). Recall that symplectic groups Sp(2n) admit a so-called metaplectic or oscillator representation in the space of functions ϕ(x i ) in n variables, with infinitesimal generators E ij = ∂ i ∂ j , F ij = x i x j , H ij = ∂ i x j + x j ∂ i (1.5) where x i , ∂ j satisfy the Heisenberg relations [∂ i , x j ] = δ ij . The F generators form a commuting subalgebra which can be exponentiated into multiplication by a Gaussian character, χ f = exp(if ij x i x j ). On the other hand, the Weyl reflection W that exchanges E ij and F ij is the Fourier transform with respect to all x i . The closure of (1.5) can ultimately be related to the fact that the Gaussian character χ f is covariant under Fourier transform W . This construction yields the unitary representation of Sp(2n) (or its double cover, rather) of minimal dimension, also called the minimal representation of Sp(2n). A similar construction can be carried out for any simple Lie group G in the split real form (see [4], [5] for details). Physically, it amounts to quantize a quantum mechanical system whose phase space is the coadjoint orbit of a nilpotent (in particular non diagonalizable) element of G. The generators acting on the wave functions take a form similar to (1.5) above, and their closure is ultimately related to the invariance of the cubic character exp(iI 3 (φ i )/φ 0 ). This construction has been recently used to produce new quantum mechanical models with enhanced conformal symmetry [6]. It is also the first step in constructing automorphic theta series for non-symplectic groups, which have been proposed to arise in the quantization of the eleven-dimensional BPS supermembrane [7, 5].</p>

				<p>Returning to the list of admissible cubic forms (i)-(vi) above, we see that we now have a set of non-Gaussian free &quot; field theories &quot; , albeit in finite dimension. The Wick theorem can be straightforwardly generalized by differentiating Eq. (1.4) with respect to J i on either side, and now involves &quot; three-pronged &quot; propagators, or more aptly junctions, φ i φ j φ k = i ¯ hJ 0 C ijk (1.6) except for propagators involving the distinguished variable φ 0 . Notice that it is no longer possible to set the source J 0 = 0 after differentiating, due to the poles appearing in the junction. It may however be sensible to set it equal to the quantum ¯ h. Under this assumption, a &quot; three-pronged &quot; version of Wick&apos;s theorem yields e.g.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ 2 1 φ 2 2 φ 3 φ 4 = − (4C 123 C 124 + 2C 122 C 134 + C 114 C 223 + +C 113 C 224 + 2C 112 C 234 ) (1.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>One may therefore perturb away from this free non-Gaussian point and carry out a standard perturbative analysis. Despite these attractive features, it should be noted that these free theories unfortunately seem to exist only in finite dimension (arbitrarily large in the D n case). Indeed, in contrast to the Gaussian case, there is no notion of tensor product of cubic forms that would allow to construct field theoretical models from finite dimensional building blocks. This is perhaps related to similar issues arising in attempts to quantize Nambu dynamics [8], in turn related to the quantization of the topological membrane [9]. Indeed, Nambu dynamics replaces the near- Gaussian action S = Hdt − pdq on the wordline of a particle by a cubic action S = HdKdt − φ 1 dφ 2 ∧ dφ 3 on the worldsheet of a string, where H and K are a pair of Hamiltonians generating the motion. It would be very interesting if a suitable modification of the cubic topological action φ 1 dφ 2 ∧ dφ 3 , possibly by introducing a new coordinate φ 0 , led to a free theory along the lines of this note. This may prove an important step in the quantization of the membrane, and of the associated non-Abelian fivebrane.</p>


			<note place="foot" n="1"> Earlier discussions of self-reciprocal functions have been brought to my attention, see e.g [10] and references [75-80] therein.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>I am grateful to D. Kazhdan for introducing me to non-Gaussian Poisson resummation, to A.</p>
				<p>Waldron for continued collaboration on this subject, and to K. Scharnhorst for comments on an earlier version of this note. It is a pleasure to thank the other organizers of the Carg ese 2002 ASI for an inspiring and refreshing session.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The minimal representation of D 4 , in Operator Agebras, Unitary representations, enveloping algebras and invariant theories, A. Connes et al eds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Kazhdan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Progress in Mathematics 92</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Birkhä</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Etingof</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kazhdan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Polishchuk</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Selecta</forename>
				<surname>Math</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page">27</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gunaydin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Koepsell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Nicolai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">221</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">57</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kazhdan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Savin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Israel</forename>
				<surname>Math</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conf. Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">209</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kazhdan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Pioline</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Waldron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">226</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Pioline</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Waldron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Pioline</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Nicolai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Plefka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Waldron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">036</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Pioline. and A. Waldron, to appear</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Takhtajan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<editor>H. Awata, M. Li, D. Minic and T. Yoneya</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1609906248</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">013</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Pioline</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">025010</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Scharnhorst</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
