<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-02-24">24 Feb 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Chuan-Hung</forename>
								<surname>Chen</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Academia Sinica</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>115</postCode>
									<settlement>Taipei</settlement>
									<country>Taiwan, Republic of China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">C</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
								<surname>Geng</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>300</postCode>
									<settlement>Hsinchu</settlement>
									<country>Taiwan, Republic of China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Theory Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">TRIUMF</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>4004 Wesbrook Mall</addrLine>
									<postCode>V6T 2A3</postCode>
									<settlement>Vancouver</settlement>
									<region>B.C</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">I-Lin</forename>
								<surname>Ho</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>300</postCode>
									<settlement>Hsinchu</settlement>
									<country>Taiwan, Republic of China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-02-24">24 Feb 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">(Dated: December 28, 2013)</note>
					<note>Forward-backward Asymmetry in K + → π + ℓ + ℓ −</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We study the forward-backward asymmetries in the decays of K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − (ℓ = e and µ) in the presence of scalar or tensor terms. We find that with the scalar (tensor) type interaction the asymmetry can be up to O(10 −3) (O(10 −1)) and arbitrary large for the electron and muon modes, respectively, without conflict with the experimental data. We also discuss the cases in the minimal supersymmetric standard model where the scalar terms can be induced. In particular we show that the asymmetry in K + → π + µ + µ − can be as large as O(10 −3) in the large tan β limit, which can be tested in future experiments such as CKM at Fermilab.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>I. INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>The flavor-changing neutral current (FCNC) processes of K ± → π ± ℓ + ℓ − (ℓ = e, µ) are suppressed and dominated by the long distance (LD) contributions involving one photon exchange [1, 2, 3, 4] in the standard model (SM). The decays have been successfully described within the framework of chiral perturbation theory (ChPT) [5] including electroweak interactions at O(p 6 ) [6] in terms of a vector interaction form factor fixed by experiments. However, it is important to compare the measurements in the two decays to see if there are differences in the form factors since they would indicate new physics.</p>

				<p>Recently, the vector form factor has been determined by the high precision measurement on the electron mode by the BNL-E865 Collaboration [7] at the Brookhaven Alternating Gradient Synchrotron (AGS) with a sample of 10300 events and branching ratio (BR) of [2.94 ± 0.05(stat) ± 0.13(syst) ± 0.05(theor)] × 10 −7 . For the muon channel, it was first observed by BNL-E787 [8] at AGS with the measured branching ratio being (5.0 ± 0.4 ± 0.9) × 10 −8 , which is too small to accommodate within the SM. However, two subsequent experiments of BNL-E865 [9] and HyperCP (E871) [10] have measured that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>BR(K + → π + µ + µ − ) = (9.22±0.60±0.49) and (9.8±1.0±0.5)×10 −8 , respectively, which are</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>all consistent with the model-independent analysis based on the data of BR(K + → π + e + e − ).</p>

				<p>However, there are still rooms for new physics, particularly in the muon mode.</p>

				<p>In Refs. [11, 12], P and T violating muon polarization effects in K + → π + µ + µ − were discussed in various theoretical models.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we study the forward-backward asymmetry (FBA) in the decay of K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − with ℓ = e or µ. It is known that the FBA in K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − violates P like the longitudinal lepton polarization but it vanishes in the SM and can only exist if there is a scalar type interaction. In the multi-Higgs doublet models such as the most popular two-Higgs doublet (2HDM) of type II [13], where two Higgs scalar doublets (H u and H d ) are coupled to up-and down-type quarks, respectively, the scalar type of four fermion operators ¯ s R d L ¯ ℓℓ can be generated at the loop level [14, 15]. This type of operators is particularly interesting in the minimal supersymmetric standard model (MSSM) [16] since it receives an enormous enhancement for the large ratio of v u /v d = tan β where v u(d) is the vacuum expectation value of the Higgs doublet H u(d) . Recently, there has been considerable interest for the large tan β effects in B decays such as B → µ + µ − and B → Kµ + µ − [14, 15, 17]. In the report, we will discuss the large tan β scenario in the MSSM for K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − .</p>

				<p>The paper is organized as follows. In Sec. II, we present the general analysis for the forward-backward asymmetries in K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − (ℓ = e and µ). In Sec. III, we discuss the experimental constraints on the asymmetries. We estimate the asymmetries in the MSSM in Sec. IV. We present our conclusions in Sec. V.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. GENERAL ANALYSIS</head>

				<p>We write the decay as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>K + (p K ) → π + (p π )ℓ + (p)ℓ − (¯ p) , (1) where p K , p π , p and ¯ p are four-momenta of K + , π + , ℓ + and ℓ − , respectively. The most</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>general invariant amplitude for the decay can be written as [11, 12, 18] M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>= F S ¯ ℓℓ + iF P ¯ ℓγ 5 ℓ + F V p µ K ¯ ℓγ µ ℓ + F A p µ K ¯ ℓγ µ γ 5 ℓ , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where F S , F P , F V and F A are scalar, pseudo-scalar, vector and axial-vector form factors, respectively. The differential decay rate in the K + rest frame is given by [11]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d 2 Γ dE d ¯ E = 1 2 4 π 3 m K |F S | 2 1 2 (s − 4m 2 l ) + |F P | 2 1 2 s + |F V | 2 m 2 K (2E ¯ E − 1 2 s) + |F A | 2 m 2 K (2E ¯ E − 1 2 s + 2m 2 l ) +2Re(F S F * V )m l m K (E − ¯ E) + Im(F P F * A )m l (m 2 π − m 2 K − s) , (3) where m l is the lepton mass, E( ¯ E) is the energy of µ + (µ − ) and s = (p + ¯ p) 2 = 2(m 2 l + E ¯ E − p · ¯ p</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is the invariant mass of the dilepton system. In terms of the invariant mass and the angle θ between the three-momentum of the kaon and the three-momentum of the ℓ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− in the dilepton rest frame, we can rewrite Eq. (3) as d 2 Γ ds d cos θ = 1 2 8 π 3 m 3 K · β l λ 1 2 (s) |F S | 2 sβ 2 l + |F P | 2 s + |F V | 2 1 4 λ(s)(1 − β 2 l cos 2 θ) + |F A | 2 1 4 λ(s)(1 − β 2 l cos 2 θ) + 4m 2 K m 2 l +Re(F S F * V )2m l β l λ 1 2 (s) cos θ + Im(F P F * A )2m l (m 2 π − m 2 K − s) , (4) where λ(s) = m 4 K + m 4 π + s 2 − 2m 2 π s − 2m 2 K s − 2m 2 π m 2 K and β l = (1 − 4m 2 l /s) 1 2 with s and cos θ bounded by 4m 2 l ≤ s ≤ (m K − m π ) 2 , −1 ≤ cos θ ≤ 1 . (5) Here, we have used that E = s + m 2 K − m 2 π + β l λ 1 2 (s) cos θ 4m K , ¯ E = s + m 2 K − m 2 π − β l λ 1 2 (s) cos θ 4m K . (6) By integrating the angle θ in Eq. (4), we obtain dΓ ds = 1 2 8 π 3 m 3 K · β l λ 1 2 (s) |F S | 2 2sβ 2 l + |F p | 2 2s + |F V | 2 1 3 λ(s)(1 + 2m 2 l s ) + |F A | 2 1 3 λ(s)(1 + 2m 2 l s ) + 8m 2 K m 2 l + Im(F P F * A )4m l (m 2 π − m 2 K − s) . (7) From Eq. (4) and the definition of the forward-backward asymmetry A F B (s) ≡ 1 0 d cos θ d 2 Γ dsd cos θ − 0 −1 d cos θ d 2 Γ dsd cos θ 1 0 d cos θ d 2 Γ dsd cos θ + 0 −1 d cos θ d 2 Γ dsd cos θ , (8) we find that A F B (s) = 1 2 8 π 3 m 3 K · 2m l β 2 l λ(s)Re(F S F * V ) dΓ ds −1 . (9) As seen from Eq. (9), to</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>get a nonzero value of A F B , it is necessary to have a scalar interaction. However, in the SM the contributions from F S to the decay widths of K + → π + e + e − and K + → π + µ + µ − are about 7 and 4 orders of magnitude smaller than those from F V [19, 20], respectively, and therefore the forward-backward asymmetries are expected to be vanishingly small.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. EXPERIMENTAL CONSTRAINTS</head>

				<p>To study the experimental constraints on A F B in K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − , we consider the amplitude adopted in Ref. [7]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>;</figDesc>
					<trash>M = αG F 4π f V P µ ¯ ℓγ µ ℓ + G F m K f S ¯ ℓℓ + G F f T P µ q ν m K ¯ ℓσ µν ℓ (10) where f V,S,T</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are dimensionless form factors of vector, scalar, and tensor interactions, respectively , P = p K + p π and q = p K − p π . It is clear that, in Eq. (10), the vector term arises from the one photon exchange in the SM, which gives the dominant contribution to the decay rate, whereas the scalar and tensor ones from some new physics beyond the SM [21].</p>

				<p>For the form factor f V , we take the form derived in the ChPT [6]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, given by f V (s) = a + + b + s m 2 K + ω ππ (s) , (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where a + and b + are free parameters and ω ππ is the contribution from a pion loop diagram given in Ref. [6]. The experimental measurement on K + → π + e + e − at BNL-E865 [7] has determined the parameters of a + and b + to be −0.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>587 ± 0.010 and −0.655 ± 0.044, respectively. The scalar and tensor form factors in Eq. (10) for K + → π + e + e − are also constrained by the experiment [7]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the results are that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|f S | &lt; 6.6 × 10 −5 or |f T | &lt; 3.7 × 10 −4 (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for the existence of either scalar or tensor interaction. We note that so far there are no similar constraints on f S,T for K + → π + µ + µ − and they can be quite different for the two channels in theoretical models.</p>

				<p>It is easy to see that the amplitude in Eq. (10) can be simplified to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M = αG F 4π f ′ V P µ ¯ ℓγ µ ℓ + G F m K f ′ s ¯ ℓℓ (13) with f ′ V = f V − 8πim l αm K f T , f ′ S = f S − iβ l λ 1 2 (s) cos θ m 2 K f T . (14)</trash>

					<figDesc>By comparing the amplitude in Eq. (13) with the general one in Eq. (2), we get</figDesc>
					<trash>F V = αG F 2π f ′ V , F S = G F m K f ′ S , F P,A = 0 . (15) From Eqs. (4), (7) and (15), we obtain d 2 Γ ds d cos θ = G 2 F 2 8 π 3 m 3 K · β l λ 1 2 (s) |f V | 2 α 2 16π 2 λ(s)(1 − β 2 l cos 2 θ) + |f S | 2 sβ 2 l m 2 K +|f T | 2 sλ(s) m 2 K (cos 2 θ + 4m 2 l s sin 2 θ) + Re(f * V f S ) αm l m K π β l λ 1 2 (s) cos θ −Im(f V f * T ) αλ(s) π m l m K − Im(f S f * T )2sβλ 1 2 (s) cos θ (16) and dΓ ds = G 2 F 2 8 π 3 m 3 K · β l λ 1 2 (s) |f V | 2 α 2 λ(s) 4π 2 1 3 (1 + 2m 2 l s ) + 2 |f S | 2 sβ 2 l m 2 K + |f T | 2 2sλ(s) 3m 2 K (1 + 8m 2 l s ) − Im(f V f * T ) 2αλ(s) π m l m K . (17) Similarly, from Eq. (9) we find A F B (s) = G 2 F 2 8 π 3 m 3 K · β 2 l λ(s) Re(f * V f S ) αm l m K π − Im(f S f * T )2s dΓ ds −1 . (18) From Eq. (17</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>), one can check that the bound for f S or f T in Eq. (12) yields at most a few percent of the decay rate in K + → π + e + e − . Moreover, the last term in Eq. (17) is</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>negligible for the electron channel no matter whether f T is real or imaginary due to the electron mass suppression. However, for the muon case this term could be large and spoil the vector dominant mechanism if the imaginary part of f T is not small. In Figure 1, we show the differential decay rate and forward-backward asymmetry as functions of s = s/m</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>K for the decay of K + → π + e + e − by using the upper value of f S in Eq. (12) and f T = 0.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Figure 2, we display them by assuming that f s ∼ −4 × 10 −5 i and f T ∼ 2 × 10 −4 . As illustrations, in Figures 3 and 4 we also give dΓ/ dând A F B in K + → π + µ + µ − with the same sets of parameters as those in Figures 1 and 2, respectively. It is clear that, as mentioned early, since there is no direct strict experimental constraint on f S or f T in the muon mode,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A F B (K + → π + µ + µ</trash>

					<figDesc>− ) can be arbitrary large.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>IV. SUPERSYMMETRY</head>

				<p>In the MSSM, the one-loop effective down-type Yukawa interaction is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L ef f = ¯ d R Y d [H d + (ǫ 0 + ǫ Y Y † u Y u )H * u ]Q L + h.c., (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where Y u,d are 3 × 3 Yukawa coupling matrices and ǫ 0,Y are defined in Ref. [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, which are typically O(10 −2 ). In the diagonal Y d basis of (Y d ) ij = y d i δ ij , the interaction in Eq. (19) becomes L ef f mass = v d ¯ d i R y d i (1 + ǫ 0 tan β)δ ij + ǫ Y V † ik (y u k ) 2 V kj d j L + h.c., (20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where V is the CKM mixing matrix. By writing the effective Hamiltonian in the transition s → dℓ + ℓ − induced by the scalar type of interactions as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H ef f S = (C S ¯ s R d L + C ′ S ¯ d R s L ) ¯ ℓℓ , (21) from Eq. (20) one has that [15] C S = − G 2 F 4π 2 m s m l m 2 t ¯ λ t 21 tan 3 β (1 + ǫ 0 tan β) 1 M 2 A µ A f (x µL , x µR ) M 2 ˜ t L , C ′ S ≃ m d m s C S , (22) where A is the coupling of the soft-breaking trilinear term and ¯ λ t 21 = λ t 21 1 + tan β(ǫ 0 + ǫ Y y 2 t ) 1 + ǫ 0 tan β 2 f (x, y) = 1 x − y x ln x 1 − x − y ln y 1 − y , f (1, 1) = 1 2 , (23) with x µL = µ 2 M 2 ˜ t L , x µR = M 2 ˜ t R M 2 ˜ t L , λ t 21 = V * ts V td , (24) and y t being the top quark Yukawa coupling. By comparing Eq. (21) with Eq. (10) and using &lt; π| ¯ d(1 + γ 5 )s|K &gt; ≃ m 2 K m s f + , (25) we find f M SSM S ≃ − G 2 F 8π 2 m K m l m 2 t ¯ λ t 21 tan 3 β (1 + ǫ 0 tan β) 2 1 M 2 A µ A f (x µL , x µR ) M 2 ˜ t L , (26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have neglected the small terms related to y u 1,2 and used f + ≃ 1.</p>

				<p>To estimate the scalar form factor in Eq. (26) in the MSSM with large tan β, we take</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ǫ 0 ∼ 1/100 ≫ ǫ Y y 2 t and tan β = 50r and we get f M SSM S | ℓ=e ∼ 1.1 × 10 −9 (1 − ¯ ρ − i¯ η) r 3 (1 + 1 2 r) 2 200 GeV M A 2 µ A f (x µL , x µR ) M 2 ˜ t L , f M SSM S | ℓ=µ ∼ 2.3 × 10 −7 (1 − ¯ ρ − i¯ η) r 3 (1 + 1 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>r) 2 200 GeV M A 2 µ A f (x µL , x µR ) M 2 ˜ t L , (27) where ¯ ρ = ρ(1−λ 2 /2) and ¯ η = η(1−λ 2 /2) with λ, ρ and η being the Wolfenstein parameters of the CKM matrix V . Since the values of f M SSM S | ℓ=e,µ in Eq. (27) are about three and one orders of magnitude smaller than the experimental bound in Eq. (12) and thus the scalar contributions to the decay rates in the MSSM are negligible, respectively. Moreover, the scalar contribution to the FBA in K + → π + e + e − is also suppressed. However, in K + → π + µ + µ − the FBA can be as large as 10 −3 as shown in Figure 5 by using ¯ ρ ∼ 0.2 [22] and assuming r ∼ 1, M A ∼ 200 GeV and µAf (x µL , x µR )/M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 ˜ t L ∼ 2. We note that A F B (K + → π + µ + µ − ) = O(10</trash>

					<figDesc>−3 ) is accessible to future experiments such as the CKM at</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Fermilab, where the order of 10 5 events can be produced [23].</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. CONCLUSIONS</head>

				<p>We have studied the forward-backward asymmetries in the decays of K + → π + ℓ + ℓ − (ℓ = e and µ) in the most general amplitudes. In particular, we have explored the experimental constraints on the asymmetries by including the scalar and tensor interactions.</p>

				<p>We have found that with the scalar (tensor) term the asymmetry can be up to O</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(10 −3 ) (O(10</trash>

					<figDesc>−1 )) and arbitrary large for the electron and muon channels, respectively, without conflict with the experimental data. We have also discussed the asymmetries in the minimal</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>supersymmetric standard model where the scalar terms can be explicitly induced. We have shown that the FBA in K + → π + e + e − is negligibly small due to the electron mass suppression, but in K + → π + µ + µ − it can be as large as O(10 −3 ) with the large tan β, which can be tested in future experiments such as the CKM experiment at Fermilab.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 0.15 0.3 0.45 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 | | term | | term s ∧ I I d ( K e e ) / ds (GeV) Γ → π + + + − 10 23 × (a) ∧ f f S V 2 2 0 0.15 0.3 0.45 0 0.0005 0.001 0.0015 0.002 s ∧ I I FB A ( K e e ) → π + + + − (b) FIG. 1: (a) Differential decay rate and (b) forward-backward asymmetry for K + → π + e + e − as functions of s = s/m 2 K with f S = 6.6 × 10 −5 and f T = 0. 0 0.15 0.3 0.45 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 | | term | | term | | term s ∧ I I d ( K e e ) / ds (GeV) Γ → π + + + − 10 23 × (a) ∧ f f f T S V 2 2 2 0 0.15 0.3 0.45 0 0.04 0.08 0.12 s I I FB A ( K e e ) → π + + + − (b) ∧ FIG. 2: Same as Figure 1 but f S ∼ −4 × 10 −5 i and f T ∼ 2 × 10 −4 0.15 0.25 0.35 0.45 0.55 0 0.1 0.2 0.3 | | term | | term s ∧ I I d ( K ) / ds (GeV) Γ → π + + + − 10 22 × µ µ (a) ∧ f f V S 2 2 0.15 0.25 0.35 0.45 0.55 0 0.1 0.2 0.3 s ∧ I I FB A ( K ) → π + + + − µ µ (b) FIG. 3: Same as Figure 1 but for K + → π + µ + µ − . 0.15 0.25 0.35 0.45 0.55 0 0.1 0.2 0.3 | | term | | term | | term s ∧ I I d ( K ) / ds (GeV) Γ → π + + + − 10 22 × µ µ (a) ∧ f f fT S V 2 2 2 0.15 0.25 0.35 0.45 0.55 0 0.04 0.08 0.12 0.16 s ∧ I I FB A ( K ) → π + + + − µ µ (b) FIG. 4: Same as Figure 2 but for K + → π + µ + µ − . 0.15 0.25 0.35 0.45 0.55 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 s ∧ I I FB A ( K ) → π + + + − µ µ</trash>

					<head>MSSM 10 3</head>

					<figDesc>× FIG. 5: Forward-backward asymmetry in K + → π + µ + µ − as a function of s in the MSSM with large tan β.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:hep-ph/0302207v1 24 Feb 2003</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>We thank Drs. D.N. Gao and H.K. Park for useful communications and Prof. T. Han for encouragement and discussions. This work was supported in part by the National Science</p>
				<figure>
					<trash>Council of the Republic of China under Contract Nos. NSC-91-2112-M-001-053 and NSC- 91-2112-M-007-043.</trash>
				</figure>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Vainshtein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Yad. Fiz.Sov. J. Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">427</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Eilam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Scadron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2263</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Bergstrom</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Singer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2633" to="1568" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Lichard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">053007</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Ecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>De Rafael</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">291</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">692</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Appel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4482</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Adler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4756</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2580</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Park</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">111801</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Belanger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
				<surname>Geng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Turcotte</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">390</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">253</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Agrawal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Ng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Belanger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
				<surname>Geng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2383</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Higgs Hunter&apos;s Guide, SCIPP-89</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Gunion</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Aliev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. G Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">014005</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Hamzaoui</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Pospelov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Toharia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Babu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Kolda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>G. Isidori and A. Retico, J. High Energy Phys A.J. Buras et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="095005" to="001" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Martin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9709356</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yan</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>P.H. Chankowski and L. Slawianowska</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">094023</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Bobeth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>A. Dedes, H.K</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="054012" to="074014" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>A. Dedes, H.K</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Dreiner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Nierste</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Arnowitt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Lett. B Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>D.A. Demir, K.A. Olive and M.B. Voloshin</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251804" to="034015" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Belanger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
				<surname>Geng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2789</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Ecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>De Rafael</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<editor>G. Ecker and A. Pich, ibid. B366</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">303</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="665" to="189" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Gao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>private. communication</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Q</forename>
				<surname>Geng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">99</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Buras</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Dukes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">HyperCP Collaboration]</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
