<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Pauli Exclusion Principle and SU (2) vs. SO(3) in Loop Quantum Gravity</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-03">May 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">John</forename>
								<surname>Swain</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>email: john.swain@cern.ch</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Northeastern University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02115</postCode>
									<settlement>Boston</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Pauli Exclusion Principle and SU (2) vs. SO(3) in Loop Quantum Gravity</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-03">May 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">(Submitted for the Gravity Research Foundation Essay Competition, March 27, 2003)</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent attempts to resolve the ambiguity in the loop quantum gravity description of the quantization of area has led to the idea that j = 1 edges of spin-networks dominate in their contribution to black hole areas as opposed to j = 1/2 which would naively be expected. This suggests that the true gauge group involved might be SO(3) rather than SU (2) with attendant difficulties. We argue that the assumption that a version of the Pauli principle is present in loop quantum gravity allows one to maintain SU (2) as the gauge group while still naturally achieving the desired suppression of spin-1/2 punctures. Areas come from j = 1 punctures rather than j = 1/2 punctures for much the same reason that photons lead to macroscopic classically observable fields while electrons do not.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>I. INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>The recent successes of the approach to canonical quantum gravity using the Ashtekar variables have been numerous and significant. Among them are the proofs that area and volume operators have discrete spectra, and a derivation of black hole entropy up to an overall undetermined constant [1]. An excellent recent review leading directly to this paper is by Baez [2], and its influence on this introduction will be clear.</p>

				<p>The basic idea is that a basis for the solution of the quantum constraint equations is given by spin-network states, which are graphs whose edges carry representations j of SU(2).</p>

				<p>To a good approximation, the area A of a surface which intersects a spin network at i edges, each carrying an SU(2) label j is given in geometrized units (Planck length equal to unity) by A ≈ i 8πγ j i (j i + 1) (1) where γ is the Immirzi-Barbero parameter [3]. The most important microstates consistent with a given area are those for which j is as small as possible, which one would expect to be j min = 1/2. In this case, each contribution to the area corresponds to a spin j = 1/2 which can come in two possible m values of ±1/2. For n punctures, we have A ≈ 4π</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>√ 3γn and entropy S ≈ ln(2 n ) ≈ ln(2) 4π √ 3γ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A.</p>

				<p>Now looking outside loop quantum gravity for help, we can use Hawking&apos;s formula [4] for black hole entropy S = A/4 to get γ =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ln(2) π √ 3 and the smallest quantum of area is then 8πγ 1 2 ( 1 2 + 1) = 4 ln(2).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Physically this is very nice as it says that a black hole&apos;s horizon acquires area, to a good approximation, from the punctures of many spin network edges, each carrying a quantum of area 4 ln(2) and one &quot; bit &quot; of information – a vindication Wheeler&apos;s &quot; it from bit &quot; philosophy [5].</p>

				<p>Bekenstein&apos;s early intuition [6] that the area operator for black holes should have a discrete spectrum made of equal area steps (something not really quite true in loop quantum gravity in full generality) was followed by Mukhanov&apos;s observation [7] that the n th area state should have degeneracy k n with steps between areas of 4 ln(k) for k some integer ≥ 2 in order to reproduce the Hawking expression S = A/4. For k = 2 one would have the n th area state described by n binary bits.</p>

				<p>On the other hand, Hod [8] has argued that by looking at the quasinormal damped modes of a classical back hole one should be able to derive the quanta of area in a rather different way. The basic idea is to use the formula A = 16πM 2 relating area and mass of a black hole to get ∆A = 32πM∆M for the change in area accompanying an emission of energy ∆M. Nollert&apos;s computer calculations [9] of the asymptotic frequency ω of the damped normal modes gave ω ≈ 0.4371235/M, so setting ω = ∆M one finds ∆A ≈ 4.39444. It is tempting then to conclude that perhaps ∆A = 4 ln(3). Motl [10] later showed that this is indeed correct, and not just a fortuitous numerical coincidence.</p>

				<p>Since then, Dreyer [11] has pointed out that one might well expect ∆A ≈ 4 ln(3) instead of ∆A ≈ 4 ln(2) if the spin network edges contributing to the area of a black hole didn&apos;t carry j = 1/2, but rather j = 1. In this case j min would be 1 rather than 1/2, there would be three possible m values, and area elements would be described not by binary &quot; bits &quot; , but by trinary &quot; trits &quot; . (See also [12]). This also suggests that perhaps the correct gauge group is not SU(2) but SO(3), although this could complicate the inclusion of fermions in the theory.</p>

				<p>Corichi has recently argued [13] that one might arrive at the conclusion that j min = 1 by suggesting that one should think of a conserved fermion number being assigned to each spin- 1/2 edge. Adding or losing an edge&apos;s worth of area would have to mean that at some point a spin-1/2 edge would be essentially dangling in the bulk (i.e. not imbuing the horizon surface with area) and this should not be allowed. If edges carried j = 1 one could imagine coupling the edge to a fermion-antifermion pair and this would locally solve the fermion number problem. This is quite appealing as one might then think of the loss of an element of area with accompanying fermion-antifermion production in Hawking radiation as the detachment of a spin-1 edge from the horizon which then couples to an f ¯ f pair. As Corichi [13] points out: &quot; the existence of j = 1/2 edges puncturing the horizon is not forbidden . . . , but they must be suppressed. Thus, one needs a dynamical explanation of how exactly the entropy contribution is dominated by the edges with the dynamical allowed value, namely j = 1. &quot;</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. THE EXCLUSION PRINCIPLE</head>

				<p>The point of this essay is to suggest that one might want to assume that a version of the spin-statistics theorem (or, equivalently, the Pauli exclusion principle) applies to loop quantum gravity. More precisely, it could be the case that no more than two punctures of j = 1/2, each with differing m values, may puncture a given surface. In this case, the dominance of j = 1 punctures (even though j = 1/2 is allowed) is very natural: if only a maximum of two spin-1/2 edges can puncture any surface then for large numbers of punctures one would have an effective j min = 1 despite the gauge group being SU(2).</p>

				<p>The spin-statistics theorem as usually formulated and proven (to the extent that one rigorously proves anything in quantum field theory!), is, of course, for matter fields in a background spacetime usually assumed to be flat. It is not entirely clear what sort of extension should apply to amplitudes in quantum gravity.</p>

				<p>On the other hand, the spin-statistics association is strongly combinatorial in flavour and seems natural in a spin-network context. Surely for a surface punctured by n edges it would be natural to associate an amplitude which returns to its original value, up to a phase, upon the exchange of two spin-1/2 (and thus identical, indistinguishable) punctures.</p>

				<p>If making the exchange twice leads to the identity 1 , one then needs merely to choose a sign, and -1 seems at least as natural as +1. In the usual quantum field theory one simply tries each possibility, finding that things only work out when the -1 is applied to half integral spin fields and the +1 to integral spin fields.</p>

				<p>In loop quantum gravity this leads then to a picture in which a black hole can get area contributions from spin-1/2 (and spin-3/2, spin-5/2, etc.) punctures, but these are always very small compared to the enormous number of j = 1 edges. The value j = 1 is the lowest value of j contributing nonzero area not being severely limited by Fermi-Dirac statistics, and able to appear arbitrarily often.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In a sense, the question of SU(2) vs. SO(3) in loop quantum gravity could be very much like one that we face in everyday physics. Integer spin particles, which fall into SO(3)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>representations, obey Bose-Einstein statistics and gregariously bunch together to give large macroscopically observable fields such as electromagnetic fields. Half-integer spin particles do not. We could well be excused for thinking that the symmetry group of our world under rotations was SO(3) rather than SU(2). Indeed, until the discovery of spin, it did appear that physical rotations were always elements of SO(3). The need for SU(2) was, in many ways, a surprise!</p>

				<p>It may be hard to find direct experimental evidence of these ideas, but it is at least possible to make some predictions. For example, the SU(2) theory with the exclusion principle proposed here will give both a) what seems to be the correct result for large black holes, with areas well-described by values which go up in steps of 4 ln(3); and b) the possibility simultaneously admitting areas as small as 4 ln(2).</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> It is interesting to consider the possibility of more exotic braid or anyon-like statistics if one would have to keep track of how one edge moved around another, but this is beyond the scope of this essay.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head>
				<p>I would like to thank the NSF for their continued and generous support.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ashtekar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Lewandowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Class. Quant. Grav</title>
		<editor>A55</editor>
		<editor>C. Rovelli and L. Smolin, Nucl. Phys. B442</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">593</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="456" to="753" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Matters of Gravity, the newsletter of the APS Topical Group on Gravitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Baez</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>J. Pullin</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Immirzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">65. F. Barbero</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="5507" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hawking</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">199</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Wheeler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sakharov Memorial Lecture on Physics</title>
		<editor>L. Keldysh and V. Feinberg</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Bekenstein, Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="2333" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Mukhanov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jetp</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<editor>J. Bekenstein and V. Mukhanov</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">360</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">4293; S. Hod</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="1639" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H.-P</forename>
				<surname>Nollert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5253</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Dreyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Motl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Neitzke</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
