<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DETERMINATION OF NEUTRINO MASSES, PRESENT AND FUTURE</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-06-04">4 Jun 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J.-L</forename>
								<surname>Vuilleumier</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Institut de physique, A.-L</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Breguet 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>CH-2000</postCode>
									<settlement>Neuchâtel</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DETERMINATION OF NEUTRINO MASSES, PRESENT AND FUTURE</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-06-04">4 Jun 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Oscillation experiments show that neutrinos have masses. They however only determine the neutrino mass differences. Information on the absolute masses can be obtained by studying the kinematics in weak decays, or by searching for neutrinoless double beta decay. Recent results are reviewed, as well as future projects.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The lagrangian for the neutrinos may contain Dirac mass terms m D , as for all other particles.</p>

				<p>In addition, Majorana mass terms m L and m R for left respectively right handed neutrinos, can appear:</p>

				<p><formula>L = ℓ,ℓ ′ (m D ℓℓ ′ ν ℓL ν ℓ ′ R + m L ℓℓ ′ ν c ℓR ν ℓ ′ L + m R ℓℓ ′ ν c ℓL ν ℓ ′ R ) + h.c.</formula></p>

				<p>The Dirac mass terms conserve the total lepton number (∆L = 0), while the Majorana terms break it by two units (∆L = 2). With them lepton number violating processes such as neutrinoless double beta (ββ0ν) decay may occur. In any case the mass matrices are not in the most general case diagonal in the flavor ℓ (ℓ = e, µ τ ...). The flavor eigenstates ν ℓ are then, assuming N generations of neutrinos, superpositions of 2N Majorana mass eigenstates ν i with mass m i . With Dirac mass terms only this reduces to a sum extending over N Dirac mass eigenstates ν i :</p>

				<p><formula>ν ℓ = N i=1 U ℓi ν i .</formula></p>

				<p>and the flavor eigenstates ν ℓ are Dirac as well. This equation also holds in the case of Majorana mass terms only. All eigenstates are then Majorana, with ν ℓ representing the left handed Majorana flavor eigenstates.</p>

				<p>With an off-diagonal mass matrix, neutrinos will undergo oscillations and transitions. With Dirac mass terms only, or Majorana mass terms only, because of the last equation, the oscillations or transitions take place between flavor eigenstates only. Oscillation experiments are sensitive to the mixings U ℓi and the squared mass differences</p>

				<p><formula>∆m 2 ik = m 2 i − m 2 k .</formula></p>

				<p>Experiments with solar neutrinos determine a value ∆m 2 sol ∼ 5 · 10 −5 eV 2 and a large, but not maximum, mixing 1 . Atmospheric neutrino experiments yield a second mass squared difference ∆m 2 atm ∼ 2.5 · 10 −3 eV 2 and a mixing consistent with the maximal value 2 . These experiments cannot however determine the absolute masses.</p>

				<p>This article is devoted to two other types of experiments providing informations on the absolute masses. First is the study of the kinematics in weak decays, such as 3 H→ 3 He+e − + ν e .</p>

				<p>These measure directly, in principle, the mixings U ℓ,i and the masses m i . And then additional information can be gained by studying ββ0ν decay, which measures an effective mass, exactly zero with Dirac masses alone, and taking the shape:</p>

				<p><formula>|m ν | = | N i=1</formula></p>

				<p>U ei U ei m i | with Majorana masses alone.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-5 -4 -3 -2 -1 0 -3 -2 -1 0 Log m eV -5 -4 -3 -2 -1 0 -3 -2 -1 0 Log m eV 000000000000000 000000000000000 000000000000000 111111111111111 111111111111111 111111111111111 0000 0000 0000 1111 1111 1111 00000000 11111111 0 0 0 1 1 1 76 Ge Katrin η = 31 η = 21 1 η = 21 31 −η = 1 η = 21 31 −η =−1 η = 21 31 −η = 1 CP! − + η = 31 η = 21 1 η = 21 31 −η =−1 η = 31 η = 21 −1 m 3 m 2 m 1 2 m m 3 m 1 sol atm atm sol log(|&lt;m&gt;| [eV]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) log(m [eV]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>) 1 Mainz, Troitsk GENIUS CUORE, EXO, normal inverted quasi degenerate m 3 1 m = (=m( H)) 3 m = 2 Figure 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: Region allowed by oscillation experiments in the mν (effective double beta decay mass) vs. m1 (lightest neutrino mass). Existing limits and projected sensitivities are indicated.</p>

				<p>Moreover it must be mentioned that the study of cosmic microwave background (CMB) anisotropies and large scale structure (LSS) surveys of galaxies constrain the sum of all light neutrino masses. Relic Big-Bang neutrinos with too large masses would wash out these structures . A careful study of the CMB anisotropies measured by the WMAP satellite and of the 2dFGRS survey, assuming three neutrino families (N = 3), yields the limit 3 i=1 m i &lt; 2.12 eV at 95 % CL 3 . It can be brought down to 1.01 eV by including additional input from cosmology.</p>

				<p>The solar and atmospheric data are described well with three neutrino families. In that case, and assuming pure Majorana masses, the effective mass reduces to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|m ν | = |m 1 |U e1 | 2 + m 2 |U e2 | 2 e iα 21 + m 3 |U e3 | 2 e iα 31 |, where α 21 and α 31 are CP violating phases 4,5 . In case of CP conservation they are such that η 21 = e iα 21 = ±1, η 31 = e iα 31 = ±1.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The aforementioned solar and atmospheric neutrino data, with their uncertainties, constrain two of the mixings, and the two squared mass differences. The third mixing is constrained by the Chooz reactor experiment 6 . All this, for a given mass scale, usually taken as the mass m 1 of the lightest neutrino, constrains in turn the allowed range of |m ν | 4,5,7 . This is illustrated in fig. 1, taken from ref. 5 , where the allowed regions in the |m ν | vs. m 1 plane are shown. For m 1 above 0.1 eV, the masse differences are small compared to the absolute masses. It is the quasi degenerate region. All masses take nearly the same value (m 1 ≃ m 2 ≃ m 3 ), which is the quantity measured in kinematic experiments. Because of possible cancellations, depending on the CP-phases, |m ν | can be smaller than m 1 , by about a factor 5. For m 1 below 0.01 eV the mass differences become large compared to m 1 itself. Here one distinguishes two scenarios.</p>

				<p>In the first one, corresponding to the normal hierarchy, solar neutrinos oscillate between the two light neutrinos, and atmospheric neutrinos between a light and a heavy one. In that case |m ν | is always less than 10 −2 eV. In the second scenario, corresponding to inverse hierarchy, the solar neutrinos oscillate between the heavy neutrinos, and atmospheric neutrinos between a heavy one and the light one. With this, |m ν | is always larger than 10 −2 eV.</p>

				<p>The study of double beta decay and of the kinematics in weak decays thus gives the possibility to discriminate between these scenarios, and to fix the absolute mass scale. In particular, if m 1 is less than 0.01 eV, double beta decay can find out about the hierarchy, normal or inverted.</p>

				<p>For this it is however necessary to push the sensitivity down to the 0.01 eV level. Even if one can hope that ongoing and future oscillation experiments, in particular Kamland 8 , will further constrain the allowed areas in fig. 1. In the following we are going to discuss existing bounds on neutrino masses, and look how far the sensitivity could extend in next generation experiments.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Kinematics in weak decays 2.1 Electrostatic spectrometers</head>

				<p>For many years the best limits on the mass of the neutrino admixed most to the electron neutrino have come from the study of tritium decay 3 H→ 3 He+e − + ν e with an end-point energy of E 0 =18.6 keV. One looks for a distortion of the beta spectrum near the end-point due to the masses, as described in more details in ref. 9 . Here the important parameters are high energy resolution, large acceptance since only a tiny fraction of the emitted electrons fall in the region of interest, and low background. The source must be such as to minimize energy losses. Presently the best results come from integral electrostatic spectrometers, built and operated in Troitsk 10 and Mainz 11 . These instruments consist in two superconducting coils, generating a magnetic field, as shown in fig. 2. The source is placed at the entrance of one of the coils. The electrons emitted in the forward half-sphere spiral toward the detector, located behind the second coil. As they move to regions with a weaker magnetic field, the transverse momentum changes into longitudinal motion. Electrodes are used to create an electric potential barrier U . Only electrons with an energy above eU can pass the barrier, and are accelerated toward the detector. Scans are performed varying the potential U , providing the integral electron spectrum. The energy resolution is given by ∆E E = B min B max .</p>

				<p>The Troitsk device uses a gaseous 3 H 2 source, which has the advantage of minimal energy losses. The energy resolution is 3.5 eV. Early spectra showed an anomaly near end points, fits with one single mass yielding a negative squared mass. This is now believed to be due to an experimental artifact, and was eliminated in the most recent spectra. Older data are necessary however to minimize the statistical errors. The negative squared mass can be eliminated by adding in the fit a step to the integral spectrum, ending at an energy below E 0 , which was found</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B max B max B min p (without E field) e 3 H source electrodes detector ∆Ω=2π −1 count rate (s ) Electric potential (kV)</trash>

					<head>Figure 2:</head>

					<figDesc>Left: principles of operation of an integral electrostatic spectrometer; evolution of the momentum of an electron spiraling in the magnetic field for no electric field; right: the Mainz 3 H spectra near end-point.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>to vary in time. With this a negative squared mass consistent with zero is obtained, leading to the limit m ν &lt; 2.2 eV at 95 % CL. The Mainz system has an energy resolution of 4.8 eV. It uses a frozen 3 H 2 source. The experiment went through several upgrades, which led in particular to a lower background, as shown in fig. 2. Distortions leading here also to negative squared masses were understood as being due to a roughening of the source film and were eliminated by substantially reducing the operating temperature. The last years of operation give a negative squared mass consistent with zero, and to the same limit m ν &lt; 2.2 eV at 95 % CL, which can thus be considered presently the best upper bound on the neutrino mass, ruling out part of the quasi degenerate region in fig. 1. The Mainz and the Troitsk groups consider that they have exhausted the potential of their instruments. They have joined efforts and, along with a few additional teams, have undertaken the construction of Katrin, a much larger device 9 . The energy resolution should be of order 1 eV. A small spectrometer will be placed in front of the main one, filtering out all the electrons clearly below the end-point, reducing the background considerably. A gaseous and a frozen 3 H source will be used, helping in pinning down the systematics associated with either source. With all this it is hoped that the sensitivity to the neutrino mass will extend down to 0.35 eV.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Bolometers</head>

				<p>Cryogenic bolometers, proposed first by the Genova group, may turn out to be fairly competitive in searching for the neutrino mass.</p>

				<p>In these, the source, in crystalline form, is the detector medium itself. The entire energy deposited by an event ends up in heat. The crystal is operated at low temperature, so that the corresponding temperature increase is large, and can be measured with a thermistor glued to the crystal. In principle, no corrections need to be made for final state or source effects. The Genova group 12 has demonstrated the feasibility of using metallic rhenium crystals to look for the decay 187 Re→ 187 Os+e − + ν e (natural abundance of 187 Re 62 %). One advantage is the low end point energy (E 0 ≃2.5 keV), which makes that a larger fraction of events falls in the region of interest. But the most recent results have been produced by the Milano group 13 .</p>

				<p>An array of 10 AgReO 4 crystals with a mass of 250-300 µg each has been built and operated for a longer period of time. The measured spectra with and without calibration source are shown in fig. 3. The energy resolution is 28 eV on average at 2.5 keV. The measured spectrum was found to be in good agreement with a vanishing neutrino mass, and the limit m ν &lt; 21.7 eV at 90 % confidence was derived. This is limited by statistics, and by the energy resolution. But clearly the method still has a lot of potential.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0.001 0.01 0.1 1 10 100 1000 2.0 4.0 6.0 8.0 10.0 12.0 14.0 16.0 18.0 20.0 counts/keV/h energy [keV]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>187 Re</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3:</head>

					<figDesc>The 187 Re spectrum measured with the Milano bolometers, with and without calibration source.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Double beta decay</head>

				<p>We are going to discuss neutrinoless and two neutrino nuclear double beta decay. The two neutrino mode ββ2ν (A, Z) −→ (A, Z + 2) + e − + e − + ν e + ν e conserves the lepton number and is allowed in the standard model. The half life is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T 2ν 1/2 −1 = G 2ν (E 0 , Z)|M 2ν GT | 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with G 2ν (E 0 , Z) an exactly calculable phase space factor depending only on the nuclear charge Z and the total energy released in the decay E 0 , and M 2ν GT a matrix element. Neutrinoless double beta decay ββ0ν (A, Z) −→ (A, Z + 2) + e − + e − breaks the lepton number by two units and requires Majorana masses. The half life depends directly on the effective mass m ν :</p>

				<p><formula>T 0ν 1/2 −1 = G 0ν (E 0 , Z) M 0ν GT − g 2 V g 2 A M 0ν F 2 |m ν | 2 ,</formula></p>

				<p>with again G 0ν (E 0 , Z) a phase space factor, g V and g A the vector and axial vector coupling constants, and M 0ν GT and M 0ν F matrix elements which are not the same as those of ββ2ν, but which depend on the same nuclear physics. Experimentally the two modes can be distinguished by measuring the total energy carried away by the two electrons. In (ββ2ν) it follows a smooth distribution peaking at about 1/3 E 0 , while in (ββ0ν) it is equal to E 0 . In either case the theoretical distributions are smeared by the instrumental resolution, as shown in figure 4. Many isotope candidates have been explored over the past years. The criterias of selection are high energy release E 0 , corresponding to a large phase space, and placing the search for ββ0ν decay in a region with lower background, and large natural abundance, which facilitates enrichment.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x 10 4 ββ2ν ββ0ν 0 0.5 1 E/E 0 Figure 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: The expected energy distributions of the sum energy of the two neutrinos for ββ0ν and ββ2ν decay, smeared by energy resolution (gaussian with σ(E)/E=2%).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T 2ν 1/2 meas. T calc 1/2 T meas 1/2 T calc 1/2 T meas 1/2 (yr) QRPA 15,16 Shell model 17 48 Ca 76 Ge 82 Se 100 Mo 130 Te (4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p><formula>.2 ± 1.2) · 10 19 (1.3 ± 0.1) · 10 21 (9.2 ± 1) · 10 19 (8 ± 0.6) · 10 18 6.1 ± 1.4stat. +2.9 −3.5 sys. · 10 20 − 1.0 1.3 0.76 0.36 0.91 2.0 0.40 − 0.38</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Table 1:</head>

					<figDesc>List of measured ββ2ν half-lives; comparison with QRPA and shell model predictions.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.1">Present experiments</head>

				<p>ββ2ν decay has now been seen in many nuclei 7 , as shown in table 1. The most recent entry comes from the Mibeta group, which built an array of 20 crystals of TeO 2 14 of 340 g each, operated as bolometers at a temperature of 8 mK. The energy resolution is excellent, of order σ(E)/E = 1.5 · 10 −3 at E 0 = 2528 keV. Most crystals use natural tellurium (34.5 % 130 Te). But recent measurements were performed with two of the crystals enriched in 130 Te, and two more enriched in 128 Te. The comparison yields a positive signal, corresponding to the half-life reported in table 1 for 130 Te, and in reasonable agreement with earlier geochemical results. A comparison is made in table 1 with calculated half-lives, using nuclear matrix elements calculated in the framework of QRPA 15,16 , and with the shell model 17 . Reasonable agreement is observed, at the level of a factor of 2 or better. This is particularly true of the QRPA results, which shows that the calculations are quite realistic. This encouraged the authors of ref. 18 to go one step further, and to use the measured half-lives to fix more precisely the parameters of the QRPA model, and to use them to calculate the ββ0ν matrix elements. These calculations should be more reliable than older ones, and will be used in the following to interpret the data on ββ0ν decay in terms of m ν . They tend to give masses slightly larger than older calculations. Some results on ββ0ν decay are listed in table 2, and deduced effective masses m ν are given with the QRPA matrix elements of ref. 18 and the shell model matrix elements of ref. 17 . They include those of the Heidelberg-Moscow collaboration in Gran Sasso, operating an array of 5 crystals of germanium (11 kg total mass) enriched to 87 % in 76 Ge, and operated as semiconductor devices, with an energy resolution of order σ(E)/E = 0.7 · 10 −3 at E 0 = 2039 keV 19 . The advantage of such a good resolution to search for ββ0ν, and also to identify the background, is illustrated in figure 5. As pointed out by the authors, the background is not flat, as naively believed previously, also in other experiments, but weak background peaks from 214 Bi activity ( 238 U chain) are visible, in spite of the high radiopurity of the detector. The peak intensities T 0ν 1/2 [yr] m ν [eV]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(90 % CL) QRPA 18 shell model 17 76 Ge 130 Te 136 Xe (0.8 − 35) · 10 25 &gt; 2.1 · 10 23 &gt; 4.4 · 10 23 0.13 − 0.85 &lt; 3.6 &lt; 3.3 0.24 − 1.6 &lt; − &lt; 5.2 Table 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: Measurements of ββ0ν half-lives; Deduced effective neutrino mass mν. Figure 5: The ββ0ν energy region in the Heidelberg-Moscow 76 Ge data (55 kg·yr). The fitted background and ββ0ν peaks are shown. are consistent with those of stronger 214 Bi peaks elsewhere in the spectrum. Fitting the region of interest with these peaks and a constant background, the authors find indications of an additional peak centered at E 0 = 2039 eV. They interpret this as an indication of ββ0ν decay, corresponding to a half-life of T 0ν 1/2 = (0.8 − 35) · 10 25 yr (95 % CL). It would correspond to a mass m ν of order 0.1 to 1.6 eV, shown in fig. 1. This result has been the cause of heated debates, which will not be covered here. What is sure, is that m ν is less than 1.5 eV or so. Other experiments at present can neither confirm nor disprove this indication, as shown in table 2. Given are the limits obtained with the already discussed Mibeta bolometers in 130 Te, and in 136 Xe with a xenon gas time projection chamber (TPC) operated in the Gotthard underground laboratory 20 . Here the source consisted in 5.3 kg of xenon enriched to 62.5 % in 136 Xe. The philosophy was somewhat different. In comparison, the energy resolution is modest (σ(E)/E = 2.5 · 10 −2 at E 0 = 2480 keV). But to a large extent this is compensated by the imaging capability of the TPC, a powerful tool to identify and suppress backgrounds, and to select double beta candidates, single continuous tracks with increased ionization due to larger dE/dx at both ends.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.2">Future experiments</head>

				<p>Clearly it is important to have improved data on ββ0ν decay, first to clear up the indication of the Heidelberg-Moscow 76 Ge experiment, and second to extend the sensitivity down to m ν ≃ 10 −2 eV. NEMO 3 which has just started taking data in the Fréjus underground laboratory should be able to perform the first task 21 . It consist in a tracking detector with excellent imaging capability. In contrast to the detectors discussed so far, the source is not the detector medium. It is a thin foil, placed inside a fiducial volume filled with helium. This has the advantage that many nuclei can be investigated, but the disadvantage of energy losses in the source, deteriorating the energy resolution. Nevertheless with a source mass of 7 kg of molybdenum highly enriched in 100 Mo, and 1 kg of selenium enriched in 82 Se, it should probe m ν down to 0.1 eV or so.</p>

				<p>Majorana 500 kg 76 Ge, 210 crystals in cryostats, segmented readout MOON 34 t nat Mo sheets between plastic scintillators XMASS 10 t of liquid nat Xe viewed by photomultipliers CUORE 760 kg nat TeO 2 bolometers GENIUS 1(10)t of 76 Ge, in crystals suspended in liquid nitrogen EXO 1(10)t of 136 Xe, in gas or in liquid TPC, with ion tagging Table 3: Future projects to study ββ0ν decay, with brief description.</p>

				<p>But more ambitious projects are required to go to 10 −2 eV. The requirements on future detectors are much larger masses, of order 1, possibly 10 t, and, at the same time, much lower background level. Masses of that kind can be envisioned, since highly efficient enrichment facilities exist in Russia, based on a variety of techniques, in particular centrifugation for components which can be brought to a gaseous form 22 . The reduction in background level which must go along can be achieved by the use of detector components with lower levels of natural and cosmogenic activities, improved event signature, and finally superior energy resolution.</p>

				<p>Energy resolution is in any event essential since it is, practically, the only way allowing to suppress the background from ββ2ν decay when looking for ββ0ν decay. The experiments being considered will search for ββ0ν half lives of order 10 26 to 10 28 yr, longer by 5 to 7 orders of magnitude comparing with ββ2ν decay, as depicted in fig. 4. The differences in angular distributions can help, but not to the same extent. This favors detectors in which the source is at the same time the detector medium.</p>

				<p>Several projects are being considered, some as general purpose detectors for low energy physics, including the study of solar neutrinos or the search for cold dark matter, others being primarily dedicated to double beta decay. Table 3 gives a non exhaustive list. In the following we will briefly discuss three of the projects, which will start on a smaller scale, before evolving to the final form. CUORE is a development of Mibeta 23 . It will consist in an array of 1000 crystals of nat TeO 2 , with a mass of 760 g each, operated as bolometers in a single low background cryostat in the Gran Sasso underground laboratory. The energy resolution should be better than 2·10 −3 at E 0 = 2480 keV. An elaborate shielding made from roman lead, copper and PET should protect the crystals against local activities. It is hoped that the sensitivity to ββ0ν decay will extend up to half-lives of order 2·10 26 yr, corresponding to roughly 0.1 eV in terms of the effective mass m ν , or somewhat better.</p>

				<p>In a first step a smaller version, CUORICINO, is being built in the Gran Sasso laboratory. It will have 56 crystals similar to those foreseen for CUORE. GENIUS has been proposed by the Heidelberg group 24 . It uses germanium crystals highly enriched in 76 Ge operated as semiconductor detectors, as in the Heidelberg-Moscow experiment. But to simplify the design, and reduce the possibility of radioactive contamination, the crystals are not mounted in a cryostat, but suspended and immersed in a large vessel filled with liquid nitrogen, as shown in fig. 6. Tests have shown that the excellent energy resolution inherent to semiconductor detectors can be maintained in such an arrangement. The FET&apos;s of the crystals, a source of background, can be mounted at a large distance. The liquid nitrogen can be cleaned to a high level of purity, and provides the innermost shielding layer against outside activities. Because of the low density, a large volume is required. Pulse shape discrimination will be used, as in the later phase of the Heidelberg-Moscow experiment, to distinguish single site events, potential double beta candidates, from multiple site events, mostly due to multiple Compton scattering. For the same reason the crystals will be operated in anti-coincidence. Careful background estimates have been performed, taking into account cosmogenic activation, leading</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>liq. N insulation steel vessel Ge crystals clean room electronics 2</trash>

					<head>Figure 6:</head>

					<figDesc>The proposed Genius detector with germanium crystals suspended in a liquid nitrogen bath.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>to encouragingly low rates. The experiment should reach a sensitivity of order 10 −2 eV or so to m ν . A test facility, with 40 kg of natural germanium, is being set up at Gran Sasso. EXO is devoted to the search of double beta decay in 136 Xe 25 . To reduce drastically the background the detector will have a much improved signature. It will be made so as to observe not only the two electrons emitted in double beta decay, as usual, but also to identify the positive ion left behind, in this case 136 Ba ++ 26 . It is first brought to the singly charged state 136 Ba + . A first 493 nm laser brings it from the 6 2 S 1/2 ground state to the 6 2 P 1/2 excited state. From there it decays back to the ground state, or to the 5 4 D 3/2 metastable state. If this happens, a second 650 nm laser brings it back to the 6 2 P 1/2 state. As long as the laser irradiation continues, photons are emitted, which allow to identify the ion. R&amp;D is in progress to develop this technique.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>650 nm 493 nm metastable 6 P 5 D 2 1/2 1/2 6 S 2 4 3/2 Ba + readout plane +electroluminescence) (amplified charge micropattern e − 5 m 650+493 nm laser system WLS PMT buffer gas acrylic vessel 5 bar 136 Xe +? vessel steel cathode meshes potential wire</trash>

					<head>Figure 7:</head>

					<figDesc>Left: The level scheme of 136 Ba + ; right: a possible layout for the gas version of the EXO TPC (1 t).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Two options are being studied for the EXO detector. In either case the source consists of xenon highly enriched in 136 Xe and acting as detection medium for the electrons. The first possibility is a liquid TPC, which has the advantage of being compact and easy to shield. After the detection of the electrons, by measuring both the scintillation light and the ionization charge, the much slower positive ion is extracted with a tip at a negative potential. It is released in an ion trap by reversing the potential. The ion tagging is then performed in the trap. A second possibility is a gas TPC, as in the Gotthard experiment. A disadvantage is the larger size of the detector. But the advantage is that the electron tracks are then long enough to be visualized. This provides a powerful additional selection criterion. The ion tagging must then be made in the TPC itself, a quencher admixed to the xenon bringing the ion from the doubly to the singly ionized state. A possible layout is shown in fig. 7, ressembling that of MUNU 27 .</p>

				<p>The TPC is enclosed in an acrylic vessel. The ionization electrons drift to the read-out planes, at both ends. The positive ion drifts much more slowly toward the cathode in the center, near which it crosses the laser beams. The desexcitation light is converted to green in wavelength shifter bars, and brought to photomultipliers at the ends. Ion tagging, if it can be made to work efficiently, will lead to an essentially background free double beta decay experiment. But an energy resolution of order 2 % or better is necessary to distinguish ββ0ν decay from ββ2ν decay. This is only marginally better than what was achieved in the Gotthard experiment however, and R&amp;D is in progress for both versions to improve on that 28 . A first test experiment will be performed with 50 kg of enriched xenon, but without tagging. The next goal is an experiment with 1 t, having a sensitivity of a few 10 −2 eV to m ν . A 10 t version could, ultimately, be envisioned.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Conclusion</head>

				<p>Next generation laboratory experiments studying the kinematics in weak decays and searching for neutrinoless double beta decay will further constrain neutrino masses. They should provide enough information to figure out what scenario holds for neutrino masses: nearly degenerate, inverted hierarchy or normal hierarchy. These experiments are real challenges, facing many difficulties, in particular fierce background problems. They will thus proceed in several steps, before reaching the final sensitivity.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">these proceedings; the SNO collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Heeger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">011302</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">these proceedings; the Super-Kamiokande collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kameda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3999</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hannestad</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Bilenky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pascoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Petcov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">053010</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pascoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Petcov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">544</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Apollonio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Eur</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">331</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Steven</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Elliott</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Petr</forename>
				<surname>Vogel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann.Rev.Nucl.Part.Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">115</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">The</forename>
				<surname>Kamland</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">(</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Eguchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">021802</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Weinheimer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Lobashev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">460</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">227</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bonn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys.(Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Galeazzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">014302</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Arnaboldi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">submitted to Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0302006</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Arnaboldi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">557</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">167</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Engel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">731</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Moe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Vogel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Rev. Nucl. Part. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Caurier</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Vogel</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9904065</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
			<publisher>Vogel</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Rodin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Klapdor-Kleingrothaus</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Dietz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Krivosheina</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Found</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1181" to="1223" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Luescher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">434</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">407</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">These</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Etienvre</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Arnold</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Instrum.Meth. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">503</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">649</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Lebedev</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Pryanichnikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Inst. and Meth. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">222</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Arnaboldi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Klapdor-Kleingrothaus</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">480</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Moe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">931</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Munu</forename>
				<surname>The</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">(</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Avenier</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Nucl.Instrum.Meth. A 482</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page">408</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Conti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">submitted to Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
