<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Sensitivity of a Lithium Experiment on Solar Neutrinos to the Mixing Angle θ 12</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-08">Aug 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Anatoly</forename>
								<surname>Kopylov</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Nuclear Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Russian Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>117312</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Valery</forename>
								<surname>Petukhov</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Nuclear Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Russian Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>117312</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Sensitivity of a Lithium Experiment on Solar Neutrinos to the Mixing Angle θ 12</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-08">Aug 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A lithium-based radiochemical detector is aimed primarily to detect neutrinos from CNO cycle what will provide a direct proof of its existence and will be a stringent test of the theory of stellar evolution. Another task which can be solved by this experiment is to measure a mixing angle θ 12. The sensitivity of a lithium experiment to θ 12 was calculated by Monte-Carlo following the proposed original technique which can be used as a complimentary one to a chi-square technique usually applied to this task. It is shown that the accuracy of measurement of the mixing angle in solar neutrino experiments is principally limited by the accuracy of a lithium experiment due to the limiting uncertainty of the energy generated in a pp chain. This paper describes the procedure to calculate the accuracy in the evaluation of the mixing angle θ (in this paper we are considering only a mixing angle θ 12) if the capture rate of solar neutrinos is measured by a lithium detector with certain accuracy. The general idea of this procedure was proposed in [1], here the computer implementation of this idea and the conclusions drawn on a basis of the results obtained are presented. First part describes the procedure. The interested reader may skip this part and start reading part 2 which presents the results obtained and their discussions. The conclusions important for the practical questions of the realization of a lithium experiment are formulated in part 3.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>This paper describes the procedure to calculate the accuracy in the evaluation of the mixing angle θ (in this paper we are considering only a mixing angle θ 12 ) if the capture rate of solar neutrinos is measured by a lithium detector with certain accuracy. The general idea of this procedure was proposed in [1], here the computer implementation of this idea and the conclusions drawn on a basis of the results obtained are presented. First part describes the procedure. The interested reader may skip this part and start reading part 2 which presents the results obtained and their discussions. The conclusions important for the practical questions of the realization of a lithium experiment are formulated in part 3. 1. The procedure to calculate.</p>

				<p>The main point of this technique is that a relatively modest accuracy (∼10%) in the measurement of the neutrino capture rate in a lithium experiment will evaluate with a very high accuracy (∼0.5%) the energy generated in a hydrogen chain what combined with the luminosity constraint proposed by M.Spiro and D.Vignaud [2] will determine precisely the mixing angle θ. And vice versa: if the energy generated in a CNO cycle is not measured this will be principal limiting factor in the evaluation of θ. Here we take ∆m 2 = 7.3 × 10 −5 eV 2 of the best fit point and take it as an accurately known value taking into consideration that very soon it will be measured with a very good accuracy in experiment KamLAND. The procedure begins with the simulation of two values: the true capture rate in a lithium experiment for a given measured capture rate and tan 2 θ within the interval limited by the global rates of solar neutrino experiments [3] and KamLAND [4] as it was shown in a number of papers [5] and most recently in [6]. It was taken here: tan 2 θ = 0.42 ± 0.08 (1σ) and the Gaussian distribution by the simulation of random θ i . It was taken also that the best fit point of θ corresponds to the fluxes of solar neutrinos given by a standard solar model of BP2000. We should stress at this moment that what are exactly the values taken on the input of the procedure is not very critical for the final result, as it will be shown later. As a next step it was necessary to find the contribution of neutrinos generated in a CNO cycle to the total rate found in experiment with a lithium target. It is a straightforward procedure of subtracting the effect for the known fluxes of neutrinos generated in a pp-chain and for the calculated factor for the electron neutrinos to survive. This factor was calculated for two different oscillation scenarios for two different energy regions: vacuum oscillations with the factor P ee = 1 − 0.5sin 2 2θ and MSW oscillations with the factor P ee = tan 2 θ. The boarder between these two regions was taken to be 2 MeV, this is an arbitrary supposition taken just for convenience. This supposition does not contradict to the experimental data so far, it will be corrected by the future experiments, but for the aim of the present paper this choice has no principal meaning. Let&apos;s just keep in mind that by the time this question is cleared the results of the calculations should be corrected. The rate was calculated for each neutrino source of pp chain:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>7 Be, pep and 8 B neutrinos according to the formula U a (θ) = f a ∫ dE · P ee (θ, E) · Φ BP a (E)S Li (E) (1) Here a denotes 7 Be, pep and 8 B neutrinos</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, f a is a reduced (relative to the one given by BP2000 model) neutrino flux which is taken 1.0 at the beginning and later on we will see the effect if it is fluctuated around 1.0 with the uncertainty σ; P ee (θ, E) is the probability for the electron neutrino to survive; Φ BP a (E) are the neutrino fluxes given by BP2000; S Li (E) is the cross section of neutrino capture on lithium calculated by J.Bahcall [7]. After subtracting the effect from neutrinos of a pp chain the rate from CNO neutrinos was obtained. The ratio of the effect found for a CNO cycle to the calculated one by the formula (1), where a means 13 N or 15 O neutrinos, will be denoted further by a factor G. If we take the ratio of 13 N to 15 O neutrinos generated in a CNO cycle fixed and equal to what BP2000 suggests, then the factor G means that the fluxes of these neutrinos generated in the Sun are equal to the ones given by BP2000 multiplied by the factor G. But then, to fulfill the luminosity constraint, one should introduce another factor D for the fluxes of neutrinos generated in a pp chain according to the equation of the luminosity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>balance 0.015 G + 0.985 D =1 (2) for CNO cycle and for a pp chain and 0.913f pp + 0.002f pep + 0.07f Be + 0.0071f N + 0.0079f O = 1 (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for all neutrino sources with the coefficient by the reduced neutrino flux greater 0.0001. The coefficients byf pp , f pep and f Be were obtained from numbers of Table 1 presented in [8], the coefficients by f N and f O were calculated accounting that the energy produced for each 13 N neutrino in a first half-cycle CNO</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α( 13 N) = M( 12 C) + 2M( 1 H) − M( 14 N) − E ν ( 13 N) = 11.00 MeV and for each 15 O neutrino for the second half-cycle CNO α( 15 O) = M( 14 N) + 2M( 1 H) − M( 4 He) − M( 12 C) − E ν ( 15 O) = 14.01MeV</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From the expression (2) it follows that the energy generated in a CNO cycle is 1.5% times G of the total energy generated in the Sun. We take here a fixed ratio of He3-He4 termination chain relative to 3 He - 3 He termination chain suggested by BP2000 model because the flux of 7 Be neutrinos has not been measured by the present time with the accuracy sufficient to establish unambiguously this ratio. For the purpose of this paper it is not very essential moment. So from this expression we find the factor D as a one by which the luminosity constraint is fulfilled. Lets note that the factor D is just the ratio of the real energy generated in a pp chain to the one suggested by a BP2000 model. And while the factor G can be large, for example, it can be 1.5 or nearby, the factor D differs from 1.0 only by a small quantity of the order of 1% . Because the fluctuations in tan 2 θ are taken rather large (σ = 20% ) sometimes the value G becomes negative what obviously has no physical meaning. These events will be rejected so that on the output the number of the real simulations is indicated out of 1000 tries. This is not very good approach from the statistical point of view, but for our study it has no dramatic consequences. It reminds the old story about Runs with negative numbers (after subtracting the background) in Davis experiment. And now we are coming to the final point. For each value of D found in each simulation we find the new tan 2 θ ′ which agrees with the luminosity constraint applied only to a pp chain. Here, at first, we don&apos;t modify the relative structure of the neutrino sources inside the chain, we take it according to BP2000 but the absolute values of neutrino fluxes in the zone of their generation become higher or lower by the factor corresponding to a new θ ′ and to the energy of the neutrino source. Then we let the fluxes of pp neutrinos (here we take the flux of pp neutrinos together with the flux of pep neutrinos using the fact that the ratio of pep neutrinos to pp neutrinos is well known) or 7 Be neutrinos, or 8 B neutrinos, or the combination of them, to vary with a certain σ and see what will be the effect. 2. The results obtained and their discussion. Fig.1 presents the summary of the calculations. Figure 1: The sensitivity plot of a lithium detector to θ 12 for different experimental uncertainties σ. The contour S+K 3 yr was taken from [6] One can see that the limit on θ ′ depends critically upon the accuracy obtained in a lithium experiment. The data presented on this figure were obtained for the extreme case when the fluxes of neutrinos from a hydrogen chain are exactly known, i.e. the uncertainty in their evaluation is zero, and they are equal to the ones suggested by BP2000 model. How this result was obtained one can see on Fig.2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>which shows the data for different accuracies of the rate measured in a lithium experiment (1σ = 1 SNU, 2 SNU, 5SNU and 10 SNU) for the average rate 21.7 SNU expected in experiment for the oscillation parameters listed above.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 21.7 ± 1 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4193 ± 0.0030 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 21.7 ± 2 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4194 ± 0.0057 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 21.7 ± 5 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4179 ± 0.0120 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 21.7 ± 10 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4098 ± 0.0202</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 2:</head>

					<figDesc>The accuracy of the evaluation of θ ′ for different uncertainties of a lithium experiment. The distribution on Y-axis is obtained with the Luminosity Constraint applied to the data. Two values were simulated: the neutrino capture rate measured by experiment and a mixing angle θ. The value of tan 2 θ ′ is found as a one to comply with the luminosity constraint. One can see the scattering of the simulated points and histograms for tan 2 θ and tan 2 θ</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>′ distributions. The most interesting result which is clearly presented on all figures is that the distribution for tan 2 θ ′ is much narrower than for tan 2 θ. This is a clear demonstration of the power of the luminosity constraint if the fluxes of CNO neutrinos are measured. The data show that the higher is the accuracy of a lithium experiment the more limiting is the result for the energy generation in a pp chain and the more precisely is determined the mixing angle θ ′ . For large experimental uncertainty 10 SNU the points get scattered in a large field and the distribution on tan 2 θ ′ is asymmetrical. As one can see later this case of 10 SNU is an extreme one, in the real experiment one can expect as very realistic the accuracy of 5 SNU which can be achieved in the time scale of 1 year even with the very simplified counting system. The accuracy of 1 SNU can be achieved with the counting system on a basis of a cryogenic detector which would enable to achieve the efficiency of counting of 7 Be close to 100% [9]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) f pp = 1 ± 0.02 f Be = 1 f B = 1 tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4195 ± 0.0051 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) f pp = 1 f Be = 1 ± 0.2 f B = 1 tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4194 ± 0.0059 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) f pp = 1 f Be = 1 f B = 1 ± 0.06 tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4191 ± 0.0030 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) f pp = 1 ± 0.02 f Be = 1 ± 0.2 f B = 1 tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4195 ± 0.0070</trash>

					<head>Figure 3:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The same as Fig.2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>but the flux of neutrinos of pp-chain are varied. Fig.3 shows the data similar to Fig.2 only here the flux of pp neutrinos is varied with σ = 2% , the flux of 7 Be neutrinos is varied with σ = 20% , the flux of 8 B neutrinos is varied with σ = 6% , both pp neutrinos and 7 Be neutrinos are varied with σ = 2% (pp) and with σ = 20% ( 7 Be) for the same average rate 21.6 SNU. Comparing the data presented on these figures with the ones presented on Fig.2 one can see how the uncertainties of the different neutrino fluxes change the result for tan 2 θ ′ . The influence of boron neutrinos is not so strong, the influence of pp and 7 Be neutrinos is quite substantial.</p>

				<p>Next two figures are similar to the Fig.2 only the data were obtained not for the average expected rate in a lithium experiment 21.7 SNU, but for 21.7 ± 5 SNU, Fig.4</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>for 16.7 SNU and Fig.5</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>for 26.7 SNU. One can see that the general picture is not changed drastically for these cases. Figure 6 shows how tan 2 θ ′ depends on the neutrino capture rate R measured in a lithium</p>

				<p><formula>experiment. 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 16.7 ± 1 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4333 ± 0.0027 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 16.7 ± 2 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4323 ± 0.0049 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 16.7 ± 5 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4262 ± 0.0096 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 16.7 ± 10 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4166 ± 0.0168</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4:</head>

					<figDesc>The same as Fig.2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>but for the experimental value 16.7 ± 1σ SNU. 3. The conclusions important for a lithium experiment.</p>

				<p>For a future lithium experiment a very important point is that even with the modest accuracy of about 5 SNU the result will be very informative not only for establishing the role of CNO cycle in the Sun but also for measuring a mixing angle. The accuracy of about 5 SNU can be achieved with 10 tons of lithium using a simplified counting system in a sense that it is aimed not to counting each decay of 7 Be what presumably is possible to do by means of a cryogenic detector, but only a gamma line 0.478 KeV of the excited state of</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 26.7 ± 1 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4055 ± 0.0033 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 26.7 ± 2 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4055 ± 0.0059 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 26.7 ± 5 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.4052 ± 0.0131 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 tan 2 (θ) tan 2 (θ ′ ) Experimental value: 26.7 ± 10 SNU tan 2 (θ ′ ) = 0.3998 ± 0.0226</trash>

					<head>Figure 5:</head>

					<figDesc>The same as Fig.2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>but for the experimental value 26.7 ± 1σ SNU.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>12 14 16 18 20 22 24 26 28 30 0.36 0.38 0.4 0.42 0.44 0.46 tan 2 (θ ′ ) R, SNU</trash>

					<head>Figure 6:</head>

					<figDesc>The dependence of tan 2 θ ′ on the neutrino capture rate measured in a lithium experiment.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>daughter 7 Li which is more convenient for counting. Because the branching ratio of this line is only 10.4% the resulting efficiency of the counting by means of a low background gamma-spectrometer will be very modest, of about 6% . But for the accuracy 5% using 10 tons of metallic lithium it still will be adequate to accomplish the task. If to take the efficiency of extraction of beryllium from metallic lithium 80% , the efficiency of counting 6% , time of exposure 80 days and 4 Runs per year, the resulting accuracy will be about 5 SNU. Then 5 counts are expected in a Run which should be counted by a very low background gamma-spectrometer within a time interval of about half a year. The dangerous source of the background comes from the line 511 keV which is a well populated peak of the background spectra. To discriminate this peak it is necessary to use a high resolution detector with 4π geometry, the best one for this aim is a module composed of several high purity germanium detectors of the kind planned to be used as a working module in a Majorana project. This work was supported in part by the Russian Fund of Basic Research, contract N01-02-16167-A and by the grant of Russia &quot; Leading Scientific Schools &quot; LSS-1782.2003.2.</p>

		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kopylov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Petukhov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0306148</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Spiro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Vignaud</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physics Letters B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">242</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Cleveland</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">GALLEX collaboration], 1999, Phys. Lett. B447, 127; T.Kirsten, talk at the XXth Int. Conf. On Neutrino Physics and Astro- physics (NU2002)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Munich</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Altmann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Of the XIXth Int. Conf. On Neutrino Physics and AstrophysicsProc. Suppl.) 91, 44; Y.Fukuda et. al</title>
		<editor>Q.R.Ahmad et al. Q.R.Ahmad et al.</editor>
		<meeting>. Of the XIXth Int. Conf. On Neutrino Physics and Astrophysics. Suppl.) 91, 44; Y.Fukuda et. al</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1638" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Eguchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">KamLAND collaboration</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Barger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Marfatia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Fogli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Lisi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Montanino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Maltoni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W F</forename>
				<surname>Schwetz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Valle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bandyopadhyay</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Choubey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Gandi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">J N</forename>
				<surname>Goswami</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Bahcall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Gonzalez-Garchia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Pena-Garay</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="212270" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>hep. -ph/0212147; P.C.de Hollanda and A.Yu.Smirnov</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">881</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Galeazzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Gallinaro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Gatti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Galeazzi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Gallinaro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Gatti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Lett. B398</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">187</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">317</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
