<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The CDF Calorimeter Upgrade for Run IIb</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2003-10-30">30 Oct 2003</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">S</forename>
								<surname>Kuhlmann</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Argonne National Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60439</postCode>
									<region>Illinois</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">H</forename>
								<surname>Frisch</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60637</postCode>
									<settlement>Chicago</settlement>
									<region>Illinois</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Cordelli</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Laboratori Nazionali di Frascati</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">INFN</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-00044</postCode>
									<settlement>Frascati</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">J</forename>
								<surname>Huston</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Michigan State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48824</postCode>
									<settlement>East Lansing</settlement>
									<region>Michigan</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">R</forename>
								<surname>Miller</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Michigan State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48824</postCode>
									<settlement>East Lansing</settlement>
									<region>Michigan</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">S</forename>
								<surname>Lami</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">INFN Pisa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-56127</postCode>
									<settlement>Pisa</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">and Rockefeller University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10021</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">R</forename>
								<surname>Paoletti</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">INFN Pisa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-56127</postCode>
									<settlement>Pisa</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">and University of Siena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-53100</postCode>
									<settlement>Siena</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">N</forename>
								<surname>Turini</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">INFN Pisa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-56127</postCode>
									<settlement>Pisa</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">and University of Siena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-53100</postCode>
									<settlement>Siena</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Iori</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Roma</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">D</forename>
								<surname>Toback</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>College Station</addrLine>
									<postCode>77843</postCode>
									<region>Texas</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">F</forename>
								<surname>Ukegawa</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tsukuba</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>305</postCode>
									<settlement>Tsukuba</settlement>
									<region>Ibaraki</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">INFN</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>I-00185</postCode>
									<settlement>Roma</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The CDF Calorimeter Upgrade for Run IIb</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2003-10-30">30 Oct 2003</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The physics program at the Fermilab Tevatron Collider will continue to explore the high energy frontier of particle physics until the commissioning of the LHC at CERN. The luminosity increase provided by the Main Injector will require upgrades beyond those implemented for the first stage (Run IIa) of the Tevatron&apos;s Run II physics program. The upgrade of the CDF calorimetry includes: 1) the replacement of the slow gas detectors on the front face of the Central Calorimeter with a faster scintillator version which has a better segmentation, and 2) the addition of timing information to both the Central and EndPlug Electromagnetic Calorimeters to filter out cosmic ray and beam related backgrounds.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>The CDF Calorimeter Upgrade for Run IIb S. Kuhlmann a , H. Frisch b , M. Cordelli c , J. Huston d , R. Miller d , S. Lami e * , R. Paoletti f , N. Turini</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>f , M. Iori g , D. Toback h , F. Ukegawa i a Argonne National Laboratory, Illinois 60439, USA b University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois 60637, USA c Laboratori Nazionali di Frascati, INFN, I-00044 Frascati, Italy d Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan 48824, USA e INFN Pisa, I-56127 Pisa, Italy, and Rockefeller University, New York, New York 10021, USA f INFN Pisa, I-56127 Pisa, and University of Siena, I-53100 Siena, Italy g University of Roma 1 and INFN, I-00185 Roma, Italy h Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, Texas 77843, USA i University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba, Ibaraki 305, Japan</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The physics program at the Fermilab Tevatron Collider will continue to explore the high energy frontier of particle physics until the commissioning of the LHC at CERN. The luminosity increase provided by the Main Injector will require upgrades beyond those implemented for the first stage (Run IIa) of the Tevatron&apos;s Run II physics program. The upgrade of the CDF calorimetry includes: 1) the replacement of the slow gas detectors on the front face of the Central Calorimeter with a faster scintillator version which has a better segmentation, and 2) the addition of timing information to both the Central and EndPlug Electromagnetic Calorimeters to filter out cosmic ray and beam related backgrounds.</p>

			<div>
				<head n="1">THE CENTRAL PRESHOWER AND CRACK DETECTORS</head>

				<p>The CDF Central Preshower (CPR) and Central Crack (CCR) detectors will be replaced at the time the silicon detector is replaced for Run IIb.</p>

				<p>In 1992 the CDF Collaboration installed gas detectors on the front face of the central calorimeter in order to sample early showers and cover the φ-cracks between calorimeter wedges, as shown in Fig. 1. The CPR has been extensively used in electron identification (ID), providing about a factor 2-3 more rejection of charged pions that pass all other cuts. This extra rejection has been crucial in soft electron ID for b-jet tagging, as was shown in the first top evidence paper [1]. The CPR has been used in several publications involving photon ID. By using conversion rates, which are energy independent, it extended the QCD measurement of direct photons by more than 100 GeV in photon transverse momentum P T [2]. The CCR, located after a 10 radiation length thick tungsten bar, has been checked for large pulse heights in all the rare events CDF has observed in Run I. The φ-cracks cover about 8% of the central detector, and in events with multiple electromagnetic objects, the possibility of one object hitting the crack is quite high.</p>

				<p>The present slow CPR and CCR gas detectors</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 1.</head>

					<figDesc>The central calorimetry wedges and the location of the preshower and crack detectors.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>will suffer the luminosity increase foreseen for Run IIb. In order to maintain the same Run I capabilities, they will be replaced by scintillator counters read out by Wave-Length Shifting (WLS) fibers. The new CPR will also have a better segmentation and will be used to improve the jet energy resolution by both correcting for energy loss in the dead material in front of it and adding its information in jet algorithms incorporating charged tracking.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="1.1">The Detector Design fron Run IIb</head>

				<p>The new CPR will be based on 2cm thick scintillator tiles segmented in η and φ and read out by a 1mm diameter WLS fiber running into a groove on the surface of each tile. Six tiles (12.5x12.5 cm 2 each) will cover the front face of each calorimeter tower, and the tiles will be assembled in 48 modules like the one shown in Fig. 2 covering the 48 central calorimeter wedges. After leaving the tiles, the WLS fibers will be spliced to clear fibers which will terminate into plastic connectors at the higher η edge of each module . There ∼5m long optical cables will transmit the light to 16-channel PhotoMultiplier Tubes (PMTs) at the back of the wedge. A current prototype, consisting in scintillator tiles provided by the CDF JINR Dubna group and Pol.Hi.Tech fibers, provided a light yield of ∼20 (12) photoelectrons at the exit of the tile (after all the optical chain), exceeding the design requirement.</p>

				<p>The new CCR will use the same technique but the available space will limit the scintillator thickness to 5mm. Ten tiles, ∼5cm wide, will cover each φ-crack with the same calorimeter segmentation of 10 towers/wedge. Figure 2. View of the CPR upgrade design.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">THE EM TIMING PROJECT</head>

				<p>The CDF Collaboration is adding timing information into the readout of the Central and Plug electromagnetic calorimeters (CEM and PEM) using a technique similar to the hadron TDC system . This upgrade would significantly improve the potential of the CDF detector to do high-P T searches for new physics in data samples with photons in the final state by: 1) reducing the the cosmic ray and beam halo sources of background ; 2) checking that all photons in unsual events are from the primary interaction. With sufficient calibration data, there is even the possibility of searching for very long-lived particles which decay (1-10ns) into photons.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.1">The Hardware Project</head>

				<p>The signal from the PMT goes to a Transition Board on the back of a calorimeter readout VME crate. All the lines are passed through the VME backplane into an Amplifier Shaper Discriminator (ASD) which effectively turns the signal into an LVDS digital pulse suitable for use by a TDC. While the 960 PEM PMTs already have a dynode output designed into the base, a custom splitter is used for the output of the 960 CEM PMTs. The splitter is a fully passive element, completely connectorized, which works by inductively coupling the primary line (for the energy</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>ment) to the secondary output. The primary output loses a negligible amount of the charge and the secondary line only takes ∼15% of the output voltage for use to fire the ASD/TDC system.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Several tests of the splitter, both on the test bench and on the detector itself, show no difference between the input shape and height before and after inserting the splitter into the system . For energies &gt; 4 (2) GeV for the CEM (PEM), the splitter fires the ASD/TDC system with 100% efficiency. The intrinsic timing resolution , measured using the CEM LED and a splitter into a TDC channel of the hadron calorimeter, is ∼1.1ns, dominated by the 1ns TDC resolution.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* Corresponding author. Tel.: +1-212-327-8832; fax: +1- 212-327-7786. E-mail address: lami@fnal.gov (S. Lami)</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Abe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">225</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Abe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">73</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
