<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Exploring Supersymmetry at a Future Global e + e − Linear Collider EXPLORING SUPERSYMMETRY AT A FUTURE GLOBAL E + E − LINEAR COLLIDER</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2004-03-08">8 Mar 2004 March 2004 June 5-10, 2003.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">André</forename>
								<surname>Sopczak</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Andre</forename>
								<surname>Sopczak</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: Andre.Sopczak@cern.ch</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Lancaster University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tucson</settlement>
									<region>AZ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Lancaster University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>LA1 4YW</postCode>
									<settlement>Lancaster</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Exploring Supersymmetry at a Future Global e + e − Linear Collider EXPLORING SUPERSYMMETRY AT A FUTURE GLOBAL E + E − LINEAR COLLIDER</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2004-03-08">8 Mar 2004 March 2004 June 5-10, 2003.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>hep-ph/0403087 Presented at SUSY 2003: Supersymmetry in the Desert, held at the</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This review illustrates by means of sample reactions the potential of a future global e + e − Linear Collider (LC) for precision measurements of Supersymmetric particles with emphasis on recent studies and addressing major research directions. This review illustrates by means of sample reactions the potential of a future global e + e − Linear Collider (LC) for precision measurements of Supersymmetric particles with emphasis on recent studies and addressing major research directions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Many searches for Supersymmetric particles and stringent limits which guide future searches have been set by the LEP experiments in an almost background-free experimental environment. Currently, the Tevatron p¯ p collider , taking data at √ s = 2 TeV, gives important search sensitivity with larger kinematic threshold. When the LHC pp collider starts to operate at √ s = 14 TeV the kinematic reach will be increased significantly. About 13 years of e + e − Linear Collider SUSY studies have been performed with the focus changing from discovery to high-precision analyses. Recent milestones are the TESLA Technical Design Report 2001, the Snowmass 2001 meeting, and the Linear Collider Workshops in Korea (2002) and Amsterdam (2003). This review focuses on new developments for a 500 GeV to 3 TeV LC and includes preliminary results.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">The Linear Collider Project 2.1. Accelerator</head>

				<p>Important accelerator parameters are summarized in Table 1. A future LC is characterized by high luminosity, tunable centre-of-mass energy, low beamstrahlung , beam polarization, additional options for γγ and e − e − collisions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Detector</head>

				<p>Extensive and increasing R&amp;D for all sub-detectors is being performed. An example is the development of CCD vertex detectors in the LC Flavour Identification (LCFI) collaboration 1 .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Table 1. Accelerator parameters.</head>

					<trash>Parameter TESLA NLC/JLC CLIC √ s (GeV) 500 800 500 1000 3000 Gradient (MV/m) 23 35 48 48 150 Lcur (10 34 cm −2 s −1 ) 3.4 5.8 2.0 3.4 10 L int /10 7 s (fb −1 ) 340 580 200 340 1000 Beamstrahlung spread (%) 3.2 4.3 4.7 10.2 31 3. Scalar Top Simulation with c-Quark Tagging In particular, hadronic background can be reduced with c-quark tagging in the reaction e + e − → ˜ t 1 ¯ ˜ t 1 → ˜ χ 0 1 c ˜ χ 0 1 ¯ c 2 . The expected signal and background rates and resulting sensitivities for the scalar top mass and mixing angle determination are shown in Fig. 1 for benchmark parameters SPS-5 (mSUGRA) m 0 = 150 GeV, m 1/2 = 300 GeV, A 0 = −1000 GeV, tan β = 5, µ &gt; 0, leading to m ˜ t1 = 220.7 ± 0.6 GeV and cos θ ˜ t1 = 0.537 ± 0.012. 1 10 10 2 10 3 10 4 0 0.05 0.1 0.15 0.2 0.25 0.3 0.35 total bg qq tt WW Weν Zee ZZ signal+bg Efficiency Events/ 500 fb -1 No beam polarisation c-quark tagging 220.7 GeV scalar top mass 0.5 0.51 0.52 0.53 0.54 0.55 0.56 218 219 220 221 222 m(stop) (GeV) cosθ t ~</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 1.</head>


				</figure>

				<p>Scalar top quark studies for SPS-5 parameters. Left: expected number of signal and background events with c-quark tagging for unpolarized beams. Right: sensitivity for mass and mixing angle from production cross section precision determinations for √ s = 500 GeV and a total luminosity of L = 2 × 500 fb −1 with P e − = −0.80, P e + = 0.60 (left-polarization) and P e − = 0.80, P e + = −0.60 (right-polarization).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Complex Phases on Scalar Top and Scalar Bottom Decays</head>

				<p>Complex phases in the Higgs potential and soft SUSY breaking terms change the scalar top decay width and branching ratios 3 , as shown in Fig. 2 for the example of a SPS-4 inspired scenario with m ˜ t1 =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>531 GeV. 5. Scalar Muon Simulation The reaction e + e − → ˜ µ + R ˜ µ − R → µ + ˜ χ 0 1 µ − ˜ χ 0 1 has been re-investigated 4 for benchmark parameters (SPS-1a) with m ˜ µR =145.9 GeV and m ˜ χ 0 1</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>=100 GeV.</head>

				<p>The isotropic scalar muon decay leads to a flat energy spectrum. From a fit of this spectrum (end-point method) the following precisions are obtained m ˜</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µR = 146.25 ± 0.15 GeV and m ˜ χ 0 1 = 99.98 ± 0.09 GeV for √ s = 500 GeV and L = 400 fb −1 . 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 1.25 1.5 1.75 Ø ½ µÎ Ø ½ · ½ Ø ½ · ¾ Ø ½ ¼ ½ Ø Ø ½ ¼ ¾ Ø 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 ´ Ø ½ µ ³ Ø</trash>

					<head>Figure 2.</head>

					<figDesc>Scalar top decay width and branching ratios as a function of the complex phase of the trilinear coupling of scalar fermion A f .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>6. tan β Sensitivity from Scalar Taus The polarization of τ leptons from the decay of scalar taus τ 1 depends on tan β. The τ polarization can be measured from the shape of the energy spectrum of hadronic τ decays, for example in the reaction e</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>+ e − → ˜ τ + 1 ˜ τ − 1 → ˜ τ + 1 τ − ˜ χ 0 1 → ˜ τ + 1 ν τ π − ˜ χ 0 1 , as illustrated in Fig. 3</trash>

					<figDesc>5 .</figDesc>
					<trash>Figure 3. Left: π energy spectrum fit (yπ = 2Eπ / √ s) determines τ polarization P = 0.57 ± 0.03. Right: resulting sensitivity tan β=40 ± 2 for √ s =500 GeV and L =500 fb −1 . 7. tan β Sensitivity from Higgs Boson Reactions Several Higgs boson</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>reactions are particularly sensitive to tan β and excellent sensitivity on tan β from Higgs boson production rate and decay width measurements can be obtained (Fig. 4) 6</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="8">Theoretical and Experimental Precision</head>

				<p>As an example for the parameters of SPS-1a (mSUGRA) theoretical precision 7 , and expected experimental precision a) from estimates of combined end-point and centre-of-mass scan methods 8 and b) from detailed simulations 9,10 are summarized in Table 2. Some current theoretical uncertainties are much larger than the expected experimental precision.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4.</head>

					<figDesc>Combined sensitivity on tan β from 1) e + e − → b ¯ b → b ¯ bA → b ¯ bb ¯ b rate; 2) e + e − → HA → b ¯ bb ¯ b rate; 3) H,A decay width; 4) e + e − → H + H − → t ¯ bb ¯ t rate; 5) H + decay width. Scenario I: no Supersymmetric particle decays, scenario II: Supersymmetric particle decays. Table 2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Expected theoretical and experimental precision of Supersymmetric particle masses for SPS-1a (mSUGRA) parameters. ∆ th : Gaussian error from Isajet 7.64, Softsusy 1.71, Spheno 2.0 and Suspect 2.101 studies. ∆ a exp : estimated error for a 500 GeV e + e − LC with L = 1000 fb −1 . ∆ b exp : detailed simulations for a 400 GeV e + e − LC with L = 200 fb −1 ( ˜ ℓ and χ 0 1 ) and for a 500 GeV e + e − LC with L = 500 fb −1 (˜ νe). [GeV]</p>

				<p><formula>m ˜ χ 0 1 m ˜ χ 0 2 m ˜ χ ± 1 m ˜ e R m ˜ e L m ˜ µ R m ˜ µ L m ˜ τ 1 m ˜ τ 2 m ˜ νe m ˜ ντ ∆ th 0.3 1.5 1.2 0.6 1.1 1.1 1.1 0.8 1.0 ∆ a exp 0.07 0.12 0.18 0.02 0.2 0.07 0.51 0.64 1.1 ∼ 1 — ∆ b exp 0.10 0.08 0.17 0.30 0.7 9.</formula></p>

				<p>Synergy between the LHC and a LC For the benchmark parameters of SPS-1a all scalar leptons are in the kinematic reach of a 500 GeV LC and the scalar top quark masses are inaccessible at a LC, but in reach of the LHC sensitivity. Figure 5 shows examples of the potential for combined LC and LHC studies 11,12 .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-1000 -500 0 500 1000 A t [GeV] 105 110 115 120 125 130 m h [GeV]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>extraction of A t in SPS 1b ∆m t</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>exp = 2.0 GeV ∆m t exp = 0.1 GeV ∆m h exp</trash>

					<head>Figure 5.</head>

					<figDesc>Left: scalar top from LHC and light Supersymmetric particles from LC. LC&amp;LHC give ∆m t 1</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>= ±7 GeV and ∆θ t = ±0.3, but no mass and mixing sensitivity can be obtained from the LHC alone. Right: trilinear coupling precision ∆At = ±20 GeV when in addition to the LHC measurements (light-shaded band), precise top mass measurements from a LC (dark-shaded band) are used.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="10">Distinguishing Supersymmetry Breaking Models</head>

				<p>At a future LC different Supersymmetry breaking models could be distinguished by their characteristic signatures.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>For example in Anomaly Mediated Supersymmetry Breaking (AMSB) models, which predict small ∆m = m ˜ χ + 1 − m ˜ χ 0 1 values, the reaction e + e − → ˜ χ + 1 ˜ χ − 1 (γ ISR ) has been studied 13 . In the decay mode χ + 1 → ˜ χ 0 1 π</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>+ this analysis is based on tagging of initial-state radiation photons γ ISR . A fit of the π spectrum E π ≈ ∆m gives ∆m = 0.413 ±</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0.017 GeV for √ s = 500 GeV and L = 500 fb −1 . Another example is the Gauge Mediated Symmetry Breaking (GMSB) model with the reaction e − γ → ˜ χ 0 1 ˜ e − R → ˜ e − R e − ˜ e − R → e − e − e − ˜ G ˜ G 14</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, where a triple electron and missing energy signature is expected in an e − γ collider.</p>

				<p>In this model the lightest Supersymmetric particle is the gravitinõ G. 11. γγ Collider and R-Parity Violation The option in the LC project of photon collisions opens new fields of research . For example, in a photon–photon collider, scalar neutrinos could be produced via the reaction γγ → f ¯ f ˜ ν → f ¯ ff ¯ f which is almost free of Standard Model background in the µ + µ − τ + τ − final state 15 . The Feynman graphs and expected production cross sections are shown in Fig. 6</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>γ l - γ l ,+ + crossed diagram 100 150 200 250 300 350 400 450 500 σ(++) σ(+-) σ(00) λ 323 =0.52 / 10 fb Mν ~ (GeV)</trash>

					<head>Figure 6. Left:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>γγ → f ¯ f ˜ ν graphs, ˜ ν (dotted line). Right: σ × BR(˜ ν → f ¯ f ) for different beam polarization states.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>12. e − e − Collider Another option in the LC project, e − e − collisions, allows precision measurements beyond the sensitivity of an e + e − LC. Figure 7 shows as an example the production cross section for e</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− e − → ˜ e − R ˜ e − R → e − e − ˜ χ 0 1 ˜ χ 0 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the precision of the mass determination of scalar electrons. With a luminosity of only 10 fb −1 the expected precision is about 20 MeV 16 .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 7.</head>

					<figDesc>Left: e − e − → ˜ e</figDesc>
					<trash>− R ˜ e − R → e − e − ˜ χ 0 1 ˜ χ 0 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>production cross section. Right: precision of the mass determination of scalar electrons for √ s = 300 GeV and P e − = 0.8.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="13">CLIC 3 TeV</head>

				<p>The CLIC project aims at higher centre-of-mass energies. An example of the expected precision on the masses of scalar muons, and neutralinos χ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 1 and χ 0 2 from the reaction e + e − → ˜ χ 0 2 ˜ χ 0 2 → µ − ˜ µ + R µ + ˜ µ − R → µ − µ + ˜ χ 0 1 µ + µ − ˜ χ 0 1</trash>

					<figDesc>is given in Fig. 8 17 .</figDesc>
					<trash>Smuon Mass (GeV) χ 0 1 Mass (GeV) 620 640 660 680 700 1110 1120 1130 1140 1150 1160 1170 1180 1190</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>M ll (GeV)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Evts / 1 ab -1 0 100 200 300 400 500 0 25 50 75 100 125 150 175 200 225</trash>

					<head>Figure 8.</head>

					<figDesc>Left: reconstructed scalar muon and neutralinõ χ 0 1 masses. Right: ˜ χ 0 2 mass from the muon mass spectrum in one hemisphere ∆m</figDesc>
					<trash>χ 0 2 /m ˜ χ 0 2 = 1.7%.</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="14">Conclusions</head>

				<p>Exploring Supersymmetry at a future linear collider is a very active field of research with many new ideas and new directions. These studies also contribute to the detector design, for example with c-quark tagging as a benchmark for vertex detectors.</p>

				<p>After a first discovery at the Tevatron or the LHC and initial precision measurements, the production and decay modes of many Supersymmetric particles will be measured with very high precision in the first phase of a LC. The Linear Collider will probe the underlying production and decay mechanisms. Detailed studies of several benchmark scenarios have been performed and Supersymmetry breaking models like mSUGRA, AMSM, or GMSB will be distinguished for a wide range of parameters. Combined LC and LHC physics will expand the precision measurements and allow for important consistency checks of the model. The physics case for a future LC is established and the High-Energy-Physics community is ready to embark on the construction of the future global LC.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>Acknowledgments I would like to thank the organizers of the SUSY03 conference for their kind hospitality, my colleagues from the Asian, European and US Supersymmetry working groups for help with the preparation of the presentation, and Alex Finch, Jan Kalinowski, Uli Martyn and Hanna Nowak for comments on the manuscript.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Lcfi Collaboration</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Damerell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Scalar Top Study with c-Quark Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Finch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Nowak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sopczak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Lc-Phsm</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>at. a Linear e + e − Collider</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bartl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hesselbach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Hidaka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Kernreiter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Porod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="311338" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Smuon Production at TESLA</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Nieto-Chaupis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Lc-Phsm</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Boos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">U</forename>
				<surname>Martyn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Moortgat-Pick</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sachwitz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sherstnev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Zerwas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">395</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Gunion</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Han</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Jiang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sopczak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">565</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">42</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Allanach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Kraml</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Porod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Workshop on Linear Collider</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Grannis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Int</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Sorim Press, p. 680 &quot; A Run Scenario for the Linear Collider</title>
		<meeting>. Sorim Press, p. 680 &quot; A Run Scenario for the Linear Collider</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">LC-PHSM-2003-071 &quot; Study of Sleptons – Supersymmetry Scenario SPS 1</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Martyn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Talk at the Int. Workshop on Linear Collider Status of SPS 1 Analysis at Colorado</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Nauenberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<pubPlace>Prague</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Desch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kalinowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Moortgat-Pick</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Nojiri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Polesello</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>private. communications</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Heinemeyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Kraml</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Porod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Weiglein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page">75</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Search for nearly mass degener- ate charginos and neutralinos in e + e − collisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Hensel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Desy-Thesis</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ghosal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kundu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Mukhopadhyaya</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Associated production of single sneutrino and fermion pairs at polarised photon colliders</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Ghosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moretti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Lc-Th</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Feng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Peskin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">115002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Battaglia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. private communications</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
