<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2004-06-21">21 Jun 2004</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2004-06-21">21 Jun 2004</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>The three dimensional theory of gravitation based on a temporal scalar field in Riemanian geometry. S.M.KOZYREV</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A new approach to the model of the universe based on work by Rippl, Romero, Tavakol is presented. We have used the scheme for relating the vacuum (D + 1) dimensional theories to D dimensional theories for setting up a correspondence between vacuum 4-dimensional Einstein theory with 3-dimensional gravity theory with temporal scalar field. These ideas we continued by using the 3-dimensional analog of Jordan, Brans-Dicke theory with temporal scalar field. As the result space and time are treated in completely different ways. For the case of a static spherically symmetric field new vacuum static solutions are found.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The problem of time in relativistic theories of gravity is deeply connected with the special role assigned to temporal concepts in standard theories of physics.</p>

				<p>In particular, in Newtonian physics, starting point is a three-dimensional manifold which serves as a model for physical space and time is external to the system itself. This is contrasted with the so-called &apos;spacetime&apos; (or &apos;covariant&apos;) approaches in which the basic entity is a four-dimensional spacetime manifold. Since the advent of general relativity, the aim of a purely geometrical description of all physical forces as well as that of geometrical origin of the matter content of the Universe has been pursued [1]. Multidimensional purely geometrical gravity has been of much interest at least since the pioneering ideas of Kaluza [2] and Klein [3]. These ideas were continued by Jordan [4] who suggested considering the more general case g 55 = const leading to the theory with an additional scalar field. It is useful here to emphasise a different interpretation of this scheme by recalling that for 5-dimensional Kaluza-Klein spacetimes with a symmetry group generated by (implying that the metric is independent of the extra spatial dimension) the field equations are formally identical to the vacuum Jordan, Brans-Dicke field equations in four dimensions with the free parameter ω = 0. Scalar fields are today again being investigated and with greater vigor than ever before. Recently [5] there has been some interest in the idea that the time is a scalar field on the manifold. Motivated by Kaluza-Klein reduction procedure from (D+1) dimension one can studied a spacetime containing temporal scalar field. These ideas can be extended to systems that are compatible with Newtonian physics: one simply replaces the time system of with the set of temporal scalar field. The addition of the temporal scalar field to the Einstein tensor gives a unique theory. Jordan and his colleagues took the step of separating the scalar field from the original five-dimensional metric context unified gravitational-electromagnetic context having applied this schema one can separate the temporal scalar field from the four-dimensional metric context. This correspondence between the vacuum Einstein theory and lower dimensional theories is of potential importance in view of the radical differences between such theories and 4-dimensional gravity. Space and time are treated in completely different ways. This might seem to be a retrogressive step, but actually the approach achieves everything that Einstein did by presupposing a four-dimensional unity of space and time. It is important to note in this connection that there is a fundamental difference between physics and geometry. In geometry there is no motion that is tightly connected with the concept of time. A basic idea for attempting to formulate a theory of gravitation which is satisfactory from the standpoint of temporal scalar field is considered in Sec. 2. In Sec. 3 the exact static spherically symmetric vacuum solutions to these theory has been obtained. A similar solution has been carried out in Sec. 4 for 3-dimensional more generalized theory with ω = 0. Finally, Sec. 5 briefly discussed some aspects of these theories. Convention in this paper follow those of [6] with Newtonian constant G =1 and c = 1. Here, Greek indices take on values 1 → D whereas Latin indices take on values 1 → D+1.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 Basic Ideas. Consider the case of (D + 1) field vacuum equations D+1 R ab = 0, (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where R ab is a Ricci tensor in the (D+1) -dimensional space. It is well known that equation (1) gives rise to D dimensional Einstein equations with source in the form [7]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>D R αβ = D T αβ . (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Provided extra terms related to the (D+1) dimension are appropriately used to define an energy momentum tensor T aß . Furthermore, the matter source in the D dimensions for that interpretation can be determined by using reasonable equation of state [6]. The investigation of a similar theory of gravity where (D+1) dimension is a time appears to be the one of the way to construct a model with vacuum properties akin to those of general relativity. Although this removes the scenario from Einsteins theory it is nevertheless of interest to seek a minimal modification that can accommodate such features as temporal field. We start with the (D +1) dimensional source-free Kaluza- Klein field equations (1) and take the metric to be in the form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>          0 0 g αβ 0 . . 0 0 0 . . g dd           , (3) where d = D + 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and both the (D + 1) and D dimensional metrics g ab and g aß are in general dependent on the coordinate x d and we write the g dd as g dd = φ 2 , g dd = 1 φ 2 . (4) Note that one could obtain part of the Jordan, Brans-Dicke action with the free parameter ω = 0 [8]. Now the source free field equations in (D + 1) dimensions are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(D+1) R αβ = 0 (D+1) R ab = 0 ⇒ (D+1) R dd = 0 (D+1) R αd = 0 (5) and (D+1) R αβ = (D) R αβ − − φ α;β φ 1 2φ 2 φ, d φ g αβ,d − g αβ,dd + g λµ g αλ,d g βµ,d − 1 2 g µν g µν,d g αβ,d , (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this way the (D + 1)-dimensional source free Einstein type equations are related to a D dimensional theory with sources, from the first of these (5) we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(D) R αβ − 1 2 (D) Rg αβ = (D) T αβ, (7) where an effective energy-momentum tensor is (D) T αβ = φ α;β φ − 1 2φ 2 φ, d φ g αβ,d − g αβ,dd + g λµ g αλ,d g βµ,d − 1 2 g µν g µν,d g αβ,d + + g αβ 8φ 2 g µν , d g µν,d + (g µν g µν,d ) 2 . (8)</trash>

					<figDesc>Note that in more general case stress-energy tensor is assumed to have been derived from the Lagrangian for matter in the usual way. The second wave equation for the scalar field (5) obtained in the usual way</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>✷φ = − 1 4φ g λµ ,d g λν,d − 1 2φ g λµ g λµ,dd + φ, d 2φ 2 g λµ g λµ,d , (9)</formula></p>

				<p>Here the generally covariant d&apos;Alembertian ✷ is defined to be covariant divergence of φ ,ρ :</p>

				<p><formula>✷φ = φ ,ρ ;ρ = √ −g √ −gφ ,ρ ,ρ .</formula></p>

				<p>Finally, the last equations in (5) have the appearance of conservation laws, the full meaning of which is not clear at the present.</p>

				<p><formula>1 2 √ g dd g βµ g µα,d − δ β α g ρν g ρν,d ;β . (10)</formula></p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Static spherically symmetric field.</head>

				<p>As a first step, we employ the 4 dimensional source-free Einstein field equations (1) and take the metric to be in the form (3) where both the 4 and 3 dimensional metrics g ab and g aß are in general dependent on the coordinate t and one can write the g 44 as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g 44 = φ 2 , g44 = 1 φ 2 . (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In empty space when the energy-momentum tensor of matter vanishes, the system of equations (7), (9) have the vacuum solution g µν = η µν and φ = const, where η µν is the Minkowski metric tensor. This solution fixes the arbitrariness in the coordinate system. Now for the static spherically symmetric field we consider line element in the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = e λ dr 2 + r 2 dθ 2 + sin 2 θ dϕ 2 . (12)</trash>

					<figDesc>Then the gravitational field equations and equation for the scalar temporal field yield</figDesc>
					<trash>λ ′ r + λ ′ φ ′ 2φ − φ ′′ φ = 0 2 e λ − 1 + r λ ′ − 2r φ ′ φ = 0 − 4 r + λ ′ − 2 φ ′′ φ = 0 (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the primes stand for derivation respect to r. The solution of these equations is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e λ = r r + m φ = −1 − m r , (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where m integration constant. Obviously in general relativity that is identical to the Schwarzschild solution. We should note, however, that despite the mathematical equivalence of the two solutions, that fact that they come from different physical theories makes them conceptually distinct.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>4</head>

				<p>Three dimensional temporal scalar fields theory with ω = 0.</p>

				<p>From the above it is seen that the field equations (7) -(9) of this model are formally identical to the vacuum Jordan, Brans-Dicke field equations in three dimension with the free parameter ω = 0. However, even more remarkable results came when we tried to couple 3-dimension tensor and scalar fields (with ω = 0). The equations satisfied by the matter variables themselves are formally the same as in standard Jordan, Brans-Dicke theory. This was done in such a way, however, as to keep the Lagrangian and action of matter itself unchanged. It is interesting to investigate whether there exists another relativistic gravity theory which does have the Newtonian theory as its weakfield limit. Consider a 3-dimensional analog of Jordan, Brans-Dicke theory where the temporal scalar field will introduce some dynamics. A model based on this assumption does declare that scalar curvature in empty space is not vanishes. Field equations in a static case are determined by the 3-dimensional tensor field (Riemann metric) and temporal scalar field.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R µν − 1 2 Rg µν = 8π φ T µν − ω φ 2 φ ,µ φ ,ν − 1 2 g µν φ ,λ φ ,λ − 1 φ (φ ,µ;ν − g µν ✷φ) , ✷φ = − 8π 3+2ω T. (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A simple calculation shows that the solution g µν = η µν and φ = const completely satisfy these equations when energy-momentum tensor of matter vanish. The most appropriate coordinates in which to study the static spherically symmetric field are isotropic. Hence, the metric will be assumed to have the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = e 2β dr 2 + r 2 dθ 2 + sin 2 θ dϕ 2 , (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where, β, φ and all matter variables will be assumed to be function of r only. Expressing the line element in isotropic form gives:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>β ′ φ ′ φ − 2β ′ r − ω φ ′ φ 2 − 2β ′′ − φ ′′ φ = 0 3β ′ + r β ′ 2 + r β ′′ + (1+r β ′ )φ ′ φ = 0 2 r + β ′ + φ ′′ φ ′ = 0 (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>One can obtain the exact vacuum solutions to these equations. There are a various branches for this solutions corresponding to different ranges of the arbitrary constants available. In the following these will be denoted by k, m, h and q have values in the indicated ranges. For example:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ = 1− m r 1+ m r k , e 2β = h r 4 (1 − r m ) −2k m −2k (r + m) 2k (r 2 − m 2 ) 2 . (18) and φ = h 1 r −4q √ 2+ω 1 r +4q √ 2+ω 2k , e 2β = m r 4 1 r −4q √ 2+ω 1 r +4q √ 2+ω 2k 1 q 2 − 16r 2 (2 + ω) 2 . (19) where k = ± √ 2 √ 2+ω . Or φ = h m+r m−r k , e 2β = (m−r) 4 8m 2 r 4 h 2 m+r m−r 2−2k (2 + ω) . (20)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusion</head>

				<p>The objectives of this paper are more limited then formulation of a complete theory of time as a scalar field on the manifold. Such a program would consist of the formulation of a suitable field theory and boundary and initial value conditions. The theory to be developed represents a modification of general relativity can be interpreted as a dynamical theory of evolution of three dimensional Riemannian geometry. Any mechanism that allows a bridge to be established between such theories and the ordinary 4 dimensional gravity is of vital interest. One possible way to proceed is to employ the equivalence between the (3 + 1) Einstein theories with 3 dimensional analog of Jordan, Brans-Dicke theories (with ω = 0). The dynamics induced by the new temporal field contains all features that one expects in a theory of gravitation. These ideas may be continued by suggested considering the more general case ω = 0 leading to the theory with an additional temporal scalar field. It is not a completely geometrical theory of gravitation, as gravitational effects are described by a scalar field in a Rimannian manifold. Thus, gravitational effects are in part geometrical and in part due to scalar interaction. There is formal connection between this theory and that of Jordan, Brans Dicke, but there are differences and the physical interpretation is quite different. We expect very interesting consequences of dynamics from these considerations , which will be investigated in future work.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:gr-qc/0406081v1 21 Jun 2004</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>Acknowledgements. The author is grateful to dr. Rolando Cardenas for the kind invitation to make a report at the Santa Clara 2004. International Workshop on Gravitation and Cosmology (31 may-3 June, 2004 Central University of Las Villas, Cuba).</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Meaning of Relativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Einstein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zum Unitä der Physik</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Th</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Kaluza</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sitz. Preuss. Akad. Wiss. Phys. Math. Klasse</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">966</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1921" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Klein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Quantentheorie</forename>
				<surname>Fü Relativitä</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Zeits</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">895</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1926" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Erweiterung der projektiven Relativitatstheorie</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jordan</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. der Phys. P. Jordan., Schwerkraft und Weltal</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Vieweg Verlag</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">219</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1947" />
			<publisher>Vieweg Verlag</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Time and Energy in Gravity Theory, gr-qc/0308073</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Pestov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">D-Dimensional Gravity from (D + 1) Dimensions, gr-qc</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Rippl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Romero</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Tavakol</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9511016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Wesson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Ponce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Leon</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="3883" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Three-dimensional classical space- times</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Barrow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Burd</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Lancaster</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Class.Quantum Grav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="567" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
