<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Complexification of The Vacuum and The Electroweak Gauge Symmetry</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Alp</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Deniz</forename>
								<surname>Ozer</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig Maximilians University Physics Section</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Theresienstr. 37</addrLine>
									<postCode>80333</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Complexification of The Vacuum and The Electroweak Gauge Symmetry</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">(Dated: September 25, 2013)</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term>1130Cp</term>
					<term>1115Ex</term>
					<term>1480Bn</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper we investigate the consequences of imposing an SO(4) symmetry both on the scalar field and on spacetime prior to any spontaneous symmetry breakdown in the electroweak model. First we argue that the local electroweak gauge symmetry is implied by the initial SO(4) symmetry of the scalar field. Then we parameterize the vacuum, in a slightly different way with respect to the conventional assignment in the electroweak model, around the ground state mainly in two different ways: Once over the local electroweak gauge transformations and once over the local γ basis which generates the SO(4) symmetry of the scalar field. Through comparing the two, we conclude that a consistent parametrization, requires the complexification of the scalar field, which simultaneously requires spacetime to obey local Lorentz invariance in the broken phase of the electroweak vacuum. After spontaneous symmetry breakdown and complexification, the SO(3, 1) invariant quantity of the scalar field is identified to be the Higgs mass, which yields mH = v/2 ∼ = 123 GeV. Also the vacuum state is normalized to a unit state by rescaling the local γ basis, so that the metric tensor inherently contains the speed of light in the Higgs vacuum. We shortly consider the validity of the SO(3, 1) invariance property of the vacuum state in terms of the Goldstone modes, in case the Higgs field departs from the ground state. The main goal of the paper is to treat spacetime and vacuum as the two faces of the same medallion, and to relate the local spacetime symmetry with the electroweak gauge symmetry, both in the broken and unbroken phases of the vacuum via complexification and spontaneous symmetry breaking.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>(Dated: September 25, 2013)</head>

				<p>In this paper we investigate the consequences of imposing an SO(4) symmetry both on the scalar field and on spacetime prior to any spontaneous symmetry breakdown in the electroweak model.</p>

				<p>First we argue that the local electroweak gauge symmetry is implied by the initial SO(4) symmetry of the scalar field. Then we parameterize the vacuum, in a slightly different way with respect to the conventional assignment in the electroweak model, around the ground state mainly in two different ways: Once over the local electroweak gauge transformations and once over the local γ basis which generates the SO(4) symmetry of the scalar field. Through comparing the two, we conclude that a consistent parametrization, requires the complexification of the scalar field, which simultaneously requires spacetime to obey local Lorentz invariance in the broken phase of the electroweak vacuum. After spontaneous symmetry breakdown and complexification, the SO(3, 1) invariant quantity of the scalar field is identified to be the Higgs mass, which yields mH = v/2 ∼ = 123 GeV. Also the vacuum state is normalized to a unit state by rescaling the local γ basis, so that the metric tensor inherently contains the speed of light in the Higgs vacuum. We shortly consider the validity of the SO(3, 1) invariance property of the vacuum state in terms of the Goldstone modes, in case the Higgs field departs from the ground state. The main goal of the paper is to treat spacetime and vacuum as the two faces of the same medallion, and to relate the local spacetime symmetry with the electroweak gauge symmetry, both in the broken and unbroken phases of the vacuum via complexification and spontaneous symmetry breaking.</p>

				<p>PACS numbers: 11.30.Cp, 11.15.Ex, 14.80.Bn</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>I. INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>The current formulation of the electroweak gauge theory inevitably requires the existence of a scalar field for a few fundamentally important reasons. First of all, the electroweak gauge interactions among elementary particles naturally occur in vacuum, which is understood to be the stable ground state of the scalar field. Historically, to our knowledge, the scalar field has not been incorporated in the electroweak gauge theory[1][2][3] to provide an underlying physical continuum for gauge interactions.</p>

				<p>The main motivation was to utilize the physics in the spontaneous breakdown of the scalar field[4][5], since it provided masses for the mediators in a gauge invariant and renormalizable way[6], and also explained the non conservation of isotopic spin. From the other side, a general fact in nature is that interactions among matter and fields are solely governed by gauge theories, which come along with their respective gauge symmetries[7]. We also demand gauge theories to be locally Lorentz invariant since initial and final particle states are expressed through quantities like energy and momentum[8] which obey the laws of special relativity . We know that Lorentz Invariance is tightly connected with the abstract notion space-time, which makes hardly physical sense unless we consider matter and fields attached to it. The remarkable thing about spacetime, * Electronic address: oezer@theorie.physik.uni-muenchen.de matter and fields is that it constitutes in a completely different fashion the ingredients of special and general relativity. In contrast to the electroweak theory, gravitational interactions or in other words the motion of massive particles governed by the laws of general relativity are accommodated by spacetime. If it is correct that the Higgs mechanism[9][10] is the ultimate formalism to create inertial and gravitational masses for elementary particles, we should somehow be able to relate the scalar field, which is responsible for the mass generation mechanism, with spacetime. In this paper we will treat vacuum and spacetime as the two faces of the same medallion and will draw certain consequences out of it, such as the Higgs boson mass and speed of light in the Higgs vacuum. The relation between the two faces will be step wise introduced through out the work, the main steps however are summarized in the conclusion part for clarity. As a starting point it would be most appropriate to consider the global transformation properties of the 4 component scalar field. Let us start by placing four real valued scalar fields in a column</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ = 1 √ 4    φ 1 φ 2 φ 3 φ 0    (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A Lagrangian of the scalar field, in the four vector representation that exhibits a global SO(4) symmetry, is</p>

				<p><formula>L φ = (∂ µ φ) T (∂ µ φ) + µ 2 φ T φ − λ φ T φ 2 (2)</formula></p>

				<p>where µ 2 , λ are initially chosen to be positive. We characterize the vacuum through these scalar fields. The vacuum state corresponds to the ground state of the scalar field. Prior to any spontaneous symmetry breakdown and phase transition the null vector φ ≡ 0, obviously defines a false vacuum since it pertains to an unstable ground state. This false vacuum is trivially SO(4) invariant. Let us additionally demand that our 4 dimensional spacetime[11] exhibits a Euclidean signature and is subject to the same symmetry of the scalar field.</p>

				<p>The real generators Σ ab , that satisfy the SO(4) Lie Algebra, can be generated through (Σ ab ) ij = − (δ ai δ bj − δ ji δ ab ) (3) [Σ ab , Σ cd ] = Σ bc δ ad + Σ ad δ bc − Σ ac δ bd − Σ bd δ ac (4)</p>

				<p>The above real valued Lie Algebra of SO(4), can be made complex by allowing Σ → i Σ as below. But in general, this complex valued Lie Algebra is satisfied by the so called spinorial representation of SO(4). The generators of this spinorial representation can be produced by a set of 4 gamma matrices : [Σ ij , Σ kl ] = −i (Σ jk δ il + Σ il δ jk − Σ ik δ jl − Σ jl δ ik )</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(5) Σ ij = i 2 [γ i , γ j ] , 2 δ ij = − {γ i , γ j } (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where δ ij carries a Euclidean signature for i, j, k, l = {0, 1, 2, 3} such that δ kk = 1, and the curly brackets denote anticommutation. Let us consider as next the gamma matrices of the chiral representation. These are explicitly stated as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>γ i = 0 σ i −σ i 0 , γ 0 = 0 −I −I 0 (7) γ 5 = I 0 0 −I where i = 1, 2, 3 and σ i are the Pauli spin matrices. The chiral representation composed of {γ 0 , γ 1 , γ 2 , γ 3 } satisfies Lorentz covariance hence belongs to SO(3, 1) and has the following signature (γ 0 ) 2 = 1 (γ 1 ) 2 = (γ 2 ) 2 = (γ 3 ) 2 = −1 (8) If we replace γ 0 by −iγ 0 def = ˜ γ 0 . The signature turns out to be Euclidean (˜ γ 0 ) 2 = −1 (γ 1 ) 2 = (γ 2 ) 2 = (γ 3 ) 2 = −1 (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Now we can use the basis {˜n eq. (6), so that the generators produced by this basis satisfy the SO(4) Lie Algebra. Let us construct a sum over the scalar fields spanned by the basis {˜e obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ = φ i γ i 4 + φ 0 ˜ γ 0 4 = 1 √ 8     0 0 φ 0 1 φ + 1 0 0 φ − 2 −φ 0 2 −φ 0 2 −φ + 2 0 0 −φ − 1 φ 0 1 0 0     (10) φ c = − φ i γ * i 4 − φ 0 ˜ γ * 0 4 = 1 √ 8     0 0 −φ 0 2 −φ − 2 0 0 −φ + 1 φ 0 1 φ 0 1 φ − 2 0 0 φ + 1 −φ 0 2 0 0     (11) Here the upper indices {+, 0, −} are showing the charges with respect to the diagonal generator Σ 12 which is obtained from Σ ij = i 2 [γ i , γ j ] = ǫ ijk σ k 0 0 σ k (12) The lower indices in {φ 0 1 , φ 0 2 , φ + 1 , φ − 2 } are introduced just to distinguish among the entries. The explicit expressions of these 4 fields in terms of {φ 1 , φ 2 , φ 3 , φ 0 } is found to be φ 0 1 = (φ 3 − i φ 0 )/ √ 2 φ 0 2 = (φ 3 + i φ 0 )/ √ 2 φ + 1 = (φ 1 − i φ 2 )/ √ 2 φ − 2 = (φ 1 + i φ 2 )/ √ 2 (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From the above expressions it is easy to see that the imaginary sign in front of φ 0 in both φ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 1 and φ 0 2 stems from γ 0 = −iγ 0 . If we had not utilized γ 0 in the expansion, the fields φ 0 1 and φ 0 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>wouldn&apos;t have had a complex form. An explicit imaginary sign was required to appear in front of φ 0 , in this respect. Also note that T r[φφ]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>is thereby an SO(4) invariant. −T r[φ φ] = 1 4 φ 2 1 + φ 2 2 + φ 2 3 + φ 2 0 (14) The Lagrangian of the scalar field can equivalently be reexpressed through φ in eq.(10) as L φ = −T r [ ∂ µ φ ∂ µ φ ] − µ 2 T r [ φ φ ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>− λ T r [ φ φ ] 2 (15) There is no Hermitian conjugation in the product φ φ. Note that the γ matrices can also be treated algebraically, so that the trace operation can be dropped as well. In Eq.(13) there are only four independent fields. These fields can be organized into two doublets.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ = φ + 1 φ 0 1 = 1 √ 2 φ 1 − iφ 2 φ 3 − iφ 0 (16) and φ * = φ − 2 φ 0 2 = 1 √ 2 φ 1 + iφ 2 φ 3 + iφ 0 (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The above doublets are complex conjugates of each other, since {φ 1 , φ 2 , φ 3 , φ 0 } are real fields. Note that they transform under Σ ij , for i, j = {1, 2, 3} independently, so that we can consider them separate SU (2) doublets. The nice thing about the expansion in Eq.(10) is that it allows each doublet to be grouped so as to include a copy of all four scalar fields. We see that the {+, 0} charges in φ, do not correspond to the σ 3 charges of SU (2) but are due to Σ 12 . We will come back to this point again. From the other side the Lagrangian of the scalar field in eq.(2) can sufficiently be reproduced by any of the above doublets, which are indeed equivalent. Since we have put the four fields into a complex representation, the Lagrangian should then be written in a complex form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L φ = 1 2 (∂ µ φ) † (∂ µ φ) + µ 2 2 φ † φ − λ 4 φ † φ 2 (18) Such a restatement imposes an overall U (2) symmetry on the Lagrangian, which is nothing but an SU (2) × U (1) symmetry. The above {+, 0} charges in φ can be retrieved from this SU (2) × U (1) symmetry, such that σ 3 2 + Y 2 (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To obtain the charges {+, 0} in the components of φ, one has to assign +1 to Y , which turns out to be the usual hypercharge of φ. In this way it becomes easier to understand how φ transforms under SU (2) but carries charges of a larger symmetry. The SU (2) × U (1) global symmetry of the scalar field is implied[12] by SO(4). After that the scalar field is restated within a complex representation of the SU (2) × U (1), we expect that, this symmetry holds also locally, and describes gauge interactions with locally conserved charges [13]. The partial derivatives in eq. (18) should be replaced with the gauge covariant ones to assure local gauge invariance with respect to the local gauge symmetry.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. COMPLEXIFICATION</head>

				<p>Prior to any spontaneous symmetry breakdown and complexification, where the latter will be clearly defined towards the end of this section, we assume that the scalar field φ in eq.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1) transforms under SO(4). Therefore φ T φ = 1 4 φ 2 1 + φ 2 2 + φ 2 3 + φ 2 0 (20) is an SO(4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) invariant of the scalar field. Prior to any spontaneous symmetry breakdown and complexification the null vector which is the unstable ground state, describes a false vacuum and is trivially SO(4) invariant. We additionally assume that space-time, prior to any spontaneous symmetry breakdown and complexification, transforms under SO(4) as well.</p>

				<p>From the other side we know that, in the spontaneously broken phase of the local SU (2) × U (1) electroweak symmetry , space-time transforms under SO(3, 1). Owing to our assumption that initially both the scalar field and space-time are transforming under SO(4), we expect analogously, that in the spontaneously broken phase, the scalar field transforms under SO(3, 1).i.e., it transforms like spacetime. Therefore in the broken phase</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ T φ = 1 4 φ 2 1 + φ 2 2 + φ 2 3 − φ 2 0</trash>

					<figDesc>(21) should be an SO(3, 1) invariant of the scalar field. The stable ground state of the scalar field corresponds to the true vacuum. Consequently, the true vacuum should also satisfy the above SO(3, 1) invariant relation. We postulate that at some stage prior to spontaneous symmetry breakdown, the scalar field must have undergone a phase transition. Note that the transformation φ 0 ↔ i φ 0 (22) switches us back and forth between eq.(20) and (21). From the other side, it is formally possible to absorb the phase into the basis, in this way the transformation switches us also back and forth between the two sets of gamma matrices given in Eq.(8) and (9). This can be clarified in the following: The complex form of the scalar fields in eq. (16) and (17) are only maintained if the component φ 0 has correctly i as a prefactor. If we let φ 0 → i φ 0 then the expansion in eq.(10) should be done over the basis {γ i , γ 0 } instead {γ i , ˜ γ 0 }. This signals us that the initial SO(4) and final SO(3, 1) symmetries of the scalar field are related over the phase of φ 0 . The respective two sets {γ i , ˜ γ 0 } and {γ i , γ 0 } specify the initial and final metric of spacetime. We will come back to this point later again. We know that three components of the scalar field are associated with the massless goldstone modes, which can be gauged away ( or parameterized ) with an SU (2) transformation. Since SU (2) is isomorphic to SO(3), it is appropriate to assign the φ 1 , φ 2 , φ 3 fields to SU (2). The fourth field φ 0 is associated with the Higgs field, we know that the vacuum even after symmetry breakdown preserves the local gauge symmetry in a hidden way, so the U (1) piece of SU (2) × U (1) should be related with the leftover field φ 0 . Note that, in contrast to the usual assignment in the Higgs mechanism implemented in the electroweak theory, the vacuum expectation value will not be assigned here to φ 3 but to φ 0 , which is a major difference[14]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>This choice covers interesting properties as will be later seen. Let us consider the vacuum at a particular minimum resulting from eq. (18) such that</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>φ 1 = φ 2 = φ 3 = 0 φ 0 = √ 2µ √ λ = v φ o = 0 i v √ 2 = v √ 2 0 i (23)</formula></p>

				<p>In the rest of this paper, the scalar fields {φ 1 , φ 2 , φ 3 , φ 0 } will be parameterized with {ξ 1 , ξ 2 , ξ 3 , ξ 0 } respectively. All degrees of freedom should be linearly independent and the vacuum should be consistently parameterizable . The above mentioned phase transition described by φ 0 → i φ 0 will turn out to be a necessity for a consistent parametrization of the vacuum or more generally of the scalar field. Two cases of parametrization are of interest : Case I : The scalar field is supposed to transform under the local gauge symmetry, therefore the parametrization of the scalar field around the vacuum state should be done over the generators of the gauge group {σ i , Y } together with the expansion parameters of the scalar field {ξ 1 , ξ 2 , ξ 3 , ξ 0 } respectively, which closely amounts to the so called unitary gauge[15]. Case II : The scalar field is supposed to transform under the SO(4) symmetry, where the γ basis has coordinate dependence. Consistency requires that the scalar field should also be parameterizable around the vacuum state through the basis {γ i , ˜ γ 0 }, with the expansion parameters {ξ 1 , ξ 2 , ξ 3 , ξ 0 } respectively. This latter parametrization might suitably called the metric gauge.</p>

				<p>Trough comparing the former and the latter parametrizations, we explore the underlying condition that nature imposes on the scalar field. The condition will turn out to become what we call Complexification, and the local Euclidean symmetry will undergo a change of signature. Parametrization -Case II : Let us start with the latter parametrization described in case II, by considering the following ground state and the exponentiated transfor- mation ;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e −i γ·ξ(x)/v−i γ0·ξ0/v ·     0 −i v √ 2 0 +i v √ 2     (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The exponential part if expanded up to first order reads</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>    1 0 −i ξ3 v − ξ0 v −i ξ1−i ξ2 v 0 1 −i ξ1+i ξ2 v i ξ3 v − ξ0 v i ξ3 v − ξ0 v i ξ1−i ξ2 v 1 0 i ξ1+i ξ2 v −i ξ3 v − ξ0 v 0 1     the product of the vacuum state with the above expansion yields 1 √ 2      ξ 1 − iξ 2 −ξ 3 − i(ξ 0 + v) ξ 1 − iξ 2 −ξ 3 + i(ξ 0 + v)     </trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is remarkable to see here that γ 0 behaves formally like the hypercharge Y , and ξ 0 plays the role of the Higgs field H, because it correctly appears beside v within the parametrization. Let us consider the last term in the exponential to investigate how the hypercharge acts:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>i ˜ γ 0 · ξ 0 = i (−i γ 0 ) · ξ 0 = γ 0 · ξ 0 ≡ −Y · ξ 0 = i Y · (i ξ 0 ) = i Y · ˜ ξ 0 (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is seen in the last line that Y selects out ξ 0 def = iξ 0 as the expansion parameter. Using the same vacuum state, we verify this choice in the forthcoming parametrization mentioned in case I. Parametrization -Case I : First we demonstrate how the parametrization works, then we identify the H field.</p>

				<p>Let us consider the following transformation acting on the minimum</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ(x) ≈ φ 0 (x) = e −i σ·ξ(x)/v− i Y ·ξ0/v 0 i v √ 2 (26) Expanding the exponential up to first order gives 1 − i ξ3 v − i ξ0 v −i ξ1−i ξ2 v −i ξ1+i ξ2 v 1 + i ξ3 v − i ξ0 v 0 i v √ 2 = 1 √ 2 ξ 1 − iξ 2 −ξ 3 + ξ 0 + iv</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is seen that ξ 0 emerges at the wrong place and does not add up to v, consequently doesn&apos;t operate like the H field. Since we demand that ξ 0 should operate[16] like H, we consider the possibility of a phase transition ξ 0 → i ξ 0 = ˜ ξ 0 which was previously postulated in eq. (22). Note that this phase transition can be compensated iñ γ 0 · ξ 0 → − γ 0 · ˜ ξ 0 , which preserves invariance, and fulfills the previously stated condition in eq. (25). If we substitute ξ 0 back in the last line above we obtain the correct form 1 √ 2 ξ 1 − iξ 2 −ξ 3 + i(ξ 0 + v)</p>

				<p>The phase transition is essential and leads the scalar field to undergo a complexification, thereby spacetime changes signature and becomes Minkowski. The four scalar fields should then subsequently be reexpressed as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ = 1 √ 4    φ 1 φ 2 φ 3 iφ 0    (27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Consequently the scalar field satisfies the condition in eq. (21). Physically we will observe the expectation value of φ 0 and not its phase, the phase is swallowed by the basis which becomes, {γ 0 , γ 1 , γ 2 , γ 3 } and exhibits a Minkowski signature 2 η µν = −{γ µ , γ ν } , ( µ, ν = 0,1,2,3 )</p>

				<p>Since the scalar field is coordinate dependent, both parameterizations should hold locally. Therefore the gamma basis should have a coordinate dependence as well, and thereby defines a local spin 2 field through η µν , which implies the incorporation of general relativity . From the other side, in our analysis, SO(4) had naturally implied the U (2) ≡ SU (2) × U (1) unitary representation of the scalar field, giving rise to local spin 1 gauge fields, which are the vector gauge bosons mediating interactions. Finally the Spinorial representation itself can naturally accommodate spinors, so are the spin 1/2 fields also incorporated.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. LORENTZ INVARIANCE</head>

				<p>In the unitary gauge, the photon has no couplings to the Higgs field, nor does it have a mass term, provided over the vacuum expectation value. As a result the photon does encounter no resistance of the Higgs vacuum and the surviving U (1) e symmetry is Lorentz invariant.</p>

				<p>In contrast, the W and the Z have couplings to H and have also mass terms. They are in contact with vacuum over tadpoles. The Lorenz invariance of weak interactions reflect somehow the following picture: If one were given the task to show that space-time is Lorentz invariant only by using the massive W and Z&apos;s as mediators of interactions, he or she would probably found out that there is a dominant SO(3) symmetry of space and an independent measure of time, in the first place.</p>

				<p>Presumably in a world made up of massive mediators, which would dramatically lead to a dominantly mechanical environment, that means forces are short ranged and appear through contact, it wouldn&apos;t be possible to find out any trace of Lorentz Invariance. The velocity of massive W and Z&apos;s are obviously no invariants with respect to different inertial observers, whereas the photon speed in vacuum is. This is told us by the coordinate transformations that leave the Maxwell equations Invariant. Another invariant property of the scalar field after becoming massive, is its (rest) mass. Therefore we can work out the vacuum state φ o by plugging it in eq. (14).</p>

				<figure>
					<head>We obtain :</head>

					<figDesc>−T r [ φ φ ] = −T r</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>  i φ i γ i 4 − γ 0 (i φ 0 ) 4 2   = 1 4 φ 2 1 + φ 2 2 + φ 2 3 + φ 2 0 vac = v 2 4 = m 2 H c 4 (28)</formula></p>

				<p>where m H c 2 is the invariant mass term of the Higgs field, at the ground state where φ 1 = φ 2 = φ 3 = 0 and φ 0 = v.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>From v = √ 2µ √ λ and m 2 H = µ 2 one finds that λ = 1</trash>

					<figDesc>2 . The potential function of the scalar field prior to spontaneous symmetry breakdown and complexification turns out to reduce in a natural form</figDesc>
					<trash>V (φ) = − 1 2 m 2 H (φ † φ) + 1 8 (φ † φ) 2 (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The Higgs mass m H is thereby determined as m H = v/2 ∼ = 123 GeV. Actually the preceding relation should be understood the other way around, conversely m H and v determine the speed of light in the Higgs vacuum. This follows from a simple consideration that we can normalize the vacuum state φ o in eq. (23), into a unit state 0 i (30) by absorbing the factor v √ 2 into γ 0 of the basis {γ 1 , γ 2 , γ 3 , γ 0 }, that spans {φ 1 , φ 2 , φ 3 , i φ 0 }. Furthermore the invariant quantity T r [ φ φ ] normalizes to 1/4 ( in SI units to c 2 /4 ), if we further absorb 1 √ 2mH into γ 0 . Thereby we redefine γ 0 for the sake of obtaining a unit vacuum state such that γ 0 −→ v 2 m H 1 2 · γ 0 (31) The Minkowski signature reveals this non uniformity (in SI units) η µν =    1 0 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 0 −c 2    (32) where the last entry is departing from 1, and normalizes the fourth spacetime component ; x 0 = i c t. The factor determines the speed of electromagnetic disturbances in the Higgs vacuum :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>c = v 2 m H 1 2 : Speed of Light in Vac. (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>After the rescaling of γ 0 , which follows from the normalization of the vacuum state, we get −T r [ φ φ ] = 1 4 (34) This equality should always hold even when the Higgs field becomes excited and departs from the ground state.</p>

				<p>In this respect the parametrization allows us to utilize the ξ 1 , ξ 2 , ξ 3 fields, which can be chosen such that the invariant −φ T φ = 1/4 is satisfied for any arbitrary value of ξ 0 = 0, which is by definition the H field. A suitable gauge would be ;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ξ 2 0 − 3 i=1 ξ 2 i = 1; ξ 0 = H; ξ 0 (0) = 1 (35)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The excited Goldstone modes ξ 1 , ξ 2 , ξ 3 can be gauged away in the unitary gauge when necessary.</p>

				<p>Complexity of the Vacuum : The time variable t is real and thus measurable, but formally can be made to enter the Lorentz transformations with a complex sign, so that the rotation is over a complex angle in a complex plane. A similar situation arose in the vacuum. The ground state in eq. (23) contains a complex sign. However the vacuum expectation value v is itself real and is gained by the component φ 0 . The ground state enters the transformation with a complex prefactor just like t.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>IV. CONCLUSION</head>

				<p>We shortly highlight here the underlying steps that lead to the complexification of the vacuum :</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(a) The real valued scalar field, can be cast in a complex representation, so that the global SO(4) invariant Lagrangian naturally implies a global U (2) invariant Lagrangian. (b) The global charges remnant of SO(4) are taken over by the unitary representation U (1) × SU (2). This symmetry turns out to hold as a local gauge symmetry . The gamma basis should also be spacetime dependent.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>(c) A consistent parametrization through the unitary and metric gauges assigns the real fields φ 1 , φ 2 , φ 3 to SU (2) and φ 0 to U (1) and also requires the complexification of the scalar field; φ 0 → iφ 0 which amounts to a change in signature of spacetime; i γ 0 → γ 0 (d) The scalar field develops an invariant mass term through the spontaneous breakdown of the unstable ground state to the stable ground state. The spontaneous breakdown is likely to be induced by the complexification; Since the product −µ 2 (φ T φ), contributes for φ 0 → iφ 0 a mass term with the correct sign.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(e) Normalization of the true vacuum state places a constant factor c = v 2 mH in front of γ 0 . The rescaled gamma basis inherently defines the speed of light in the Higgs vacuum, over the SO(3, 1) invariance of the Maxwell equations.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>priate to call it 4 dimensional space only, so that time is treated on equal footing with other coordinates. [12] With the phrase implied we mean that the real scalar fields of SO(4) can be cast in a complex field of U (2) . Note that this is not an embedding. We think that in this way can the global charges of SO(4) be taken over by the global SU (2) × U (1) symmetry. The same applies to the currents as well. Note that non-trivial currents require complex conjugation, and make sense only within unitary representations. [13] Since the scalar fields are local fields the γ basis spanning φ should be spacetime dependent as well, consequently the SO(4) symmetry should be a local symmetry but not a local gauge symmetry, so that a local metric is defined. [14] The field φ0 is by definition initially real, but the U (1) symmetry requires complex representations. This is another hint to see why the scalar field is apt to undergo complexification. [15] In principle this parametrization is like that in the unitary gauge but differs in the assignment of the expansion parameters as we discussed before. See also eq. (26) [16] This requirement might be understood in the context of consistent parametrization of the scalar field around the vacuum.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1264</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Originally printed in *Svartholm: Elementary Particle Theory, Proceedings Of The Nobel Symposium Held</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Salam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">At Lerum, Sweden*</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="377" />
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Iliopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Maiani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1285</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Goldstone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nuovo Cim</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">154</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Goldstone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Salam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">965</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1962" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J G</forename>
				<surname>Veltman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">189</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sec(4.2) and the latter two were unified in the electroweak model by several authors in [1][2][3], whose gauge sector is mainly based on pio- neering works of H</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Coral Gables Conf</title>
		<editor>H. Fritzsch and M. Gell-Mann in C.N.Yang and R. Mills</editor>
		<meeting>. of Coral Gables Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1929" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Particle Data Group Collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Eidelman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">592</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Higgs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Higgs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">508</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Instead of 4 dimensional spacetime, it would be</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
