<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Note on the evolution of cosmic string/superstring networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2005-03-30">30 Mar 2005</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">M</forename>
								<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: msakel@cc.uoa.gr</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Division of Astrophysics, Astronomy and Mechanics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Athens</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>GR-15784</postCode>
									<settlement>Zografos (Athens), Hellas</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Note on the evolution of cosmic string/superstring networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2005-03-30">30 Mar 2005</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In the context of brane world scenario, cosmic superstrings can be formed in D-brane annihilation at the end of the brane inflationary era. The cosmic superstring network has a scaling solution and the characteristic scale of the network is proportional to the square root of the reconnection probability. A Note on the evolution of cosmic string/superstring networks 2</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Cosmic superstrings have recently gained a lot of interest. They are expected to be formed in the context of a brane world scenario and it was advertised that they lead to observational predictions which might distinguish them from the gauge theory solitons, we are most familiar with.</p>

				<p>Cosmic strings are formed in a large number of Spontaneous Symmetry Breaking (SSB) phase transitions. Suppose we have the symmetry breaking of a group G down to a sub-group H of G. The formation of cosmic strings is related to the first homotopy group π 1 (G/H) of the vacuum manifold M = G/H, i.e., if M is not simply connected then cosmic strings form. In an exhaustive study of symmetry breaking schemes from a large gauge group down to the standard model gauge group, Jeannerot et al [1] have shown that in the context of supersymmetric grand unified theories, cosmic strings generically appear at the end of a hybrid inflationary era. However, the measurements of the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) temperature anisotropies impose severe constraints on the cosmic strings contribution to the CMB data, as it was shown by Bouchet et al [2], and more recently by Pogosian et al [3, 4]. Thus, CMB measurements can impose upper limits to the value of the dimensionless parameter Gµ ∼ η 2 /m</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>Pl , where the SSB scale η determines the critical temperature T cr for the phase transition leading to string formation, and G = 1/m</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>Pl is Newton&apos;s constant.</p>

				<p>Recently, Rocher and Sakellariadou [5, 6] have shown that F-term as well as D-term supersymmetric hybrid inflation, accompanied by cosmic string formation at the end of the inflationary era, are still compatible with CMB measurements, provided the couplings and the mass scales are tuned within acceptable limits. As the string network evolves, a number of string intersections take place, and this, with a given probability, can lead to an exchange of partners. String intercommutations lead to the creation of kinks along the long strings, which implies that long strings are not straight but they develop wiggles, and thus they emit gravitational radiation, as it was calculated by Sakellariadou [7]. In addition, the loops which are chopped off from certain string intersections and selfstring intercommutations also emit gravitational waves. Gravitational radiation is conventionally believed to be the most efficient mechanism for string decay. This issue is not settled since Vincent et al [8, 9] have shown that the string network looses energy directly into scalar and gauge radiation. Numerical studies by Vincent et al [8] have for the first time shown that particle production, and not gravitational radiation, is the dominant energy loss mechanism for cosmic string networks. Whether or not gravitational radiation is the most efficient mechanism for cosmic string decay is a very important issue, which however we will not address here and we will come to this question later, in Ringeval and Sakellariadou [10].</p>

				<p>In the context of brane world scenario one naturally expects an era of brane inflation, as proposed by Dvali and Tye [11]. The end of brane inflation is taken place when, either a brane and an anti-brane, or a pair of branes oriented at angles, collide. The inter-brane separation, which is an open string mode, plays the rôle of the inflaton field, while the inflaton potential emerges from the exchange of closed string modes between the branes. As the inter-brane separation becomes smaller than some critical value, an open string mode stretching between the branes becomes tachyonic and the rolling of the tachyon field describes the decay of the pair of branes. This leads to heating of the universe and the beginning of the big bang. Brane annihilation can lead to the formation of lower dimensional D-branes ‡ which are seen as topological defects by brane observers. As it was shown by Sarangi and Tye [13], cosmic superstrings are copiously produced during brane collisions. These cosmic superstrings are Dp-branes with (p − 1) dimensions compactified. It is important that neither monopoles, nor domain walls, nor textures, are produced during this process. Cosmic superstrings share a number of properties in common with the familiar cosmic strings. It is however important to identify their differences which may lead to distinctive observational signatures.</p>

				<p>In what follows we examine the behavior of the characteristic scale of the string network with respect to the string reconnection probability. We reach conclusions which differ from results by Dvali and Vilenkin [14] and Jones et al [15]. This may lead to important consequences regarding the observational signatures of cosmic superstrings and their differences with respect to their solitonic analogues.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Numerical experiments</head>

				<p>The picture we have in mind is brane annihilation leading to independent stochastic networks of Dirichlet (D) and Fundamental (F) strings. In other words, we will not consider the interaction between D-and F-networks. D-and F-strings may be observed as cosmic strings. The evolution of string networks and thus, their observational consequences, depend on the outcome of string collisions. It is well known that reconnections may lead to closed loop formation and the straightening of long open strings. Regarding this issue, it seems to be an important difference between superstrings and the gauge theory soliton strings. The microscopic structure of the string core will only affect the string evolution when two strings collide and their cores come to an interaction. A basic difference between superstrings and cosmic strings is that the first move in extra compact dimensions. This motion leads to a suppression of the reconnection probability since strings can miss each other. The effect of extra dimensions on superstring evolution can be seen by choosing a small reconnection probability, as it was stated by Dvali and Vilenkin [14] and earlier it had been shown numerically in the context of string gas cosmology by Sakellariadou [16]. Performing numerical simulations of cosmic string evolution we find that some aspects of the evolution of strings moving in a 3-dimensional space with reconnection probability smaller than 1, are qualitatively comparable to that of strings moving in a higher dimensional space with reconnection probability equal to 1.</p>

				<p>For gauge theory solitons, the probability of reconnection when two strings meet is equal to 1. As vortex strings in the Abelian Higgs model collide, reconnection is classically inevitable, provided the collision velocity is small and the relative angle between the orientation of the motion of the colliding strings is also small, as shown by Hanany and Hashimoto [17]. The collisions between all possible pairs of superstrings have been studied in string perturbation theory by Jackson et al [18]. For F-strings, the reconnection probability is of order of g 2 s , where g s stands for the string coupling. For F-F string collisions, it was found by Jackson et al [18] that the reconnection probability P is 10 −3 &lt; ∼ P &lt; ∼ 1.</p>

				<p>For D-D string collisions, one has 10 −1 &lt; ∼ P &lt; ∼ 1. Finally, for F-D string collisions, the reconnection probability can take any value between 0 and 1.</p>

				<p>The results by Jackson et al [18] have been confirmed by a quantum calculation of the reconnection probability for colliding D-strings. More precisely, classically nothing happens for colliding D-strings, since the D-string action permits a solution describing D-strings passing through each other. One has to study colliding D-strings quantum mechanically, and then one gets a a tachyonic instability, which is characteristic for intersecting D-branes. The tachyon condensation leads then to D-string reconnection, with reconnection probability derived from the time evolution of the tachyon wave function [17]. Following Sen&apos;s conjecture [19], we consider the D-strings as vortex-like topological defects in tachyon condensation on a brane and anti-brane pair. We study numerically the evolution of the superstring network as a function of the reconnection probability. Our initial string configuration is generated by the Monte Carlo algorithm of string formation, given by Vachaspati and Vilenkin [21]. Alternatively, either we artificially form an initial string network consisting of long winding strings accompanied by a loop gas, or we just consider a gas of small loops. This approach is often preferable since we have control over the initial string density. The strings are represented by discrete points on a lattice and they are contained in a d-dimensional box with periodic boundary conditions, i.e. a torus. This implies that all strings are closed loops. Our results are independent of the choice of boundary conditions and we have checked their validity by choosing instead reflecting boundary conditions. Points on strings are equally spaced in energy, and therefore the total energy of a loop is proportional to the number of points by which it is discretised. We choose the energy between neighboring points on a string as being the unit of energy and the lattice spacing as the unit of length and time. Strings formed with a Monte Carlo algorithm are initially at rest and are composed of straight links pointing in three orthogonal directions. When the initial string network is composed from a loop gas, the strings have initially non-zero velocities. The string network is divided into long strings (strings of infinite length) and small loops. We have checked that this division is not sensitive to the exact choice of the separating line, since we find only very few loops in the intermediate range of sizes. In our numerical simulations we have tested the robustness of our findings against three possible definitions of infinitely long strings. (1) We define an infinitely long string, a loop whose energy is equal or greater to the square of the size (or half the size) of the box. This choice is made since on large scales the strings are Brownian [22]. (2) We define an infinitely long string, a closed loop for which at least one of its extents exceeds kξ, where k ∼ 1 is a numerical coefficient and the characteristic length scale ξ(t) is determined using the density of long strings from the previous evolution timestep. An alternative definition using the extents, is to say that a string is infinitely long if at least one of its extents is greater than the size (or half the size) of the box. (3) We define a string as being infinitely long if it satisfies both criteria (1) and (2). Our results are not sensitive to the choice of one of the conditions (1), (2) or (3). We let the string network evolve by discretising the Nambu equations of motion in a Minkowski space. When two strings intersect, they intercommute with a given probability P . To approach the realistic expanding universe, we do not allow small loops to interact with the rest of the network. Thus, small loops are not allowed to reconnect to long strings at later stages of the evolution; they freeze out. We decouple a small loop from the string network if all its extents are smaller than k ′ ξ, where k ′ is an adjustable numerical factor k ′ ∼ 1. We let the string network evolve up to L/2 timesteps since late-time behavior of the network is dominated by finite-size effects. The long strings are characterised by a single length scale</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ξ(t) = ρ l µ −1/2 , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ρ l denotes the energy density of long strings and µ stands for the linear mass density, which equals the string tension. Thus, the typical distance between the nearest string segments and the typical curvature of the strings are both of order ξ. We study the characteristic length ξ as a function of evolution time t, performing a number of runs with a range of values for the free parameters of the model. These free parameters set, for a box of a given size L, the reconnection probability P , the energy E c of the smallest allowed loop, the definition of an infinitely long loop (i.e., k), and the definition of the very small loops which freeze out in the subsequent evolution (i.e., k ′ ). Most of our numerical experiments were done in a 3-dimensional box of size</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = 60, 80, 120, 160, 200 with parameters ξ(t = 0) = 4, 6; E c = 2, 4, 6; k = 0.75, 1.5, 2; k ′ = 0.5, 0.7, 1 and P ∈ [10 −4 , 1]. We find that ξ grows linearly with time. ξ(t) ∝ ζt , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the slope ζ depends on the reconnection probability P , as well as on the energy of the smallest allowed loops (energy cut-off). We now turn to the dependence of the slope ζ on the reconnection probability P . This will set the dependence of the length scale ξ on the reconnection probability P . Our results are shown in Fig. 1 below.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0.01 0.1 0.001 0.01 0.1 1 slope reconnection probability P Slope as a function of reconnection probability 0.01 0.1 0.001 0.01 0.1 1 slope reconnection probability P</trash>

					<figDesc>Slope as a function of reconnection probability</figDesc>
					<head>Figure 1.</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The slope ζ as a function of the reconnection probability P in a logarithmic scale. The dots give our data. The straight line shows the squareroot fit.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Clearly, for small values of the reconnection probability, a good fitting is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ζ ∝ √ P ⇒ ξ(t) ∝ √ P t , (3</trash>

					<figDesc>) for reconnection (or intercommuting) probability in the range 0.001 &lt; ∼ P &lt; ∼ 0.3. We thus agree with the old results by Sakellariadou and Vilenkin [23]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, while we do not agree with the more recent statements by Dvali and Vilenkin [14], and Jones et al [15]. More precisely, Dvali and Vilenkin [14] claim that for relativistic strings the scale of the network should be proportional to the reconnection probability and to the time evolution, namely ξ ∼ P t. The explanation of our square root dependence on the reconnection probability was suggested to have an origin on the presence of small-wiggles superimposed on the long strings. These wiggles could lead to a higher number of reconnection opportunities per string encounter. To check this possible explanation we have artificially created large straight strings winding around a cubic box. For such a network we have studied the dependence of the characteristic scale on the reconnection probability, for a range of values for P lower than the one considered earlier in the numerical study by Sakellariadou and Vilenkin [23]. Our current studies confirm the numerical fit to the data given in Eq. 3. In the same way, our results are in disagreement with statements by Jones et al [15]. It is clear that as a long string of length l moves with velocity u sweeps out a surface equal to lu(∆t)/D 2 in a unit time interval ∆t, where D denotes the size of the box. We set l = D ≡ L. Then, the number of collisions per unit time interval ∆t, between two long strings is (u/L)N , where N stands for the number of long strings in the whole volume. Thus, the number of intercommutations for relativistic strings per unit time and per unit volume is P N (1/L)(1/L 3 ), where P stands for the intercommutation probability per string intersection. Up to this point, we basically agree with Jones et al [15]. However, the misleading point is that string intersections do not, in principle, chop off loops. Thus intersections between two long strings is not the most efficient mechanism for energy loss of the string network. The possible string intersections can be divided into three possible cases, which are drawn in Figs. 2, 3, 4 respectively. These cases are: (1) Two long strings collide in one point and exchange partners with intercommuting probability P 1 ; (2) two strings collide in two points and exchange partners chopping off a small loop with intercommuting probability P 2 1 ; and (3) one long string self-intersects in one point and chops off a loop with intercommuting probability P 2 , which in general is different than P 1 .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 2.</head>

					<figDesc>Illustration of string-string intersections in one point, and the formation of two new long strings via exchange of partners.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Clearly, only cases (2) and (3) lead to a closed loop formation and therefore remove energy from the long string network. Between cases (2) and (3), only case (3)</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 3.</head>

					<figDesc>Illustration of string-string intersections in two points. Two new long strings are created as well as a closed loop.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4.</head>

					<figDesc>Illustration of self-string intersections leading to the formation of one new long string and a closed loop.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>is an efficient way of forming loops and therefore dissipating energy. We have checked numerically that case (3) appears more often than case (2), and besides, case (2) has in general a smaller probability, since one expects that P 1 ∼ P 2 . However, the heuristic argument employed by Jones et al [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>does not refer to self-string intersections (i.e, case (3)); it only applies for intersections between two long strings. This is clear since intersections between two long strings depend on the string velocity, however selfstring intersections should not depend on how fast the string moves. In other words, a string can intersect itself even if it does not move but it just oscillates locally §. A cosmic string network has at formation 80% of its energy density in the form of long strings and only 20% in closed string loops [21]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. A thermodynamical study of the string network has shown that as we increase the string energy density, we reach a critical value, the Hagedorn energy density, which is characterised by the appearance of long strings [22]. Above the critical energy density, whose value depends on the dimensionality of the space where the strings move [16], the extra energy density goes to long strings, while below the critical energy density the string network chops off small closed loops and the long strings disappear, provided the space dimensionality is d = 3 and the reconnection probability P = 1. In the low energy regime, closed string loops are constantly produced as long strings intersect or self-intersect, provided the reconnection probability is large. As P increases, the number of string intersections increases, leading to a decrease of long strings and an increase of small closed loops. Thus, the energy density of long strings is inversely proportional to the reconnection probability P , while the energy density of closed string loops is proportional to P .</p>

				<p>Performing numerical simulations, we address the question of scaling of the long strings network. More precisely, for P ∈ [10 −4 , 1], we study the time evolution of the slope ζ. We find that ζ reaches a constant value at relatively the same time t for various values of P . This implies that the long strings reach scaling. We illustrate our results in Figs. 5, 6 below.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 log(rate) log(t) Evolution rate in a log-log plot for P=1 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 log(rate) log(t)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Evolution rate in a log-log plot for P= 0.1 Figure 5. Time evolution of the rate ζ in a log-log plot. The strings are moving in a cubic box of size L = 80 with N = 12996 lattice points occupied by strings. The reconnection probability is P = 1 for the left panel and P = 0.1 for the right one.</p>

				<p>Our network is characterised by two components: (1) a few long strings with a scale-invariant evolution; the characteristic curvature radius of long strings, as well as the typical separation between two long strings are both comparable to the horizon size, ξ(t) ≃ √ P t, and (2) a large number of small closed loops having sizes ≪ t. We have studied the energy distribution of small string loops in the high energy density regime. For strings moving in a 3-dimensional lattice, the number of small loops, with a given energy, per unit volume is shown in Figs. 7, 8 below for several</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-2 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 log(rate) log(t) Evolution rate in a log-log plot for P=0.01 -2.5 -2 -1.5 -1 -0.5 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 log(rate) log(t)</trash>

					<figDesc>Evolution rate in a log-log plot for P=0.001</figDesc>
					<head>Figure 6.</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Time evolution of the rate ζ in a log-log plot. The strings are moving in a cubic box of size L = 80 with N = 12996 lattice points occupied by strings. The reconnection probability is P = 10 −2 for the left panel and P = 10 −3 for the right one.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>values of the reconnection probability P . In these figures we only change the value of the reconnection probability and we see that the results seem not to be sensitive on the exact value of P. Clearly, as the reconnection probability decreases, the relaxation time increases. Thus, to get the energy distribution of short loops we have to wait much longer time, if the reconnection probability is well below 1. The energy distribution of short loops, with a given energy, per unit volume is well fitted by dn dE ∼ E −5/2 for ρ &gt; ρ H (= 0.172) . (4)</p>

				<p>We then perform the same study but for strings moving in a higher dimensional space with reconnection probability P = 1. In Fig. 9 below we show the energy distribution of short loops, in the high energy density regime, for strings moving in a 4-dimensional torus with reconnection probability P = 1. We see that the number distribution is well fitted by dn dE ∼ E −3 for ρ &gt; ρ H (= 0.062) .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(5) Thus, Eqs. (4), (5) confirm the behavior dn dE ∼ E −(1+d/2) , (6</trash>

					<figDesc>) where d stands for the space dimensionality of the torus in which the strings move.</figDesc>
					<trash>-8.5 -8 -7.5 -7 -6.5 -6 -5.5 -5 -4.5 -4 -3.5 0.6 0.8 1 1.2 1.4 1.6 1.8 2 2.2 log(n) log(E) Energy distribution of loops for P=1 and d=3 -8 -7.5 -7 -6.5 -6 -5.5 -5 -4.5 -4 0.6 0.8 1 1.2 1.4 1.6 1.8 2 2.2 log(n) log(E)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Energy distribution of loops for P=0.1 and d=3</figDesc>
					<head>Figure 7.</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Energy distribution of small string loops in the high-energy regime. The strings are moving in a 3-dimensional torus and the reconnection probability is equal to P = 1 for the left panel and P = 0.1 for the right one.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>This distribution does not depend on the particular value of the string energy density ρ, provided ρ &gt; ρ H = 0.172 [16], and is well fitted by dn/dE ∼ E −5/2 , which is also plotted.</p>

				<p>Our results lead to the following asymptotic energy density of the long strings network, providing there are string interactions (i.e., P = 0):</p>

				<p><formula>ρ l = µ P t 2 . (7)</formula></p>

				<p>This implies that the extra dimensions increase the energy density of the long strings, which however results to a less enhancement than what it was previously believed. As a result, for fixed linear mass density, the cosmic superstring energy density may be higher than the field theory case, but at most only by one order of magnitude. More precisely, the fraction of the total density in the form of strings in the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dominated era reads ρ str ρ total = 32π 3 Gµ P . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Oscillating string loops loose energy by emitting graviton, dilaton and Ramond- Ramond (RR) fields. These three mechanisms for energy loss are comparable to each other provided the dilaton and RR fields can be considered as massless. Constraints on the allowed energy scale of cosmic strings from the observational bounds on dilaton decays have been earlier discussed by Damour and Vilenkin [25]. In the case of cosmic superstrings, the effect of the extra compact dimensions on the superstring evolution will decrease the number density of the chopped off closed loops. Since the energy density of long strings is inversely proportional to the reconnection probability P ,</p>

			<note>-7.5 -7 -6.5 -6 -5.5 -5 -4.5 -4 -3.5 -3 0.6 0.8 1 1.2 1.4 1.6 1.8 2 2.2 log(n) log(E)</note>

				<p>Energy distribution of loops for P=0.001 and d=3 Figure 8. Energy distribution of small string loops in the high-energy regime.</p>

				<p>The strings are moving in a 3-dimensional torus and the reconnection probability is equal to P = 0.001. This distribution does not depend on the particular value of the string energy density ρ, provided ρ &gt; ρ H = 0.172 [16], and is well fitted by dn/dE ∼ E −5/2 , which is also plotted.</p>

				<p>provided string interactions are present in the network, the energy density of closed loops is proportional to P . Clearly the number density of these loops at the time of decay is also proportional to P . Thus, the dilaton density parameter Y φ = n φ (t)/s(t), where n φ (t) denotes the dilaton density and s(t) the entropy density, should be proportional to the reconnection probability P . Assuming that the mass of the dilaton field is m φ ∼ 1TeV, Damour and Vilenkin [25] have set upper bounds to Y φ , which depend on the dilaton lifetimes τ . For dilaton lifetime in the range 10 7 s &lt; ∼ τ &lt; ∼ t dec , one roughly has Y φ &lt;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∼ 1.4 × 10 −12 (m φ /1GeV) −1 , where for a dilaton mass m φ ∼ 1TeV we obtain Gµ &lt; ∼ P −2/3 10</trash>

					<figDesc>−16 , which leads to an upper bound η &lt; ∼ P −1/3 10 11 GeV for the energy scale of cosmic superstrings, which determines the critical temperature for the transition. Thus, a lower reconnection probability allows a higher energy scale of strings, by at most one order of magnitude. The cosmic superstring network formed towards the end of the brane inflationary era, can lead to a number of observational predictions, which in principle can be distinguishable from the signatures of gauge theory solitons. Thus, cosmic superstrings might be observable, at least in principle, via gravitational lensing, linear discontinuities on the angular spectrum of the CMB temperature anisotropies, or through the spectrum of gravity waves [20]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Clearly, these signatures depend on the reconnection probability P . Since P for cosmic superstrings is lower than in the case of gauge theory solitons, the evolution of the superstring network will slow down, in</p>

			<note>-9 -8.5 -8 -7.5 -7 -6.5 -6 -5.5 -5 -4.5 -4 0.6 0.8 1 1.2 1.4 1.6 1.8 2 2.2 log(n) log(E)</note>

				<p>Energy distribution of loops for P=1 and d=4</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 9.</head>

					<figDesc>Energy distribution of small string loops in the high-energy regime.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The strings are moving in a 4-dimensional torus and the reconnection probability is equal to P = 1. This distribution does not depend on the particular value of the string energy density ρ, provided ρ &gt; ρ H = 0.062 [16], and is well fitted by dn/dE ∼ E −3 , which is also plotted. the sense that the network will have a larger number of long strings with somehow less kinks than in the case of cosmic string networks where P = 1. Similarly, the process of closed loop formation slows down in the case of cosmic superstrings.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Conclusions</head>

				<p>Cosmic superstrings are expected to be the outcome of brane inflation in the context of a brane world scenario. These objects are quite similar to their solitonic analogues, even though they have some distinguishable features which may lead to different observable signatures. The main difference between cosmic superstrings and cosmic strings is the fact that the former live in extra dimensions. This results to a smaller reconnection probability, which will alter the subsequent evolution of a superstring network as compared to the most familiar string network evolution. We have studied numerically the evolution of a cosmic superstring network in a Minkowski space. We have found that the network reaches a scaling solution, which means that the characteristic length scale of the string network, which gives the typical curvature radius of long strings and the characteristic distance between long strings, grow both proportional to the Hubble radius 1/H, or the age of the universe t. In addition, we found that the evolution rate ζ is proportional to the square root of the reconnection probability. This will effect the string energy density and may lead to distinguishable observational signatures.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">‡ Due to brane intersections leading to reconnection and unwinding, Durrer et al [12] argue that all Dp-branes of dimension p &gt; 3 disappear and that one of the stable 3-dimensional branes plays the rô of our Universe.</note>

			<note place="foot">§ Recently, Damour and Vilenkin [20] also agree with the square-root fit.</note>

			<note place="foot">We would like to bring to the attention of the reader that Avgoustidis and Shellard [24] reached different conclusions regarding the scaling issue.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Jeannerot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Rocher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023506</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Bouchet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Peter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Riazuelo</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">021301</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Pogosian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S-H H</forename>
				<surname>Tye</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Wasserman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Wyman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023506</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Pogosian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Wyman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Wasserman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Rocher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">011303</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Rocher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">JCAP 0503 004</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">354</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Vincent</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Hindmarsh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">637</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Vincent</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Antunes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Hindmarsh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2277</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Ringeval</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Dvali</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Tye S-H</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">450</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">72</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Why do we live in 3 + 1 dimensions?</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Durrer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kunz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Sarangi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Tye S-H</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">536</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">185</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Dvali</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vilenkin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JCAP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0403</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">010</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Jones</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Stoica</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S-H H</forename>
				<surname>Tye</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">563</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">468</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">319</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reconnection of Colliding Cosmic Strings [arxiv:hep-th/0501031</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Hanany</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hashimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Collisions of Cosmic F-and D-strings [arxiv:hep-th/0405229</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Jackson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Jones</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Polchinski</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tachyon dynamics in open string theory [arxiv:hep-th/0410103</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Damour</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vilenkin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">063510</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Vachaspati</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vilenkin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2036</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vilenkin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">885</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sakellariadou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vilenkin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">349</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cosmic String Evolution in Higher Dimensions [hep-ph</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Avgoustidis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E P S</forename>
				<surname>Shellard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Damour</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Vilenkin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2288</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
