<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Extended quintessence with an exponential coupling</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2005-01-18">18 Jan 2005</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Valeria</forename>
								<surname>Pettorino</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Universit a di Napoli Federico II</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">INFN</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Sezione di Napoli</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Complesso Universitario di Monte Sant&apos;Angelo</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Via Cintia</addrLine>
									<postCode>I-80126</postCode>
									<settlement>Napoli</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Carlo</forename>
								<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">SISSA/ISAS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">INFN</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Via Beirut 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>I-34014</postCode>
									<settlement>Trieste</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Sezione di Trieste</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Via Valerio 2</addrLine>
									<postCode>I-34127</postCode>
									<settlement>Trieste</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Gianpiero</forename>
								<surname>Mangano</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Universit a di Napoli Federico II</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">INFN</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Sezione di Napoli</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Complesso Universitario di Monte Sant&apos;Angelo</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Via Cintia</addrLine>
									<postCode>I-80126</postCode>
									<settlement>Napoli</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Extended quintessence with an exponential coupling</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2005-01-18">18 Jan 2005</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We study a class of extended quintessence cosmologies where the scalar field playing the role of the dark energy is exponentially coupled to the Ricci scalar. We find that the dynamics induced by the effective gravitational potential in the Klein-Gordon equation dominates the motion of the field in the early universe. The resulting &quot; R−boost &quot; trajectory is characterized by a kinetic dark energy density, given by [3ρ mnr0 (1 + z)] 2 [32ρ r0 ω JBD 0 ] −1 , where ω JBD 0 , ρ r0 and ρ mnr0 are calculated at present, and represent the Jordan Brans Dicke parameter, the density of relativistic matter and of those species which are non-relativistic at redshift z, respectively. We show that such a trajectory represents an attractor, equivalent to a tracking solution with equation of state w = −1/3, providing a large basin of attraction for the initial dark energy density regardless of the properties of the potential energy yielding acceleration today. We derive the up to date constraints from Big Bang Nucleosynthesis (BBN) on the present scenario, and we show that they are largely satisfied for interesting trajectories of the dark energy scalar field in the early universe. We compute the cosmological perturbation spectra in these cosmologies. For a fixed value of ω JBD 0 , the projection and Integrated Sachs-Wolfe effects on the cosmic microwave background anisotropy are considerably larger in the exponential case with respect to a quadratic non-minimal coupling, reflecting the fact that the effective gravitational constant depends exponentially on the dynamics of the field.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>

				<p>Extended quintessence with an exponential coupling</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Valeria Pettorino 1 , Carlo Baccigalupi 2 , Gianpiero Mangano 1 1 Universit a di Napoli Federico II and INFN, Sezione di Napoli, Complesso Universitario di Monte Sant&apos;Angelo, Via Cintia, I-80126 Napoli, Italy 2 SISSA/ISAS, Via Beirut 4, I-34014 Trieste, Italy and INFN, Sezione di Trieste, Via Valerio 2, I-34127 Trieste, Italy</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Abstract. We study a class of extended quintessence cosmologies where the scalar field playing the role of the dark energy is exponentially coupled to the Ricci scalar.</p>

				<p>We find that the dynamics induced by the effective gravitational potential in the Klein-Gordon equation dominates the motion of the field in the early universe. The resulting &quot; R−boost &quot; trajectory is characterized by a kinetic dark energy density, given by [3ρ mnr0 (1 + z)] 2 [32ρ r0 ω JBD 0 ] −1 , where ω JBD 0 , ρ r0 and ρ mnr0 are calculated at present, and represent the Jordan Brans Dicke parameter, the density of relativistic matter and of those species which are non-relativistic at redshift z, respectively. We show that such a trajectory represents an attractor, equivalent to a tracking solution with equation of state w = −1/3, providing a large basin of attraction for the initial dark energy density regardless of the properties of the potential energy yielding acceleration today. We derive the up to date constraints from Big Bang Nucleosynthesis (BBN) on the present scenario, and we show that they are largely satisfied for interesting trajectories of the dark energy scalar field in the early universe.</p>

				<p>We compute the cosmological perturbation spectra in these cosmologies. For a fixed value of ω JBD 0 , the projection and Integrated Sachs-Wolfe effects on the cosmic microwave background anisotropy are considerably larger in the exponential case with respect to a quadratic non-minimal coupling, reflecting the fact that the effective gravitational constant depends exponentially on the dynamics of the field.</p>

			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>According to the present cosmological observations, the universe today is nearly geometrically flat, with an expansion rate of about 72 km/sec/Mpc, and structures grown out of a primordial linear spectrum of nearly Gaussian and scale invariant energy density perturbations. About 5% of the critical energy density is made of baryons, while 20% is thought to be composed by particles interacting at most weakly with them (Cold Dark Matter, CDM). The remaining 75% is some sort of vacuum component, the dark energy, with negative pressure acting as a repulsive gravitational force, and responsible for a late time cosmic acceleration era. Several independent observables support the picture above, i.e. type Ia supernovae (hereafter SNIa [1, 2]), the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) anisotropies (see [3] and references therein), the Large Scale Structure (LSS, see [4] and references therein) and the Hubble Space Telescope (HST [5]). While a dark matter component is generically predicted in the super-symmetric extensions of the standard model for particle physics, the dark energy component poses severe questions to the whole picture (see [6, 7] and references therein). Specifically, a reliable dark energy candidate should explain why the present amount is so small with respect to the fundamental scale (a fine tuning of 123 orders of magnitude if compared to the Planck scale), and why it is comparable with the critical density today (coincidence). The Cosmological Constant is affected by both these problems. As an alternative, the concept of vacuum energy in cosmology has been generalized in terms of a scalar field, named quintessence, which for a broad class of potentials is able to converge to the present regime starting from a wide set of initial conditions in the past, thus alleviating the fine tuning (scaling or tracking trajectories, [8, 9]). The lack of a clear prediction for the dark energy scalar field in any fundamental theory motivated the investigation, also phenomenological, of its coupling with other cosmological components, such as dark matter [10, 11] or gravity [12]. This work belongs to the second class. The interest in connecting dark energy and gravity is related to the original Brans-Dicke idea (see [13] and references therein), and on the temptation to explain the evidence for cosmic acceleration entirely in terms of a modification of general relativity. Although such attempts were unsuccessful so far, several interesting effects have been discovered in these scenarios, generally called extended quintessence models, concerning background evolution as well as cosmological perturbations [12], [14]-[28]. A major achievement concerns the early universe dynamics of the quintessence field in these scenarios. It was shown that the species which are non-relativistic in the radiation dominated era make the Ricci scalar diverging, activating an effective potential in the Klein-Gordon equation coming from the non-minimal coupling only (R-boost, [19]). This effect is acquiring a crucial importance recently: as we stressed above, a broad class of quintessence potentials allows for a large basin of attraction in the early universe, alleviating the corresponding fine tuning problem. On the other hand, the latter condition holds only if the present dark energy equation of state w is sufficiently far from −1. As the observations are constraining w to be close to −1 (see e.g. [4]) the basin of attraction in the early universe shrinks, threatening the basis of the whole quintessence picture [29]. It was recently argued that in these conditions the coupling of the dark energy with other entities may be relevant at early times, possibly saving the existence of attractors for the initial field dynamics [12]. Despite the broad interest on this subject, most of the analysis so far was carried out considering a quadratic coupling between the dark energy scalar field and the Ricci scalar.</p>

				<p>In this paper we work out the first generalization of those claims, providing a comprehensive analysis of cosmologies involving an exponential coupling. The latter case may be relevant for string cosmology, where the dilaton appears in an exponential in the fundamental lagrangian [30], although in the usual formulation the coupling involves all terms, not just the Ricci scalar. This paper is organized as follows. In Section II we describe the framework of exponential couplings in extended quintessence cosmology. In Section III we discuss the observational constraints on the coupling magnitude from solar system experiments and Big Bang Nucleosynthesis. In Section IV we study the R-boost trajectories of the dark energy scalar field. In Section V we work out the most important effects on cosmological perturbations. Finally, in Section VI we draw our conclusions. 2. Exponential scalar-tensor couplings in cosmology A wide class of cosmological models can be described by the action</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = d 4 x √ −g 1 2κ f (φ, R) − 1 2 ω(φ)φ ;µ φ ;µ − V (φ) + L fluid , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where g is the determinant of the background metric, R is the Ricci scalar, φ is a scalar field whose kinetic energy and potential are specified by ω(φ) and V (φ), respectively. L fluid includes contributions from all components different from φ and κ = 8πG * represents the bare gravitational constant [20]. The usual gravity term R/16πG has been generalized by the function f (φ, R)/2κ, where f (φ, R) may describe a coupling between the quintessence field φ and gravity, as well as a pure geometrical modification of general relativity, featuring a non-linear dependence on R. Note also that the gravitational constant appearing in the Lagrangian and the one measured in Cavendish like experiments differ by corrections being negligible in the limit ω JBD ≫ 1 [20]. The Lagrangian in (1) has been considered and analysed in its full generality in a cosmological context including linear perturbations [31]; this framework has been exploited in several works [12, 17, 19, 21, 24, 26], leading to the formulation of the weak lensing theory [27].</p>

				<p>In this work we consider a simple class of extended quintessence models with exponential coupling</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ω(φ) = 1 , f (φ, R) 2κ = F (φ)R 2 = R 16πG exp ξ m P (φ − φ 0 ) , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ξ is a dimensionless coupling, φ 0 is the present value for the φ field and m P the Planck mass m P = 1/ √ G in natural units. Note that the constant φ 0 has been introduced to make explicit that at present F (φ 0 ) = 1/8πG. The Jordan-Brans-Dicke parameter in this scenario is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ω JBD = F dF dφ −2 = 8π ξ 2 exp − ξ m P (φ − φ 0 ) . (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that at present ω JBD 0 = 8π/ξ 2 .</p>

				<p>We give now a brief overview of the relevant equations describing the cosmological expansion assuming a Friedmann Robertson Walker (FRW) background metric, since it is relevant in the following. In Section V we describe the effects on the cosmological perturbations; however, we do do not write down explicitely the perturbation equations here, which can be found elsewhere (see e.g. [31, 21, 27]) written for a generic function F . The most relevant differences with respect to ordinary cosmologies are represented by the time variation of F , which plays the role of a varying gravitational constant in the Poisson equation. For flat cosmologies, the line element can be written as ds 2 = a 2 (τ )(− dτ 2 + δ ij dx i dx j ) , where a(τ ) is the scale factor, τ represents the conformal time variable, related to the cosmic time t by the transformation dt = a(τ ) dτ .</p>

				<p>The expansion and field dynamics are determined by the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Friedmann and Klein Gordon equations H 2 = ˙ a a 2 = 1 3F a 2 ρ f luid + 1 2 ˙ φ 2 + a 2 V − 3H ˙ F , (4) ¨ φ + 2H ˙ φ = a 2 2 dF dφ R − a 2 V φ , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where dot means derivative with respect to the conformal time τ and V φ is the derivative of the quintessence potential with respect to φ. For our analysis, it is relevant to write down the explicit form of the Ricci scalar in terms of the cosmological content</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R = − 1 F −ρ f luid + 3p f luid + ˙ φ 2 a 2 − 4V + 3 ¨ F a 2 + 2 H ˙ F a 2 , (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ρ f luid and p f luid are the energy density and pressure that need to be summed up over all possible cosmological components but φ. Note also that, as it was shown in [31], the usual conservation equations ˙ ρ i = −3H(ρ i + p i ), where ρ i and p i are respectively the energy density and pressure of the i-th component, hold for all species but φ.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Observational constraints</head>

				<p>In this Section we briefly review the constraints on scalar-tensor cosmology coming from the solar system physics [32] and derive the up to date bounds from the BBN.</p>

				<p>The time variation of the gravitational constant is related to the coupling function F by the expression</p>

				<p><formula>1 G dG dt = 1 F dF dt , (7)</formula></p>

				<p>which does not take into account corrections due to the effective gravitational constant in Cavendish like experiments which are small in the limit ω JBD ≫ 1 [20]. Both local laboratory and solar system experiments constrain the ratio in (7) to be less than 10 −11 per year [32]. An independent bound is given by the effects induced on photon trajectories by a varying gravitational constant, which was recently greatly strengthened by the Cassini solar system probe [33]: at two sigma, the new constraint is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ω JBD 0 ≥ 4×10 4 . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It may not be straightforward to extend these limits, obtained on solar system scales, to cosmology, as it was pointed out recently [34]. Indeed we probe regions well within our Galaxy, which is a self-gravitating virialized system: in physical theories where fundamental constants vary, the latter may acquire local values which are different from their large scale, cosmologically effective ones. For this reason, cosmology is likely to become a source of constraints for the underlying theory of gravity [35], in a complementary way with respect to the solar system.</p>

				<p>The BBN is indeed the only direct cosmological probe for the field value in the radiation dominated era. As it is well known, the amount of light nuclides produced when the photon temperature was in the range 0.01 ÷ 10 MeV is rather sensitive to the value of the Hubble parameter during that epoch, as well as to its time dependence.</p>

				<p>In particular the 4 He mass fraction Y p strongly depends on the freeze-out temperature of weak processes which keep neutrons and protons in chemical equilibrium. Changing the value of H affects the neutron to proton number density ratio at the onset of the BBN, which is the key parameter entering the final value of Y p and more weakly in the Deuterium abundance. For a fixed baryon density parameter ω b = Ω b h 2 in the range suggested by results of the Wilkinson Microwave Anisotropy Probe (WMAP), ω b = 0.023±0.001 [36] both nuclei yields are in fact monotonically increasing functions of H. For recent reviews on BBN see [37, 38, 39]. As we read from (4) the introduction of the field φ changes the value of H in two different ways. First of all there is a shift in the effective gravitational constant by a factor exp[−ξ(φ − φ 0 )/m P )]. Second, it gives an extra contribution to H.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>By using the coupling defined in (2), we can solve (4) with respect to H, getting H = 8πG 3    a 2 (ρ f luid + ρ φ ) exp − 8π ω JBD 0 φ − φ 0 m P + 3 ˙ φ 2 4ω JBD 0 − 3 4ω JBD 0 ˙ φ    .(9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the following we shall assume that the Universe is indeed radiation dominated during the BBN epoch, so that ρ φ can be neglected with respect to ρ f luid which receives contributions from photons, neutrinos and e ± . Moreover the last two terms in</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Equation (9) are suppressed by 1/ √ ω JBD 0 . In this case the squared Hubble parameter takes the simple form H 2 = H 2 a 2 = 8πG 3 exp − ξ(φ − φ 0 ) m P ρ f luid . (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this limit we see that by comparing the theoretical values for the light nuclei abundances with the corresponding experimental determinations we can constrain the value of the effective gravitational constant during the BBN epoch, i.e. the quantity ξ(φ − φ 0 )/m P .</p>

				<p>Before discussing this issue let us briefly summarize the present knowledge of the BBN both from the experimental and theoretical points of view, see e.g. [38] for a review. The most accurate measurement of primordial Deuterium number density, normalized to Hydrogen, X D , is obtained from DI/HI column ratio in QSO absorption systems at high redshifts. The most recent estimate [40]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>gives X exp D = (2.78 +0.44 −0.38 )·10 −5 , (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and is in good agreement with the theoretical expectation for a standard scenario with three active neutrinos and a baryon density given by the WMAP result [38]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>; the latter is X th D = (2.44 +0.19 −0.17 )·10 −5 , (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the (1σ) theoretical uncertainty accounts for both the propagated error due to the several rates entering the BBN nuclear reaction network as well as the 5% uncertainty on ω b . On the other hand the 4 He mass fraction Y p obtained by extrapolating to zero the metallicity measurements performed in dwarf irregular and blue compact galaxies is still controversial and possibly affected by large systematics. There are two different determinations [41, 42] which are only compatible by invoking the large systematic uncertainty quoted in [41]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Y p = 0.238±(0.002) stat ±(0.005) sys , (13) Y p = 0.2421±(0.0021) stat . (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Both results are significantly lower than the theoretical estimate [38]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Y th p = 0.2481±0.0004 , (15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where again we use ω b = 0.023 and the small error is due to the uncertainty on the baryon density and, to a less extent, to the error on experimental determination of the neutron lifetime. As in [38] we use in our analysis a more conservative estimate for the experimental 4 He abundance obtained by using the results of [43]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Y exp p = 0.245±0.007 . (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We finally recall that the Spite plateau value for 7 Li found in PopII dwarf halo stars is smaller by a factor 2 ÷ 3 with respect to the standard BBN prediction [38, 39]. In view of this problem, suggesting a large depletion mechanism of primordial 7 Li, we do not consider this nuclide in the following. To bound the value of the quintessence field we construct the likelihood function</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L(ξφ) ∝ e −χ 2 [ξ(φ−φ 0 )/m P ]/2 , (17) with χ 2 [ξ(φ − φ 0 )/m P ] = i,j=D, 4 He X th i [ξ(φ − φ 0 )/m P ] − X exp i W ij X th j [ξ(φ − φ 0 )/m P ] − X exp j . (18)</trash>

					<figDesc>The proportionality constant can be obtained by requiring normalization to unity of the integral of L, and with W ij we denote the inverse covariance matrix</figDesc>
					<trash>W ij = [σ 2 ij,th + σ 2 i,exp δ ij ] −1 , (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where σ i,exp is the uncertainty in the experimental determination of nuclide abundance X i and σ 2 ij,th the theoretical error matrix. We also consider the two likelihood functions for each of the two nuclei to show how at present the Deuterium and 4 He can separately constrain the value of the effective gravitational constant at the BBN epoch. It is important to stress that we consider the simplest case of a constant value of φ during the whole BBN phase. This is justified a posteriori by the discussion in the next Section; although the dynamics of the field in the radiation dominated era is cosmologically relevant, it is too small to provide any change of φ during BBN which is significant compared with the bounds we derive here. It is also worth mentioning that in view of the possible systematics affecting mainly the experimental determination of 4 He it is unfortunately impossible at present to use BBN to get detailed constraints on the time evolution of the quintessence field during this phase, while it can only provide a conservative bound on the largest (or smaller) values attainable by ξ(φ − φ 0 )/m P during the nuclei formation era.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-0.6 -0.4 -0.2 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 1 2 3 4 5 6</trash>

					<head>Figure 1.</head>

					<figDesc>The behavior of the likelihood functions versus the parameter ξ(φ−φ 0 )/m P for ω b = 0.023. The three curves refer to the D (dashed curve), 4 He (solid) and the combined D+ 4 He (dotted) analysis discussed in the text.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Our results are summarized in Figure 1, where we show the likelihood contours obtained using Deuterium, 4 He and finally , combining the two nuclei . As expected the</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Extended quintessence with an exponential coupling 8 4</head>

					<figDesc>He mass fraction gives the most stringent constraint since it is much more sensitive to the value of the Hubble parameter with respect to Deuterium . In particular using 4 He only we get</figDesc>
					<trash>− 0 . 13 ≤ ξ ( φ − φ 0 ) / m P ≤ 0 . 20 , 95% C . L . ( 20 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>while adding the information on D abundance does not change this result significantly :</figDesc>
					<trash>− 0 . 14 ≤ ξ ( φ − φ 0 ) / m P ≤ 0 . 17 , 95% C . L . . ( 21 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>We see how a clear understanding of the role of systematics in the Y p measurements would have a large impact on further constraints on the value of the effective gravitational constant , at least in the minimal BBN scenario we are here considering , with no other extra parameters , such as extra relativistic degrees of freedom . We close this Section by recalling that for a constant value of φ during the BBN epoch , its effect in renormalizing the gravitational constant can be also conveniently recasted in terms of the effective number of relativistic species contributing to the total energy density , as it was noticed in earlier works [ 17 , 44 ]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>We parameterize the value of the Hubble parameter at the onset of BBN and before the e ± annihilation phase in terms of an excess ( or deficit ) of relativistic degrees of freedom ∆N</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>H 2 = 8πG 3 g * 2 + 7 8 ∆N ρ γ , ( 22 )</formula></p>

				<p>where ρ γ is the photon energy density and g * = 10 . 75 the standard value obtained by summing over photons , e ± and neutrinos . By using ( 10 ) it is straightforward to get the simple relation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ξ φ − φ 0 m P = − log 1 + 7 43 ∆N . ( 23 )</trash>

					<figDesc>This relation can be used to recast the bounds on the effective number of neutrinos , which are routinely used in the literature , in terms of a constraint on ξ ( φ − φ 0 ) / m P for the exponential coupling considered in this paper . As we show in the next Section , interesting values of the field at Nucleosynthesis largely satisfy the bounds represented in Figure 1 .</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">. R - boost</head>

				<p>In this Section we derive the dark energy dynamics before the onset of acceleration . The central point is that extended quintessence scenarios may possess attractor trajectories in the early universe , generated only by the non - minimal coupling , as it was pointed out recently [ 12 ] ; that allows to remove the fine tuning in the early universe , even if the potential is constrained to be almost flat in order to be consistent with the observations ; the latter occurrence indeed limits the capability of minimally coupled quintessence models to avoid the fine tuning problem [ 29 ] . The attractors in minimally coupled quintessence models were called scaling [ 8 ] or tracking [ 9 ] solutions ; the corresponding trajectories in extended quintessence coming from the non - minimal coupling are called R - boost solutions [ 19 ] . In the following we derive the R−boost for exponential coupling . We shall write an analytic expression for that , both in matter dominated and radiation dominated eras , which is manifestly independent on the initial conditions ; that represents an important new aspect with respect to earlier works [ 19 ] , in which the initial field value appeared explicitely in the R−boost energy density . Moreover , exploiting a perturbative analysis [ 8 ] , we demonstrate that such solution represents an attractor . Also , we shall see that the energy density corresponding to the R−boost depends on the value of ω JBD .</p>

				<p>We shall compare what we find here with previous models of extended quintessence , based on a quadratic coupling between the dark energy and the Ricci scalar , and with a case of minimally coupled quintessence ( QCDM ) . In order to satisfy the constraint ( 8 ) the constant ξ is obtained through ( 3 ) by fixing ω JBD0 = 10 5 . The remaining cosmological parameters are chosen consistently with the concordance model ( see e . g . [ 36 ] ) .</p>

				<p>The present dark energy density is 73% of the critical density , Ω φ = 0 . 73 , with a Cold Dark Matter contribution of Ω CDM = 0 . 226 , three families of massless neutrinos , baryon content Ω b = 0 . 044 and Hubble constant H 0 = 72 Km / sec / Mpc . The quintessence potential is an inverse power law</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V ( φ ) = M 4+α φ α , ( 24 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with α close to zero in order to have w φ close to −1 at present ( see e . g . [ 45 ] and references therein ) . We choose the initial conditions at 1 + z = 10 9 ; in typical runs , with w φ = −0 . 9 at present , the value of the field today is φ 0 = 0 . 35m P ; the dynamics induced by the potential V and the R−boost makes φ ≪ φ 0 at early stages ; the condition on ω JBD 0 sets the value of the coupling constant ξ = 1 . 6×10 −2 . As a consequence , the BBN bounds ( 20 ) or ( 21 ) are largely satisfied .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">. 1 . Radiation dominated era ( RDE )</head>

				<p>The crucial point is that in ( 6 ) the term ρ f luid −3p f luid gets no contribution from radiation but , as long as one or more sub - dominant non - relativistic species exists , the Ricci scalar gets a non - zero contribution that diverges as 1 / a 3 , thus becoming increasingly relevant at early times</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R ≃ 1 F ρ mnr0 a 3 for a → 0 . ( 25 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The parameter ρ mnr0 above indicates the energy density of the species which are non - relativistic at the time in which the dynamics is considered . As a consequence , the term proportional to R in the Klein Gordon equation acts as a new source on the quintessence field besides the true potential V ( φ ) ; the resulting motion is the R−boost . With our choice of the coupling ( 2 ) the Klein Gordon equation ( 5 ) for the field can be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>¨ φ + 2H ˙ φ − 1 2 ξ m P ρ mnr0 a + a 2 V φ = 0 , ( 26 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have used ( 6 ) to write the Ricci scalar in terms of the total energy density , neglecting the remaining terms in ( 6 ) since they get negligible for a sufficiently small .</p>

				<p>For our purposes here we neglect the departure from general relativity in the RDE , i . e .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>10 - 13 10 - 9 10 - 5 10 - 1 10 3 10 7 10 11 10 15 10 19 10 23 1 10 10 2 10 3 10 4 10 5 10 6 10 7 10 8 1+z ρ m ρ r ρ ϕ exp ρ ϕ quadratic ρ ϕ m . c . analytical Rboost RDE ( exp ) analytical Rboost MDE ( exp )</trash>

					<head>Figure 2 .</head>

					<figDesc>Energy density of matter ( solid ) , radiation ( heavy dashed ) and φ for minimal ( dot dashed ) , quadratic ( heavy dotted ) and exponential ( heavy solid ) coupling . Also shown the analytical behavior of the R - boost during radiation dominated era ( dashed ) and matter dominated era ( dotted ) .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>we assume F ≃ 1 / 8πG and we ignore all the contributions in the Friedmann equation except radiation . The above assumption is justified because we aim at deriving the R−boost dynamics at first order in 1 / ω JBD : a general analysis would yield corrections of higher order in 1 / ω JBD in the effective gravitational potential appearing in the Klein Gordon equation . The expansion is given by a ≃ Cτ , ( 27 ) where C = 8πGρ r0 / 3 and ρ r0 represents the cosmological radiation density calculated at present ; since H ∼ 1 / τ , the equation of motion for φ reduces to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>¨ φ + 2 τ ˙ φ − 1 2 ξ m P ρ mnr0 Cτ = 0 , ( 28 ) which is solved by φ ( τ ) = ξ 4 ρ mnr0 3 8πρ r0 ( τ − τ beg ) + φ beg , ( 29 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where φ beg is the initial condition for φ . This solution corresponds to the slow roll phase which starts when the cosmological friction and effective gravitational potential effects in the equation of motion are comparable , yielding the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R−boost equation 2H ˙ φ ≃ a 2 R 2 dF dφ . ( 30 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this phase , the energy of the quintessence field is dominated by its kinetic contribution</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 dφ dt 2 = 3 32 ρ mnr0 2 ρ r0 1 ω JBD 0 ( 1 + z ) 2 . ( 31 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>from which it is possible to derive that the R - boost solution is equivalent to a tracking one with equation of state −1 / 3 . It is interesting to note that at first order in 1 / ω JBD the R−boost energy density is related only to the present value of the Jordan - Brans - Dicke parameter . In Figure 2 we have plotted the energy density of the various cosmological components : besides matter and radiation we can observe the behavior of φ for minimal and extended quintessence , starting from zero initial kinetic energy . In the minimal coupling case the field behaves nearly as a cosmological constant until the true potential V starts to be relevant . In the extended quintessence case , instead , the field accelerates and soon enters the R−boost phase . In Figure 3 we show the absolute values of the four terms in the Klein Gordon equation ( 28 ) . The potential term starts to be dominant only for z ≤ 10 2 ; the friction term is zero at the beginning and then increases , joining the R−boost . The quintessence field accelerates until the sign inversion in φ occurs ; then the field accelerates again for z ∼ 10 2 when the potential V starts to have a relevant effect . The timing of the different phases of the trajectory depends on the details we have fixed , but the general behavior is model independent .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>10 - 11 10 - 10 10 - 9 10 - 8 10 - 7 10 - 6 10 - 5 10 - 4 10 - 3 10 - 2 10 - 1 1 10 10 2 10 3 10 4 10 5 10 6 10 7 10 8 1+z 2 H φ ˙ φ ¨ a 2 V φ a 2 F φ R − 2</trash>

					<head>Figure 3 .</head>

					<figDesc>Absolute values of the four terms in the Klein Gordon equation ( 28 ) for an exponential coupling .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>4 . 2 . Matter dominated era ( MDE )</p>

				<p>In the matter dominated era , equation ( 30 ) still holds but the expansion parameter has a different behavior with time</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a = 2 3 πGρ mnr0 τ 2 . ( 32 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As in the RDE case , we neglect the departure from general relativity to get the R−boost dynamics at the lowest order in 1 / ω JBD . The R−boost equation is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>˙ φ = 3 16π ξ τ m P , ( 33 ) which is solved by φ = 3 16π ξm P log τ τ beg + φ beg , ( 34 ) also shown in Figure 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. As a consequence , the behavior of the kinetic energy of the field changes , too</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 dφ dt 2 = 3 32 1 ω JBD 0 ρ mnr0 ( 1 + z ) 3 . ( 35 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>If we now look at Figure 2 again , we notice that the R−boost has a bigger effect on ρ in the exponential case with respect to the quadratic coupling , also shown in the figure . In both cases φ receives a strong kick , which determines a major change in the dynamics with respect to the minimally coupled scenario . However , for an exponential coupling the path of the field departs from the standard one earlier with respect to the case of a quadratic coupling , reflecting the fact that the exponential coupling enhances the departure from general relativity as it depends exponentially on the field dynamics . We shall come back to this issue in the next Section .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">. 3 . Stability</head>

				<p>Following the method exploited in [ 8 ] , we now show that the R−boost solution above is an attractor . We look for scaling solutions of the Klein Gordon equation , i . e . solutions in which the energy density of quintessence field scales as a power of the scale factor</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dφ dt 2 ∝ a −2 , ( 36 ) in the RDE and dφ dt 2 ∝ a −3 , ( 37 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in the MDE , as found in ( 31 , 35 ) . The behavior of the background energy density is also given by a power of the scale factor .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>In particular ρ r ∝ a −4 , ρ m ∝ a −3 , ( 38 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for radiation and non - relativistic matter respectively . As far as a ( t ) is concerned , neglecting again the corrections of the order 1 / ω JBD induced by 1 / F in front of the right hand side of the Friedmann equation ( 4 ) as well as the other dark energy terms , one has</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a RDE ∝ t 1 / 2 , ( 39 ) a M DE ∝ t 2 / 3 . ( 40 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The corresponding time dependence of the field φ is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ e RDE = φ * t t * 1 2 , ( 41 ) φ e M DE = φ * log t t * , ( 42 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the subscript &apos; * &apos; stands for a given reference time and the subscript &apos; e &apos; reminds us that this is the R− boost exact solution . We verify that the R−boost solution is an attractor by rewriting the Klein Gordon equation ( 5 ) , with the change of variables given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>u = φ φ e , ( 43 ) and ˜ τ = log t t * . ( 44 ) During RDE , we obtain 2u ′′ + 3u ′ + u − 1 = 0 , ( 45 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the prime stands for the derivative with respect tõ τ . As we immediately see , this equation admits a critical trajectory for u = 1 and u ′ = 0 , corresponding to the R−boost . Linearizing equation ( 45 ) by choosing small exponential perturbations around the critical point ( u = 1 + e λτ ) and solving for the eigenvalues λ 1 , 2 we get</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ 1 = −1 ; λ 2 = − 1 2 . ( 46 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The fact that the eigenvalues are real and negative shows that the generic perturbation will be suppressed with time , thus flattening the trajectory on the critical one φ = φ e .</p>

				<p>Similarly , during the MDE , the Klein Gordon equation ( 5 ) can be rewritten as u ′′ + u ′ = 0 , ( 47 ) which again admits u = 1 as a solution . In this case , by substituting u = u + e λτ in the equation and solving for the λ eigenvalues , we find the two values λ 1 = 0 and λ 2 = −1 , independently of the value of u . As a consequence , the generic solution of the Klein Gordon equation will tend to u = constant . The constant is fixed to be equal to 1 by the initial conditions for the MDE , corresponding to the final regime in the RDE , where the trajectory joined the R−boost solution represented by φ e .</p>

				<p>Summarizing , the simple choice of an exponential as a coupling between dark energy and Ricci scalar in the Lagrangian leads to the existence of an attractive R−boost solution in both the matter and radiation dominated eras .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 4 .</head>

					<figDesc>The behavior of H as a function of the redshift in three cosmological models , extended quintessence with exponential coupling ( solid ) , quadratic coupling ( dashed ) and QCDM ( dotted ) .</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">. Effects on cosmological perturbations</head>

				<p>In this section we analyze the effect that the exponential coupling in ( 1 ) has on the spectra of cosmological perturbations . We find that these effects are qualitatively consistent with those corresponding to a quadratic coupling , but quantitatively different . For our purposes , an analysis based on the CMB power spectrum only is sufficient . The scalar perturbations are Gaussian and described by a scalar power spectrum with spectral index n = 0 . 96 , and no tensors , consistently with the cosmological concordance model , see [ 36 ] and references therein . Since the constant ξ is chosen to be positive and the field φ is smaller in the past with respect to φ 0 , F &lt; 1 / 8πG in the past . As a consequence , our model describes a cosmology in which the gravitational constant ( and thus the Hubble parameter ) is higher in the past than in the QCDM case . It follows that for a fixed ω JBD 0 , we expect a larger amplitude of the effects induced by the behavior of F for the exponential case with respect to the quadratic coupling : indeed , the exponential is sensitive to the field dynamics also at the linear level , which dominates for small values of φ / φ 0 − 1 . This can be seen in Figure 4 , where we plot H ( z ) for three cosmological models : two of them represent extended quintessence with the same value of ω JBD at present , but featuring an exponential and quadratic coupling , while the third one is the QCDM case . For the first two cases , we have set ω JBD 0 = 50 ; we stress that we have chosen this small value with respect to the existing bounds from solar system [ 33 ] , in order to highlight the differences in the models considered . The value of H 0 is the same , but H ( z ) are quite different functions in the three cases , in particular for the exponential case with respect to the QCDM cosmology .</p>

				<p>In Figures 5 and 6 we plot the total intensity and polarisation power spectra of anisotropies for the models considered in Figure 4 . Two features are immediately evident . First the different amplitude in the tail at low multipoles , and second a projection difference in the location of the acoustic peaks . The spectra have been normalized to the amplitude of the first peak , which roughly corresponds to fixing the amplitude of the signal at last scattering . Both the effects come from the different behavior of the coupling F with redshift . The projection feature simply follows from the difference in the curves in Figure 4 . Indeed , smaller ( higher ) values of H −1 project the CMB power spectrum onto smaller ( larger ) angular scales in the sky . The power at low multipoles is modified through the Integrated Sachs - Wolfe ( ISW ) effect , which is sensitive to the change of the cosmic equation of state at low redshift ( see [ 46 ] and references therein ) . The larger is that change , the larger is the ISW power .</p>

				<p>Summarizing , the different form of the coupling function F determines a relevant difference of amplitude in the effects induced by extended quintessence models on the cosmological perturbations . Larger departures from general relativity in the dynamics of the field in the early universe correspond to larger effects on the perturbations . The latter aspect has to be taken into account when constraining different theories on the basis of the present observations .</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Figure 5 .</head>

					<figDesc>CMB angular total intensity power spectra for a QCDM cosmology ( dotted ) , quadratic ( dashed ) and exponential coupling extended quintessence ( solid ) with ω JBD = 50 . The spectra are in arbitrary units , normalized to 1 at the first acoustic peak in total intensity .</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">. Conclusions</head>

				<p>We made a general analysis of quintessence cosmologies where the dark energy scalar field is exponentially coupled with the Ricci scalar . With respect to the case of a non - minimal quadratic coupling , we find relevant new results concerning both background expansion and perturbations .</p>

				<p>The dynamics of the field in the early universe is dominated by the effective potential in the Klein - Gordon equation , entirely due to the non - minimal interaction . Figure 6 . CMB angular polarisation power spectra for a QCDM cosmology ( dotted ) , quadratic ( dashed ) and exponential coupling extended quintessence ( solid ) with ω JBD = 50 . The spectra are in arbitrary units , normalized to 1 at the first acoustic peak .</p>

				<p>The presence of non - relativistic species , although sub - dominant with respect to radiation , makes the behavior of the Ricci scalar actually diverging in the early universe , determining the dynamics of the field . The whole trajectory , the R - boost , corresponds to the slow roll of the field on the effective gravitational potential . Interestingly , in the present scenario the R - boost looses any sensitivity on the initial conditions of the field , while in the case of a quadratic coupling the latter enters into the expression for the energy density along the trajectory . The R−boost solution is then equivalent to a tracking one with equation of state −1 / 3 , and energy density [ 3ρ mnr0 ( 1 + z ) ] 2 [ 32ρ r0 ω JBD 0 ] −1 , where ρ r0 is the radiation energy density today , ρ mnr0 the present energy density of the species which are non - relativisitc at redshift z , and ω JBD 0 is the Jordan - Brans - Dicke parameter , also calculated at present . This aspect is extremely relevant in dark energy cosmology ; indeed , the basin of attraction of the true quintessence potential shrinks if the equation of state today gets close to −1 as suggested by the observations . In this context , it is important to check whether the coupling of the field with other entities , gravity in this case , is able to restore the existence of attractors for the initial dynamics of the scalar field . We find that if the coupling is exponential the answer to that question is positive . We studied the impact of this scenario on the observations . In particular we derived the limits from the Big Bang Nucleosynthesis ; the constraints affect both the strength of the non - minimal coupling as well as the field value during the nuclide formation epoch . For interesting trajectories , those bounds are largely satisfied . We have finally considered the Cosmic Microwave Background ( CMB ) perturbation spectra , comparing the effects in the cases of exponential , quadratic and minimal couplings . The main effects are due to the time variation of the effective gravitational constant ; the latter represents an extra - source of dynamics for the Hubble expansion rate . That modifies distances and perturbation growth rate , shifting the angular location of the acoustic peaks in the CMB power spectrum , and enhancing its tail at low multipoles , by means of the modified dynamics of the gravitational potentials on large scales ( Integrated Sachs - Wolfe ) . For a fixed ω JBD at present , a marked difference exists between the amplitude of these effects in the two extended quintessence cosmologies considered . Indeed , the exponential form enhances the departure from general relativity as the field moves , with respect to the case of a quadratic coupling . The reason is just the shape of the coupling , for which the motion of the field gets exponentially amplified .</p>

				<p>In conclusion , two main remarks can be made . The first one is the capability of generalized theories of gravity to provide attractors for the early universe dynamics of the dark energy scalar field , independently of the shape of the potential inducing acceleration . The relevance of this issue goes beyond the mere capability of avoiding the fine tuning on the initial conditions . Actually , this aspects shows that the relation between dark energy and other entities deserves a careful study , providing a rich physics even if the present behavior is forced by observations to be close to that of a cosmological constant . The second remark concerns the capability of cosmology to constrain modified theories of gravity . Interestingly the imprint on the cosmological perturbations spectra depend on the actual form of the non - minimal interaction . The analogy existing between different scalar - tensor theories of gravity cannot be extended to their imprint on cosmological perturbations , which has to be done properly case by case . This aspect is relevant having in view of the possibility to constrain the theory of gravity on cosmological scales and from cosmological observations , in a complementary way with respect to what is done via observations in the solar system .</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>We are pleased to thank M. Doran and E. Linder for useful discussions and comments.</p>
			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="7">References</head>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Riess</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A G</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Perlmutter</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">517</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">565</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Bennett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J. Supp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">97</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tegmark</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Freedman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">553</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">47</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Padmanabhan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">380</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">235</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J E</forename>
				<surname>Peebles</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Ratra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">599</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Liddle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Scherrer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023509</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Steinhardt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Zlatev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">123504</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Amendola</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103524</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Mangano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Miele</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Pettorino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mod. Phys. Lett. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">831</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">061301</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Scalar-Tensor Theory of Gravitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Fujii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Maeda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">083508</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Uzan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Bartolo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Pietroni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023507</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Faraoni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023504</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Esposito-Farese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Polarski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">063504</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">123508</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Riazuelo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Uzan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023525</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Torres</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">043522</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Pietroni</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Schimd</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">084004</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Linder</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">061302</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Caresia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Moscardini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">605</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">21</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Acquaviva</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023515</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Nojiri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Odintsov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">599</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">137</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bludman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">122002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gasperini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Veneziano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">373</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hwang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">443</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Will</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C M</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Liv. Rev. Rel</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Bertotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Iess</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Tortora</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">425</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">374</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Clifton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Mota</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Barrow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Acquaviva</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Liddle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Leach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Rap. Comm. submitted</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Spergel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J. Supp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">97</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Cuoco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Iocco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Mangano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Miele</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Pisanti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Serpico</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International J. Mod. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4431</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Serpico</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Esposito</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Iocco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Mangano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Miele</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Pisanti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">0408076</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to. appear on J. Cosm. Astroparticle Phys. , astro-ph</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Cyburt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023505</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kirkman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Tytler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Suzuki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Meara</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J M</forename>
				<surname>Lubin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Fields</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Olive</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">506</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">177</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Izotov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">X</forename>
				<surname>Thuan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">602</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="0200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Olive</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Skillman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Chen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Scherrer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Steigman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">123504</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Baccigalupi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Balbi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Matarrese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Perrotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Vittorio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">506</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="063520" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
