<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Photonic measurements of the longitudinal expansion dynamics in Heavy-Ion collisions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2005-03-08">8 Mar 2005</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Thorsten</forename>
								<surname>Renk</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Duke University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>PO Box 90305</postBox>
									<postCode>27708</postCode>
									<settlement>Durham</settlement>
									<region>NC</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Photonic measurements of the longitudinal expansion dynamics in Heavy-Ion collisions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2005-03-08">8 Mar 2005</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">PACS numbers: 2575-q 
 1</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Due to the smallness of the electromagnetic coupling, photons escape from the hot and dense matter created in an heavy-ion collision at all times, in contrast to hadrons which are predominantly emitted in the final freeze-out phase of the evolving system. Thus, the thermal photon yield carries an imprint from the early evolution. We suggest how this fact can be used to gain information about where between the two limiting cases of Bjorken (boost-invariant expansion) and Landau (complete initial stopping and re-expansion) hydrodynamics the actual evolution can be found. We argue that both the rapidity dependence of the photon yield and photonic HBT radii are capable of answering this question.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>I. INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>The boost-invariant hydrodynamic model proposed by Bjørken [1] for the description of ultrarelativistic heavy-ion collisions is frequently used at RHIC energies for estimates of the initial energy density in heavy-ion collisions or the lifetime from the measured Hanbury- Brown Twiss (HBT) correlation radius R long [2] as well as in hydrodynamical descriptions of the evolving system (see. e.g. [3]).</p>

				<p>While the original notion of boost-invariance is an asymptotic concept, its application to RHIC energies usually implies two things: 1) the distribution of matter in some finite interval around midrapidity is assumed to be (almost) independent of rapidity and 2) the longitudinal dynamics is assumed to be unaccelerated expansion which in turn means that momentum</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>rapidity y = 1 2 ln E+pz E−pz is always equal spacetime rapidity η s = 1 2 ln t+z t−z</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(this is not true in the presence of longitudinal acceleration).</p>

				<p>In contrast, charged meson rapidity distributions as obtained by the BRAHMS collaboration [4] do not show a flat plateau around midrapidity even at top RHIC energy. The distributions are however well described by Landau hydrodynamics [5] as argued in [6]. Likewise there is no boost invariance seen in the rapidity dependence of elliptic flow as measured by the PHOBOS collaboration [7].</p>

				<p>In a model framework adjusted to reproduce the full set of observables characterizing the hadronic freeze-out, i.e. single particle transverse mass spectra and rapidity distributions and two particle HBT correlation radii [8] it was found that simultaneous agreement with all data sets can only be achieved if the assumption of a boost-invariant expansion is dropped.</p>

				<p>In fact, a sizeable difference of ∆y = 2 · 1.8 between initial and final width of the source in momentum space rapidity is required.</p>

				<p>This, however, is rather indirect evidence since it rests on a backward extrapolation of the observed final state. In contrast, thermal photons would offer the opportunity to test the longitudinal evolution directly [9]. The essential idea is as follows: In a Landau scenario, the source is initially very narrow around midrapidity. Since the hard photon emission rate is strongly temperature dependent, the dominant contribution to the photon yield arises from early times. Thus, we expect that the hard photon yield as a function of rapidity shows a thermal smearing of the initial (narrow) source extension in rapidity. In contrast, in a boost-invariant expansion we expect a much broader distribution reflecting the initial distribution of matter across a large rapidity interval.</p>

				<p>There is an additional factor which needs to be taken into account: Due to its large initial extension in rapidity, a Bjørken scenario leads to much more rapid cooling than a Landau one. Hence, while in a Landau scenario the hot, early phase will be dominant, this is not so in a Bjørken framework. The different weights of the contributions of early times and late times are expected to leave a characteristic imprint on HBT correlation radii measured even at midrapidity.</p>

				<p>In this work, we discuss both ideas and demonstrate what predictions for the photonic observables can be made using either the scenario determined from a fit to spectra and HBT in [8] or a Bjørken or a Landau one.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. THE MODEL FRAMEWORK</head>

				<p>Several calculations studying photon emission based on a hydrodynamical fireball evolution model have been made so far for different collision systems and energies[10, 11, 12, 13]. In the present study investigating 200 AGeV AuAu collisions, we will use a parametrized evolution model instead which allows for a complete description of hadronic transverse mass spectra as well as HBT correlation parameters [8] and which can easily be tuned to interpolate between</p>

				<p>Bjørken and Landau dynamics.</p>

				<p>The model for the evolution of hot matter is described in detail in [8, 14]. Here we only present the essential outline and focus on (almost) central collisions: For the entropy density at a given proper time we make the ansatz</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>s(τ, η s , r) = NR(r, τ ) · H(η s , τ ) (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with τ the proper time measured in a frame co-moving with a given volume element and</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R(r, τ ), H(η s , τ ) two functions describing the shape of the distribution and N a normalization factor. We use Woods-Saxon distributions R(r, τ ) = 1/ 1 + exp r − R c (τ ) d ws H(η s , τ ) = 1/ 1 + exp η s − H c (τ ) η ws (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for the shapes. Thus, the ingredients of the model are the skin thickness parameters d ws and η ws and the parametrizations of the expansion of the spatial extensions R c (τ ), H c (τ ) as a function of proper time. From the distribution of entropy density, the thermodynamics can be inferred via the EoS and particle emission is then calculated using the Cooper-Frye formula. For simplicity, we assume that the flow is built up by a constant acceleration a ⊥ ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>hence R c (τ ) = R 0 c + a ⊥ 2 τ 2 with R 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>c an initial radial extension as found in overlap calculations. The rapidity distribution is assumed to grow from some initial width 2 · y 0 to a final width 2 · y F . This determines the extension of the emitting source in spacetime rapidity η s [8, 14].</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>[8], the model parameters have been adjusted such that the model gives a good description of the data. This implies an initial rapidity width of y 0 = 1.7. In order to compute a Bjørken scenario, we set the initial width of the rapidity distribution equal to the final distribution width y 0 = y F . For a Landau scenario we choose y 0 = 0. In both cases we readjust the model parameters such that the single particle spectra are reproduced (this implies losing agreement with the HBT data).</p>

				<p>The spectrum of emitted photons can be found by folding the photon emission rates for the quark-gluon plasma (QGP) phase [15] and for a hot hadronic gas [16] with the fireball evolution. In order to account for flow, the energy of a photon emitted with momentum k µ = (k t , k t , 0) has to be evaluated in the local rest frame of matter, giving rise to a product k µ u µ with u µ (η s , r, τ ) the local flow profile. Following the results in [8] we assume for the spatial dependence of the flow field the relations y = f (τ ) · η s and y ⊥ = g(τ ) · r with y ⊥ the transverse rapidity and f, g two functions determined by the evolution. The distribution of entropy density is manifest in the dependence of the temperature T = T (η s , r, τ ) on the spacetime position. In order to account for the breakup of the system once a temperature T F is reached, a factor θ(T − T F ) has to be included into the folding integral.</p>

				<p>Using the folding integral of the rate with the fireball evolution as emission function S(x, K) (describing the amount of photons with momentum K µ emitted at spacetime point x µ ) we calculate the HBT parameters as [17, 18]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R 2 side = ˜ y 2 R 2 out = (˜ x − β ⊥ ˜ t) 2 R long = ˜ z 2 (3) with x µ = x µ − x µ and f (x)(K) = d 4 xf (x)S(x, K) d 4 xS(x, K) . (4) 4</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. RAPIDITY DEPENDENCE OF HARD THERMAL PHOTON EMISSION</head>

				<p>We show the resulting spectra of hard thermal photons in the momentum range between 1 and 4 GeV in Fig. 1 at two different rapidities.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 k t [GeV]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>10</p>

				<p><formula>-4 1 dN/d 2 k t dy [GeV -2 ] best fit Bjorken Landau y = 0 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 k t [GeV] 10 -4 1 dN/d 2 k t dy [GeV -2 ]</formula></p>

				<p>best fit Bjorken Landau y = 2</p>

				<p>FIG. 1: The hard thermal photon spectrum at midrapidity (y=0. left panel) and forward rapidity (y=2, right panel) for the best fit scenario described in [8], a Bjørken and a Landau scenario.</p>

				<p>It is instructive to observe that both slope and absolute yield changes strongly as a function of y for the Landau scenario. This reflects the fact that the initial high temperature phase (leading to a relatively flat slope) never radiates out into the y = 2 slice — only in the later stages when hot matter expands across y = 2 there is a significant contribution, albeit from matter with a much lower temperature, leading to a steeper spectral slope and reduced yield.</p>

				<p>In contrast, the photon yield from a Bjørken scenario is practically unchanged as a function of rapidity, reflecting the approximate boost-invariance.</p>

				<p>In order to highlight the differences more clearly we show in Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>the k T -integrated yield (1 GeV &lt; k T &lt; 4 GeV) at rapidity y 0 divided by the integrated yield at midrapidity. This choice has the additional advantage that model-dependences such as the precise normalization of the emission rates tend to cancel out. The different longitudinal source structure is now directly apparent. The Landau scenario is characterized by thermal smearing of about 1 unit of rapidity of a source at midrapidity (without any longitudinal flow) whereas the Bjørken scenario shows the broad distribution of matter across ∼ 3 units of rapidity at all times. A measurement of the thermal photon</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>0 1 2 3 4 5 y 0 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 dN γ /dy| y=y 0 /dN γ /dy| y=0 best fit Bjorken Landau 1 GeV &lt; k T &lt; 4 GeV</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 2: Integrated yield (1.0 GeV &lt; k T &lt; 4 GeV) of thermal photons as a function of rapidity y 0 .</p>

				<p>yield at midrapidity and at y 0 = 2 would well be capable of making a distinction between the three scenarios.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>IV. HARD THERMAL PHOTON HBT AT MIDRAPIDITY</head>

				<p>HBT correlation measurements do not measure the true geometrical size of the source but rather a region of homogeneity [17, 18] which is only identical with the geometry for vanishing flow gradients in the source. For finite flow gradients, the measured correlation radii show a characteristic falloff with the correlated pair momentum k T . The precise shape of the correlation radii as a function of transverse momentum results from a complex interplay between temperature and flow during the whole evolution. Nevertheless, we can formulate some basic expectations. Due to the high initial compression, the hard photon yield from a Landau scenario is expected to be dominated by the initial phase of the expansion. In this phase, however, there is no significant transverse flow (which builds up gradually driven by transverse pressure) and the geometrical size of the source in longitudinal direction is very small (for complete stopping it is given by the Lorentzcontracted size of the overlapping nuclei). Thus, we would expect only a weak falloff of R side with k T and R long to be determined primarily by the spatial resolution scale of photons with a given momentum.</p>

				<p>In contrast, a Bjørken expansion may well receive significant relative contributions to the yield from later stages due to the shorter duration of the inital hot phase. This would imply a slightly larger R side for vanishing k T but a stronger falloff with k T and an increased value R long as compared to the initial size at equilibration time. The relevant underlying scale for R side is in all cases the nuclear overlap radius.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 k t [GeV] 2.6 2.8 3 3.2 3.4 3.6 R side [fm] best fit Bjorken Landau 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 k t [GeV] 0 1 2 3 4 R long [fm]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>best fit Bjorken Landau FIG. 3: Hard photon HBT correlation radii R side (left panel) and R long (right panel) for the best fit scenario described in [8], a Bjørken and a Landau scenario.</p>

				<p>The result of the calculation can be seen in Fig. 3. To a good degree, the expected behaviour is indeed seen. In particular, the different falloff of R side for k T &gt; 2.5 GeV appears to be a good indicator of the longitudinal dynamics. R long in contrast is presumably only capable of identifying a scenario very similar to a Landau one, otherwise the qualititive behaviour of the different curves is too similar. Note that the observed R long for the Landau scenario could not be as small as shown in the plot due to constraints posed by the uncertainty relation which doesn&apos;t allow to narrow down the photon emission region to arbitrary small size.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. THE ROLE OF PRE-EQUILIBRIUM PHOTONS</head>

				<p>It is well known that in addition to thermal photons a sizeable contribution of prompt photons (calculable in perturbative QCD) is expected to contribute to the hard photon yield, and various attempts have been made to calculate its magnitude (see e.g. [19, 20, 21]). This contribution might well outshine the signals proposed here and change the conclusions.</p>

				<p>In order to address this question carefully, we do not only have to take into account the primary hard scattering processes as a potential source of photons but also hard re-scattering processes as the system approaches equilibrium. Therefore we use here the VNI/BMS parton cascade model (PCM) to estimate the role of pre-equilibrium hard photon production [22, 23].</p>

				<p>There is still the caveat that the re-scattering described by the PCM does not lead to a</p>

				<p>Landau-like stopping of the incoming matter, nevertheless we use the results to gain some intuition in the orders of magnitude involved.</p>

				<p>Including the LPM suppression in the PCM, we find that thermal photons may dominate the yield below 2–2.5 GeV for the best fit and the Bjørken scenario whereas they would dominate the yield in the whole momentum range for a pure Landau evolution [24].</p>

				<p>Since the photon yield drops (almost) exponentially with k t , this implies that the rapidity dependence of the integrated yield would still be a reliable signal (being dominated by the low k T yield).</p>

				<p>However, the behaviour of the HBT correlation radii in the interesting region above 2 GeV is likely to be distorted by pre-equilibrium photons (which would incidentially resemble Landau dynamics as they are characterized by small transverse flow).</p>

				<p>Turning the argument around, a simultaneous measurement of the HBT correlations at midrapidity and of the integrated yield at forward rapidity could still provide valuable insight into the magnitude of the pre-equilibrium contribution at different momenta. A detailed investigation of this question is however beyond the scope of this work.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>VI. SUMMARY</head>

				<p>We have argued that photons provide a direct measurement of the early longitudinal dynamics of a heavy-ion collision which can otherwise only be inferred indirectly from hadronic probes. The underlying reason is that due to the smallness of the electromagnetic coupling the measured photon yield represents an integral over the whole fireball evolution rather than a snapshot at breakup.</p>

				<p>In particular, we have argued that the rapidity dependence of the hard photon yield is a good probe to distinguish between Landau and Bjørken-like dynamics since it directly reveals the rapidity extension of the emission source. Since we compare the rapidity dependence of a ratio of integrated yields many uncertainties associated with the calculation of emission rates drop out and the result mainly reflects kinematic properties of the source.</p>

				<p>In addition, we have investigated the potential of using HBT correlation measurements at midrapidity to investigate the longitudinal evolution. HBT correlations show what part of the evolution dominates the photon yield rather than directly reflecting longitudinal dynamics. We found that the falloff of R side with k t above 2.5 GeV would indeed give a good indication if the photon emission is dominated by matter without significant transverse flow or not, however this signal is easily obscured by pre-equilibrium photon emission which would never show significant transverse flow.</p>

				<p>Nevertheless, both measuring the rapidity dependence of the hard photon yield and the HBT correlation parameters at midrapidity are capable of revealing interesting details of the early fireball evolution which cannot easily be studied otherwise.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>I would like to thank C. Gale, S. Turbide, J. Ruppert, S. A. Bass and B. Müller for helpful discussions and comments during the preparation of this paper. This work was supported by the DOE grant DE-FG02-96ER40945 and a Feodor Lynen Fellowship of the Alexander von Humboldt Foundation.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Bjorken</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">140</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Sinyukov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">498</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">151</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Gersdorff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kataja</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Mclerran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Ruuskanen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. C Eur. J. Phys. C</title>
		<editor>794</editor>
		<editor>J. Cleymans, K. Redlich and D. K. Srivastava 1431</editor>
		<editor>D. K. Srivastava</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">399</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Bearden</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BRAHMS Collaboration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0403050</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Landau</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Izv</forename>
				<surname>Akad</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nauk SSSR Physics Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">51</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1953" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Steinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0405022</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Back</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PHOBOS Collaboration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0407012</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Renk</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">021903</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Dumitru</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Katscher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Maruhn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Stocker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Greiner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Rischke</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">353</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">187</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Dumitru</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Katscher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Maruhn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Stocker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Greiner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Rischke</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2166</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Alam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Srivastava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Sinha</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Basu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<editor>1117. [12] J. J. Neumann, D. Seibert and G. I. Fai</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1460</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Srivastava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Renk</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">1495</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Arnold</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Yaffe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Arnold</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yaffe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0112" to="009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Turbide</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Rapp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Gale</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">014903</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Wiedemann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Heinz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rept</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">319</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">145</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Tomasik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Wiedemann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="210250" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Dumitru</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Frankfurt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Gerland</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Stocker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Strikman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">054909</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
				<surname>Wong</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">376</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Srivastava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">129</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bass</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Muller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Srivastava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">082301</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bass</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Muller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Srivastava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Bass</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Muller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Renk</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Srivastava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
