<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">F D -Term Hybrid Inflation with Electroweak-Scale Lepton Number Violation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2006-03-28">28 Mar 2006 January 2006</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Björn</forename>
								<surname>Garbrecht</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Physics and Astronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Manchester</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>M13 9PL</postCode>
									<settlement>Manchester</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Apostolos</forename>
								<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Physics and Astronomy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Manchester</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>M13 9PL</postCode>
									<settlement>Manchester</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">CERN</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Theory Division</addrLine>
									<postCode>CH-1211</postCode>
									<settlement>Geneva 23</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">F D -Term Hybrid Inflation with Electroweak-Scale Lepton Number Violation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2006-03-28">28 Mar 2006 January 2006</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We study F-term hybrid inflation in a novel supersymmetric extension of the SM with a subdominant Fayet–Iliopoulos D-term. We call this particular form of inflation, in short, F D-term hybrid inflation. The proposed model ties the µ-parameter of the MSSM to an SO(3)-symmetric Majorana mass m N , through the vacuum expectation value of the inflaton field. The late decays of the ultraheavy particles associated with the extra U(1) gauge group, which are abundantly produced during the preheating epoch, could lower the reheat temperature even up to 1 TeV, thereby avoiding the gravitino overproduction problem. The baryon asymmetry in the Universe can be explained by thermal electroweak-scale resonant leptogenesis, in a way independent of any pre-existing lepton-or baryon-number abundance. Further cosmological and particle-physics implications of the F D-term hybrid model are briefly discussed.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The inflationary paradigm constitutes an ingenious theoretical framework, in which many of the outstanding problems in standard cosmology can be successfully addressed [1]. The recent WMAP data [2], compiled with other astronomical observations [3, 4], improved upon the precision of about a dozen of cosmological parameters. These include the power spectrum P</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1/2</head>

				<p>R of curvature perturbations, the spectral index n s , the baryon-to-photon ratio of number densities η B and others. The values of these cosmological observables put severe constraints on the model-building of successful models of inflation and their theoretical parameters. For instance, one of the basic requirements for slow-roll inflation is that the so-called inflaton potential be flat. In this respect, supersymmetry (SUSY) emerges as a compelling ingredient in model-building for protecting the flatness of the inflaton potential against quantum corrections.</p>

				<p>In addition to the aforementioned element of naturalness, inflationary models would have a greater value if they were predictive and testable as well. One such predictive and perhaps most appealing scenario is the well-celebrated model of hybrid inflation [5]. In this model, the inflaton field φ can start its slow-roll from values well below the Planck scale m Pl = 2.4 × 10 18 GeV. This renders the model very predictive, in the sense that an infinite set of possible higher-dimensional non-renormalizable operators, being suppressed by inverse powers of 1/m Pl , will not generically contribute significantly to cosmological observables, such as P 1/2 R and n s . In the hybrid model, inflation ends through the socalled waterfall mechanism, once the field φ passes below a critical value φ c . When this happens, another field X different from φ, with vanishing initial value, develops a tachyonic instability and rolls fast down to its true vacuum expectation value (VEV). Supersymmetric realizations of hybrid inflation from F -terms were first analyzed in [6,7], whereas hybrid inflation triggered by a dominant Fayet–Iliopoulos (FI) D-term [8] was subsequently considered in [9].</p>

				<p>In this paper we study F -term hybrid inflation in a novel supersymmetric extension of the Standard Model (SM) that includes a subdominant FI D-term. We call this scenario for brevity, the F D -term hybrid model. To account for the low-energy neutrino data, we introduce 3 singlet neutrino superfields N 1,2,3 that contain 3 right-handed neutrinos ν 1,2,3 R and their supersymmetric scalar counterparts N 1,2,3 . Most importantly, the model ties the µ-parameter of the Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model (MSSM) to an SO(3) symmetric Majorana mass m N , through the VEV of the inflaton field φ [10, 11]. Hence, the F D -term hybrid model naturally predicts lepton-number violation at the TeV or even at the electroweak scale. In this scenario, the non-zero baryon asymmetry in the Universe (BAU), η B ≈ 6.1 × 10 −10 , can be explained by leptogenesis [12, 13] and specifically by thermal electroweak-scale resonant leptogenesis [10, 14].</p>

				<p>In this paper we also study the constraints on the parameters of the F D -term hybrid model that result from a reheat temperature T reh &lt; ∼ 10 9 GeV, which is necessary to avoid the well-known gravitino overproduction problem. This consideration puts severe limits on the size of the superpotential couplings of the theory, forcing them all to acquire rather suppressed values, namely to be smaller than about 10 −5 [15]. To overcome this problem of unnaturalness, the presence of a subdominant FI D-term in the F D -term hybrid model is very crucial and provides a new mechanism of relaxing dramatically the above upper limit. More explicitly, the size of the D-term controls the decay rates of the ultraheavy fermions and bosons associated with the extra gauge group U(1) X .</p>

				<p>In the absence of the D-term and any other non-renormalizable interaction, these ultraheavy gauge-sector particles are absolutely stable. On the other hand, these particles are abundantly produced during the preheating epoch, thus dominating the energy density of the Universe shortly after the period of the first reheating caused by the perturbative inflaton decays. Therefore, their late decays induced by a non-vanishing D-term could give rise to a second reheating phase in the evolution of the early Universe. Depending on the actual size of the FI D-term, this second reheat temperature may be as low as 1 TeV, giving rise to an enormous entropy release that can dilute the gravitinos produced during the first reheating to an unobservable level.</p>

				<p>The paper is organized as follows: Section 2 presents the model-building aspects of the F D -term hybrid model with electroweak-scale lepton-number violation. Technical details related to the radiatively-induced FI D-term are relegated to Appendix A. In Section 3, we estimate the reheat temperature from the perturbative inflaton decays and derive the resulting gravitino constraint on the theoretical parameters. We then discuss the nonperturbative production of the supermassive fields associated with the U(1) X gauge group during the preheating epoch and how their late decays can help to lower the reheat temperature even up to 1 TeV. Section 4 is devoted to inflation. Here we investigate two regimes: (i) cold hybrid inflation, where dissipative effects can be ignored, and (ii) warm hybrid inflation, where dissipative effects dominate over the expansion rate of the Universe. In Section 5 we illustrate how the F D -term hybrid model can realize thermal electroweak-scale resonant leptogenesis. Finally, Section 6 summarizes our conclusions, including a brief discussion of further possible implications of the F D -term hybrid model for particle physics and cosmology.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 The F D –Term Hybrid Model The F D -term hybrid model may be defined by the superpotential W = κ S X 1 X 2 − M 2 + λ S H u H d + ρ 2 S N i N i + h ν ij L i H u N j + W (µ=0) MSSM , (2.1) where W (µ=0) MSSM is the MSSM superpotential without the µ term: W (µ=0) MSSM = h u ij Q i H u U j + h d ij H d Q i D j + h l H d L l E l . (2.2) In (2.1),</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>S is the SM-singlet inflaton superfield, and X 1 and X 2 is a chiral multiplet pair of the so-called waterfall fields which have opposite charges under the additional U(1) X gauge group. The superpotential (2.1) of the model is uniquely determined by the R</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>transformation: S → e iα S, X 1,2 → e ±iβ X 1,2 , L → e iα L, Q → e iα Q, with W → e iα W , whereas</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>all other fields remain invariant under an R transformation. As a consequence of the R symmetry, higher-dimensional operators of the form X 1</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>X 2</head>

				<p>N i N i /m Pl , for example, are not allowed.</p>

				<p>In addition, the model contains a subdominant FI D-term, −</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 g m 2 FI D, giving rise to the D-term potential V D = g 2 8 |X 1 | 2 − |X 2 | 2 − m 2 FI 2 . (2.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The FI D-term plays no role in the inflationary dynamics, as long as gm FI ≪ κ M. In Appendix A, we show how a subdominant D-term can be generated radiatively after Planckscale heavy degrees of freedom have been integrated out. The presence of the D-term is important to break an accidental discrete charge symmetry that survives after the spontaneous symmetry breaking (SSB) of the U(1) X . Such a breaking is crucial to render all U(1) X gauge-sector particles unstable. As we will see in Section 3, an upper limit on the size of the FI term is obtained by requiring a sufficiently low reheat temperature, e.g. T reh &lt; ∼ 10 9 GeV, in order to suppress the gravitino abundance to an unobservable level.</p>

				<p>From (2.1) it is straightforward to read the Lagrangian of the inflationary soft SUSYbreaking sector,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− L soft = M 2 S S * S + κA κ SX 1 X 2 + λA λ SH u H d + ρ 2 A ρ S N i N i − κa S M 2 S + H.c. , (2.4) where M S , A κ,λ,ρ and a S are soft SUSY-breaking mass parameters of order M SUSY ∼ 1 TeV.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the regime |S| ≫ M relevant to inflation, the dominant tree-level and one-loop contributions to the renormalized effective potential may be described by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V inflation ≈ κ 2 M 4 1 + 1 64π 2 4κ 2 + 8λ 2 + 6ρ 2 ln |S| 2 M 2 − κa S M 2 S + H.c. + V SUGRA , (2.5)</trash>

					<figDesc>where V SUGRA denotes the supergravity (SUGRA) correction that results from the Kähler potential. Assuming a minimal Kähler potential, the SUGRA correction of interest to us takes on the simple form [6, 16, 17]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>V</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>SUGRA = κ 2 M 4 |S| 4 2 m 4 Pl , (2.6) where m Pl = 2.4 × 10 18</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>GeV is the reduced Planck mass. Possible one-loop contributions to V inflation from A κ,λ,ρ -terms become significant only for relatively low values of M, e.g. M &lt; ∼ 10 8 GeV, for κ, λ, ρ ∼ 1, and may therefore be neglected. At the tree level, however, only the tadpole term κa S M 2 S may become relevant for values of κ &lt; ∼ 10 −4 , whereas the other soft SUSY-breaking terms are negligible during inflation [15].</p>

				<p>We now investigate the stability of the inflationary trajectory in the presence of the Higgs doublets H u,d and the right-handed scalar neutrinos N 1,2,3 . Specifically, the initial condition for inflation is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Re S in = |S in | ≫ M , X in 1,2 = 0 , H in u,d = 0 , N in 1,2,3 = 0 . (2.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>At the end of inflation, one should ensure that the waterfall fields acquire a high VEV,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>i.e. X end 1,2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>= M, while all other fields have small VEVs, possibly of the electroweak order. To achieve this, we have to require that the Higgs-doublet and the sneutrino mass matrices stay positive definite throughout the inflationary trajectory up to the critical value |S c | ≈ M, whereas the corresponding mass matrix of X 1,2 will be the first to develop a negative eigenvalue and tachyonic instability close to |S c |. In this way, it will be the fields X 1,2 which will first start moving away from 0 and set in to the &apos;good&apos; vacuum</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X end 1 = X end 2 = M, instead of having the other fields, e.g. H 1,2 and N in 1,2,3 , go to a &apos;bad&apos; vacuum where X end 1,2 = 0, H end 1,2 = κ λ M and N in 1,2,3 = κ ρ M. To see this, let us write down the mass matrix in the background Higgs-doublet field space (H † d , H u ) as M 2 Higgs = |λ| 2 |S| 2 − κλ(M 2 − X 1 X 2 ) + λA λ S − κ * λ * (M 2 − X * 1 X * 2 ) + λ * A * λ S * |λ| 2 |S| 2 . (2.8)</trash>

					<figDesc>The requirement of positive definiteness may be translated into the simple condition:</figDesc>
					<trash>|λ| |S| 2 ≥ |κ(M 2 − X 1 X 2 ) − A λ S| . (2.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From this last inequality, we may see that the condition λ &gt; ∼ κ is sufficient for ending hybrid inflation to the &apos;good&apos; vacuum. Likewise, one obtains a condition analogous to (2.9) from the sneutrino mass matrix, which amounts to having ρ &gt; ∼ κ. The above two restrictions on the superpotential couplings λ and ρ will be imposed throughout our analysis.</p>

				<p>As mentioned above, after the end of inflation, one has X</p>

				<figure>
					<head>end 1</head>

					<figDesc>,2 = M, giving rise to a high mass for the inflaton field, i.e. 2|κ| 2 M 2 |S| 2 . Combining this fact with the soft SUSYbreaking tadpole −κa S M 2 S and the trilinear coupling κA κ SX</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<figure>
					<head>end 1 X</head>

					<figDesc>end 2 , one gets a VEV for the inflaton [18]:</figDesc>
					<trash>v S ≡ S end = 1 2|κ| A κ − a S , (2.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have neglected the VEVs of the Higgs doublets H u,d . The VEV of S induces an effective µ-term and an SO(3) symmetric lepton-number-violating Majorana mass m N of the electroweak order [10]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>
					<trash>µ = λ v S , m N = ρ v S . (2.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>If ρ and λ are comparable in magnitude, then these two mass parameters are tied together and can naturally be of the TeV or even of the electroweak scale.</p>

				<p>In Sections 3 and 4, we will derive the constraints on the key theoretical parameters κ, λ, ρ and M from the requirement of a low reheat temperature, T reh</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>&lt; ∼ 10 9 GeV, and successful inflation.</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Preheating and Second Reheating</head>

				<p>In the SUGRA framework, the reheat temperature is constrained by the fact that an overabundant amount of gravitinos may destroy, through their possible late decays, the successful predictions of Big Bang nucleosynthesis [19]. This possibility is avoided, if the gravitino abundance Y 3/2 is small enough, i.e. Y 3/2 &lt; 10 −12 . The latter may be translated to an upper limit on the reheat temperature, i.e. T reh &lt; ∼ 10 9 GeV. If the gravitinos are stable, the above limit may be relaxed by one order of magnitude to ∼ 10 10 GeV. This depends on whether the so-called next-to-lightest supersymmetric particle (NLSP) has a small branching fraction to hadronic decay modes [20]. In addition to the above upper limit, the reheat temperature T reh is also constrained from below, depending on the mechanism of baryogenesis. Thus, for successful electroweak-scale resonant leptogenesis, a lower bound of order TeV on T reh should be considered.</p>

				<p>In the following we will study the post-inflationary dynamics. To this end, let us define the fields:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X ± = 1 √ 2 (X 1 ± X 2 ) = X ± + δX ± , δX ± = 1 √ 2 (R ± + iI ± ) . (3.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As mentioned in the introduction, inflation ends, once the inflaton field, φ = √ 2 Re S, rolls below a critical value φ c ≈ √ 2 M. Then, the waterfall regime begins, where the waterfall fields S and R + evolve rapidly (we use the gauge freedom to ensure that all VEVs point to real directions).</p>

				<p>Ignoring small corrections due to a non-vanishing FI D-term, m FI , the VEVs of S and R + oscillate around zero, whereas X + attains its U(1) X -breaking VEV, X + = √ 2M.</p>

				<p>The masses of the waterfall-or κ-sector fields φ and R + are equal to m κ = √ 2κM. The inflaton φ decays predominantly into pairs of charged and neutral higgsinos, ˜ h</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>± u,d , ˜ h 0 u,d , ˜ ¯ h 0 u,d , and into pairs of right-handed Majorana neutrinos ν 1,2,3 R . The decay width of the inflaton is given by Γ φ = 1 32π 4λ 2 + 3ρ 2 m κ . (3.2)</trash>

					<figDesc>It turns out that the field R + decays into the scalar SUSY partners of the aforementioned fields at the same rate. Hence, we find</figDesc>
					<trash>Γ φ = Γ R + ≡ Γ κ . (3.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The reheat temperature resulting from the perturbative decays of the κ-sector fields may usually be estimated by</figDesc>
					<trash>T κ reh = 90 π 2 g * 1/4 Γ κ m Pl , (3.4) where g * = 228</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>.75 is the number of the relativistic degrees of freedom in the supersymmetric model under consideration. The gravitino bound then implies that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>κ λ 2 + 3 4 ρ 2 &lt; ∼ 3 · 10 −15 × T κ reh 10 9 GeV 2 10 16 GeV M . (3.5) Sector Boson Fermion Mass Waterfall S, R + , I + ψ κ =   1 √ 2 1 − v 2M ψ X 1 + 1 + v 2M ψ X 2 ψ † S   √ 2κM (κ-sector) U(1) X Gauge V µ , R − ψ g = 1 √ 2 1 + v 2M ψ X 1 − 1 − v 2M ψ X 2 −iλ † gM (g-sector)</trash>

					<head>Table 1:</head>

					<figDesc>Particle spectrum of the waterfall and U(1) X gauge sectors after inflation, where V µ denotes the U(1) X gauge boson and λ its associate gaugino.</figDesc>
					<trash>If κ ≈ λ ≈ ρ, this amounts to being each individual coupling smaller than about 10 −5 , for M = 10 16 GeV and T κ reh &lt; ∼ 10 9 GeV.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>So far, we have only considered the post-inflationary dynamics of the κ-sector fields, S, R + and I + , to which all the energy of the inflationary potential is stored at the onset of the waterfall regime. We now turn our attention to the g-sector, namely to the particles associated with the extra U(1) X gauge group. This distinction of the different fields involved after inflation is made clear in Table 1. Thus, the g-or U(1) X gauge-sector contains the U(1) X gauge boson V µ , the Dirac fermion ψ g , which consists of the gaugino λ and the fermionic superpartner of X − , and the scalars R − and I − ; the field I − is a massless wouldbe Goldstone boson which becomes the longitudinal component of V µ . Each of the g-sector particles has a mass m g = 2 −1/2 gX + . In fact, during the waterfall transition, their masses evolve rapidly from 0 to gM. As we will see below, this rapid non-adiabatic mass variation triggers the so-called preheating mechanism, through which the g-sector particles can be produced in sizeable amounts. Their decays can only be induced by the presence of a non-vanishing D-term, which breaks explicitly a discrete charge symmetry in the F -and the D-term sectors which would remain otherwise intact even after the SSB of the U(1) X .</p>

				<p>To make this last point explicit, let us express the relevant F -and D-term potential in terms of the fields X ± defined in (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3.1): V F D = κ 2 4 X 2 + − X 2 − − 2 M 2 2 + g 2 8 X * + X − + X * − X + − m 2 FI 2 . (3.6)</trash>

					<figDesc>It is obvious that the potential V F D possesses an additional discrete charge symmetry under the transformation, X ± → ±X ± , if the FI mass term vanishes, m</figDesc>

				</figure>

			<note>2</note>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>FI = 0. In the absence of a FI term, this symmetry will still survive even after the SSB of the U(1) X</figDesc>
					<trash>along the flat direction X 1 = X 2 = M, 1 or equivalently when X + = √ 2M and X − = 0. As a consequence, the U(1) X gauge boson V µ , the scalar field R − = √ 2 Re(X − ) and</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>their fermionic superpartner ψ g are all stable with a mass gM. This feature is highly unsatisfactory for the hybrid model without a FI term, since these particles can be produced in large numbers during the preheating process, and since they are very massive, they could dominate and so overclose the Universe at later times.</p>

				<p>The presence of the FI term m FI breaks explicitly the above discrete charge symmetry and so provides a new decay mechanism for making these particles unstable. To leading order in the expansion parameter m FI /M, the potential V F D given in (3.6) can be minimized using the linear field decompositions</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X + = √ 2 M + δX + , X − = v √ 2 + δX − , (3.7) where v = m 2 FI /(2M).</trash>

					<head>Table 1 exhibits the particle spectrum of the waterfall and U(1)</head>

					<figDesc>X gauge sectors to leading order in m FI /M. Unlike the case of a vanishing FI D-term, the scalar field R − of mass gM will now decay into pairs of two lighter scalars, R + and I + , of mass √ 2 κM, assuming that g ≫ κ. The strength of this coupling is given by the Lagrangian</figDesc>
					<trash>L int = g 2 m 2 FI 8M R − (R 2 + + I 2 + ) . (3.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The D-term induced decay width of the R − particle can readily be found to be</figDesc>
					<trash>Γ R − = g 3 128π m 4 FI M 3 , (3.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>and the same rate also holds true for the decay of I − , or equivalently for the longitudinal polarization of V µ . Correspondingly, the decays of the g-sector fermions ψ g are induced by the Lagrangian</figDesc>
					<trash>L int = − g 8 m FI M 2 (R + − iI + ) ¯ ψ g 1 − γ 5 2 ψ κ + H.c. (3.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Neglecting soft SUSY-breaking, we find that Γ ψg = Γ R − ≡ Γ g .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>If the decay rate Γ g of the g-sector particles is sufficiently low, they may dominate the energy density of the Universe at later times, eventually leading to a second reheating phase due to their out of equilibrium decays. To offer an initial estimate, consider that, after the first reheating, the energy density ̺ κ of the waterfall-sector fields gets distributed among their decay products and so diluted as relativistic radiation ∝ a −4 , where a is the usual cosmological scale factor describing the expansion of the Universe. Meanwhile, the energy density ̺ g of the ultraheavy g-sector particles produced via preheating scales as ∝ a −3 , such that ̺ g /̺ κ ∝ a. Moreover, during a radiation-dominated epoch, the dependence of</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 0.0005 0.001 0.0015 0.002 0.0025 0.003 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 ρ/ρ WF g ρ F /ρ WF ρ B /ρ WF</trash>

					<head>Figure 1:</head>

					<figDesc>The ratio of the energy density ̺ F (̺ B ) of the gauge-sector fermions (bosons) produced via preheating to the energy density ̺ WF ≡ ̺ κ carried by the waterfall-sector particles as a function of g, for κ = 10 −3 .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>the Hubble expansion rate H on a is H ∝ a −2 . Let us therefore denote with H reh the Hubble rate at the first reheating of the Universe and H eq the Hubble rate at the time, when ̺ g = ̺ κ . Then, the U(1) X gauge-sector particles will dominate the energy density of the Universe, when</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H eq = H reh ̺ 0 g ̺ 0 κ 2 ≫ Γ g , (3.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the superscript 0 stands for the energy density right after preheating. Note that ̺ g /̺ κ is conserved until the time of the first reheating, since both ̺ g and ̺ κ scale as a</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>−3</head>

				<p>during this period.</p>

				<p>The g-sector particle production via preheating can be computed numerically [21], by first solving for the mode functions and then using these to calculate the Hamiltonian energy density. For the evolution of the VEVs X 1 ≈ X 2 , we assume that they initially undergo strong damping due to tachyonic preheating [22]. This phenomenon can be mimicked by setting</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X 1 = X 2 =      0 , for t ≤ −π/(4 √ 2κM) , 1 2 M [1 + sin( √ 2κMt)] , for − π/(4 √ 2κM) &lt; t &lt; π/(4 √ 2κM) , M for t ≥ π/(4 √ 2κM) , (3.12)</trash>

					<figDesc>More precise forms of field evolutions may be obtained using numerical simulations [22]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. For an initial estimate, however, only the velocity of the transition is important. In Fig. 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>we display the energy densities ̺ F and ̺ B of the g-sector fermions ψ g and bosons R − and V µ (produced via preheating), normalized to the energy density ̺ WF ≡ ̺ κ carried by the waterfall-sector particles, as functions of the U(1) X gauge coupling g, for κ = 10 −3 . For the given profile (3.12) of field evolutions, these normalized energy densities depend only very weakly on κ. The above results strongly suggest that the U(1) X gauge-sector particles, ψ g , R − and V µ , if sufficiently long-lived, will dominate the energy density of the early Universe. We may estimate the second reheat temperature T g reh caused by their late decays, by employing a formula very analogous to (3.4). Solving this last relation for the ratio m FI /M yields</figDesc>
					<trash>m FI M ≈ 8.4 · 10 −4 × 0.5 g 3/4 T g reh 10 9 GeV 1/2 10 16 GeV M 1/4 . (3.13) For second reheat temperatures of cosmological interest, i.e. 1 TeV ≤ T g reh ≤ 10 9 GeV, we obtain the combined constraint for M = 10 16 GeV: 10 −6 &lt; ∼ m FI M &lt; ∼ 10 −3 . (3.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>From our discussion in this section, it is evident that the late decays of the ultraheavy U(1) X gauge-sector fields, which are copiously produced during the preheating epoch, will give rise to a second reheating phase in the evolution of the early Universe at a temperature</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>T g reh ≪ T κ reh .</formula></p>

				<p>This makes the F D -term hybrid model an interesting cosmological scenario that could even lead to a complete relaxation of the strict bound (3.5) on the couplings κ, λ, ρ. The reason is that gravitinos, which are produced very efficiently at high reheat temperatures T κ reh &gt; 10 9 GeV, will now be diluted by the large entropy release from the late decays of the g-sector particles. In this way, the so-called gravitino overproduction problem can be completely avoided. A detailed study of this topic will be given elsewhere [23]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Inflation</head>

				<p>In this section we will discuss the additional constraints on the theoretical parameters of the F D -term hybrid model from the power spectrum P</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1/2</head>

				<p>R and the spectral index n s . We distinguish two possible regimes of inflation: (i) the cold hybrid inflation (CHI), where dissipative effects on inflation are negligible, e.g. for κ, λ, ρ &lt; ∼ 10 −2 and (ii) the warm hybrid inflation (WHI), where dissipation might dominate over the expansion rate of the Universe [24]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4.1">Cold Hybrid Inflation</head>

				<p>In models of hybrid inflation, the spectral index n s may well be approximated as follows [1]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>n s − 1 = d ln P 1/2 R d ln k ≈ 2η , (4.1)</formula></p>

				<p>where k is the comoving wavenumber at the horizon exit and</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>η = m 2 Pl V φφ V (4.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is the so-called η-parameter. In (4.2), V denotes the inflationary potential, and V φ = dV /dφ, V φφ = d 2 V /dφ 2 etc. The current WMAP data [2] show a strong preference for a red-tilted spectrum, with n s − 1 ≤ 0, implying that V φφ ≤ 0. The actual value is n s = 0.98 ± 0.02 [4].</p>

				<p>The T reh constraint (3.5) on the theoretical parameters imply that κ, λ, ρ &lt; ∼ 10 −5 .</p>

				<p>In this case, the radiative correction to the potential becomes subdominant and may be ignored to a good approximation. The potential driving inflation simplifies considerably to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V inflation = κ 2 M 4 − √ 2 κ a S M 2 φ + 1 2 M 2 S φ 2 + κ 2 M 4 8 m 4 Pl φ 4 , (4.3) where φ = √ 2 Re S is the inflaton field canonically normalized. For M S &lt; 1 TeV, κ ≥ 10 −6 and M ≥ 10 15</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>GeV, the soft SUSY-breaking term M S can be omitted. The inflationary potential V inflation of (4.3) generically leads to a blue-tilted spectrum, i.e. n s − 1 = 2η &gt; 0, which is slightly disfavoured by the recent WMAP data.</p>

				<p>In the following, we will concentrate on the regime where the loop correction dominates the slope of the potential, such that a negative value for n s − 1 becomes possible.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>This possibility arises for 10</head>

				<p>−4 &lt; ∼ κ, λ, ρ &lt; ∼ 10 −2 . Naively, such large values of the parameters lead to a too high reheat temperature T reh , i.e. T reh &gt; ∼ 10 10 GeV. However, as we have discussed in Section 3, the presence of a subdominant D-term renders the stable U(1) X gauge-sector fields unstable, and so a large amount of entropy can be released from their late decays, leading to a T reh which may even be as low as 1 TeV.</p>

				<p>Our results simplify considerably if one assumes that the slope of the inflationary potential given in (2.5) is dominated by the λ-dependent term. To be specific, the number of e-folds N e is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N e = 1 m 2 Pl φ N φ end dφ V V φ ≈ 2π 2 λ 2 φ 2 N m 2 Pl . (4.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that at the horizon exit, it is φ N =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N e /2 (λ/π) m Pl and φ N &lt; ∼ 10 −1 m Pl , for λ &lt; ∼ 0.1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and N e = 60. Hence inflation starts at values of φ N well below m Pl . In terms of the number of e-folds N e , the power spectrum P</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1/2</head>

				<p>R of the curvature perturbations may now be given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P 1/2 R = 1 2 √ 3 πm 3 Pl V 3/2 |V φ | ≈ 2N e 3 κ λ M m Pl 2 = 5 × 10 −5 . (4.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Evidently, for N e = 60 and M = 10 16 GeV, the parameter λ cannot be by more than one order of magnitude larger than κ, i.e. λ &lt; ∼ 10 κ. Finally, the spectral index n s in terms of N e may be expressed as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n s − 1 = − 1 N e ≈ − 0.02 , (4.6) for N e = 50–60.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this CHI regime, the model predicts a red-tilted spectrum, as currently favoured by the WMAP data.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4.2">Warm Hybrid Inflation</head>

				<p>It has been extensively argued [24] that dissipative effects due to radiation production of massless particles during inflation may dominate over the expansion rate H of the Universe. This form of inflation is known as warm inflation. Although a firm first principles derivation for the existence of a strong dissipative regime of inflation is still missing, 2 it might be worth presenting tentative results for such a possible situation, using the semi-empiric formalism on warm inflation developed in [24].</p>

				<p>In the framework of WHI, dissipation occurs from the radiation produced by the decays of the excited H u doublet of mass λS. Specifically, the interactions relevant to WHI are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− L WHI int = |S| 2 |λ| 2 |H u | 2 + |ρ| 2 3 i=1 | N i | 2 + h t H u ¯ Q t t R + h ν ij ¯ L i ˜ h u N j + H.c. . (4.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The dominant decay mode will be H u → Q t t R [25]; the other possible decay channel N j → L i ˜ h u is Yukawa-coupling suppressed and kinematically allowed only when ρ &gt; λ.</p>

				<p>Adapting the results of [24, 25] to our model, the dominant friction term for |S| ≫ M is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Y S ≈ √ π α 3/2 λ α t 20 √ 2 φ , (4.8) where α λ = λ 2 /(4π) and α t = h 2 t /(4π). The dynamics of warm inflation is governed by the following two equations: ¨ φ + 3H (1 + r) ˙ φ + V φ = 0 , (4.9) ˙ ρ rad + 4 Hρ rad = Y S ˙ φ 2 , (4.10) where r = Y S /(3H), with H 2 ≈ κ 2 M 4 /(3m 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Pl ). In the strong dissipative regime where r ≫ 1, inflation usually ends when ρ rad &gt; ρ vac ≈ κ 2 M 4 .</p>

				<p>Assuming conditions of slow roll during WHI, i.e. η/r 2 ≪ 1, we may determine the number of e-folds by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N e = 1 m 2 Pl φ N φ end dφ (1 + r) V V φ = πα 1/2 λ α t 60 κ φ 3 N m Pl M 2 . (4.11) In the limit r ≫ 1, the power spectrum P 1/2 R due to WHI is approximately given by (P 1/2 R ) WHI ≈ 3π 4 1/4 T rad H r 5/4 (P 1/2 R ) CHI . (4.12)</trash>

					<figDesc>The temperature T rad associated with radiation production can be calculated from (4.10), by solving the approximate equation</figDesc>
					<trash>ρ rad = π 2 30 g * T 4 rad ≈ 3r 4 ˙ φ 2 , (4.13) where ˙ φ ≈ −V φ /(3rH) is evaluated at the horizon exit. Putting everything together, we find (P 1/2 R ) WHI ≈ g −1/8 * N 5/8 e (2κ) 1/4 α 5/8 λ α 1/2 t M m Pl 1/2 = 5 × 10 −5 . (4.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is interesting to observe that WHI leads to a viable inflationary scenario even for strong couplings, e.g. for κ, α λ , α t ∼ 1. In this case, the U(1) X -breaking scale M will be as low as 10 10 GeV, in agreement with the earlier discussion in [25]. Obviously, it would be difficult to associate such a low scale for M with gauge coupling unification. Finally, the spectral index n s in WHI is calculated in terms of N e to be: n s − 1 ≈ −5/(4N e ) ≈ −0.025.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Baryon Asymmetry in the Universe</head>

				<p>As discussed in Section 3, the late decays of the U(1) X gauge-sector particles may lead to a second reheating phase in the evolution of the early Universe, giving rise to a very low final reheat temperature T reh . Depending on the size of the D-term, T reh may even be as low as 1 TeV. In such a case, the BAU may be explained by thermal electroweakscale resonant leptogenesis [10, 14]. The F D -term hybrid model under study can realize such a scenario even within a minimal SUGRA framework, where all soft SUSY-breaking parameters are constrained at the gauge-coupling unification point M X , which can be chosen to be M = M X ≈ 10 16 GeV. Instead, electroweak baryogenesis is no longer viable in minimal SUGRA, since it requires an unconventionally large hierarchy between the lefthanded and right-handed top squarks [26].</p>

				<p>An advantageous feature of resonant leptogenesis is that the predictions for the BAU are almost independent of any pre-existing lepton-or baryon-number abundance. This kind of fixed-line attractor behaviour is a consequence of the quasi-in-thermal equilibrium dynamics governing the heavy Majorana neutrino sector. It results from the fact that the heavy neutrino decay widths can be several orders of magnitude larger than the expansion rate H of the Universe. A detailed analysis of this dynamics was presented in [10], where single lepton-flavour and freeze-out sphaleron effects were systematically considered for the first time. In particular, it was shown that single lepton-flavour effects resulting from the Yukawa-neutrino couplings h ν ij can have a dramatic impact on the predictions for the BAU, enhancing its value by many orders of magnitude. From the model-building point of view, phenomenologically rich scenarios are now possible with testable implications for high-energy colliders [27] and low-energy observables, such as µ → eγ, µ → eee and µ → e conversion in nuclei [28].</p>

				<p>We will not reiterate all these results here, but only underline some of the key modelbuilding aspects related to the neutrino sector of the F D -term hybrid model. The F D -term hybrid model contains a 3 × 3 Majorana mass matrix M S , which is SO(3) symmetric at the gauge-coupling unification point M X = M ≈ 10 16 GeV, i.e. M S = m N 1 3 . The parameter m N = ρv S is a universal Majorana mass whose natural value is of the order of the soft SUSY-breaking or the electroweak scale, i.e. m N ∼ M SUSY or m t . The SO(3) symmetry of the heavy neutrino sector is broken explicitly by the Yukawa neutrino couplings h ν ij . In order to explain the low-energy light neutrino data, the breaking of the SO(3) symmetry should proceed via an intermediate step, namely SO(3) should first break into its subgroup SO(2) ≃ U(1) l . This can be achieved by coupling all lepton doublets L e,µ,τ to the linear combination:</p>

				<p><formula>1 √ 2</formula></p>

				<p>(ν 2R + iν 3R ). These Yukawa couplings could be as large as the τ -Yukawa coupling h τ , i.e. h</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ν i2 = ih ν i3 ∼ 10</trash>

					<figDesc>−2 . As a consequence of the U(1) l symmetry, the resulting light neutrino mass matrix m ν vanishes identically to all orders in perturbation theory. The remaining U(1) l symmetry can be broken by smaller Yukawa couplings of the order of the electron Yukawa coupling h e , i.e. h</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>ν i1 = ε i ∼ 10 −6 –10 −7 , which arise when one couples L e,µ,τ to ν 1R [29].</p>

				<p>Further breaking of the U(1) l symmetry is induced in the heavy-neutrino sector by renormalization-group and threshold effects while running M S from M to m t [30]. Thus, M S will generically modify to: M S = m N 1 3 +∆M S , where one typically has (∆M S ) ij /m N ∼ 10 −5 –10 −7 . Taking the effect of U(1) l -breaking parameters (∆M S ) ij and ε i into account, one obtains a light neutrino mass matrix which can comfortably accommodate the lowenergy light neutrino data, e.g. with an inverted hierarchical light neutrino spectrum [10]. On the other hand, the heavy neutrino sector of the F D -term hybrid model consists of 3 nearly degenerate heavy Majorana neutrinos N 1,2,3 of mass m N 1,2,3 ≈ m N , which can give rise to successful baryogenesis through thermal electroweak-scale resonant leptogenesis [29]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have studied F -term hybrid inflation in a novel supersymmetric extension of the SM, to which a subdominant FI D-term was added. We called this particular form of inflation F D -term hybrid inflation. The F D -term hybrid model we have been analyzing in this paper ties the µ-parameter of the MSSM to an SO(3) symmetric Majorana mass m N , through the VEV of the inflaton field. As a consequence, the model predicts naturally lepton-number violation at the electroweak scale.</p>

				<p>In order to obtain predictions for the observables P</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1/2</head>

				<p>R , n s and η B compatible with global cosmological analyses [4], as well as interesting particle-physics phenomenology that could be tested in laboratory experiments, one needs to make certain assumptions for the model of F D -term hybrid inflation: (i) Successful hybrid inflation relies on the assumption that the inflaton field is displaced from its minimum in the beginning of inflation, whereas all other non-inflaton fields have zero VEVs, according to (2.7).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(ii)</head>

				<p>The present F D -term hybrid scenario utilizes a minimal Kähler potential, where terms of order H 2 |S| 2 in the potential are set to zero or assumed to be negligible. This consideration introduces some tuning in general SUGRA models with non-minimal Kähler potentials. (iii) In order to get a red-tilted spectrum with negative n s − 1, one has to assume that the radiative corrections dominate the slope of the inflationary potential. This possibility arises for superpotential couplings:</p>

				<p><formula>10 −4 &lt; ∼ κ, λ, ρ &lt; ∼ 10 −2 .</formula></p>

				<p>(iv) Even though a bare D-tadpole may be present as a bare parameter in the tree-level Lagrangian, we have considered here, however, the possibility that such a term is generated radiatively after heavy degrees of freedom have been integrated out. These heavy degrees of freedom are assumed to be Planck-mass chiral superfields which are oppositely charged under the U(1) X and which break explicitly the discrete charge symmetry discussed after (3.6) and in Appendix A. (v) We have assumed that the coupling ρ of the inflaton to neutrino superfields is SO(3) symmetric or very close to it. After the inflaton receives a VEV, one ends up with 3 nearly degenerate heavy Majorana neutrinos with masses at the electroweak scale. This enables one to successfully address the BAU within the thermal electroweak-scale resonant leptogenesis framework (see our discussion in Section 5). As has also been discussed in Section 5, if one assumes that the neutrino-Yukawa couplings h ν ij have a certain hierarchical structure controlled by the approximate breaking of global flavour symmetries, the model can have further testable implications for e + e − colliders and low-energy experiments of lepton flavour and/or number violation.</p>

				<p>The requirement for a sufficiently low reheat temperature T reh &lt; ∼ 10 9 GeV, which does not lead to overproduction of gravitinos, provides an important constraint on the basic theoretical parameters κ, λ and ρ. The naive limits on these couplings derived from reheating due to perturbative inflaton decay are very strict, i.e. κ, λ, ρ &lt; ∼ 10 −5 . These limits may be completely avoided by considering the late decays of the U(1) X gauge-sector particles which are induced by a non-vanishing FI D-term m 2 FI . Their decay rates depend crucially on m 2 FI . As menioned above in point (iv) and in Appendix A, the generation of a FI D-tadpole and its size may be engineered by adding Planck-scale heavy degrees of freedom to the theory and by subjecting these into extended R symmetries. In this way, a phase of second reheating takes place in the evolution of the early Universe, which can lead to a significant lowering of the reheat temperature even up to 1 TeV.</p>

				<p>The F D -term hybrid model with electroweak-scale lepton number violation can easily be embedded within a minimal SUGRA theory, where all soft SUSY-breaking parameters are constrained at the gauge coupling unification point M X which can be chosen to be M ≈ 10 16 GeV. Instead, electroweak baryogenesis is not viable in a minimal SUGRA scenario of the MSSM. Moreover, the CP-odd soft SUSY-breaking phases required for successful electroweak baryogenesis face severe constraints from the non-observation of the electron and neutron electric dipole moments, even though the latter arise diagrammatically at the 2-loop level [31].</p>

				<p>The F D -term hybrid model under discussion conserves R-parity. The reason is that all superpotential couplings either conserve the B − L number or break it by even number of units. Specifically, the operator S N i N i breaks explicitly L, as well as B − L, by 2 units. Consequently, the lightest supersymmetric particle (LSP) of the spectrum is expected to be stable, thus providing a viable candidate to address the so-called Cold Dark Matter (CDM) problem. The new aspect of our model is that right-handed sneutrinos could be the LSPs, opening up new possibilities in the phenomenology of CDM and its detection.</p>

				<p>From the particle-physics point of view and in the low-energy limit where the waterfall sector has decoupled and the ρ-coupling neglected for simplicity, the F D -term hybrid model becomes identical to the so-called Minimal Nonminimal Supersymmetric Standard Model (MNSSM) in the decoupling limit of a large tadpole [32]. In particular, in the framework of WHI discussed in Section 4, the coupling λ can be sizeable, i.e. λ ∼ 0.6. In this case, the Higgs phenomenology of the MSSM will modify drastically, despite the decoupling of the singlet Higgs states. One striking possibility in the MNSSM is that the charged Higgs boson H + could be lighter than the SM-like Higgs boson [33], thus pointing to particular collider phenomenologies [34]. However, even within the traditional scenario of CHI, where κ, λ &lt; ∼ 10 −2 , the F D -term hybrid model will favour particular benchmark scenarios of the MSSM. For example, if λ ≫ κ, the F D -term hybrid model may account for a possible large value of the µ-parameter. Specifically, if λ = 4κ, one gets from (2.10) the hierarchy µ ≈ 4M SUSY , which is the so-called CPX benchmark scenario [35] describing maximal CP violation in the MSSM Higgs sector at low and moderate values of tan β.</p>

				<p>A possible natural solution to the famous cosmological constant problem is expected to provide further constraints on the model building of cosmologically viable models in future. Nevertheless, the F D -term hybrid model presented in this paper constitutes a first attempt towards the formulation of a minimal Particle-Physics and Cosmology Standard Model, whose validity could, in principle, be tested in laboratory experiments and further vindicated by astronomical observations.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>A D–Term Engineering</head>

				<p>The generation and the size of a D-term may be engineered by adding Planck-scale heavy degrees of freedom to the theory and by subjecting these into extended R symmetries.</p>

				<p>To elucidate our point, let us first consider a model augmented by a pair of oppositely charged superfields</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X 1,2 , with U(1) X charges: Q( X 2 ) = −Q( X 1 ) = Q( X 1 ) = −Q( X 2 ) = 1. The extended superpotential W of our interest is W = κ S X 1 X 2 − M 2 + ξ m Pl X 1 X 2 + ξ 1 ( X 1 X 1 ) 2 2 m Pl + ξ ′ 1 ( X 2 X 2 ) 2 2 m Pl . (A.1)</trash>

					<figDesc>This form of the superpotential may be enforced by the R symmetry:</figDesc>
					<trash>S → e iα S, X 1,2 → e ±iβ X 1,2 , X 1,2 → e i( a 2 ∓β) X 1,2 , L → e iα L, Q → e iα</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Q, with W → e iα W . As before, all remaining fields are considered to be neutral under the R symmetry. Notice that the same R-symmetry allows for the operator κ</figDesc>
					<trash>′ S( X 1 X 2 ) 2 /m 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Pl . The presence of this superpotential term can trigger shifted hybrid inflation, where the gauge symmetry U(1) X is broken along the inflationary trajectory, thereby inflating away unwanted topological defects [36].</p>

				<p>A D-term will now be generated after integrating out the Planck-scale superfields</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X 1,2 . The loop-induced D-tadpole m 2 FI is found to be m 2 FI ≈ ξ 2 1 − ξ ′2 1 8π 2 M 4 m 2 Pl ln m Pl M . (A.2) For M = 10 16 GeV, we find that m FI /M &lt; ∼ 10 −3 , for ξ 1 , ξ ′ 1 &lt; ∼ 0.3. Observe that if ξ 1 = ξ ′ 1</trash>

					<figDesc>, the discrete charge symmetry discussed after (3.6) gets restored again and m FI vanishes identically.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The size of the D-term may be suppressed further, if the Planck-mass chiral superfields X 1,2 possess higher U(1) X charges. In general, one may assume that the U</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1) X charges of X 1,2 are: Q( X 2 ) = −Q( X 1 ) = n, where n ≥ 1. In addition, we require for X 1,2 to transform under U(1) R as follows: X 1,2 → e i 2 [a ∓ (n+1)β] X 1,2 , (A.3) while S, X 1,2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and all other fields transform as before. With this symmetry restriction, the superpotential reads:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>W = κ S X 1 X 2 − M 2 + ξ m Pl X 1 X 2 + ξ n ( X 1 ) 2 ( X 1 ) n+1 2 m n Pl + ξ ′ n ( X 2 ) 2 ( X 2 ) n+1 2 m n Pl . (A.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this case, the loop-induced D-term is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m 2 FI ≈ ξ 2 n − ξ ′2 n 8π 2 M 2(n+1) m 2n Pl ln m Pl M . (A.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To obtain a small ratio m FI /M ∼ 10 −6 , with ξ n , ξ ′ n ∼ 1, one would need n = 5, 6. Finally, it is important to remark that the loop-induced D-term does not lead to spontaneous breakdown of global supersymmetry.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Observe that an analogous discrete charge symmetry also survives after SSB in the so-called D-term inflationary model [9], where M = 0 and m FI = 0. In this case, the waterfall fields X 1,2 transform as X 1,2 → ±X 1,2 , while their VEVs after inflation are X 1 = m FI and X 2 = 0.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> A detailed calculation based on a two-particle irreducible effective action in an expanding deSitter background metric would be highly preferable.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgements</head>
				<p>We thank Arjun Berera, Rudnei Ramos and Antonio Riotto for useful discussions. We also thank Constantine Pallis for collaboration in the early stages of this project. AP dedicates this work to the memory of Darwin Chang, an invaluable friend and collaborator. This work is supported in part by the PPARC research grants: PPA/G/O/2002/00471 and PP/C504286/1.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">See</forename>
				<surname>For Reviews</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Lyth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Riotto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rept</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Spergel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">175</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tegmark</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<surname>Seljak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103515</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Linde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">259</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">38</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Copeland</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Liddle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Lyth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Stewart</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Wands</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6410</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Dvali</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Q</forename>
				<surname>Shafi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Schaefer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1886</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Fayet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Iliopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">461</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Halyo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>223</editor>
		<editor>P. Biné and G. Dvali</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">387</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">388</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">241</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E J</forename>
				<surname>Underwood</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>φ, see, F. Borzumati and Y. Nomura 053005</editor>
		<editor>N. Arkani-Hamed, L. J. Hall, H. Murayama, D. R. Smith and N. Weiner S. Dar, S. Huber, V.N. Senoguz and Q. Shafi</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">077701</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Fukugita</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Yanagida</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">174</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Davidson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Ibarra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Buchmuller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Di</forename>
				<surname>Bari</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Plumacher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Branco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Gonzalez Felipe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Joaquim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Masina</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Rebelo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Savoy</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Nucl. Phys. B Phys. Rev. D Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<editor>073035</editor>
		<editor>G. F. Giudice, A. Notari, M. Raidal, A. Riotto and A. Strumia</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">535</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">89</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E J T</forename>
				<surname>Underwood</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hambye</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>March-Russell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>West</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Nucl. Phys. B JHEP Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>E. J. Chun</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">095010</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>070. ; A. Pilaftsis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Senoguz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Q</forename>
				<surname>Shafi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">043514</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Panagiotakopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1841</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>063516. . [17] A. D. Linde and A. Riotto</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>See</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Dvali</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Q</forename>
				<surname>Lazarides</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Shafi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>259</editor>
		<editor>S. F. King and Q. Shafi</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">424</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">135</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Nanopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J R</forename>
				<surname>Sarkar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Gelmini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Lopez</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Nanopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sarkar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B Nucl. Phys. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>M. Fujii, M. Ibe and T. Yanagida</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25920</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Traschen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H L</forename>
				<surname>Brandenberger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Kofman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Linde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J H</forename>
				<surname>Starobinsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Chung</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Kolb</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">I</forename>
				<surname>Riotto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Tkachev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Garbrecht</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Prokopec</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Schmidt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D Eur. Phys. J. C Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">91</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>135. ; J. Berges and J. Serreau</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prokopec, arXiv:hep-ph/9708428</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Prokopec</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Roos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Felder</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Garcia-Bellido</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Greene</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Kofman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Linde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Tkachev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>J. Garcia-Bellido and E. Ruiz Morales</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">193</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pallis and A. Pilaftsis, work in progress</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Garbrecht</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Berera</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">O</forename>
				<surname>Berera</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ramos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>103509</editor>
		<editor>L. M. H. Hall, I. G. Moss and A. Berera</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">023513</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>083525. ; A. Berera and R. O. Ramos</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Bastero-Gil</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Berera</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Carena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Quiros</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Seco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E M T</forename>
				<surname>Wagner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Konstandin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Prokopec</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Schmidt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Carena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Megevand</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E M</forename>
				<surname>Quiros</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Wagner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Seco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Postma, JHEP 0505 (2005) 071. [26] For recent analyses, see</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="0505103" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Buchmuller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Greub</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>345</editor>
		<editor>G. Cvetic, C. S. Kim and C. W. Kim 4761</editor>
		<editor>F. del Aguila, J. A. Aguilar-Saavedra, A. Martinez de la Ossa and D. Meloni F. del Aguila and J. A. Aguilar-Saavedra 026</editor>
		<editor>S. Bray, J. S. Lee and A. Pilaftsis</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">363</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">250</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">See</forename>
				<surname>Studies</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Fujihara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Kang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kimura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Morozumi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Deppisch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W F</forename>
				<surname>Kosmas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Valle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="ph see" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>29. ] For more details</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Gonzalez Felipe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Joaquim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Nobre</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>085009</editor>
		<editor>G. C. Branco, R. Gonzalez Felipe, F. R. Joaquim and B. M. Nobre</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0507092</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Chang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
				<surname>Keung</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Nucl. Phys. B Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>263</editor>
		<editor>D. Chang, W. F. Chang and W. Y. Keung</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">116008</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>900. ; A. Pilaftsis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Panagiotakopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">055003</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Panagiotakopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">505</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">184</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Ghosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Godbole</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Roy</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">628</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">131</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Carena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E M</forename>
				<surname>Wagner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">495</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">155</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Jeannerot</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Khalil</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Lazarides</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Q</forename>
				<surname>Shafi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">012</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
