<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">QCD Corrections to Dilepton Production near Partonic Threshold in ¯ pp Scattering *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2006-01-31">31 Jan 2006</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">H</forename>
								<surname>Shimizu</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Hiroshima University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>739-8526</postCode>
									<settlement>Higashi-Hiroshima</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Stony Brook University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>11794 – 3840</postCode>
									<settlement>Stony Brook</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
									<country key="US">U.S.A</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">G</forename>
								<surname>Sterman</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">W</forename>
								<surname>Vogelsang</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Physics Department and RIKEN-BNL Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brookhaven National Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>11973</postCode>
									<settlement>Upton</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
									<country key="US">U.S.A</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">H</forename>
								<surname>Yokoya</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Niigata University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>950-2181</postCode>
									<settlement>Niigata</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">C</forename>
								<forename type="middle">N</forename>
								<surname>Yang</surname>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">QCD Corrections to Dilepton Production near Partonic Threshold in ¯ pp Scattering *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2006-01-31">31 Jan 2006</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>BNL-NT-06/7</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a recent study of the QCD corrections to dilepton production near partonic threshold in transversely polarized ¯ pp scattering. We analyze the role of the higher-order perturbative QCD corrections in terms of the available fixed-order contributions as well as of all-order soft-gluon resummations for the kinematical regime of proposed experiments at GSI-FAIR. We find that perturbative corrections are large for both unpolarized and polarized cross sections, but that the spin asymmetries are stable. The role of the far infrared region of the momentum integral in the resummed exponent and the effect of the NNLL resummation are briefly discussed.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>A polarized antiproton beam of energy E ¯ p = 15 − 22 GeV may be available in future experiments at the GSI-FAIR project. Measurements of dilepton production in transversely polarized ¯ pp collisions are the main motivation for the proposed GSI-PAX [1] and GSI-ASSIA [2] experiments . The measurements would be carried out using a transversely polarized fixed proton target, or a proton beam of moderate energy E p =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3.5 GeV. Measurements of the transverse double-spin asymmetry A T T ≡ δσ σ = σ ↑↑ − σ ↑↓ σ ↑↑ + σ ↑↓ , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>defined as the ratio of transversely polarized and unpolarized cross sections, may provide information of the transversely polarized parton distribution functions of the proton, dubbed &quot; transversity &quot; δf [3,4]. Transversity will be probed by * Presented by H. Yokoya at the &quot; 7th International Symposium on Radiative Corrections (RADCOR 2005) &quot; , October 2-7, 2005, Shonan Village, Japan measurements of A T T in polarized pp collisions at the BNL-RHIC collider [5]. However, since the δf for sea quarks are expected to be small, the asymmetry is estimated to be at most a few percent [6].</p>

				<p>In contrast, since for the Drell-Yan process in ¯ pp collisions the scattering of two valence quark densities contributes, and since in addition the kinematical regime of the planned GSI experiments is such that rather large parton momentum fractions x ∼ 0.5 are relevant, a very large A T T of order 40% or more is expected [7,8,9]. Therefore, unique information on transversity in the valence region may be obtained from the GSI measurements , and information from RHIC and the GSI would be complementary. Here we give a brief report on a recent study of perturbative-QCD corrections to the cross sections and to A T T for Drell-Yan dilepton production at GSI-FAIR [8]. We discuss the available fixed order corrections as well as all-order softgluon &quot; threshold &quot; resummation.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">2. DRELL-YAN CROSS SECTIONS</head>

				<p>By virtue of the factorization theorem, the cross section for the Drell-Yan process at large lepton pair invariant mass M can be written in terms of a convolution of parton distribution functions and partonic scattering cross sections:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d(δ)σ dM 2 dφ = a,b 1 τ dx a (δ)f a (x a , µ 2 ) (2) × 1 τ /xa dx b (δ)f b (x b , µ 2 ) d(δ)ˆ σ ab dM 2 dφ + O λ M p , where τ = M 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>/S with S the hadronic c.m. energy , and where φ is the azimuthal angle of one of the leptons. µ is the factorization scale. As indicated in Eq. (2), there are corrections suppressed with some power p and some hadronic scale λ. These corrections will become important for small M and in particular for lower-energy collisions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.1">Fixed-order perturbative calculation</head>

				<p>The partonic cross section is calculated in QCD perturbation theory as a series in α s ;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d(δ)ˆ σ ab dM 2 dφ = (δ)ˆ σ (0) ab ω (0) ab (z) + α s π (δ)ω (1) ab (z, r) + α s π 2 (δ)ω (2) ab (z, r) + . . . , (3) where z = M 2 /ˆ s, ˆ s = x a x b S and r = M 2 /µ 2 . For the unpolarized cross section the calculation has been performed up to O(α 2 s ) [10]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, for the transversely polarized case to O(α s ) [11]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. The lowest order gives ˆ σ (0) q ¯ q = 2α 2 e 2 q 9M 2 ˆ s , δê 2 q 9M 2 ˆ s cos 2φ (4) with ω (0) q ¯ q = δ(1 − z</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). The higher-order functions may be found in the literature [10,11].</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Threshold resummation</head>

				<p>Threshold resummation addresses large logarithmic perturbative corrections to the partonic cross section that arise when the initial partons have just enough energy to produce the lepton pair. Only emission of relatively soft gluons is allowed in this case. The large corrections exponentiate when Mellin moments of the partonic cross section, defined as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(δ)ω (k),N q ¯ q (r) = 1 0 dz z N −1 (δ)ω (k) q ¯ q (z, r) , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are taken. To next-to-leading logarithmic (NLL) accuracy one then has for the resummed cross section [12,13]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(δ)ω res,N q ¯ q (r, α s (µ)) = exp [C q (r, α s (µ))] (6) × exp 2 1 0 dz z N −1 − 1 1 − z × (1−z) 2 M 2 µ 2 dk 2 T k 2 T A q (α s (k T )) , where A q (α s ) = α s π A (1) q + α s π 2 A (2) q + . . . , (7) with A (1) q = C F and [14]: A (2) q = C F 2 C A 67 18 − π 2 6 − 5 9 N f , (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where N f is the number of flavors and C A = 3. The coefficient C q (r, α s (µ)) collects mostly hard virtual corrections. It is given as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C q (r, α s ) = α s π −4 + 2π 2 3 + 3 2 ln r + O(α 2 s ). (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We note that it was shown in [15] that these coefficient functions also exponentiate. Eq. (6) is ill-defined because of the divergence in the perturbative running coupling α s (k T ) at k T = Λ QCD . The perturbative expansion of the expression shows factorial divergence, which in QCD corresponds to a power-like ambiguity of the series. It turns out, however, that the factorial divergence appears only at nonleading powers of momentum transfer. The large logarithms we are resumming arise in the region [13]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>z ≤ 1 − 1/ ¯ N in the integrand in Eq. (6). Therefore to NLL they are contained in the simpler expression 2 M 2 M 2 / ¯ N 2 dk 2 T k 2 T A q (α s (k T )) ln ¯ Nk T M (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for the second exponent in (6). Here we have chosen µ = M . This form, to which we will return below, is used for &quot; minimal &quot; expansions [16] of the resummed exponent. For the NLL expansion of the resummed exponent one finds from Eqs. (6),(10) [16]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>: ln δω res,N q ¯ q (r, α s (µ)) = C q (r, α s (µ)) (11) +2 ln ¯ N h (1) (λ) + 2h (2) (λ, r) , where λ = b 0 α s (µ) ln ¯ N . (12)</trash>

					<figDesc>The explicit expressions for the functions h (1) and h (2) can be found e.g. in Refs. [16,8]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The hadronic cross section is obtained by performing an inverse Mellin transformation of the resummed partonic cross section, multiplied by the appropriate moments of two parton densities:</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>d(δ)σ res dM 2 dφ = C dN 2πi τ −N × ab (δ)f N a (δ)f N b d(δ)ˆ σ res,N ab dM 2 dφ . (13)</formula></p>

				<p>In order to perform the inverse Mellin integral, we need to specify a prescription for dealing with the singularity in the perturbative strong coupling constant in Eq. (6). We will use the minimal prescription developed in Ref. [16], which relies on use of the NLL expanded form involving the h i (λ), and on choosing a contour to the left of the Landau singularity at λ = 1/2 in the complex-N plane. Figure 1 shows the effects of the higher orders generated by resummation for S = 30 GeV 2 and S = 210 GeV 2 . We define a resummed &quot; Kfactor &quot; as the ratio of the resummed cross section to the leading order (LO) cross section,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>K (res) = dσ (res) /dM dφ dσ (LO) /dM dφ , (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is shown by the solid line in Fig. 1. As can be seen, K (res) is very large, meaning that resummation results in a dramatic enhancement over LO, sometimes by over two orders of magnitude for the collisions at lower energy. It is then interesting to see how this enhancement builds</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 M (GeV) 10 0 10 1 10 2 10 3 σ / σ LO NLO NNLO full resummed 1st order expansion 2nd 3rd 4th 6th 8th 2 4 6 8 10 12 M (GeV) 10 0 10 1 σ / σ LO NLO NNLO full resummed 1st order expansion 2nd 3rd 4th 6th 8th</trash>

					<head>Figure 1.</head>

					<figDesc>K-factors as defined in Eqs. (14), (15) for the Drell-Yan cross section as a function of lepton invariant mass M , in ¯ pp collision with S = 30 GeV 2 (left), and S = 210 GeV 2 (right).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>up order by order in perturbation theory. We expand the resummed formula to next-to-leading order (NLO) and beyond and define the &quot;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>gluon K-factors &quot; K n ≡ dσ (res) /dM dφ O(α n s ) dσ (LO) /dM dφ , (15)</trash>

					<figDesc>which for n = 1, 2, . . . give the effects due to the O(α n s ) terms in the resummed formula. The results for K 1−8 are also shown in Fig. 1</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. One can see that there are very large contributions even beyond NNLO, in particular at the higher M .</p>

				<p>Clearly, the full resummation given by the solid line receives contributions from high orders. We stress that the O(α s ) and O(α 2 s ) expansions of the resummed result are in excellent agreement with the full NLO and NNLO ones, respectively (circle and square symbols in Figure 1). This shows that the higher-order corrections are really dominated by the threshold logarithms and that the resummation is accurately collecting the latter. 2.3. Far infrared cut-off There is good reason to believe that the large enhancement from soft-gluon radiation seen above is only partly physical. The large corrections arise from a region where the integral in the exponent becomes sensitive to the behavior of the integrand at small values of k T . As long as Λ QCD ≪ M/ ¯ N ≪ M , the use of perturbation theory may be justified, but when |N | becomes very large, k T will reach down to nonperturbative scales. We seek a modification of the perturbative expression in Eq. (6) that excludes the region in which the absolute value of k T is less than some nonperturbative scale µ 0 . To implement this idea, we will adopt a modified resummed hard scattering, which reproduces NLL logarithmic behavior in the moment variable N so long as M/ ¯ N &gt; µ 0 , but &quot; freezes &quot; once M/ ¯ N &lt; µ 0 . If nothing else, this will test the importance of the region k T ≤ Λ QCD for the resummed cross section . If N were real and positive, we could simply replace the resummed exponent in (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>10) by 4 M ρ(M/ ¯ N , µ0) dk T k T A q (α s (k T )) ln ¯ Nk T M , (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ρ(a, b) = max(a, b), and where µ 0 then serves to cut off the lower logarithmic behavior . To provide an expression that can be analytically continued to complex N , we choose ρ(a, b) = (a p + b p ) 1/p , with integer p. This simple form is consistent with the minimal expansion given above, and it also allows for a straightforward analysis of the ensuing branch cuts in the complex-N plane. For definiteness, we choose p = 2. We will continue to use the expansions in Eq. (11), but redefine λ in</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eq. (12) by λ = b 0 α s (µ) ln ¯ N − 1 2 b 0 α s (µ) ln 1+ ¯ N 2 µ 2 0 M 2 . (17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Of course, different choices of µ 0 give different results, but we should think of µ 0 as a kind of factorization scale, separating perturbative contributions from nonperturbative. Thus changes in µ 0 would be compensated by changes in a nonperturbative function. Our interest here, however , is simply to illustrate the modification of the perturbative sector, which we do by choosing µ 0 = 0.3 GeV and µ = 0.4 GeV.</p>

				<p>Results for the &quot; K-factor &quot; with these values of µ 0 are shown in Fig. 2, compared to the same NLO, NNLO and resummed cross sections as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 M (GeV) 10 0 10 1 10 2 10 3 σ / σ LO res. (µ 0 =0) res. (µ 0 =0.3 GeV) res. (µ 0 =0.4 GeV) NLO NNLO 4 6 8 10 12 M (GeV) 10 0 10 1 σ / σ LO res. (µ 0 =0) res. (µ 0 =0.3 GeV) res. (µ 0 =0.4 GeV) NLO NNLO</trash>

					<head>Figure 2.</head>

					<figDesc>K-factors as in Fig. 1</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, at S = 30 GeV</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>(left) and S = 210 GeV 2 (right). The dashed (dot-dashed) lines show the effects of a lower cutoff µ 0 = 300 MeV (400 MeV) for the k T integral in the exponent. presented before. The ratios of the infraredregulated resummed cross sections to LO show a smoother increase than the &quot; purely minimally &quot; resummed ones. The difference is particularly marked at the lower center of mass energy in Fig. 2 (left), with only a modest enhancement over NNLO remaining. We interpret these results to indicate a strong sensitivity to nonperturbative dynamics at the lower energies, and much less at the higher.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">SPIN ASYMMETRY</head>

				<p>A T T</p>

				<p>To perform numerical studies of the asymmetry A T T we need to make a model for the transversity densities in the valence region. Here, guidance is provided by the Soffer inequality [17]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 δq(x, Q 2 ) ≤ q(x, Q 2 ) + ∆q(x, Q 2 ) , (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which gives an upper bound for each δq. Following [6] we utilize this inequality by saturating the bound at some low input scale Q 0 ≃ 0.6 GeV using the NLO GRV [18] and GRSV ( &quot; standard scenario &quot; ) [19]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>densities q(x, Q 2 0 ) and ∆q(x, Q 2 0 ), respectively. For Q &gt; Q 0 the transversity densities δq(x, Q 2</trash>

					<figDesc>) are then obtained using the NLO evolution equations [11]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Figure 3 shows that A T T is very robust under the QCD corrections, including resummation with and without a cutoff. This is expected to some extent because the emission of soft-gluons does not change the spin of the parent parton.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 M (GeV) 0.2 0.25 0.3 0.35 0.4 A TT LO NLO pert. resummed µ 0 =0.3 GeV 2 4 6 8 10 12 M (GeV) 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 A TT LO NLO pert. resummed µ 0 =0.3GeV Figure 3. Spin asymmetry A T T (φ = 0) at LO, NLO and for the NLL-resummed case at S = 30 GeV 2 (left) and S = 210 GeV 2 (right). 4. NNLL RESUMMATION Thanks to the recent calculation of the threeloop splitting functions by Moch, Vermaseren and 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 M (GeV) 10 -4 10 -3 10 -2 10 -1 10 0 10 1 10 2 10 3 10 4 M 3 dσ/dM (pb GeV 2 ) LO NLO NNLO NLL NNLL 2 4 6 8 10 12 M (GeV) 10 -2 10 -1 10 0 10 1 10 2 10 3 10 4 10 5 M 3 dσ/dM (pb GeV 2 ) LO NLO NNLO NLL NNLL Figure 4. Unpolarized cross section M 3 dσ/dM at S = 30 GeV 2 (left) and S = 210 GeV 2 (right) at LO, NLO, NNLO</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, and NLL-, NNLL-resummed, as function of lepton pair invariant mass M .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Vogt [20]</head>

				<p>, we can now perform the threshold resummation for the Drell-Yan process to NNLL accuracy. This leads to a new term in the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>nent in Eq. (11): ln δω res,N q ¯ q (r, α s (µ)) = C q (r, α s (µ)) +2 ln ¯ N h (1) (λ) + 2h (2) (λ, r) +2α s (µ)h (3) (λ, r) , (19) where h (3) includes the new A (3) q and D (2) DY coefficients [21,22]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, and where an additional C (2) q term is included in the coefficient function, which may be extracted [23] from the known [10] NNLO results for the Drell-Yan process. The effects of NNLL resummation on the unpolarized cross section are displayed in Fig. 4. One finds that the resummed cross section has a fast convergence, even at the lower energy.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">SUMMARY</head>

				<p>We have studied the perturbative QCD corrections to Drell-Yan dilepton production in transversely polarized ¯ pp collisions for the kinematical regime of proposed experiments at GSI-FAIR. We find that the K-factor for the available fixed-order corrections, and for the all-order NLL soft-gluon resummation, can be very large. In contrast, the spin asymmetry is quite stable. We have highlighted the importance of rather small momentum scales in the resummed exponent at the lower energies . We have also examined the resummation to NNLL and found it to give a rather modest correction.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>The work of G.S. was supported in part by the National Science Foundation, grants PHY-0098527, PHY-0354776, and PHY-0354822. W.V. is grateful to RIKEN, BNL and the U.S. Department of Energy (contract number DE-AC02- 98CH10886) for providing the facilities essential for the completion of his work. The work of H.Y. was supported in part by a Research Fellowship of the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Barone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PAX Collaboration]</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Maggiora</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ASSIA Collaboration]</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Ralston</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Soper</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">152</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">109</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Jaffe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Ji</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">527</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>See</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Bunce</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Rev. Nucl. Part. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">525</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Martin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">117502</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Anselmino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Eur. Phys. J. C Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>8. H. Shimizu, G. Sterman, W. Vogelsang and H. Yokoya</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">594</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">114007</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">arXiv:hep-ph/0512121</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Barone</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>A. Bianconi and M. Radici</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">074013</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Hamberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Van Neerven</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Matsuura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. BErratum-ibid. B Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>R. V. Harlander and W. B. Kilgore</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">359</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">88</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Vogelsang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">1886. 12. G. Sterman</title>
		<editor>310. 13. S. Catani and L. Trentadue</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="353" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kodaira</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Trentadue</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>15. T. O. Eynck, E. Laenen and L. Magnea</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">335</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0306" to="057" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Catani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Mangano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nason</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Trentadue</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">478</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">273</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Soffer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Eur. Phys. J</title>
		<editor>1292. 18. M. Glü, E. Reya, and A. Vogt</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="461" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Glü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Reya</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Stratmann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Vo-Gelsang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">094005</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A M</forename>
				<surname>Vermaseren</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Vogt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">688</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">691</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Vogt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">497</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">228</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Catani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>De Florian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Grazzini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nason</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0307" to="028" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Vogt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">631</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">48</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
