<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2007-03-26">26 Mar 2007</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">L</forename>
								<forename type="middle">L</forename>
								<surname>Zhu</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Particle Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Hua-Zhong Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>430079</postCode>
									<settlement>Wuhan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P.R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">C</forename>
								<forename type="middle">B</forename>
								<surname>Yang</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Particle Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Hua-Zhong Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>430079</postCode>
									<settlement>Wuhan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P.R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2007-03-26">26 Mar 2007</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Universal Scaling of p T Distribution of Particles in Relativistic Nuclear Collisions</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">PACS numbers: 2575Dw</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>With the experimental data from STAR, PHENIX and BRAHMS on the centrality and rapidity dependence of the pT spectrum in Au+Au and d+Au collisions, we show that there exists a scaling distribution which is independent of the colliding system, centrality and rapidity. The parameter for the average transverse momentum pT increases from peripheral to central d+Au collisions. This increase accounts for the enhancement of particle production in those collisions. A non-extensive entropy is used to derive the scaling function.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>dp 3 for a given species of particles depends on the collision centrality β, (pseudo)rapidity y (or η) and the transverse momentum p T . When we focus on the particle production in a collision with given centrality in a small rapidity region around y, we should distinguish two different factors . One is the number density dN/dy in rapidity, which tells us how many particles are produced in the region. The other is the probability for a produced particle having transverse momentum p T . It is this probability that dictates the shape of the transverse momentum distri- butions.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we are interested only in such a</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 10 −7 10 −6 10 −5 10 −4 10 −3 10 −2 10 −1 10 0 10 1 BRAHMS(200 GeV) h − Au+Au η=2.6 η=3.2 0−10% 10−20% 20−40% 40−60% u Ψ(u) FIG. 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: Scaling distribution Ψ(u) showing the coalescence of four rapidity bins in the BRAHMS data for h − production at η = 2.6 and 3.2 in Au+Au collisions. The data points are taken from Fig.1 in [4]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>probability which can be defined as Φ(p T , y, β) ≡ 2π E d 3 N dp 3 dN dy , (1) where dN dy = 2π E d 3 N dp</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>3 p T dp T is the multiplicity of particles produced in a unit rapidity region. So Φ(p T , y, β) satisfies the normalization condition Φ(p T , y, β)p T dp T = 1 . (2)</p>

				<p>In the definition of Φ, the centrality and rapidity dependence is written explicitly. Experimental data show similar shape of the distributions for different centralities and rapidities. Because of the similarity in the shape, those distributions of pions produced in Au+Au collisions in the mid-rapidity region at difference centralities have been put together in [1] to the same curve by shrinking p T by a factor K and shifting the distribution by another factor A. Then a scaling variable is defined as u = p T /p T , and the normalized distribution is obtained as a function Ψ(u) = p T 2 Φ(p T u, y, β). Here the average transverse momentum is defined as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p T = Φ(p T , y, β)p 2 T dp T . (3) The scaling function reads Ψ(u) = 2.1 × 10 4 (u 2 + 11.65) −4.8 [1 + 25 exp(−1.864u)].(4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The obtained Ψ(u) is universal in the sense that it is independent of the centrality β at mid-rapidity in Au+Au collisions. Now we extend the discussion to the particle production in non-central rapidity region in Au+Au collisions at 200 GeV. For this purpose, we work on the experimental data [4] for negatively charged particles h − at large η with exactly the same procedures as in [1] and try to put all the data points to the curve for the scaling function Ψ(u). It turns out that the scaling function given by Eq. (4) can also describe the charged particle production at η =2.6 and 3.2 for different centralities, as can be seen in Fig. 1. The shrinking factor for p T is given in TABLE I. Fig.1 Fig. 2 Fig. 3</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(π − ) β(%) η = 2.6 η = 3.2 β(%) PHENIX β(%) y = 3 0-10 0.4340 0.3448 0-20 0.563 0-20 0.3228 10-20 0.4359 0.3452 20-40 0.572 30-50 0.3151 20-40 0.4363 0.3458 40-60 0.601 60-80 0.3108 40-60 0.4366 0.3462 60-88 0.601 TABLE I: Fitted parameter pT in the scaling distribution for Au+Au and d+Au collisions at √ sNN = 200 GeV, for different centralities and rapidities shown in Figs. (1-3).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The second observation in this paper is that the same scaling p T distribution can describe the p T distributions of charged particles produced in d+Au collisions [5] and π 0 data [6]in central rapidity region at different centralities , as shown in Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>. The fitted values of parameter p T for the PHENIX data are also tabulated in TABLE I. To investigate the rapidity dependence of the distribution in d+Au collisions, we take the data for π + and π at y = 3 for different centrality cuts [7]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>and try to put the data points to the obtained scaling curve with exactly the same procedure as mentioned above. The agreement is quite good, as shown in Fig. 3. The fitted values of the parameter p T are also given in TABLE I. Then we can conclude that the same scaling function can describe pion and charged particle production in both Au+Au and d+Au collisions at different centralities and rapidities . In this sense, we can say that the obtained scaling distribution is universal.</p>

				<p>To show the degree of agreement between the experimental data and the fitted results, we define B as the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 10 −7 10 −6 10 −5 10 −4 10 −3 10 −2 10 −1 10 0 10 1 d+Au STAR 0−20% 20−40% 40−100% PHENIX 0−20% 20−40% 40−60% 60−88% u Ψ(u) FIG. 2: Scaling distribution Ψ(u) showing</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the coalescence spectra from the STAR data for charged particle and from PHENIX π 0 data production in d+Au collisions at midrapidity . The data points are taken from [5, 6].</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 10 −7 10 −6 10 −5 10 −4 10 −3 10 −2 10 −1 10 0 10 1 BRAHMS(200 GeV) d+Au y=3 π + π − 0−20% 30−50% 60−80% u Ψ(u) FIG. 3:</trash>

					<figDesc>Scaling distribution Ψ(u) showing the coalescence of four centrality bins in the BRAHMS data for π − production in d+Au collisions at forward direction. The data points are taken from [7]. ratio of the data to the fitted results. For illustration, B, calculated from results in Fig. 3</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, as a function of u is shown in Fig.4. Obviously, values of B are very close to 1, indicating that the scaling of the produced pion spectrum is true with high accuracy. Once we have found a scaling law for the distributions for Au+Au and d+Au collisions for different centralities and rapidities, we need to dig out the physical implications behind the scaling behavior. From the scaling function Ψ(u), one can see that the only parameter characterizing the normalized distribution is the average transverse momentum p T which depends on the centrality, rapidity and the colliding energy and system. Once p T is known, both the soft part with low p T and the hard part with high p T are determined from Ψ(u).</p>

				<p>Traditionally it was assumed that the bulk of particles is produced by soft processes which determine p T . If the soft and hard processes can be separated, as used in</p>

				<p><formula>0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 0.8 0.9 1 1.1 1.2 u B</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 4: Ratio B of the experimental data and the fitted results , as shown in Fig. 3, for the pion production as forward direction. the two-component model [8], and each part has different dynamical origin, it is extremely hard to imagine that they can be united into a single scaling function. Thus, we conclude that the hard process must contribute considerably to the average p T and is a coherent part of particle production. In fact, we have known from the study of particle correlations in central Au+Au collisions at RHIC energies that the lost energy from hard partons must heat the medium and increase the mean transverse momentum. On the other hand, we have known from experiments that the particle production is suppressed, called jet quenching [9], in central Au+Au collisions because of the possible formation of dense hot medium but enhanced in d+Au collisions due to the Cronin effect [10], possibly because of the p T broadening from multiple soft collisions before a hard one [11], or from the recombination of soft partons with those from showers [12].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>One can show that the enhanced production in d+Au collisions can be accounted for from our fitted results that the mean transverse momentum p T increases from peripheral to central collisions. We can define a new variable Q CP to measure the suppression or enhancement from the scaling function Φ(p T , y, β) as</figDesc>
					<trash>Q CP = Φ(p T , y, β) C Φ(p T , y, β) P = Ψ(p T /p T )/p T 2 C (Ψ(p T /p T )/p T 2 ) P . (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>An advantage of this definition of Q CP over the traditional R CP is that it involves only the probability for a produced particle having certain transverse momentum and is independent of the total multiplicity. So the overall enhancement in the backward region (y &lt; 0) in d+Au collisions cannot be shown in Q CP . In calculating the value of Q CP we do not need to use the number of binary hard collisions, which is model dependent. Q CP is shown in Fig. 5 as a function of p T for d+Au collisions at midrapidity and it increases slowly to about 1.33. Thus the production of high p T pions is enhancement by about 30 percent. This is in agreement with experimental observations [13]. In this way the enhancement or suppression behavior can be shown clearly in a model independent way.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 2 4 6 8 10 0.9 1 1.1 1.2 1.3 1.4 d+Au 0−20%/40−100% p T (GeV) Q CP FIG. 5</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: QCP as a function of pT for d+Au collisions. The centrality cuts are 0-20% and 40-100%, respectively.</p>

				<p>Finally, we investigate nucleon-nucleon collisions at √ s = 200 GeV to see whether the particle spectrum can be described by the same scaling function. The experimental data on the p T distribution in the central rapidity region in p+p collisions can be parameterized [14]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>as dN p T dp T = A(a + p T ) −n , (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where A, a and n can be determined from fitting the data. It is astonishing that this parameterization for pion distribution in p+p collisions, with the parameters suitably chosen, can also be put to the scaling curve for Ψ(u) by shrinking horizontally and shifting vertically. As shown in Fig. 6 the π + spectrum in p+p collisions can be fitted to the scaling function. Then we come to our final conclusion that the same scaling function can be used, for different colliding systems at different centralities and rapidities, to give the probability for a produced particle having p T once the parameter p T for the average transverse momentum is known, thus the scaling function is universal. Since Ψ(u) is universal, the centrality and rapidity dependence in Φ(p T , y, β) is totally encoded in p T .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Straightforwardly, we can have p n T ≡ p n T Φ(p T , y, β)p T dp T = p T n ∞ 0 u n Ψ(u)udu . (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Therefore, the ratio p n T /p T n is a constant independent of the colliding system, the centrality, and rapidity. This consequence can be easily checked experimentally. For n = 2, 3 and 4, the ratio equals to 1.65, 4.08 and 14.39, respectively.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 2 4 6 8 10 10 −6 10 −5 10 −4 10 −3 10 −2 10 −1 10 0 10 1 π + (STAR) p+p (200 GeV) Eq. (4) Eq. (9) u Ψ(u) 0 2 4 6 8 10 0.9 1 1.1 u r</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>FIG. 6: Comparison between Ψ(u) from fitting the data and from the maximum entropy method. The insert gives the ratio between them. The points are π + distribution in p+p collisions taken from [15].</p>

				<p>We are now in a position to derive an expression for the particle distribution from some statistical consideration. One method is from the principle of maximum entropy. The scaling function is not an exponential form, therefore the well-known Shannon entropy cannot be used for our purpose. Instead, as suggested in [16], a non-extensive entropy may be used, considering the complex nonlinear interactions and the possible presence of fractal chaotic behavior in nuclear collisions, to derive an expression for the particle distribution. The entropy we will use here is the Tsallis entropy [17] which reads for our case</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S q = (1 − Φ q (p T )p T dp T )/(q − 1) , (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with parameter q as a measure of the non-extensiveness of the system. The maximum entropy under conditions demanded by Eqs. (2) and (3) gives, after the same shrinking and shifting as above,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ψ(u) = A(a + u) −n , (9) with n = 1/(1−q) and a = (n−3)/2, A = a n−2 (n−1)(n− 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). So there is one parameter q to determine the shape of the distribution. The functional form of Ψ(u) derived from the maximum entropy method is very different from that given by Eq. (4) but is the same as that used in parameterizing the p+p data. Then one can compare the distributions Ψ(u) from our fitting procedure and from the maximum entropy. As shown in Fig. 6, they agree with each other extremely well in a very wide range of u when n = 13.2. There in log scale one can hardly see any difference between them. Small difference can be seen if we show a ratio between them in a linear scale. As can be seen from the insert in Fig. 6 the largest difference is less than ten percent, though the distribution covers six orders of magnitudes in the shown range of u. This agreement indicates that the produced particle system, including both the soft and hard particles, may be a non-extensive fractal system and the fractal property is independent the colliding system. The parameter characterizing the fractal property of the system is then q = 1 − 1/n = 0.924, not too far from 1.</p>

				<p>In summary, a scaling distribution for pions is found for Au+Au, d+Au and p+p collisions at RHIC energy. The scaling distribution is universal, since it does not depend on the colliding system, the centrality and rapidity . What characterizes the dynamical difference in the particle production is the value of the average transverse momentum p T . A simple prediction which can be checked experimentally is that p n T /p T n is independent of the colliding system, the colliding centrality and rapidity. Possible statistical origin for the scaling distribution of pions is discussed from a non-extensive entropy.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Different particles may have different scaling properties.</head>

					<figDesc>This work was supported in part by the National Natural Science Foundation of China under grant No. 10475032.</figDesc>

				</figure>


			<note place="foot">arXiv:nucl-th/0608016v2 26 Mar 2007</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Hwa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Yang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev. C Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212301" to="034902" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Zborovsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tokarev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. ref- erences therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Schaffner-Bielich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kharzeev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Mclerran</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Venugopalan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">705</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">494</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AIP. Conf. Proc. 828</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Adams</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">STAR Collaboration), nucl-ex/0408016</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">064907</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">]</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S S</forename>
				<surname>Adler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PHENIX Collaboration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0610036</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Yang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">for BRAHMS Collaboration), Rom. Rep. Phys. 58</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gyulassy</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3496</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2321</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Cronin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">764</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">For a review, see A. Accardi, hep-ph/0212148 and refer- ences therein</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Hwa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Yang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">082302</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Adler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PHENIX Collaboration, Phys. Rev. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">024904</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Hagedorn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Riv. Nuovo Cimento</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">STAR Collaboration), nucl-th/0601033</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Adams</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">637</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">161</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Parvan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Biro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">340</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">375</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Tsallis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Stat. Phys. Braz. J. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="479" to="1" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
