<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">N and N to ∆ transition form factors from Lattice QCD</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2006-11-06">6 Nov 2006 February 7, 2008</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">C</forename>
								<surname>Alexandrou</surname>
							</persName>
							<email>E-mail: alexand@ucy.ac.cy</email>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cyprus</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 20537</postBox>
									<postCode>CY-1678</postCode>
									<settlement>Nicosia</settlement>
									<country key="CY">Cyprus</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">N and N to ∆ transition form factors from Lattice QCD</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2006-11-06">6 Nov 2006 February 7, 2008</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>10:0 WSPC -Proceedings Trim Size: 9in x 6in Durham 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present recent lattice QCD results on nucleon form factors and N to ∆ transition form factors. We predict the parity violating asymmetry in N to ∆ and check the off-diagonal Goldberger-Treiman relation. We present the evaluation, within lattice QCD, of fundamental physical quantities of the nucleon-∆ system. On the theoretical side, providing a complete set of form factors and coupling constants constitutes an important input for model builders and for fixing the parameters of chiral effective theories. On the experimental side, there is ongoing effort to measure accurately these quantities. Examples are the recent polarization experiments, of the electric, G E , and magnetic, G M , nucleon form factors, and the accurate measurements on the electric and scalar quadrupole multipoles and the magnetic dipole in N to ∆ transition as well as the ongoing experiment to measure the parity violating asymmetry in N to ∆. Using state-of-the-art-lattice techniques we obtain results with small statistical errors for pion masses, m π , in the range 600-360 MeV. We use two flavors of dynamical Wilson fermions and domain wall valence quarks (DWF) on MILC configurations to study the role of pion cloud contributions. Results obtained with dynamical Wilson fermions and DWF are in agreement showing that lattice artifacts are under control. In this work only the isovector nucleon form factors are evaluated since isoscalar contributions involved quark loops that are technically difficult to calculate. In Fig. 1 we display the momentum dependence of the ratio of the isovector electric to magnetic form factors for the lightest pion mass namely 410 MeV in the quenched theory and 380 MeV for dynamical Wilson fermions. 1 The lattice results are in agreement but higher than experiment. Given the weak quark mass dependence of this ratio for the quark masses</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>1</head>

				<p>N and N to ∆ transition form factors from Lattice QCD</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C. Alexandrou</head>

				<p>Department of Physics, University of Cyprus, P.O. Box 20537, CY-1678 Nicosia, Cyprus E-mail: alexand@ucy.ac.cy We present recent lattice QCD results on nucleon form factors and N to ∆ transition form factors. We predict the parity violating asymmetry in N to ∆ and check the off-diagonal Goldberger-Treiman relation.</p>

				<p>We present the evaluation, within lattice QCD, of fundamental physical quantities of the nucleon-∆ system. On the theoretical side, providing a complete set of form factors and coupling constants constitutes an important input for model builders and for fixing the parameters of chiral effective theories. On the experimental side, there is ongoing effort to measure accurately these quantities. Examples are the recent polarization experiments, of the electric, G E , and magnetic, G M , nucleon form factors, and the accurate measurements on the electric and scalar quadrupole multipoles and the magnetic dipole in N to ∆ transition as well as the ongoing experiment to measure the parity violating asymmetry in N to ∆. Using state-of-theart-lattice techniques we obtain results with small statistical errors for pion masses, m π , in the range 600-360 MeV. We use two flavors of dynamical Wilson fermions and domain wall valence quarks (DWF) on MILC configurations to study the role of pion cloud contributions. Results obtained with dynamical Wilson fermions and DWF are in agreement showing that lattice artifacts are under control.</p>

				<p>In this work only the isovector nucleon form factors are evaluated since isoscalar contributions involved quark loops that are technically difficult to calculate. In Fig. 1 we display the momentum dependence of the ratio of the isovector electric to magnetic form factors for the lightest pion mass namely 410 MeV in the quenched theory and 380 MeV for dynamical Wilson fermions. 1 The lattice results are in agreement but higher than experiment. Given the weak quark mass dependence of this ratio for the quark masses February 7, 2008 10:0 WSPC -Proceedings Trim Size: 9in x 6in Durham</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>used in this work a linear extrapolation in m 2 π to the physical limit fails to reproduce experiment. On the other hand, the isovector magnetic moments extracted from lattice results using a dipole Ansatz are well described by chiral effective theory 2 that includes explicitly the ∆. As can be seen in Fig. 1 the extrapolated value of the magnetic moment is in agreement with experiment. This is consistent with the fact that lattice results are closer to experiment for the magnetic than for the electric form factor. Fig. 1. Top: µG E /G M with µ = 4.71 versus Q 2 = −q 2 for the lightest pion for quenched and dynamical Wilson fermions. Bottom: The magnetic moment versus mπ . Fig. 2. Top: C A 5 /C V 3 versus Q 2 for Wilson and DWF fermions at mπ ∼ 500 MeV and, at the physical limit for Wilson fermions. Bottom: The ratio R GT for Wilson fermions versus Q 2 for the two smallest pion masses.</p>

				<p>We evaluate the three electromagnetic Sachs and four axial Adler form factors for the N to ∆ transition. We show in Fig. 2 the the ratio C A 5 /C V 3 , which is the analogue of g A /g V and determines, to a first approximation , the parity violating asymmetry 3 . The off-diagonal</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Treiman relation implies that the ratio R GT = fπ gπN∆(Q 2 ) 2MN C A 5 (Q 2 is one, where g πN ∆ (Q 2 ) is determined from the matrix element of the pseudoscalar density &lt; ∆ + | ¯ ψ(x)γ 5</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>τ 3 2 ψ(x)|p &gt; and f π is the pion decay constant. As can be seen in Fig. 2 this ratio approaches unity as m π decreases from ∼ 500 MeV to ∼ 410(380) MeV for quenched (dynamical) Wilson fermions.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Alexandrou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">034508</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Hemmert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Weise</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">487</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Alexandrou</forename>
				<surname>Alexandrou</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0607030</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
