<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Phase structure and phase transitions of the SU(2) × O(N) sym- metric scalar field theory</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2007-07-21">21 Jul 2007</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">A</forename>
								<surname>Patkós</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Atomic Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">EötvösUniversity</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H-1117</postCode>
									<settlement>Budapest</settlement>
									<country key="HU">Hungary</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">ResearchGroupforStatisticalandBiologicalPhysics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">HungarianAcademyofSciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H-1117</postCode>
									<settlement>Budapest</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Zs</forename>
								<surname>Szép</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">ResearchInstituteforSolidStatePhysicsandOptics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">HungarianAcademyofSciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H-1525</postCode>
									<settlement>Budapest</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Phase structure and phase transitions of the SU(2) × O(N) sym- metric scalar field theory</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2007-07-21">21 Jul 2007</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>epl draft PACS 11.10.Wx – Finite-temperature field theory PACS 11.10.Gh – Renormalisation PACS 12.38.Cy – Summation of perturbation theory</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Radiatively induced SU (2) symmetry breaking is shown to be a genuine feature of SU (2) × O(N) globally symmetric renormalisable field theories in the large N limit, describing interaction of a complex SU (2) doublet, O(N)-singlet field with an SU (2) singlet, O(N) vector. Symmetry breaking solutions are found even when all fields have positive renormalised squared mass. The emerging novel mechanism of symmetry breaking can reproduce with a choice of N ∼ 300 the standard range of the electroweak condensate and the Higgs mass occurring in the extended Higgs dynamics of an SU (2) symmetric Gauge+Higgs model. Introduction. – The Landau-Weiss mean field description of spontaneous symmetry breaking is based on assuming negative sign to the quadratic term of the expansion of the classical potential around the symmetric extremal point (mostly the origin) of the order parameter field. It has been demonstrated by Coleman and Weinberg, that for a classically conformal (m 2 = 0) theory renormalised radiative corrections might generate such wrong sign mass term in the effective potential [1]. The present paper extends the validity of the Coleman-Weinberg phenomenon to a large class of renormalisable models of interacting scalar fields all having right (positive) sign squared masses. We shall study a complex SU (2) doublet Φ = (σ + iφ 1 , φ 2 + iφ 3) which develops a nonzero vacuum expectation value v under the influence of the fluctuations of a multicomponent SU (2) singlet field. We assume an O(N) symmetric quartic self-interaction for this latter field ψ i , i = 1. .. N and an SU (2) × O(N) symmetric interaction between the two fields resulting in the Lagrangian:</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>Introduction. – The Landau-Weiss mean field description of spontaneous symmetry breaking is based on assuming negative sign to the quadratic term of the expansion of the classical potential around the symmetric extremal point (mostly the origin) of the order parameter field. It has been demonstrated by Coleman and Weinberg, that for a classically conformal (m 2 = 0) theory renormalised radiative corrections might generate such wrong sign mass term in the effective potential [1].</p>

				<p>The present paper extends the validity of the Coleman- Weinberg phenomenon to a large class of renormalisable models of interacting scalar fields all having right (positive ) sign squared masses. We shall study a complex SU (2) doublet Φ = (σ + iφ 1 , φ 2 + iφ 3 ) which develops a nonzero vacuum expectation value v under the influence of the fluctuations of a multicomponent SU (2) singlet field.</p>

				<p>We assume an O(N ) symmetric quartic self-interaction for this latter field ψ i , i = 1 . . . N and an SU (2) × O(N ) symmetric interaction between the two fields resulting in the Lagrangian:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L[ψ i , Φ] = 1 2 ∂ µ Φ † ∂ µ Φ + 1 2 (∂ µ ψ i ) 2 − 1 2 m 2 2 ψ 2 i − 1 2 m 2 3 Φ † Φ − λ 1 24N (ψ 2 i ) 2 − λ 2 24N (Φ † Φ) 2 − λ 3 12N ψ 2 i Φ † Φ. (1) (a) E-mail: patkos@ludens.elte.hu (b) E-mail: szepzs@achilles.elte.hu</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The leading order large N renormalised solution of this model was constructed by us in a previous publication [2]. This model is a generalisation of the model of [3]. There, however, σ and φ j , j = 1 . . . 3 real fields were part of the O(N ) multiplet. The clear distinction between the symmetries of the Φ and ψ i fields leads to very different results. The consequences of introducing a large(!) number (N ) of SU (2) singlet scalars were discussed recently in [4]. These authors apparently did not address the issue of N -scaling of the couplings unavoidable to keep the self-energies O(N 0 ). The model (1) can be interpreted as an extension of the Higgs sector of the Standard Model, since after the symmetry breaking the SM Higgs sector appears to have the same form as the SU (2) part of this model after the shift σ → σ + √ N v (the real field σ corresponds to the Higgs particle, the other three components are the would-be- Goldstone modes becoming the longitudinal gauge excitations). Gauge fields interact with the scalar fields via the covariant derivative of Φ, and contribute to the equations of both the vacuum condensate and the propagators of the Higgs fields. It can be shown that in the leading large N order this contribution is subdominant in any gauge and to this order the symmetry breaking effect is induced solely by the gauge singlet O(N ) vector. For this reason the novel symmetry breaking mechanism to be presented here works also for the Higgs effect in extensions of the A. Patkós and Zs. Szép</p>

			<div>
				<head>Standard Model.</head>

				<p>In Higgs physics at present renewed attempts are made to answer the recurring question [3, 4] &quot; Can Nature hide the Higgs particle? &quot; With the advent of LHC experiments increasing variety of alternative Higgs scenarios are proposed and analysed. Most extensions of the standard Higgs sector (Φ) by further scalars (ψ) start from supersymmetry . Consequences of adding singlet scalars in various versions to minimal supersymmetric extensions are summarised in [5]. Other singlet extensions were simply guided by the &quot; principle of minimal modification &quot; [4,6–10].</p>

				<p>The possibility of electroweak symmetry breaking induced by the vacuum expectation value in the hidden (phantom) sector was first envisaged in Ref. [9]. One might note, however, that the tree level mechanism proposed by these authors still assumes a destabilising negative sign for the strength of the biquadratic Higgsphantom interaction. Radiative symmetry breaking was also considered for such case by [11]. The extra scalars appear as natural candidates also for the role of the cosmological inflaton and/or dark matter [6, 12, 13].</p>

				<p>The aim of this paper is to give a complete description the phase structure of the model (1) for N → ∞, without relying on any weak coupling argument. Features of gauged models will be commented where it is appropriate . The investigation will focus on the region where all (quadratic, biquadratic and quartic) couplings are positive . It will be shown that in this case no simultaneous breakdown of the O(N ) and of the SU (2) symmetry (e.g. v = 0, u = 0, cf. eq.(2)) is possible. The statement remains valid even at next-to-leading order (NLO) in the large N expansion.</p>

				<p>With an extensive numerical study it will be shown that in a considerable part of the coupling space one finds solutions compatible with our actual physical picture on the electroweak symmetry breaking. The consistency of the solutions requires the cut-off effects inherent for a trivial theory to lie above the physical spectra and the normalisation scale. These effects are signalled in the present renormalised formulation by the location of the Landau ghost pole in the σ channel. For moderate values of the quartic couplings it turns out that generically M σ &lt; 2m ψ , therefore no hidden decays would hide the Higgs signal. Increasing these couplings makes accessible consistent models with σ → ψψ decay. The finite temperature fluctuations destroying the vacuum expectation value of σ are dominated in this model by the hidden O(N ) multiplet.</p>

				<p>The range of the values of T c follows that of the Higgs mass and is not very sensitive to the quartic couplings.</p>

				<p>Leading large N analysis of the phase structure at T = 0. – The phase structure is investigated by applying to the Lagrangian density the shifts</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ψ 1 → ψ 1 + √ N u, σ → σ + √ N v. (2) The shifted Lagrangian is of the following form: L free = 1 2 (∂ µ σ) 2 + 1 2 (∂ µ φ j ) 2 + 1 2 (∂ µ ψ i ) 2 − 1 2 m 2 2 (ψ 2 i + 2 √ Nuψ 1 + N u 2 ) − 1 2 m 2 3 (σ 2 + 2 √ N vσ + N v 2 + φ 2 j ), L int = − λ 1 24N (ψ 2 i + 2 √ N uψ 1 + N u 2 ) 2 − λ 2 24N (σ 2 + 2 √ N vσ + N v 2 + φ 2 j ) 2 − λ 3 12N (ψ 2 i + 2 √ N uψ 1 + N u 2 ) × (σ 2 + 2 √ N vσ + N v 2 + φ 2 j ). (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The equations for the expectation values of the fields ψ 1 , σ are reached by taking first the appropriate functional derivatives of the classical action:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δS δσ = −( + m 2 3 + λ 2 2 v 2 + λ 3 6 u 2 )σ − √ N v(m 2 3 + λ 2 6 v 2 + λ 3 6 u 2 ) − λ 2 6N (σ 3 + φ 2 j σ) − λ 3 6N ψ 2 i σ − λ 2 2 √ N vσ 2 − λ 3 6 √ N vψ 2 i − λ 3 3 √ N uψ 1 σ − λ 3 3 uvψ 1 , δS δψ 1 = −( + m 2 2 + λ 1 2 u 2 + λ 3 6 v 2 )ψ 1 − √ N u(m 2 2 + λ 1 6 u 2 + λ 3 6 v 2 ) − λ 3 3 uvσ − λ 1 6N ψ 2 i ψ 1 − λ 3 6N ψ 1 (σ 2 + φ 2 j ) − λ 3 3 √ N vψ 1 σ − λ 1 6 √ N u(3ψ 2 1 + ψ 2 α ) − λ 3 6 √ N u(σ 2 + φ 2 j ), (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with α = 2, ..., N . The corresponding quantum equations are obtained by replacing a generic field ϕ A by ϕ A + G ϕA,ϕB (δ/δϕ B ) on the right hand sides of the previous equations cf. Eq. (3) of [2]. The leading order equations for the order parameters arise by keeping in δΓ/δσ and δΓ/δψ 1 only terms proportional to √ N and setting the fluctuating fields to zero:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δΓ δσ ψi,σ=0 = − √ N v m 2 3 + λ 2 6 v 2 + λ 3 6 u 2 + λ 3 6 T ψ = 0, (5) δΓ δψ 1 ψi,σ=0 = − √ Nu m 2 2 + λ 1 6 u 2 + λ 3 6 v 2 + λ 1 6 T ψ = 0. (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, in the tadpole contribution T ψ the propagator of the ψ α modes is understood. It has a well-known singular (T ψ,div ) and a regular (T ψ,F ) part. T ψ,F (and also the bubble integral I ψ,F (M σ ) below) contains contributions inversely proportional to some power of the cut-off. This cannot be sent to infinity because of the triviality of the Phase structure of the SU (2) × O(N ) symmetric model model. They can be neglected only if m</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 ψ /Λ 2 or M 2 σ /Λ 2 are small [14,15]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. In (5) and (6) the tadpole contributions from σ and φ j are neglected as O(1/N ) effects. The same refers to the contribution of the gauge field tadpoles which couple to σ through the covariant derivative in an SU (2) Gauge+Higgs model. The renormalisation of the equations of state (5) and (6) can be done with help of the formulae established in the previous paper [2]. For instance let us divide (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>6) by λ 1 : √ N u m 2 2 λ 1 + 1 6 T ψ,div + 1 6 u 2 + λ 3 6λ 1 v 2 + 1 6 T ψ,F = 0. (7) It renormalises by [2] to √ N u m 2 2,R λ 1,R + 1 6 u 2 + λ 3,R 6λ 1,R v 2 + 1 6 T ψ,F = 0. (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let us multiply (5) by u and (6) by v, and subtract λ 3 /λ 1 times the second from the first:</p>

				<p><formula>√ Nuv m 2 3 − λ 3 λ 1 m 2 2 + 1 6 λ 2 − λ 2 3 λ 1 v 2 = 0, (9)</formula></p>

				<p>which coincides with its renormalised form by the results of [2]. These two renormalised equations imply also the validity of the renormalised equation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>√ N v m 2 3,R + λ 2,R 6 v 2 + λ 3,R 6 u 2 + λ 3,R 6 T ψ,F = 0. (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In what follows we will need also the gap-equation for the mass of the ψ α modes, obtained from the leading order Dyson-Schwinger equation for iG</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−1 ψα (p) = δ 2 Γ/δψ α δψ α using the parametrisation iG −1 ψα (p) = p 2 − m 2 ψ : m 2 ψ = m 2 2,R + λ 1,R 6 u 2 + λ 3,R 6 v 2 + λ 1,R 6 T ψ,F . (11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This equation is gauge independent by the SU (2) singlet nature of the ψ i field. Therefore the equations (5), (6) and (11) which determine the phase structure to leading order in N are gauge independent! The analysis of the phase structure starts by examining first the existence of phases with partially broken symmetries (Case A and Case B below). In these cases Eq. (9) is satisfied automatically, since it contains the factor uv.</p>

				<p>Case A: Higgs condensate only (u = 0, v = 0)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The relevant equation cf. (10) is m 2 3,R + λ 2,R 6 v 2 + λ 3,R 6 T ψ,F = 0. (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The tadpole integral is determined by the solution of (11). This phase was qualitatively investigated in [2].</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Case B: O(N ) symmetry breaking (u = 0, v = 0) The relevant equation of state cf. (8) is the following: m 2 2,R + λ 1,R 6 u 2 + λ 1,R 6 T ψ,F = 0. (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The tadpole integral contains now the massless Goldstone propagators. The fact that here the ψ α components are massless can be be readily checked by comparing (13) and (11). This is the text-book case of the large N symmetry breaking in the O(N ) model, which requires m 2 2,R &lt; 0. Case C: Two-condensate phase The interesting question of the possible existence of a phase with two condensates (u = 0, v = 0) starts by noting that Eq. (9) in this case implies a temperature independent v condensate if the renormalised couplings are chosen to ensure the positivity of</p>

				<p><formula>v 2 = −6 m 2 3,R − λ 3,R m 2 2,R /λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R /λ 1,R &gt; 0. (14)</formula></p>

				<p>Substituting this into any of the two original renormalised equations of state, it will modify the renormalised mass term in a kind of effective theory of the ψ field:</p>

				<p><formula>λ 3,R λ 2,R m 2 2,R − λ 3,R m 2 3,R λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R + 1 6 u 2 + 1 6 T ψ,F = 0. (15)</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Since the O(N ) symmetry is broken Goldstone&apos;s theorem ensures the masslessness of the propagators to be used in T ψ,F . Due to this, at T = 0 the renormalised tadpole T ψ,F vanishes and the effective mass in (15) is unavoidably negative for a physical u condensate. From this and (14) one concludes that for the existence of phase C the following two inequalities should be satisfied:</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>λ 2,R m 2 2,R − λ 3,R m 2 3,R λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R &lt; 0, λ 3,R m 2 2,R − λ 1,R m 2 3,R λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R &gt; 0. (16)</formula></p>

				<p>However, these inequalities cannot be satisfied simultaneously with potentials whose all couplings are positive: m 2 i,R &gt; 0 and λ i,R &gt; 0. For the case of positive denominator the two inequalities are satisfied only if</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ 2,R λ 3,R &lt; m 2 3,R m 2 2,R &lt; λ 3,R λ 1,R (17) is valid for λ 1,R λ 2,R &gt; λ 2 3,R .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This requirement, however, contradicts the assumption on the denominator. The same type of contradiction is arrived at when λ 1,R λ 2,R &lt; λ 2 3,R .</p>

				<p>The only way to reconcile the two conditions is to choose both renormalised mass squares to be negative: m 2 i,R &lt; 0. It is tempting to guess next that the v = 0, u = 0 phase might be of the form</p>

				<p><formula>v = v 0 + 1 N v 1 , u = 1 N u 1 , (18)</formula></p>

				<p>and Case C might be realised as next-to-leading order perturbation of Case A. This can be checked by substituting this Ansatz into the next-to-leading order (NLO) equations of state. The equation for u 1 arises from δΓ/δψ 1 which reads with NLO accuracy as follows:</p>

				<p><formula>δΓ δψ 1 = − √ N u m 2 2 + λ 1 6 u 2 + λ 3 6 v 2 − A. Patkós and Zs. Szép λ 1 6 √ N u(G αα + 3G 11 ) − λ 3 6 √ N uG σσ − λ 3 3 √ N vG 1σ − i 6N</formula></p>

				<p>A,B,C (λ 1 G iA G iB G 1C + λ 3 G σA G σB G 1C ) Γ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(3) ABC . (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The A symbols appearing above denote summationintegration over discrete and continuous coordinates of the intermediary fields. In this equation only terms of O(1/ √ N ) are to be kept. Therefore all propagators G AB are evaluated with leading order accuracy only. In view of the Ansatz (18) and the fact that G 1σ to leading order vanishes, one can neglect the second, third and fourth terms on the right hand side of the equation. In the last term the relevant 3-point functions are all suppressed by at least a factor 1/ √ N , therefore the conclusion is that u stays zero even at NLO.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>This means that with all couplings of the potential chosen positive in Case A the physically interesting Higgs (e.g. SU (2)) symmetry breaking phase does not lead to mixing of the Higgs field and the hidden O(N ) multiplet. In the rest of the paper we concentrate on the analysis of Case A. We shall demonstrate at leading order in N that it is compatible in a large range of the parameters with our present knowledge about the Higgs sector of the electroweak theory.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Leading order finite temperature behaviour of case A. – The analysis is based on combining Eq. (12) with the gap equation (11) in which one sets u = 0, and which selfconsistently determines the mass of the ψ-field. When one eliminates the renormalised tadpole integral T ψ,F from these two equations one finds</p>

				<p><formula>1 6 v 2 = λ 3,R (m 2 2,R − m 2 ψ ) − λ 1,R m 2 3,R λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R . (20)</formula></p>

				<p>This equation can be reexpressed in terms of effective quantities which are analogous to the expression of the vacuum expectation value in the Standard Model:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 6 v 2 = − m 2 Higgs λ Higgs N , λ Higgs N ≡ λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R λ 1,R m 2 Higgs ≡ m 2 3,R − λ 3,R λ 1,R (m 2 2,R − m 2 ψ ), (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(recall that √ N v gives the physical strength of the condensate ). Stable symmetry breaking occurs when m</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>Higgs &lt; 0, λ Higgs &gt; 0. It is clear that the temperature dependence of the order parameter comes in only through m 2 ψ . Its equation arises after eliminating v 2 from Eqs.(11) and (12):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>µ 2 ψ (1 − C ln(eµ 2 ψ )) = µ 2 2 − λ 3,R λ 2,R µ 2 3 + λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R λ 2,R M 2 0 T (T ) ψ , (22) where the notations µ 2 i = m 2 i,R M 2 0 , µ 2 ψ = m 2 ψ M 2 0 , C = λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R 96π 2 λ 2,R (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are introduced and the T = 0 part of the tadpole integral is separated from its temperature dependent part denoted by T</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(T )</head>

				<p>ψ . The explicit expression of the T = 0 part is used on the left hand side of (22). Below we assume (cf.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eq. (21)) λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R &gt; 0, that is C &gt; 0. The left hand side of (22) has a maximum for C &gt; 0 as a function of µ 2 ψ at µ 2 ψ,max = exp(1/C)/e</trash>

					<figDesc>2 . Therefore, the condition for the existence of the solution of this equation (at T = 0) reads as</figDesc>
					<trash>C e 2 e 1/C ≥ µ 2 2 − λ 3,R λ 2,R µ 2 3 + λ 1,R λ 2,R − λ 2 3,R λ 2,R M 2 0 T (T ) ψ . (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Under this condition one finds two solutions for µ 2 ψ , one is smaller than µ 2 ψ,max the other is larger. The smaller starts to increase with T , which leads to decreasing value of v 2 . The phase transition is accessible to our treatment if the above inequality is maintained until v vanishes. The procedure which determines T c starts by putting zero on the left hand side of (20):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m 2 ψ,c = m 2 2,R − λ 1,R λ 3,R m 2 3,R , (25) where m ψ,c = m ψ (T c ). This can be substituted into Eq. (12) in which we set v = 0 and solve for T c : 6m 2 3,R λ 3,R + T ψ,F (m 2 ψ,c , T c ) = 6m 2 3,R λ 3,R + m 2 ψ,c 16π 2 ln em 2 ψ,c M 2 0 + T 2 c 2π 2 ∞ m ψ,c /Tc dx x 2 − m 2 ψ,c /T 2 c e x − 1 = 0. (26)</trash>

					<figDesc>When one starts to increase the temperature the right hand side of Eq. (22) first increases at all values of m ψ .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>As a consequence it cuts the temperature independent left hand side in such a way that both roots move towards m ψ,max . The temperature value when the roots become degenerate is the maximal one for which the solution of our model has sensible physics. If this happens before v reaches zero, one can not access the phase transition. Depending on the actual couplings it might happen that the two poles become degenerate at a mass value larger than m ψ,max . In this case Eq. (26) will have a solution even when m ψ,c &gt; m ψ,max . A particular set of renormalised parameters is considered by us acceptable if the Higgs transition falls into the temperature range of validity of the model.</p>

				<p>Numerical study of case A. – We restrict our further investigation to the special case: λ 2,R = λ 3,R = λ, λ 1,R = λ + λ ′ , in order to diminish the number of the tunable parameters. The results presented below should be representative for the more general parameter choice.</p>

				<p>The renormalised parameters of the theory are fixed using the T = 0 equation of state for v and the gap equation of m ψ . In addition one can make use of the gap equation of σ, obtained to leading order in N by summing up the Phase structure of the SU (2) × O(N ) symmetric model insertion of bubbles I ψ in the σ self-energy [2]. In the gauged theory one should add to the Higgs self-energy the contribution of the one loop gauge diagrams. Here we omit this contribution. This way the following set of equations is to be solved:</p>

				<p><formula>v 2 + 6m 2 3,R λ = − m 2 ψ 16π 2 ln em 2 ψ M 2 0 ≤ M 2 0 16π 2 e 2 , (27) M 2 σ = v 2 3 λ λ + λ ′ λ ′ + λ 1 − λ+λ ′ 6 I ψ,F (M 2 σ ) , (28) m 2 2,R = m 2 ψ + m 2 3,R − λ ′ 96π 2 m 2 ψ ln em 2 ψ M 2 0 . (29)</formula></p>

				<p>The upper bound on v displayed in Eq. (27) restricts it to values which are at least 4πe smaller than the renormalisation scale. In order to have the physical value for the electroweak condensate √ Nv ≈ 250 GeV with a normalisation scale M 0 at least twice as large, one has to choose N &gt; (2πe) 2 ≃ 292. In this range our leading large N solution should work quite well. The compatibility of this large number of &quot; dark &quot; degrees of freedom with cosmological constraints should be investigated. Our strategy for investigating the solutions of these equations is to fix a reasonable value for the Higgs mass and some acceptable value for the renormalisation scale M 0 . The latter is chosen below the unitarity limit of validity of the scalar theory. Since at present direct search results combined with electroweak precision tests indicate 114 GeV ≤ M H ≤ 200 GeV, below we choose M σ = 140 GeV, M 0 = 500 GeV (and also M 0 = 800 GeV). Then λ is varied in the range λ ∈ (0, 400). v 2 and m 2 3,R are chosen to respect the inequality appearing in (27). Next, the first equation of the above set allows to find m ψ . This equation has two solutions like Eq. (22), one root is below M 0 /e the other one is above it. Using one of the roots in the renormalised bubble integral I ψ,F (M σ ), one finds λ ′ from (28) which can be rewritten in a very enlightening way:</p>

				<p><formula>λ ′ = 6 I ψ,F (M σ ) − 1 λ − v 2 3M 2 σ −1 . (30) Finally m 2 2</formula></p>

				<p>,R is determined from the third equation of the above set, Eq. (29). These two couplings depend on which m ψ root was chosen. A very restrictive criterion used to select the allowed models is represented by the choice of the Landau ghost&apos;s scale defined as the absolute value of the imaginary pole solution of the Higgs propagator. Its equation is the imaginary continuation of (28) with the following analytic form of the bubble integral for M σ = im L :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I ψ,F (m L ) = 1 16π 2 ln m 2 ψ M 2 0 Q − 1 Q + 1 −Q , (31) where Q = 1 + 4m 2 ψ m 2 L</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>.</head>

				<p>Only those parameter sets are accepted where the Landau-ghost scale is above M 0 . This</p>

				<p><formula>100 150 200 250 300 350 400 450 500 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 m ψ [GeV] 10 4 [v 2 +6m 3 2 /λ]/M 0 2 (4πe) -2 M 0 =800 GeV M 0 =500 GeV Fig. 1</formula></p>

				<p>: The solution of Eq. (27) for two different values of the normalisation scale M0. criterion is dictated by the expectation that a solution which fulfills the relations M σ , m ψ ≪ M 0 &lt; Λ &lt; m L coincides with that of a fixed cut-off analysis carried out in the spirit of Refs. [14, 15].</p>

				<p>Using the above criterion practically all points are excluded in the λ region (0, 200) while for λ ∈ (200, 400) one finds acceptable sets which allow us to densely populate the two branches of m ψ roots. It turns out that the m ψ values obtained from (27) fall on the physical branch of (22), that is for which v decreases with increasing T . Eventually the allowed parameters lead to λ Higgs of Eq. (21) in the range (0, 0.9). It is worth mentioning that the 3-point function Γ ψαψασ and 4-point function Γ ψαψαψαψα taken at vanishing momentum , which are the coefficients up to a negative sign of the cubic and quartic values in the leading large N expression of the effective potential V eff (ψ, σ), are actually negative only in the range where the ghost scale is above M 0 . This ensures the stability of the effective potential.</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Fig. 1 we show the two branches of m ψ for M 0 = 500, 800 GeV as found by solving (27). The shorter lower arm is the consequence of the cut applied through the implementation of the ghost criterion. The range of the m ψ values is mostly above the Higgs mass (e.g. 140 GeV in the present example).</p>

				<p>The temperature of the phase transition falls slightly below this range. The spreading of T c over the two branches is displayed in the left hand side of Fig. 2 for M 0 = 500 GeV. A well-defined region, sharply limited both from above and from below is filled by the values of T c found for the different acceptable models. It is interesting to see that the region filled by the T c values shows a certain characteristic shape when displayed as a function of v and m L , the Landau-ghost scale. This can be seen for the upper branch m ψ in the right hand side of Fig. 2.</p>

				<p>The lower edge of the T c surface is due to the requirement of not allowing models with much too low Landau</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-ghost A. Patkós and Zs. Szép 60 80 100 120 140 160 180 200 220 120 150 180 210 240 270 90 95 100 105 110 115 T c [GeV] [v 2 +6m 3 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>/λ] [GeV 2 ] m ψ [GeV] T c [GeV] 500 1000 1500 2000 2500 3000 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 94 98 102 106 110 114 T c [GeV] m L [GeV] v [GeV] T c [GeV] Fig. 2: The dependence of Tc on an appropriate combination of coupling parameters and/or physical data of the model. The lines in the horizontal plane of the figure on the left hand side display the two branches of the m ψ curve of Fig. 1. The figure on the right hand side presents Tc as function of v and mL for the upper branch of m ψ .</p>

				<p>scale (low cut-off value).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Conclusions. –</head>

				<p>In this paper we have pointed out the possibility of having Coleman-Weinberg type symmetry breaking for an order parameter field with positive renormalised mass parameter, induced by quantum fluctuations of a multicomponent hidden &quot; phantom &quot; field. Numerical investigation showed that one finds large sets of positive renormalised couplings of the extended model which lead to m</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>Higgs &lt; 0, λ Higgs &gt; 0 (e.g. (21)). The wrong-sign mass terms receives in this way a natural origin. For λ ∈ (0, 400) and M 0 = 500 GeV the solution of the gap equation of the phantom field always leads to heavy quanta: 2m ψ &gt; M σ , and also the Higgs-phantom mixing was shown to be absent even at NLO level. Therefore in this toy model (where the gauge field contribution to the Higgs mass is omitted) we conclude that in a large part of the parameter space one would discover the Higgs particle with the characteristics predicted by the Standard Model. Scanning through the solutions obtained in a wider range of the λ we find that also lower m ψ values become accessible as λ grows. Above λ ≈ 750 solutions appear for which m ψ &lt; M σ /2. The corresponding range of λ Higgs is (0.8, 0.94). Also, the critical temperatures overlap with the values found for models with no hidden Higgs decay. More realistic investigations ought to include also gauge and fermion contributions to the Higgs self-energy. The order of the finite temperature phase transition can be examined conveniently by combining large N techniques with finite temperature dimensional reduction. * * * This research was supported by the Hungarian Scientific Research Fund (OTKA) under the grants No. T-046129 and PD-050015. Fruitful discussions with J. Kuti and A.</p>

				<p>Jakovác are acknowledged.</p>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Coleman</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S R</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev.D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1888</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Patkó</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Szé</forename>
				<surname>Zs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">642</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">384</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Chivukula</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Golden</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">267</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">233</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Bahat</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Grossman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Rozen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Barger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Langacker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Shaughnessy</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Davoudiasl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kitano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Murayama</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">609</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">117</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Van</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Bij</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">636</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">56</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O &apos;</forename>
				<surname>Connell</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Ramsey-Musolf</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Wise</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="037701" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Patt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Wilczek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Calmet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Oliver</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Europhys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">51002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Espinosa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Quiros</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ignatiev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Volkas</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R R</forename>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">487</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">294</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Shaposhnikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Tkachev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">639</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">414</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Jansen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kuti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">309</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">U</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Heller</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Neuberger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Vranas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="271" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
