<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Lightest Higgs Boson and Relic Neutralino in the MSSM with CP Violation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2007-01-26">26 Jan 2007</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Jae</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Sik</forename>
								<surname>Lee</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">School of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center of Theoretical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Seoul National University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>151–747</addrLine>
									<settlement>Seoul</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Stefano</forename>
								<surname>Scopel</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Korea Institute for Advanced Study</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>130-722</postCode>
									<settlement>Seoul</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Lightest Higgs Boson and Relic Neutralino in the MSSM with CP Violation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2007-01-26">26 Jan 2007</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term>1260Jv</term>
					<term>9535+d</term>
					<term>1480Cp</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We discuss the lower bound to the lightest Higgs boson H1 in the minimal supersymmetric extension of the standard model (MSSM) with explicit CP violation, and the phenomenology of the lightest relic neutralino in the same scenario. In particular, adopting the CPX benchmark scenario, we find that the combination of experimental constraints coming from LEP, Thallium Electric Dipole Moment (EDM) measurements, quorkonium decays, and Bs → µµ decay favours a region of the parameter space where the mass of H1 is in the range 7 GeV &lt; ∼ MH 1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV, while 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 5. Assuming a departure from the usual GUT relation among gaugino masses (|M1| ≪ |M2|), we find that through resonant annihilation to H1 a neutralino as light as 2.9 GeV can be a viable dark matter candidate in this scenario. We call this the CPX light neutralino scenario, and discuss its phenomenology showing that indirect Dark Matter searches are compatible with the present experimental constraints, as long as mχ &lt; ∼ MH 1 /2. On the other hand, part of the range mχ &gt; ∼ MH 1 /2 which is allowed by cosmology is excluded by antiproton fluxes.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>H 1 and that of the lightest possible mass for the relic neutralino χ, when standard assumptions are made for the origin and evolution of its relic density. In fact, by combining present experimental constraints, a very simple picture (albeit tuned) emerges, where the mass of the lightest Higgs boson H 1 is found to be in the range 7 &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 7.5 GeV, with the ratio of the two vacuum expectation values almost fixed, tan β ≃ 3. This range can be relaxed to: 7 &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV and 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 5, with quite mild assumptions on the Thallium EDM. In this scenario, resonant annihilations of neutralinos with mass m χ ≃ M H1 /2 through H 1 exchange in the s channel can drive their thermal relic abundance within the limits coming from observation, for values of m χ significantly below those allowed in CP–conserving scenarios [13] (to our knowledge, the issue of resonant χ annihilation in the context of CP violation was first raised at the qualitative level in [12]).</p>

				<p>In the following we will analyse in detail the implications for direct and indirect DM searches of these light neutralinos , which we will refer to as the CPX light neutralino scenario, concluding that it is indeed viable scenario, with prospects of detection in future experiments.</p>

				<p>The plan of the paper is as follows. In Section II the CPX scenario in the MSSM with CP violation is introduced.</p>

				<p>In Section III we discuss various experimental bounds. Section IV is devoted to the discussion of the cosmological relic density of CPX light relic neutralinos, and Section V to their phenomenology in DM searches. Our conclusions are contained in Section VI.</p>

				<p>II. MSSM WITH EXPLICIT CP VIOLATION: THE CPX SCENARIO</p>

				<p>The tree level Higgs potential of the MSSM is invariant under CP transformations. However, CP can be explicitly broken at the loop level. In the presence of sizable CP phases in the relevant soft SUSY breaking terms, a significant mixing between the scalar and pseudo–scalar neutral Higgs bosons can be generated [4, 5, 6]. As a consequence of this CP–violating mixing, the three neutral MSSM Higgs mass eigenstates, labeled in order of increasing mass as M H1 ≤ M H2 ≤ M H3 , have no longer definite CP parities, but become mixtures of CP-even and CP-odd states. In this scenario, all masses are usually calculated as a function of the charged Higgs boson mass M H ± , instead of the pseudoscalar Higgs mass M A , which is no longer a physical parameter. Much work has been devoted to studying the phenomenological features of this radiative Higgs-sector CP violation in the framework of the MSSM [7, 8].</p>

				<p>Due to the large Yukawa couplings, the CP-violating mixing among the neutral Higgs bosons is dominated by the contribution of third-generation squarks and is proportional to the combination:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>3 16π 2 ℑm(A f µ) m 2 ˜ f2 − m 2 ˜ f1 , (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with f = t, b. Here µ is the Higgs–mixing parameter in the superpotential and A f denotes the trilinear soft coupling.</p>

				<p>In particular, the amount of CP violation is enhanced when the product of |A b,t | and |µ| is larger than the difference of the sfermion masses squared. At the two–loop level, also the gluino mass parameter M 3 becomes relevant through threshold corrections to the top-and bottom-quark Yukawa couplings. This contribution depends on the combination Arg(M 3 µ) and can be important especially when tan β ≡ v 2 /v 1 is large, where v 2 and v 1 are the vacuum expectation values of the neutral components of the two Higgs doublets that give masses to up–type and down–type quarks, respectively. More CP phases become relevant by including subdominant radiative corrections from other sectors [9].</p>

				<p>In presence of CP violation, the mixing among neutral Higgs bosons is described by a 3×3 real orthogonal matrix O, instead of a 2×2 one. The matrix O relates the electro–weak states to the mass eigenstates as:</p>

				<p><formula>(φ 1 , φ 2 , a) T = O (H 1 , H 2 , H 3 ) T . (2)</formula></p>

				<p>We note that the elements O φ1i and O φ2i are the CP-even components of the i-th Higgs boson, while O ai is the corresponding CP-odd component.</p>

				<p>The Higgs-boson couplings to the SM and SUSY particles could be modified significantly due to the CP violating mixing. Among them, one of the most important ones may be the Higgs-boson coupling to a pair of vector bosons, g HiV V , which is responsible for the production of Higgs bosons at e + e − colliders:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L HV V = gM W W + µ W −µ + 1 2c 2 W Z µ Z µ 3 i=1 g HiV V H i , (3) where g HiV V = c β O φ1i + s β O φ2i , (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>when normalized to the SM value. Here we have used the following abbreviations: s β ≡ sin β, c β ≡ cos β. t β = tan β, etc. We note that the two vector bosons W and Z couple only to the CP-even components O φ1,2i of the i-th Higgs mass eigenstate, and the relevant couplings may be strongly suppressed when the i-th Higgs boson is mostly CP-odd,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>O 2 ai ∼ 1 ≫ O 2 φ1i , O 2 φ2i .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The so called CPX scenario has been defined as a showcase benchmark point for studying CP-violating Higgs-mixing phenomena [14]. Its parameters are all defined at the electro–weak scale, and are chosen in order to enhance the combination in Eq.(1). In this scenario, SUSY soft parameters are fixed as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M ˜ Q3 = M ˜ U3 = M ˜ D3 = M ˜ L3 = M ˜ E3 = M SUSY , |µ| = 4 M SUSY , |A t,b,τ | = 2 M SUSY , |M 3 | = 1 TeV , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where, with a usual notation, Q, L, U , D and E indicate chiral supermultiplets corresponding to left– and right– handed quarks and leptons. In this scenario tan β, M H ± , and M SUSY are free parameters. As far as CP phases are concerned, we adopt, without loss of generality, the convention Arg(µ) = 0, while we assume a common phase for all the A f terms, Φ A ≡ Arg(A t ) = Arg(A b ) = Arg(A τ ). As a consequence of this, we end–up with two free physical phases: Φ A and Φ 3 = Arg(M 3 ).</p>

				<p>In addition to the parameters fixed by the CPX scenario, we need to fix the gaugino masses M 1,2 for our study. We take them as free parameters independently of M 3 since, for them, we chose to relax the usual relations at the electroweak scale: M i /M j = g 2 i /g 2 j with g i,j =gauge coupling constants, which originate from the assumption of gaugino–mass unification at the GUT scale. The neutralino χ is defined as usual as the lowest-mass linear superposition of B</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-inõ B, W -inõ W (3) , and of the two Higgsino states H 0 1 , ˜ H 0 2 : χ ≡ a 1 ˜ B + a 2 ˜ W (3) + a 3 ˜ H 0 1 + a 4 ˜ H 0 2 . (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In Ref. [15] it was proved that in a CP–conserving effective MSSM with |M 1 | &lt;&lt; |M 2 | light neutralinos of a mass as low as 7 GeV are allowed. Indeed, for |M 1 | &lt;&lt; |M 2 | the LEP constraints do not apply, and the lower bound on the neutralino mass is set by the cosmological bound. As shown in [15], these neutralinos turn out to be mainly B</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-inos, a 1 ≃ 1 and m χ ≃ |M 1 |, with a small Higgsino component given by: |a 3 | |a 1 | ≃ sin θ W sin β M Z µ , (7)</trash>

					<figDesc>where θ W is the Weinberg angle and M Z is the Z–boson mass. In the following we will assume vanishing phases for M 1 and M 2 , and we will fix for definiteness M 2 =200 GeV (the phenomenology we are interested in is not sensitive to these parameters in a significant way). On the other hand, we will vary M 1 , which is directly correlated to the lightest neutralino mass m χ .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In this work, we rely on CPsuperH [16] for the computation of mass spectra and couplings in the MSSM Higgs sector.</p>

			<div>
				<head>III. EXPERIMENTAL CONSTRAINTS ON THE CPX SCENARIO A. LEP2 searches</head>

				<p>The most relevant feature of the CPX scenario for our analysis is that the lightest Higgs boson H 1 can be very light,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV, with the other two neutral Higgs bosons significantly heavier, M H2,3 &gt; ∼ 100 GeV, when Φ A ∼ 90 o and M H ± ∼ 130 GeV for moderate values of 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 10.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this case, the lightest Higgs boson is mostly CP odd and its production at LEP is highly suppressed since |g H1V V | ≪ 1 though it is kinematically accessible. On the other hand, the second–lightest Higgs H 2 can be produced together with a Z boson since its complementary coupling g H2V V is sizeable. But its mass is close to the kinematical limit ∼ 110 GeV and, moreover, it dominantly decays into two H 1 &apos;s. Depending on M H1 , the lightest Higgs boson decays into two b quarks or two τ leptons. This leads to a dominant production and decay mode containing 6 jets in the final state, a topology which was covered by LEP2 with a very low efficiency. The similar situation occurs for H 1 –H 2 pair production. Therefore, in the presence of CP-violating mixings, a very light Higgs bosons with M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV could easily escape detection at LEP2. For the CPX scenario, taking Φ A = Φ 3 = 90 • and M SUSY = 0.5 TeV, the combined searches of the four LEP collaborations at √ s = 91 − 209 GeV reported the following two allowed regions [17]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>
					<trash>R1 : M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV for 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 10, R2 : 30 GeV &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 50 GeV for 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 10. (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These regions will not be fully covered even at the LHC for tan β &lt; ∼ 7 (R1) and &lt; ∼ 5 (R2) [18]. In our analysis we will focus on region R1. We observe that in the scenario analysed by the LEP collaborations one has |µ|=2 TeV. For this large value of |µ|, the neutralino is a very pure B-ino configuration, with a Higgsino contamination a 3 ≃0.02 (see Eq. 7). As will be shown in Section IV, this has important consequences for the phenomenology of relic neutralinos, in particular suppressing their annihilation cross section, and restricting the possibility of having a relic abundance in the allowed range only to the case of resonant annihilation. So, the exploration of different possibilities with lower values of |µ| could in principle be very relevant for relic neutralinos. However, this would require a re–analysis of LEP data which is beyond the scope of this paper.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B. Electric Dipole Moments</head>

				<p>CP phases in the MSSM are significantly constrained by the EDM measurements. In particular, the EDM of the</p>

				<p>Thallium atom provides currently the most stringent constraint on the MSSM scenario of our interest. The atomic EDM of 205 Tl gets its main contributions from two terms [19, 20]: d Tl [e cm] = −585 · d e [e cm] − 8.5 × 10 −19 [e cm] · (C S TeV 2 ) + · · · , (9) where d e denotes the electron EDM and C S is the coefficient of the CP-odd electron-nucleon interaction L CS = C S ¯ eiγ 5 e ¯ NN . The dots denote sub-dominant contributions from 6-dimensional tensor and higher-dimensional operators . The above quantity is constrained by the experimental 2 − σ upper bound on the Thallium EDM, which is [21]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|d Tl | &lt; ∼ 1.3 × 10 −24 [e cm] . (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The contributions of the first and second generation phases, e.g. Φ Ae,µ , Φ A d,s etc., to EDMs can be drastically reduced either by assuming these phases sufficiently small, or if the first-and second-generation squarks and sleptons tanβ M H1 [ GeV ]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>■■■■ 10 ≤ |d ∧ Tl | &lt; 100 ■■■■ 1 ≤ |d ∧ Tl | &lt; 10 ■■■■ |d ∧ Tl | &lt; 1 |d ∧ Tl | ≥ 100 |d ∧ Tl | ≥ 100 CUSB B ∧ (B S → µµ) = 2 B ∧ (B S → µµ) = 20 B ∧ (B S → µµ) = 200 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 FIG. 1: The Thallium EDM d Tl ≡ d Tl × 10 24 e cm in the CPX scenario with MSUSY = 0.5 TeV in the region MH 1 &lt; ∼ 15 GeV and 3 &lt; tan β &lt; 10.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The different shaded regions correspond to different ranges of | ˆ d Tl |, as shown: specifically, the narrow region consistent with the current thallium EDM constraint, | ˆ d Tl | &lt; 1, is denoted by black squares. In the blank unshaded region we have | ˆ d Tl | &gt; 100. The region below the thick solid line is excluded by data on Υ(1S) decay [25]. For comparison, the thin line shows an estimation of the same boundary obtained using the tree-level coupling taking Oa1=1, i.e. |g P H 1 ¯ bb | = tan β. Also shown are the three contour lines of the rescaled</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B(Bs → µµ) ≡ (Bs → µµ) × 10 7 : ˆ B(Bs → µµ) = 2 (solid), 20 (dotted), and 200 (dashed).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are sufficiently heavy. However, even when the contribution of the first and second generation phases to EDM&apos;s is suppressed, there are still sizeable contributions to EDMs from Higgs-mediated two loop diagrams [22]. Their explicit forms for (d e /e) H and C S may be found in Ref. [23], expressed in the conventions and notations of CPsuperH [16].</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>In Fig. 1</head>

				<p>, we show the rescaled Thallium EDM d Tl ≡ d Tl × 10 24 in units of e cm in the M H1 -tan β plane. Here, we consider only the contributions from the Higgs-mediated two–loop diagrams. Different ranges of | ˆ d Tl | are shown explicitly by different shadings. In the blank unshaded region we have obtained | ˆ d Tl | &gt; 100. We find that a cancellation between the contributions from (d e /e) H and C S occurs when tan β &lt; 5. This cancellation is responsible for the narrow region denoted by black squares with | ˆ d Tl | &lt; 1, where it is at the level of about about 5 %.</p>

				<p>Finally, we note that the Thallium EDM constraint can be evaded by assuming cancellations between the two–loop contributions considered here and other contributions, such as those from first– and second–generation sfermions discussed above. In this way the allowed region shown in Fig. 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>can be enlarged. The amount of cancellation can be directly read–off from Fig. 1. For instance, in the region | ˆ d Tl | &lt; 10 it would be less severe than 1 part in 10 (10 %).</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C. Bottomonium decay</head>

				<p>In the region R1, see Eq. (8), the bottomonium decay channel Υ(1S) → γH 1 is kinematically accessible [24]. There are two experimental limits on this process, depending on whether the H 1 decays to visible particles [25] or to invisible ones [26]. The second case is allowed when 2m χ &lt; M H1 , so that H 1 can decay to neutralinos which escape detection. On the other hand, in the case 2m χ &gt; M H1 also the three–body decay (i.e. with a non–monochromatic γ spectrum) Υ(1S) → γχχ has been constrained [25]. The branching ratio for the two–body decay calculated in our scenario is related to its SM counterpart by [24]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>
					<trash>B(Υ(1S) → γ H 1 ) SUSY = B(Υ(1S) → γ H 1 ) SM × (g P H1 ¯ bb ) 2 , (11) where g P H1 ¯ bb denotes the Higgs coupling to two b quarks given by g P H1 ¯ bb</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>= −O a1 tan β at the tree level. This implies that the experimental upper bounds on this process can be directly converted to a constraint in the plane tan β–M H1 .</p>

				<p>The result is shown in Fig. 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>, where the thin (red) line corresponds to the limit obtained by setting (g</figDesc>
					<trash>P H1 ¯ bb ) 2 = tan 2 β.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Finite–threshold corrections induced by the gluino and chargino exchanges can modify the coupling g P H1 ¯ bb , although this effect is negligible at low values of tan β. Moreover, although for our choice of parameters H 1 is mostly pseudoscalar, O a1 can be smaller than 1 up to about 20%. The thick solid line in Fig. 1 shows the bottomonium constraint when the threshold corrections and O a1 are fully included.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>From Fig. 1</head>

				<p>one can see that, when the following constraints are combined: (i) the LEP constraint; (ii) Thallium EDM; (iii) the limit from bottomonium decay, the allowed parameter space is reduced to:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>7 GeV &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 7.5 GeV and tan β ≃ 3. (12) This region may be enlarged to 7 GeV &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV and 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 5 , (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>if we assume 10 %-level cancellation in the Thallium EDM.</p>

				<p>In light of the above discussion and for definiteness, from now on we will fix M H1 =7.5 GeV and tan β=3 in our analysis. Taking into account the CPX parameter choice of</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Eq.(5) with Φ A = Φ 3 = 90 • and M SUSY = 0.5 TeV, this implies, in particular: M H ± ≃ 147 GeV, M H2 ≃ 108 GeV, M H3 ≃ 157 GeV.</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>D. Other constraints</head>

				<p>As will be discussed in the following sections, if the pseudoscalar Higgs boson mass is in the range (12), a CPX light neutralino with m χ &lt; ∼ M H1 /2 can be a viable DM candidate. Due to their very pure B-ino composition, and to the quite low value of tan β, neutralinos in this mass range evade constraints coming from accelerators. For instance, in the CPX light neutralino mass range the present upper bound to the invisible width of the Z–boson implies |a</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 3 −a 2 4 | &lt; ∼ a few</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>percent, a constraint easily evaded in this case.</p>

				<p>As far as Flavour Changing Neutral Currents (FCNC) are concerned, they strongly depend on the assumptions about flavour violation in the squark sector. For instance, assuming squarks diagonal in flavour, the SUSY contribution to the b → sγ decay rate is dominated by chargino–stop and H ± –W loops, which are strongly suppressed in our case by the low value of tan β and by the fact that there are no light masses to compensate this.</p>

				<p>The situation is potentially different in the case of the decay B s → µµ, since its dominant SUSY contribution scales as tan 6 β |µ| 2 /M 4 H1 and may have a resonance enhancement when H 1 is so light that M H1 ∼ M Bs . Neglecting the threshold corrections which are not so important in our case, we estimate the branching ratio based on the approximated expression [27]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B(B s → µµ) ≃ 2 τ Bs M 5 Bs f 2 Bs 64π |C| 2 (O 4 φ11 + O 4 a1 ) (14) with C ≡ G F α √ 2π V tb V * ts tan 3 β 4 sin 2 θ W m µ m t |µ| M 2 W (M 2 H1 − M 2 Bs ) sin 2θ t 2 ∆f 3 (15) where ∆f 3 = f 3 (x 2 ) − f 3 (x 1 ) with x i = m 2 ˜ ti /|µ| 2 and f 3 (x) = x log x/(1 − x) and θ ˜ t the stop mixing angle [49]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. In Fig. 1, we show three contour lines of the rescaled</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B(B s → µµ) ≡ (B s → µµ) × 10 7 : ˆ B(B s → µµ) = 2 (solid), 20 (dotted), and 200 (dashed). For the parameters chosen by combining the results from LEP2 searches, Thallium EDM, and Bottomonium decay, Eq. (12), we get: B(B s → µµ) CP X ≃ 6 × 10 −7 taking f Bs = 0.23 GeV. This is three</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>times larger than the present 95 % C.L. limit [28]: B(B s → µµ) &lt; 2 × 10 −7 . This can be easily made consistent with the present experimental constraint if some mild cancellation takes place. The &quot; GIM operative point &quot; mechanism discussed in Ref. [29] may be an example of such cancellation, when the squark mass matrices are flavour diagonal.</p>

				<p>In particular, we find that B(B s → µµ) CP X is consistent to the experimental upper bound by choosing 0.8 &lt; ∼ ρ &lt; ∼ 0.9, where ρ ≡ m ˜ q /M SUSY is the hierarchy factor introduced in Ref. [29], with m ˜ q the soft mass for squarks of the first two generations [50].</p>

				<p>As far as the SUSY contribution to the anomalous magnetic dipole moment of the muon δa SUSY µ is concerned, as is well known uncertainties in the SM make a comparison with the experimental results difficult. In particular, by combining the SM hadronic vacuum polarization results obtained from e + e − and τ + τ − data, the SM calculation turns out to be compatible with observation, and the following 2–σ allowed interval for δa SUSY µ is found [15]:</p>

				<p><formula>-160 &lt; ∼ δa SUSY µ × 10 11 &lt; ∼ 680.</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The corresponding contribution from light neutralinos in the CPX scenario falls comfortably into this range: δa SUSY µ CP X × 10 11 ≃ 1.5 (to estimate this we have assumed for the trilinear coupling of the smuon the same value of the trilinear couplings of the third family given in Eq. (5)).</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>IV. THE RELIC DENSITY</head>

				<p>Taking into account the latest data from the cosmic microwave data (CMB) combined with other observations [2] the 2–σ interval for the DM density of the Universe (normalized to the critical density) is:</p>

				<p><formula>0.096 &lt; Ω m h 2 &lt; 0.122 , (16)</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<head>where h is the Hubble parameter expressed in units of 100 km s −1 Mpc −1 . In Eq.(16) the upper bound on Ω m h 2</head>

					<figDesc>establishes a strict upper limit for the abundance of any relic particle. In particular, the neutralino relic abundance is given by the usual expression:</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>Ω χ h 2 = x f g ⋆ (x f ) 1/2 3.3 · 10 −38 cm 2 &lt; σ ann v &gt; , (17) where &lt; σ ann v &gt; ≡ x f σ ann v int , σ ann v int ≡ T f T0</formula></p>

				<p>σ ann v dT /m χ being the integral from the present temperature T 0 up to the freeze-out temperature T f of the thermally averaged product of the annihilation cross-section times the relative velocity of a pair of neutralinos σ ann v, x f is defined as x f ≡ mχ T f and g ⋆ (x f ) denotes the relativistic degrees of freedom of the thermodynamic bath at x f . For the determination of x f we adopt a standard procedure [30].</p>

				<p>In absence of some resonant effect, the natural scale of the annihilation cross section times velocity σ ann v of CPX light neutralinos is far too small to keep the relic abundance below the upper bound of Eq.(16) (in particular they are very pure B–inos and their mass is below the threshold for annihilation to bottom quarks, which is usually the dominant channel of σ ann v for light neutralinos [15]). However, when m χ ≃ M H1 /2 neutralinos annihilate through the resonant channel χχ → H 1 → standard particles, bringing the relic abundance down to acceptable values. In the Boltzmann approximation the thermal average of the resonant σ ann v to the final state f can be obtained in a straightforward way from the following relation among interaction rates:</p>

				<p><formula>n 2 χ 2</formula></p>

				<p>&lt; σ ann v &gt; res,f =&lt; Γ(χχ → f ) &gt;=&lt; Γ(χχ → H 1 )B(H 1 → f ) &gt;= n H1 Γ χ K 1 (x H1 ) K 2 (x H1 ) B f , (18) where brackets indicate thermal average, Γ χ is the zero–temperature H 1 annihilation amplitude to neutralinos and the thermal average of this quantity is accounted for by the ratio of modified Bessel functions of the first kind K 1 and K 2 , B f is the H 1 branching ratio to final state f , n i = g i m 3 i K 2 (x i )/(2π 2 x i ) are the equilibrium densities with x i = m i /T , T the temperature, and g i the corresponding internal degrees of freedom, g χ = 2, g H1 =1. The factor of 1/2 in front of Eq.(18) accounts for the identical initial states in the annihilation. From Eq.(18), and summing over final states f , one gets:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>&lt; σ ann v &gt; res = π 2 M 2 H1 m 5 χ x χ K 1 (x H1 ) K 2 2 (x χ ) Γ(H 1 )B χ (1 − B χ )Θ x H1 x χ − 2 , (19)</trash>

					<figDesc>with B χ = Γ χ /Γ(H 1 ) , Γ(H 1 ) the total decay amplitude of H 1 , while Θ is the Heaveside step function [51]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>By making use in Eq.(19) of the approximations K 1 (z) ≃ K 2 (z) ≃ (π/(2z)) 1/2 exp(−z), valid for z ≫ 1, the integral over temperature can be done analytically, leading to: &lt; σ ann v &gt; res ≃</figDesc>
					<trash>4π 2 x f Γ(H 1 ) m 3 χ B χ (1 − B χ ) β χ δ(δ + 1) 2 1 − erf 2(δ − 1)x f , (20) where δ ≡ M H1 /(2m χ ), β χ = √ 1 − δ −2 and erf (x) = 2/ √ π x 0 exp(−t 2 ) dt.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The result of our calculation is shown in Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>, where the neutralino relic abundance Ω χ h 2 is shown as a function of the mass m χ . In this calculation the annihilation cross section has been calculated including the off–resonance contribution to the annihilation cross section.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In this way we have checked that, for m χ &lt; M H1 /2, &lt; σ ann v &gt; res is always the dominant contribution in the calculation of Ω χ h 2 , and Eq.(20) is an excellent approximation of &lt; σ ann v &gt;.</p>

				<p>The off–resonance contribution to the annihilation cross section is also responsible for regularizing the relic density for m χ &gt; M H1 /2, where &lt; σ ann v &gt; res is vanishing. The asymmetric shape of the curve in Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>is due to the fact that thermal motion allows neutralinos with m χ &lt; M H1 /2 to reach the center–of–mass energy needed to create the resonance, while this is not possible for m χ &gt; M H1 /2. In the same figure, the two horizontal lines indicate the range of Eq.(16). The point shown as a circle and indicated as &quot; case A &quot; will be used in the following section as a representative point to calculate some signals.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Fig. 2 the neutralino mass range allowed by cosmology is: 3.15 GeV ≃ m χ ≃ 3.83 GeV. Allowing for the variation of M H1 within the range of Eqs.(12,13), this range is enlarged to:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.93 GeV &lt; ∼ m χ &lt; ∼ 5 GeV. (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this scenario the neutralino relic abundance can fall in the range of Eq.(16) only with some level of tuning at the boundaries of the allowed mass range. For intermediate values of m χ either the neutralino is a sub–dominant component of the DM, or some non–thermal mechanism for its cosmological density needs to be introduced. Of course all our considerations are valid if standard assumptions are made about the evolution of the early Universe (e.g. about the reheating temperature at the end of inflation, the energy budget driving Hubble expansion, entropy production, etc). FIG. 2: Relic abundance as a function of the neutralino mass mχ for the CPX scenario with MH 1 =7.5 GeV, tan β=3, MSUSY=0.5 TeV and ΦA = Φ3 = 90 • . The two horizontal lines indicate the interval of Eq.(16). The circle, where Ωχh 2 = (Ωmh 2 )min, is discussed as &quot; case A &quot; in Section V.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. DARK MATTER SEARCHES</head>

				<p>Neutralinos are CDM particles, and are supposed to clusterize at the galactic level. This implies that they can provide the DM density which is gravitationally measured in our Galaxy. In particular, in this section we will assume for the DM density in the neighborhood of the solar system the reference value ρ 0 = 0.3 GeV/cm 3 . When we compare our calculation of Ω χ h 2 to the interval of Eq.(16), we interpret the lower bound on the DM relic density (Ω m h 2 ) min =0.096 as the average abundance below which the halo density of a specific CDM constituent has to be rescaled as compared to the total CDM halo density. So, whenever Ω χ h 2 &lt; (Ω m h 2 ) min we assume that neutralinos provide a local density ρ χ which is only a fraction of ρ 0 . For the determination of the rescaling factor ξ ≡ ρ χ /ρ 0 we adopt the standard recipe:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ξ = min[1, Ω χ h 2 /(Ω m h 2 ) min ]. (22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Neutralinos in the halo of our Galaxy can be searched for through direct and indirect methods. In particular, CPX light neutralinos are quite hard to detect through direct detection. Direct detection consists in the measurement of the elastic scattering of neutralinos off the nuclei of a low–background detector. For the mass range of Eq.(21), the most stringent upper bound on the neutralino–nucleon coherent elastic cross section σ (nucleon) scalar is provided by the CRESST-1 experiment [32]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, σ (nucleon) scalar &lt; ∼ 10 −38 cm 2 [52]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. This value is much above the cross section expected in our scenario, which falls in the range (σ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(nucleon) scalar ) CP X ≃ 10 −42 cm 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. This is due to the fact that the neutralino-Higgs coupling which dominates this process is suppressed, since tan β is small and χ&apos;s are very pure B-inos due to the large value of |µ|.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Moreover, σ (nucleon) scalar</trash>

					<figDesc>is dominated by the exchange of scalar Higgs bosons, while H 1 is mostly pseudoscalar. Finally, contrary to annihilation, no resonant enhancement is present in the elastic cross section, since scattering proceeds through t–channel.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>For this reason in this section we concentrate on the indirect detection of CPX light neutralinos. In our scenario the neutralino relic density Ω χ h 2 is driven below the observational limit by the resonant enhancement of the annihilation cross section &lt; σ ann v &gt;. The same cross section calculated at present times, &lt; σ ann v &gt; 0 , enters into the calculation FIG. 3: Rescaled, zero–temperature neutralino annihilation cross section to two photons, as a function of mχ. For the solid line the rescaling factor ξ is calculated according to Eq. (22), while for the dashed one ξ = 1. The solid horizontal line shows the corresponding constraint from a search for a γ line from the GC from EGRET [36]. The dashed horizontal line is an estimate for the sensitivity of GLAST [37] for a similar search, when model A − N 2 of Ref.[38] is used to extrapolate HESS data to lower energies. Circle: see caption of Fig. 2. of the annihilation rate of neutralinos in our galaxy. This could produce observable signals, like γ&apos;s, ν&apos;s or exotic components in Cosmic Rays (CR), like antiprotons, positrons, antideuterons. Note, however, that one can have &lt; σ ann v &gt; 0 ≪ &lt; σ ann v &gt;. In fact, as already shown in Section IV, the thermal motion in the early Universe (x χ ≃ x f ≃ 20) allows neutralino resonant annihilation when m χ &lt; M H1 /2. However, for the same neutralinos the contribution of the resonance to &lt; σ ann v &gt; 0 can be negligible at present times, since their temperature in the halo of our Galaxy is of order x χ,0 ≃10 −6 ≪ x f . This implies that the annihilation cross section can be large enough in the early Universe in order to provide the correct relic abundance, but not so large at present times as to drive indirect signals beyond observational limits.</p>

				<p>In the following we will discuss expected signals for γ rays and antiprotons. The results of our analysis are summarized in Figs. 3,4,5 and 6. In all figures observables are calculated in the CPX scenario with M H1 =7.5 GeV, tan β=3, M SUSY =0.5 TeV and Φ A = Φ 3 = 90 • , and plotted as a function of the neutralino mass m χ . The solid lines show our results obtained by adopting the rescaling procedure for the local density explained above, while for comparison, dashed lines are calculated assuming ρ χ = ρ 0 . When rescaling is applied, indirect signals are proportional to the combination ξρ 2 χ &lt; σ ann v &gt; 0 , so they reach their maximum value when Ω χ h 2 = (Ω m h 2 ) min .</p>

				<p>For all our results we have adopted, as a reference model, a Navarro-Frenk-White (NFW) profile for the DM density:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ρ(r) = ρ 0 (r 0 /a) γ [1 + (r 0 /a) α ] (β−γ)/α (r/a) γ [1 + (r/a) α ] (β−γ)/α , (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where r 0 = 8.5 kpc is the distance of the solar system from the Galactic Center (GC), a = 25 kpc is the core radius, while (α, β, γ) = (1, 3, 1).</p>

				<p>FIG. 4: Continuum γ flux from the GC calculated for Eγ=122 MeV. For the solid line the neutralino local density is rescaled according to Eq. (22), while for the dashed one, ξ = 1. The fluxes are compared to the corresponding measurement from EGRET [39], shown as the horizontal solid line. Circle: see caption of Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>A. Gamma flux from the Galactic Center</head>

				<p>In Figs. 3 and 4 we show our results for a γ signal from the GC, which is the most promising source of γ&apos; from neutralino annihilation. Note that signals from the GC are proportional to the line–of–sight integral (i.e., performed on a path pointing from the observer to the γ source) ¯ J ≡ 1/∆Ω l.o.s. ρ 2 χ dl dΩ, where Ω is the pointing angle of observation in the sky and ∆Ω is the experimental angular resolution. The quantity ¯ J is very sensitive to the particular choice of density profile, and may span several orders of magnitude, especially for those models that diverge in the origin, as for the NFW, where a cut–off radius r cut is needed [40]. In particular, in our calculation we use: r cut = 10 −2 pc.</p>

				<p>The γ signal from neutralinos takes two contributions: a line with E γ = m χ , produced by direct annihilation of χ&apos;s to two γ&apos;s, and a continuum, which is mainly due to the annihilation of π 0 &apos;s produced in the fragmentation and decay of other final states (quarks,gluons and τ &apos;s).</p>

				<p>In the first case, the zero–temperature annihilation cross section of neutralinos to photons &lt; σ ann v &gt; 0,γγ is usually suppressed, since it takes place at the one–loop level. However, in our case the contribution of the H 1 resonance, χχ → H 1 → γγ can lead to a strong enhancement of the signal, as is evident from Fig. 3, where our calculation of ξ 2 &lt; σ ann v &gt; 0,γγ is compared to the upper bound (horizontal solid line) on the same quantity from EGRET [36] (such analysis has been performed on a region of 10 • ×10 • around the GC, which, for our assumptions, implies ¯ J ≃ 120 GeV 2 cm −6 kpc). In this figure the solid line shows our result when ξ 2 is calculated according to Eq.(22), while for the dashed line ξ = 1.</p>

				<p>In the same figure we also show with a horizontal dashed line an estimate for the prospect of detection of the same quantity with GLAST (in this case we have assumed an angular resolution of ∆ = 10 −5 sr in the calculation of ¯ J, leading to ¯ J ≃ 2500). This estimate is somewhat uncertain, since HESS [41] has detected a TeV source of γ&apos;s in the GC which is likely to be of standard origin, representing a background for DM searches, and potentially making detection of new physics in that region more difficult [38]. Our estimate of the background is obtained by extrapolating the HESS source to lower energies by using the model A − N 2 described in [38] (we have made the same assumptions also to estimate the horizontal solid line in Fig. 6). Our choice of model A − N 2 is optimistic, FIG. 5: Left: χ 2 calculated for the top–of–atmosphere ¯ p flux compared to the experimental data from BESS and AMS [46] (explicitly shown in the right–hand panel). For the solid line the neutralino local density is rescaled as explained in Section V. For the dashed one, ξ = 1. The solid horizontal line indicates the 99.5 % C.L. upper bound for the χ 2 . The comparison of the χ 2 with its upper limit allows to set an upper bound to mχ, indicated by case B and shown as a triangle. On the other hand the circle indicates case A, introduced in Fig. 2.Right: Top–of–atmosphere antiproton flux as a function of the kinetic TOA energy of ¯ p&apos;s, for the cases A (solid curve) and B (dashes), shown in the left panel as a circle and a triangle, respectively. In both cases the lower curve shows the contribution from primaries produced by neutralino annihilation, while the upper curve is the total flux where the primary contribution is added to the standard secondary one. The 32 experimental points [46]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>are the same that are used to calculate the χ 2 shown in the left–hand panel: full circles: BESS 1995-97; open squares: BESS 1998; stars: AMS.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>since it implies the smallest extrapolated background at low energies among those discussed in [38]. Of course, a more conservative choice for the model adopted to explain the HESS source could make prospects of DM detection for GLAST in the GC much worse. As far as the continuum signal is concerned, we have calculated the γ yield from the final states of neutralino annihilation using PYTHIA [42]. The result of the calculation is shown in Fig. 4, where we have evaluated the γ flux φ γ from the GC for E γ = 122 MeV, and compared it with the corresponding flux measurement from EGRET [39], shown as a horizontal solid line (this particular energy bin is within the range where the data are well fitted by a standard background. In this case the flux has been measured in an angular region of 10 • ×4 • around the GC, which corresponds, for our choice of parameters, to ¯ J ≃ 184 GeV 2 cm −6 kpc).</p>

				<p>From Figs. 3,4 we can conclude that, with reasonable choices for the DM density profile, γ signals in our scenario are compatible with observations. In both figures we have indicated with a circle the point indicated as &quot; case A &quot; in Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B. Antiproton flux</head>

				<p>As far as light neutralinos are concerned, a particularly stringent limit is provided by the flux of primary antiprotons that are produced from the hadronization of neutralino–annihilation final states [43, 44, 45]. This is due to the fact that the ¯ p flux observed experimentally is quite in agreement with that expected from ¯ p secondary production from cosmic rays [46], so that not much room is left for exotic contributions. Moreover, as all other annihilation processes, the primary neutralino signal scales with the neutralino number density ∝ 1/m 2 χ , so it is enhanced for light masses. However, once they are produced in the DM halo, primary ¯ p&apos;s interact with the magnetic field of the Galaxy, and a complex propagation model is needed in order to calculate the fraction of them that reaches the Earth. Unfortunately, the main parameters of the propagation model are fixed by using secondary CR data (such as the B/C ratio) which</p>

				<p><formula>0.1 1 10 0.0001 0.001 A B</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 6: Expected signal for GLAST [37] for a gamma continuum flux from the Galactic Center as a function of the γ energy for the cases A (solid curve) and B (dashes) indicated in Fig. 2, 3 and 4 as a circle and a triangle, respectively. The horizontal line is an estimate of the background for GLAST (see text).</p>

				<p>mainly depend on the galactic disk, while primary ¯ p&apos;s from neutralino annihilation are produced in the galactic halo. This induces uncertainties in the primary flux as large as two orders of magnitude [44]. In particular, for our analysis we have used the public code provided by Ref. [45] for the ¯ p propagation. Although the code of Ref. [45] is a simplified one, where in particular energy–redistribution effects are neglected, it serves well our needs for checking the viability of our scenario. In the left panel of Fig. 5 we show the χ 2 calculated by comparing the sum of the primary and secondary top-of-atmosphere (TOA) ¯ p fluxes to the experimental data from BESS and AMS. In particular, for the calculation of the χ 2 we have used the same 32 data points from BESS 1995-97, BESS 1998 and AMS 1998 [46] shown in the right panel. For our calculation we have used a solar modulation parameter φ= 500 MV, corresponding to the period of minimal solar activity when these experiments have taken data. Moreover, in order to be conservative, we have used the minimal propagation model in Table III of Ref. [45]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, i.e. δ=0.85, K 0 =0.0016 kpc 2 Myr −1 , L=1 kpc, V c =13.5</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>km/s and V A = 22.4 km/s for the propagation parameters δ and K 0 , for the size of the diffusion zone L, and for the galactic wind V c . In absence of a SUSY contribution we find χ 2 ≃30, which confirms the good agreement between the data and the standard secondary production (for this latter flux we use the quantity calculated in [45]).</p>

				<p>As a conservative upper bound for the χ 2 we take χ 2 = 60, which for 32 degrees of freedom implies a statistical disagreement at the level of 99.5 %. This value is shown in Fig. 5 as a solid horizontal line.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>From Fig. 5</head>

				<p>one can see that, even when the rescaled neutralino local density is used, the χ 2 from ¯ p data exceeds 60 for m χ ≃ 3.77 GeV. This values for the neutralino mass is indicated with a triangle (case B), along with the circle which indicates case A introduced in Fig. 2. Both cases are shown in the right–hand panel, where the upper curves show the total ¯ p fluxes, while the lower curves show the SUSY contributions.</p>

				<p>From the discussion of this section, where m H1 =7.5 GeV and tan β=3, we obtain for m χ the allowed range: 3.15 GeV &lt; ∼ m χ &lt; ∼ 3.77 GeV. The boundaries of this range correspond to the cases A and B introduced previously. Assuming for M H1 and tan β the range of Eqs. (12, 13) this interval for m χ is enlarged to 2.93 GeV &lt; ∼ m χ &lt; ∼ 5 GeV. We conclude this section by showing and example for the prospects of detection for cases A and B in future DM searches: in Fig. 6</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>the γ continuum flux from the GC is estimated for GLAST (we have assumed here an angular resolution of ∆ = 10 −5 sr in the calculation of ¯ J, leading to ¯ J ≃ 2500). This flux is compared to an estimate of the background for the same detector, shown as a horizontal line, calculated with the same assumptions as in Fig. 3,</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>where model A − N 2 of Ref.[38] is used to extrapolate HESS data to lower energies.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>VI. CONCLUSIONS</head>

				<p>In the present paper we have discussed the lower bound to the lightest Higgs boson H 1 in the MSSM with explicit CP violation, and the phenomenology of the lightest relic neutralino in the same scenario. In particular, we have examined the parameter space region M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV and 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 10, in the CPX scenario, an interval which has not been excluded by the combined searches of the four LEP collaborations. We find that the combination of experimental constraints coming from Thallium EDM measurements and quorkonium decays restricts the region allowed by LEP to: 7 GeV &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 7.5 GeV, tan β ≃ 3. In this range, the branching ratio B(B s → µµ) is compatible to the present experimental upper bounds provided some moderate cancellation is allowed between the stop–loop contribution and that of other squarks. Furthermore, the allowed parameter space can be relaxed to 7 GeV &lt; ∼ M H1 &lt; ∼ 10 GeV and 3 &lt; ∼ tan β &lt; ∼ 5 if a cancellation less severe than 1 part in 10 is also assumed in Thallium EDM between two–loop contributions and, for example, those depending from first– and second–generation phases. For the above choice of parameters and assuming a departure from the usual GUT relation among gaugino masses (|M 1 | ≪ |M 2 |) we find that neutralinos with 2.9 GeV &lt; ∼ m χ &lt; ∼ 5 GeV can be viable DM candidates. We refer to them as CPX light neutralinos. In particular, in the CPX scenario the neutralino is a very pure B-ino configuration, suppressing its Higgs–mediated cross sections. However, through resonant annihilation to H 1 the thermal relic density of neutralinos with m χ ≃ M H1 /2 can be either tuned within the range compatible to WMAP or virtually erased, allowing for alternative non-thermal mechanisms. The cosmologically allowed range for m χ extends to mχ &lt; ∼ M H1 /2 due to the effect of thermal motion in the early Universe. We also have discussed the phenomenology of CPX light neutralinos, showing that signals for indirect Dark Matter searches are compatible with the present experimental constraints, as long as m χ &lt; ∼ M H1 /2. On the other hand, part of the range m χ &gt; ∼ M H1 /2 allowed by cosmology is excluded by antiproton fluxes.</p>

				<p>Finally, we note that our study shares some generic features with other models such as the next–to–minimal supersymmetric model (NMSSM), in which a light Higgs boson may escape LEP searches and the observed amount of DM is explained through neutralino resonant annihilation [47, 48].</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> φ 1 1 + O 2 a1 ) 2 .</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>The work of J.S.L. was supported in part by the Korea Research Foundation (KRF) and the Korean Federation of Science and Technology Societies Grant and in part by the KRF grant KRF–2005–084–C00001 funded by the Korea Government (MOEHRD, Basic Research Promotion Fund). S.S. would like to thank A. Bottino for useful discussions.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>For</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">See</forename>
				<surname>Recent Reviews</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J H</forename>
				<surname>For</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Chung</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Everett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Kane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>King</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Lykken</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rept</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">407</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Rept</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page">195</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Spergel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">arXiv:hep-ph/9508249]</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Berezinsky</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bottino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Mignola</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Scopel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Astropart</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J R</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Olive</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Santoso</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Spanos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<editor>M. Battaglia, A. De Roeck, J. R. Ellis, F. Gianotti, K. A. Olive and L. Pape</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">273</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>arXiv. :hep-ph/0306219]; R. Arnowitt, B. Dutta and B</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">88</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E M S Y</forename>
				<surname>Wagner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Choi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Drees</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B Phys. Rev. D Phys. Lett. B Nucl. Phys. B Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<editor>3</editor>
		<editor>D.A. Demir 57</editor>
		<editor>M. Carena, J. Ellis, A. Pilaftsis and C.E.M. Wagner M. Carena, J. Ellis, A. Pilaftsis and C.E.M. Wagner</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">553</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">625</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">345</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Heinemeyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Frank</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hahn</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Heinemeyer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Hollik</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Rzehak</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Weiglein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Phys. J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Accomando</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pilaftsis, Mod. Phys. Lett. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1405</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Ibrahim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S W</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Ham</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Oh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Yoo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Son</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">055003</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Nihei</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">035005</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Belanger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Boudjema</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Kraml</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pukhov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Semenov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">115007</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Gondolo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Freese</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page">052</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bottino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Donato</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Scopel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">043506</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Carena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E M</forename>
				<surname>Wagner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">495</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">155</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bottino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Scopel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">063519</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Carena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Y</forename>
				<surname>Choi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Drees</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E M</forename>
				<surname>Wagner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Phys. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">156</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">283</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">49 [arXiv:hep-ex/0406057]; OPAL Physics Note PN505</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Abbiendi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Abdallah et al. [DELPHI Collaboration]</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>pn505. .html; A. Heister et al.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Achard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">545</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">30</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>L3. Collaboration]. Bechtle. in Ref. [7]</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Schumacher In Ref</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Khriplovich</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Lamoreaux</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CP Violation Without Strangeness</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">For a recent review, see, M. Pospelov and A. Ritz, Annals Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">318</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Regan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Commins</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Schmidt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Demille</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">071805</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">For two-loop Higgs-mediated contributions to EDMs in the CP-violating MSSM, see D</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Keung and A</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chang, W</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">82 (1999) 900; A. Pilaftsis</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Rev</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<editor>263</editor>
		<editor>D. A. Demir, O. Lebedev, K. A. Olive, M. Pospelov and A. Ritz 339</editor>
		<editor>K. A. Olive, M. Pospelov, A. Ritz and Y. Santoso</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">644</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">680</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0506106</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Lee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">095006</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Higgs Hunter&apos;s Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Gunion</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Haber</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Kane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Dawson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>Perseus Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Franzini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2883</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Balest</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CLEO Collaboration] Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2053</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Ibrahim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Nath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">016005</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Abulencia</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CDF Collaboration] Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221805" to="249905" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">[arXiv:hep-ex</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Acosta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett.CDF Collaboration] Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<editor>A. Abulencia et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="032001" to="071802" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Dedes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Pilaftsis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">015012</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Kolb</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Turner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Addison Wesley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Gondolo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Gelmini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">360</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">145</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Jochum</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. Proc. Phys. Atom. Nucl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">521</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Bernabei</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Riv. Nuovo Cim</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bottino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Donato</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Scopel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">037302</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Bernabei</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Mod. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1445</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Pullen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Chary</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kamionkowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">See</forename>
				<surname>For Instance</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Zaharijas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Hooper</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103501</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Hunger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Astrophys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">481</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">205</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Pieri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Scopel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103529</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Aharonian</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The HESS Collaboration] Astron. Astrophys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">425</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Sjostrand</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Mrenna</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Skands</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">026</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bottino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Donato</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Scopel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">015005</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bottino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Donato</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fornengo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Salati</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>Bottino, F. Donato, N. Fornengo and P. Salati</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">589804137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123503" to="083518" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">arXiv:astro-ph/0609522. To calculate the ¯ p propagation we have used the code provided by the authors at the link</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Maurin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Taillet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Combet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">[arXiv:astro-ph/9906426]</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Orito</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BESS Collaboration Phys. Rev. Lett.BESS Collaboration], Astropart. Phys.AMS Collaboration], Phys. Rept</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1078" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Ferrer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Krauss</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Profumo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Gunion</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Hooper</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Mcelrath</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<editor>R. Dermisek, J. F. Gu- nion and B. McElrath</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">015011</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Following the calculation in Ref. [29], one might get a different expression than that of Eq. (14), in that the branching ratio would scale as: (O [50] To be consistent with the the present B(Bs → µµ) limit, one may take a point in the region</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>above. thê B(Bs → µµ</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">1 where one needs a cancellation in the Thallium EDM. We note that an appropriate choice of the phases ΦA e,µ , ΦA d,s always allows to make the parameter region of Eq. (13) consistent with the Thallium EDM constraint when ρ ≃ 0.9. We keep Eq. (12) as our reference point</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">line in Fig</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>assuming. cancellation in B(Bs → µµ</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">larger than the corresponding expression calculated in [31] We explain this discrepancy with the fact that in [31] the Breit–Wigner expression of the cross section, Eq.(6.1), should be a factor 2 larger, to compensate for a factor 1/2 contained in the decay amplitude of the resonance to 2 (identical) neutralinos [52] We remind that the DAMA Collaboration measures an annual modulation effect [33], compatible to what expected by relic neutralinos in some supersymmetric models</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>or. by other dark matter candidates [35]. The model discussed in the present paper provides elastic cross-sections too low to explain the DAMA modulation effect</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
