<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Strings and D-branes in a supersymmetric magnetic flux background</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2007-07-11">11 Jul 2007</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Roberto</forename>
								<surname>Iengo</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">International School for Advanced Studies (SISSA)</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Sezione di Trieste</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">INFN</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Via Beirut 2-4</addrLine>
									<postCode>I-34013</postCode>
									<settlement>Trieste</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Jaume</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Lopez</forename>
								<surname>Carballo</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Departament ECM</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Facultat de Física</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitatdeBarcelona</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Jorge</forename>
								<forename type="middle">G</forename>
								<surname>Russo</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Departament ECM</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Facultat de Física</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UniversitatdeBarcelona</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">InstitucióCatalanadeRecercaiEstudisAvançats(ICREA)</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Strings and D-branes in a supersymmetric magnetic flux background</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2007-07-11">11 Jul 2007</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>UB-ECM-PF/07/14 hep-th/yymmnnn</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We investigate how the presence of RR magnetic F p+2 fluxes affects the energy of classical Dp branes, for specific string theory supersymmetric backgrounds which are solutions to the leading order in α ′ including back-reaction effects. The Dp brane dynamics is found to be similar to the well known dynamics of particles and strings moving in magnetic fields. We find a class of BPS solutions which generalize the BPS fundamental strings or BPS branes with momentum and winding to the case of non-zero magnetic fields. Remarkably, the interaction with the magnetic fields does not spoil the supersymmetry of the solution, which turns out to be invariant under four supersymmetry transformations. We find that magnetic fields can significantly reduce the energy of some BPS strings and Dp branes, in particular, some macroscopic Dp branes become light for sufficiently large magnetic fields.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Introduction</head>

				<p>Flux compactifications in string theory stabilize the moduli and presently provide the main framework to connect strings to the real world [1, 2]. The fluxes induce a non-trivial potential energy for the moduli. In addition, the fluxes can significantly affect the energy spectrum of some quantum states. The precise modification of the energy of a given quantum state depends on the particular string compactification, but there are some general features which are part of the well known physics of particles interacting with magnetic fields. In quantum theory, the energy of a state with electric charge e and spin S moving in a magnetic field is given by the formula</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E 2 = k 2 i + 2eB z (l + 1 2 − S z ) , l = 0, 1, 2, ... , −S ≤ S Z ≤ S . (1.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For states with spin aligned with the magnetic fields, the energy is reduced and the state can even become tachyonic for certain values of the magnetic field, leading to instabilities. A natural question is whether analogous instabilities could be present in superstring theory in spaces containing NSNS or RR magnetic fluxes turned on in some directions. In the context of type II string theory, there are exactly solvable models where the magnetic field originates by Kaluza-Klein reduction from the metric or from the antisymmetric tensor B µν [3]. These models include gravitational back reaction effects due to the energy density of the magnetic field, and exhibit tachyonic instabilities for magnetic fields greater than some critical values [3, 4, 5]. It is possible to consider similar closed string models with magnetic field configurations that preserve supersymmetry [6]. In this case the physical string spectrum is tachyon free. Nevertheless, one can expect that for certain values of the magnetic field, the energy can be significantly reduced due to a negative contribution from the gyromagnetic interaction, so that a macroscopic string of size ≫ l s can even become light, E ∼ l −1 s .</p>

				<p>In this paper we will show that this is indeed the case and study the analog phenomenon for Dp branes. To this aim, we will consider a string-theory background with a RR magnetic F p+2 flux which is obtained by S and T-dualities from the magnetic background found in [6]. This background has two magnetic parameters B 1 , B 2 . When B 1 = B 2 , the background preserves 1/2 of the 32 supersymmetries. We will find classical string and Dp brane configurations becoming light for certain values of the magnetic field parameters B 1 , B 2 . Remarkably, these solutions are BPS, despite the interaction with the magnetic field. The solutions break an additional fraction 1/4 of the 16 supersymmetries of the background and therefore are invariant under 4 supersymmetry transformations. Studies of Dp brane classical solutions in flat space can be found for example in [7] and more recently [8]. Different studies of the conditions to have supersymmetric Dp branes in some supersymmetric compactifications with Ramond-Ramond (RR) fluxes are in [9, 10, 11].</p>

				<p>The organization of this paper is as follows. In Sect. 2.1 we review the string spectrum in a particular flat (but globally non-trivial) background which gives rise to a magnetic field by Kaluza- Klein reduction; we recall the supersymmetry properties of the background and the presence of tachyons when supersymmetry is broken (the main points of this quantum analysis are reviewed in the Appendix A). In Sect. 2.1.1 we identify BPS states for the supersymmetric background with B 1 = B 2 . In Sect. 2.2 we construct a family of classical solutions which corresponds to BPS states by solving the classical equations of motion. In Sect. 2.3 we show that these classical solutions indeed preserve a fraction of supersymmetry, by using both cartesian and polar coordinates. In Sect. 3.1 we study the background obtained by a T-duality transformation; this background contains explicitly a B µν field and the metric is curved due to the back reaction produced by the magnetic energy density. The spectrum, and in particular the BPS states, are obtained from Sect. 2.1 by the standard T-duality rules. In Sect. 3.2 we consider a family of classical solutions corresponding to the BPS states by solving the classical equations in the background of Sect. 3.1 by using the Polyakov formalism. In Sect. 3.3 we repeat this computation using the Nambu-Goto formalism; this is done in preparation for the study of classical Dp-branes solutions, whose dynamics is governed by the Dirac-Born-Infeld action. In fact, in the case of the Dp-branes, studied in Sect.4, the method and the various steps for obtaining the solutions will be seen to be essentially the same. We find a family of BPS classical solutions, the energy spectrum being a generalization of the BPS spectrum in the magnetic background discussed in Sect. 3. One important feature of the result is the presence of light states which have macroscopic features. This result is further discussed in Sect. 5. Finally, in the Appendix B we consider another family of classical F-string solutions in the background of Sect. 3 (or, equivalently, D-string solutions in the background of Sect. 4). These solutions, although not BPS, are nevertheless interesting because they generalize to a non-flat background with fluxes the widely studied case of the folded rotating string.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Fundamental string in magnetic backgrounds 2.1 Magnetic fields from Kaluza-Klein reduction</head>

				<p>We shall consider a simple magnetic string model given in terms of the background [6]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = −dt 2 + dx 2 s + dy 2 + dr 2 1 + r 2 1 (dϕ 1 + B 1 dy) 2 + dr 2 2 + r 2 2 (dϕ 2 + B 2 dy) 2 , (2.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where all other supergravity fields are trivial and s = 6, ..., 9. This is an exact conformal string model, since the metric is flat. It is globally non-trivial, due to the fact that y is a periodic coordinate, y = y + 2πR. The background preserves 1/2 of the 32 supersymmetries provided</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B 1 = ±B 2 . (2.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The string model is a simple generalization of the non-supersymmetric string model with B 2 = 0 that was solved in [3]. The exact physical string spectrum is found in a similar way and it is given by [6]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α ′ M 2 = 2(N L + N R ) + α ′ ( n R − B 1 J 1 − B 2 J 2 ) 2 + m 2 R 2 α ′ − 2B 1 Rm(J 1R − J 1L ) − 2B 2 Rm(J 2R − J 2L ) , N R − N L = mn , (2.3) where B 1 and B 2 are in the interval 0 ≤ γ 1,2 &lt; 1, γ 1,2 ≡ B 1,2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Rm. For other intervals the spectrum is repeated periodically in the parameters γ 1,2 with period 1. The angular momentum operators for the two planes (r 1 , ϕ 1 ) and (r 2 , ϕ 2 ) are given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>J = J R + J L , J L,R = ± l L,R + 1 2 + S L,R , (2.4) where for the sake of clarity we omitted the obvious indices 1,2. N L,R = 0, 1, 2, .... are the standard excitation number operators of flat-space type II superstring theory and S L,R are the standard Left and</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Right contributions to the flat-space spin operator (the main points of the derivation are reported in the Appendix A, see [3] for details). The parameters l L,R = 0, 1, 2, ... are orbital angular momenta (Landau numbers). The parameters m, n represent winding and momentum in the y direction. If there are other compact coordinates among the x s , then their winding and momentum contributions to the energy is added in the standard way as in the flat case. The spin operators satisfy the inequalities</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S 1L,R + S 2L,R ≤ N L,R + 1 , S 1L,R − S 2L,R ≤ N L,R + 1 . (2.5) One finds that M 2 ≥ 0 for B 1 = ±B 2 (see Appendix A), but The spectrum contains tachyons in some regions of the parameter space [3, 6], if B 1 = ±B 2 . For example, consider a state with the following quantum numbers: N R = N L = 0 , S 1R = −S 1L = 1 , S 2R = S 2L = 0 , l 1L,R = l 2L,R = 0 , m = 1 , n = 0 , (2.6) so that J 1 = J 2 = 0 , J 1R − J 1L = 1 , J 2R − J 2L = −1 and α ′ M 2 = R 2 α ′ − 2(B 1 − B 2 )R . (2.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The state becomes tachyonic for B 1 − B 2 &gt; R/(2α ′ ). In the case B 1 = B 2 , the full spectrum is tachyon free for any B 1 , consistently with supersymmetry. Another example is a state classically identical to the BPS state discussed below, see Sects.2.1.1 and 2.2. In Appendix A we show that, for instance for B 2 = 0, this state can have M 2 &lt; 0 in some parameters range. For B 2 = B 1 (taking here both positive) the positive zero point energy of the Landau levels in the plane 2 (a quantum effect of the sigma model) insures that M 2 ≥ 0. Therefore the classical analysis, that would give M 2 as a sum of contributions ≥ 0, is not enough to guaranty the absence of tachyons, if supersymmetry is completely broken. However, this occurs when in parameters regions where the classical result for the mass is microscopic, that is of the order of the inverse string length or of the inverse compactification radius. Most of the present paper is devoted to the study of states having macroscopic features but microscopic mass. Those are precisely the cases which could give rise to tachyonic instabilities, if they are not protected by supersymmetry. In [12, 13] the D brane spectra in the background (2.1) has been determined by using the boundary state formalism, exhibiting a number of interesting features (the orientifold spectrum was studied in [14]). In section 4, instead, we will be interested in studying Dp branes not in (2.1), but in backgrounds containing F p+2 fluxes, which are obtained from (2.1) by dualities. The spectrum, and the physics in general, are clearly different in each case, the former [12, 13] being analogous to a neutral particle (or zero-winding string) moving in the geometry (2.1) (and on the curved-space generalization discussed in section 3), whereas the latter (section 4) involves a physics which is similar to that of a charged particle moving in a magnetic field.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.1.1">BPS states</head>

				<p>In the B 1 = B 2 = 0 case, an important class of quantum string states are the BPS string states with [15]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N L = 0 , N R = mn . (2.8) Then M 2 becomes a perfect square: α ′ M 2 BPS = 2mn + α ′ n 2 R 2 + m 2 R 2 α ′ = α ′ n R + mR α ′ 2 , (2.9) or M BPS = n R + mR α ′ . (2.10) Note that mn = N R &gt; 0. When mn &lt; 0, there are BPS states with N R = 0, N L = −mn for which M BPS = n R − mR α ′ = n R + mR α ′ . (2.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We now look for similar supersymmetric states in the presence of magnetic fields B 1 , B 2 . We will restrict to the case B 1 = B 2 ≡ B where the background preserves 16 supersymmetries. The</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>state (2.8) has the energy α ′ M 2 = 2mn + α ′ n 2 R 2 + m 2 R 2 α ′ − 2Bα ′ n R (J 1 + J 2 ) − 2BmR(J 1R + J 2R − J 1L − J 2L ) + α ′ B 2 (J 1 + J 2 ) 2 . (2.12) This becomes a perfect square if J 1 + J 2 = J 1R + J 2R − J 1L − J 2L , i.e., S 1L + S 2L = −1 − l 1L − l 2L . (2.13) Since N L = 0, S 1,2L can be zero or ±1 and |S 1L + S 2L | ≤ 1. This implies l 1L = l 2L = 0 and the following possible values: (S 1L , S 2L ) = (−1, 0) or (0, −1) . (2.14) Then we get M 2 BPS = n R + mR α ′ − B(J 1 + J 2 ) 2 . (2.15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Remarkably, the mass square is a perfect square which indicates that the state is still supersymmetric despite the presence of the magnetic fields. It is worth noting that in the case B 1 = B 2 , M 2 is not a perfect square. Moreover, the state can become tachyonic above some critical magnetic field. Assume for definiteness B &gt; 0, m, n &gt; 0. Taking into account the fact that mRB &lt;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 and (J 1 + J 2 ) ≤ N R = mn, one can see that n R − B(J 1 + J 2 ) &gt; 0 and therefore eq. (2.15) can be written as M BPS = |m|R α ′ + n R − B(J 1 + J 2 ) . (2.16)</trash>

					<figDesc>This form will be suitable for comparison with the energy of classical strings.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The effect of the magnetic field on a quantum state with spin aligned with the magnetic field is to reduce its energy. The maximum reduction is attained for the state with maximum spin S 1R + S 2R = N R + 1 and l 1,2R = 0, so that J 1 + J 2 = N R = nm. For this state</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M BPS = |m|R α ′ + n R − Bmn . (2.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The minimum mass occurs when B approaches the limit of the interval,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>BRm → 1, where M BPS → |m|R α ′ . (2.18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Assuming that R is of the same order of magnitude as α ′ , this implies that there are states with very large n and small m which become light (mass of O(R/α ′ )) at some magnetic field. Such states have a macroscopic mass = O(n/R) ≫</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>√ α ′ in the absence of magnetic fields. This result can be understood from the periodicity of the spectrum: the full quantum string spectrum at BRm → 1 is the same as the spectrum at B = 0, with some relabelling of the states. In the coordinate system where the metric becomes Minkowski at B = 0, a given large classical string becomes very light, E ∼ 1/l s , as BRm approaches 1. But when BRm → 1 the metric approaches the Minkowski metric in another coordinate system where the polar coordinate is ϕ</figDesc>
					<trash>′ 1,2 = ϕ 1,2 + y/mR. The energy (2.18) then corresponds to a state with n ′ = 0 and orbital angular momentum (see sect 2.2). 2.2 Classical BPS solution There is an exponential number = O exp(2 √ 2π √ N R ) of</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>quantum states satisfying the condition N R = mn, N L = 0. A particular class of classical solutions representing a small subset of these states is given by</figDesc>
					<trash>Z 1 = r 1 e iϕ1 = X 1 + iX 2 = L 1 e ik1σ+iω1τ , Z 2 = r 2 e iϕ2 = X 3 + iX 4 = L 2 e ik2σ+iω2τ , t = κτ , y = mRσ + qτ . (2.19) where 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>≤ σ &lt; 2π and m, k 1 , k 2 are integer numbers. When k 1 = k 2 = 1, these solutions represent the states with maximum angular momentum having S 1R + S 2R = N R + 1.</p>

				<p>In section 2.3, we will show that these solutions are indeed supersymmetric. Classically, the condition (2.14) does not appear, since it arises due to normal ordering terms. The classical string description applies when N R , J R ≫ 1 and S 1,2L = −1 becomes negligible.</p>

				<p>In this subsection we will reproduce the energy (2.16) of the quantum string states for the cases of the circular BPS ( &quot; chiral &quot; ) string (2.19). The Polyakov action is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = − 1 4πα ′ dσdτ − ∂ α t∂ α t + ∂ α y∂ α y + r 2 1 ∂ α ϕ 1 + B 1 ∂ α y ∂ α ϕ 1 + B 1 ∂ α y + r 2 2 ∂ α ϕ 2 + B 2 ∂ α y ∂ α ϕ 2 + B 2 ∂ α y . (2.20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here the indices α are contracted with the world-sheet metric h αβ = diag(−1, 1). Then the string equations of motion are automatically satisfied provided</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(k a + B a mR) = ±(ω a + B a q) , a = 1, 2 , (2.21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which follow from the r a equations of motion assuming that both L 1 , L 2 are different from zero.</p>

				<p>In addition, from the Virasoro constraints, we get the following conditions</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>mRq + 2 a=1 L 2 a (k a + B a mR)(ω a + B a q) = 0 , (2.22) κ 2 = m 2 R 2 + q 2 + 2 a=1 L 2 a (k a + B a mR) 2 + (ω a + B a q) 2 . (2.23) Combining these equations, we find κ 2 = (mR ± q) 2 + 2 a=1 L 2 a (k a + B a mR) ± (ω a + B a q) 2 . (2.24) Using (2.21), this gives κ 2 = (mR ± q) 2 , (2.25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the plus sign holds for the solution with (k a + B a mR) = −(ω a + B a q) (the &quot; Right &quot; circular string) whereas the minus sign holds for the solution with (k a + B a mR) = (ω a + B a q) (the &quot; Left &quot; circular string). Now we would like to express the energy in terms of the physical conserved quantum numbers J 1 , J 2 and m, n.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>We have E = 2π 0 dσ δS δ(∂ τ t) = − 1 α ′ κ , J a = 2π 0 dσ δS δ(∂ τ ϕ a ) = L 2 a α ′ (ω a + B a q) , n R = 2π 0 dσ δS δ(∂ τ y) = 1 α ′ q + L 2 1 B 1 (ω 1 + B 1 q) + L 2 2 B 2 (ω 2 + B 2 q) . (2.26) Using (2.25) we find E = |m|R α ′ + n R − B 1 J 1 − B 2 J 2 , (2.27)</trash>

					<figDesc>reproducing exactly the result (2.16) of the quantum string spectrum, upon setting B 1 = B 2 .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>As mentioned in the previous subsection, for some parameters, there are states that have macroscopic features but have microscopic energy. Take for instance a string in the plane 1 that is L 2 = J 2 = 0 with m = 1, n large and mRB 1 = 1 − 1/n, m, n &gt; 0 (inside the periodicity interval).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Choosing k 1 = −1 and using (2.21) and (2.26) we get J 1 = mn and E = mR α ′ + n R 1 − B 1 mR = mR α ′ + 1 R . (2.28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The energy is microscopic for R ∼ √ α ′ but the string is large in the non compact space: from (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2.26) one finds L 2 1 = α ′ J 1 k 1 + mRB 1 = J 2 1 α ′ (mn − mRB 1 J 1 ) (2.29) which gives L 2 1 = mn 2 α ′ ≫ α ′ for this state. In a coordinate system ϕ ′ 1 = ϕ 1</trash>

					<figDesc>+ y/mR the string state that has energy (2.28) corresponds to a small string with orbital angular momentum in a large orbit. More generally, for any BPS state one can choose coordinates ϕ</figDesc>
					<trash>′ 1 = ϕ 1 − k 1 y/mR so that B ′ 1 = B 1 + k 1 /(</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Rm) and the new classical solution is represented by the ansatz ϕ</figDesc>
					<trash>′ 1 = ω ′ 1 τ , therefore k ′ 1 = 0, with the same J ′ 1 = J 1 , m</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>′ = m and zero momentum along y, i.e. n ′ = 0. It represents a string extended only in the compact dimension y, and looking like a particle on a large cyclotron orbit with radius L 1 in the non-compact space. In this solution, instead of a large size we get a large radius of the orbit. This is in agreement with the periodicity of the spectrum mentioned in Sect. 2.1.1. Later we will be interested in the case of Dp branes in a background with a RR F p+2 flux where the full quantum spectrum is not known and it is not clear whether the spectrum can have any periodicity.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.3">Supersymmetry</head>

				<p>In this section we will prove that the circular strings (2.19) with B 1 = B 2 preserve a fraction 1/4 of the 16 supersymmetries of the background (2.1). As shown in [6]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, the background with B 1 = B 2 preserves 16 supersymmetries satisfying the condition (1 − Γ 1234 )ε = 0 , (2.30) where Γ 1234 = Γ 1 Γ 2 Γ 3 Γ 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and Γ µ are the ten-dimensional Dirac matrices, {Γ µ , Γ ν } = 2g µν . As we will see below, Γ 1234 = γ 1234 where γ µ are the Minkowski space Dirac matrices, {γ µ , γ ν } = 2η µν .</p>

				<p>In type IIA theory, for the circular string (2.19) with winding and momentum we will find in addition two conditions:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>γ 05 ε = ∓ε , γ 05 γ 11 ε = −ε . (2.31)</trash>

					<figDesc>The minus or plus sign arise for the Right or Left circular string (they are related to the signs in κ 2 = (mR ± q)). From these conditions we conclude that the circular string of section 2.2 preserves 1/4 supersymmetries of the background, leaving four unbroken supersymmetries. The reduction of 1/4 is due to the presence of two charges, winding (fundamental string charge) and momentum (the &quot; wave &quot; ). Remarkably, the conditions (2.31) are the same conditions that one obtains in the B 1 = B 2 = 0 case, so the interaction with the magnetic background does not break any additional supersymmetry. There is only a reduction by a factor 1/2 because the background B 1 = B 2 itself preserves 1/2 of the 32 supersymmetries of the type IIA theory.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="1">A classical</head>

				<p>string solution is supersymmetric if there exist covariantly constant (Killing) spinors ε such that [16, 17] Γε = ε , (2.32) where Γ is the κ-symmetry matrix [18], which in the type IIA theory is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ = 1 − det G αβ ˙ X µ X ′ ν Γ µν γ 11 , Γ µν = 1 2 [Γ µ , Γ ν ] , (2.33) and G αβ = ∂ α X µ ∂ β X ν g µν . We begin by using Cartesian coordinates. The matrices Γ µ must satisfy the Dirac algebra {Γ µ , Γ ν } = 2g µν for the metric (2.1), which in Cartesian coordinates becomes, ds 2 = −dt 2 + dx 2 s + 1 + B 2 1 (x 2 1 + x 2 2 ) + B 2 2 (x 2 3 + x 2 4 ) dx 2 5 + dx 2 1 + dx 2 2 + dx 2 3 + dx 2 4 + 2B 1 x 1 dx 2 dx 5 − 2B 1 x 2 dx 1 dx 5 + 2B 2 x 3 dx 4 dx 5 − 2B 2 x 4 dx 3 dx 5 , (2.34) where i = 6, . . . , 9. The Dirac matrices are given by Γ µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>= γ µ , µ = 5 , Γ 5 = γ 5 + B 1 x 1 γ 2 − x 2 γ 1 + B 2 x 3 γ 4 − x 4 γ 3 . (2.35) Consider the solution (2.19) (t ≡ X 0 , y ≡ X 5 ) X 0 = κτ , X 5 = mRσ + qτ ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X 1 = L 1 cos(k 1 σ + ω 1 τ ) , X 2 = L 1 sin(k 1 σ + ω 1 τ ) , X 3 = L 2 cos(k 2 σ + ω 2 τ ) , X 4 = L 2 sin(k 2 σ + ω 2 τ ) . (2.36)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We now consider eq. (2.33). Making use of the results of the previous subsection 2.2, the determinant of the induced metric can be written as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− det G αβ = m 2 R 2 + 2 a=1 L 2 a k a + mRB a 2 . (2.37) and ˙ X µ X ′ ν Γ µν = −κk 1 x 2 Γ 01 + κk 1 x 1 Γ 02 − κk 2 x 4 Γ 03 + κk 2 x 3 Γ 04 + κmRΓ 05 + x 1 Γ 25 − x 2 Γ 15 ω 1 mR − k 1 q + x 3 Γ 45 − x 4 Γ 35 ω 2 mR − k 2 q . = κmRγ 05 + 2 a=1 x 2a−1 κ(k a + mRB a )γ 0 2a + (ω a mR − k a q)γ 2a 5 − 2 a=1 x 2a κ(k a + mRB a )γ 0 2a−1 + (ω a mR − k a q)γ 2a−1 5 . (2.38) Hence, the supersymmetry condition (2.33) becomes Aγ 05 − 2 a=1 ǫ ij x 2a−i P a γ 0 2a−j + Q a γ 2a−j 5 γ 11 ε = ε , i, j = 0, 1 , (2.39) where ǫ ij is the complete antisymmetric Levi-Civita symbol, with ǫ 01 = 1 and A = κmR − det G αβ , P a = κ(k a + mRB a ) − det G αβ , Q a = ω a mR − k a q − det G αβ . (2.40) If we chose a constant spinor, ε = ε 0 , eq. (2.39) implies Aγ 05 γ 11 ε 0 = ε 0 , (2.41) (P a γ 0b + Q a γ b5 )γ 11 ε 0 = 0 , a = 1, 2 , b = 1, . . . , 4 . (2.42)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first equation will leave half of the supersymmetries of the background if, and only if, A = ±1. Multiplying the second condition by γ b5 from the left we end up with</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(P a γ 05 − Q a )γ 11 ε 0 = 0 , (2.43) which requires P a = ±Q a . The classical string solution must therefore satisfy the conditions κmR = m 2 R 2 + 2 a=1 L 2 a k a + B a mR 2 , κ(k a + mRB a ) = ±(ω a mR − k a q) , a = 1, 2 . (2.44) From the constraints (2.21) and (2.24) one can easily see that these conditions are indeed satisfied. Thus we have two conditions on the Killing spinors: γ 05 ε 0 = ∓ε 0 , γ 05 γ 11 ε 0 = −ε 0 , (2.45) as</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>anticipated above, showing that the classical string solution preserves 1/4 of the 16 supersymmetries of the B 1 = B 2 background. Note that conditions (2.44) are also satisfied if the string rotates only on one plane, i.e. L 2 = 0, ω 2 = k 2 = 0. 2. It is instructive to repeat the previous derivation in polar coordinates. For simplicity, here we will consider a string rotating only in the plane 12,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>t = κτ , r 1 = r 0 , ϕ 1 = ωτ + kσ , y = qτ + mRσ , (2.46) and the remaining coordinates equal to zero. The relevant Γ matrices are found to be Γ 0 = γ 0 , Γ ϕ = r 0 γ 1 , Γ y = γ 5 + r 0 Bγ 1 , (2.47) in fact {Γ ϕ , Γ ϕ } = 2r 2 0 , {Γ ϕ , Γ y } = 2r 2 0 B, {Γ y , Γ y } = 2(1 + r 2 0 B 2 ). We get the condition r 0 P 1 γ 0 γ 1 + Aγ 0 γ 5 + r 0 Q 1 γ 1 γ 5 γ 11 ε = ε , (2.48) where P 1 , Q 1 , A were given in (2.40), (2.37), now with (L 1 , L 2 ) = (r 0 , 0). This leads to the same conditions (2.45) as in the previous derivation. 3 Magnetic field from Kaluza-Klein reduction from B µν 3.1 The quantum string spectrum</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The model is obtained by a T-dual transformation in the y direction from the previous model (2.1). We recall the standard rules of T-duality [19]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>:</figDesc>
					<trash>g ′ yy = g −1 yy , e 2φ ′ = e 2φ g yy , B ′ yµ = g yµ g yy , g ′ yµ = B yµ g yy . (3.1) We get (dropping &quot; primes &quot; ) ds 2 = −dt 2 + dx 2 s + dr 2 1 + dr 2 2 + r 2 1 dϕ 2 1 + r 2 2 dϕ 2 2 + Λ −1 dy 2 − B 1 r 2 1 dϕ 1 + B 2 r 2 2 dϕ 2 2 , e 2(φ−φ0) = Λ −1 , B 2 = Λ −1 (B 1 r 2 1 dϕ 1 + B 2 r 2 2 dϕ 2 ) ∧ dy , Λ = 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 + B 2 2 r 2 2 . (3.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>It represents an exact solution of string theory to all α ′ orders (being related by T-duality to a flat spacetime). The string spectrum is obtained from the spectrum of the previous model by exchanging m and n and R → α</figDesc>
					<trash>′ /R. Thus α ′ M 2 = 2(N L + N R ) + α ′ mR α ′ − B 1 J 1 − B 2 J 2 2 + n 2 R 2 − 2α ′ B 1 n R (J 1R − J 1L ) − 2α ′ B 2 n R (J 2R − J 2L ) , N R − N L = mn . (3.3) Now the spectrum is periodic in the parameters γ 1,2 ≡ α ′ B 1,2 n R with period 1.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The state dual to (2.6) has zero winding m = 0 and n = 1 and becomes tachyonic for B 1 − B 2 &gt; 1/(2R). Note that this is a Kaluza-Klein state of the supergravity multiplet. This tachyon was studied in [4, 5, 6].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Consider the supersymmetric model B 1 = B 2 ≡ B. The BPS states have similar quantum numbers as in the previous T-dual case:</figDesc>
					<trash>N L = 0 , N R = mn , (S 1L , S 2L ) = (−1, 0) or (0, −1) , (3.4) and mass given by (cf. eq. (2.16)) M BPS = n R + mR α ′ − B(J 1 + J 2 ) . (3.5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>B is now restricted to be in the interval 0 &lt; α ′ B n R &lt; 1, outside which the spectrum is repeated periodically. For the states with maximum spin S 1R + S 2R = N R + 1 and l 1,2R = 0 we get</figDesc>
					<trash>M BPS = n R + mR α ′ − Bnm , (3.6) The minimum mass is achieved for α ′ n R B → 1, where the mass becomes M BPS → n R . (3.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The macroscopic strings becoming light are now strings with large m and small n. We will see that their size is much greater than the string length √ α ′ .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.2">Classical solution for the BPS string using Polyakov formalism</head>

				<p>We consider a string rotating on one plane 12 only, and set r 2 = ϕ 2 = 0. The</p>

				<p><formula>Polyakov action becomes S = 1 2π dτ dσ L , (3.8) with L = 1 2α ′ − ˙ t 2 + ˙ r 2 1 − r ′ 1 2 + 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 r 2 1 ( ˙ ϕ 2 1 − ϕ ′ 1 2 ) + ˙ y 2 − y ′ 2 + 2B 1 r 2 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 ˙ ϕ 1 y ′ − ϕ ′ 1 ˙ y , (3.9) where ˙ x ≡ ∂x ∂τ and x ′ ≡ ∂x ∂σ .</formula></p>

				<p>The ansatz for the circular string is:</p>

				<p><formula>˙ t = κ , ˙ r 1 = r ′ 1 = 0 → r 1 = r 0 , ˙ ϕ 1 = ω , ϕ ′ 1 = k , ˙ y = q , y ′ = mR . (3.10)</formula></p>

				<p>The equation of motion for ϕ 1 , y are automatically satisfied and the equation for r 1 gives</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∂L ∂r 2 1 r1=r0 = 0 → (ω + B 1 mR) 2 = (k + B 1 q) 2 . (3.11) The conserved (quantized) momenta are α ′ J 1 = ∂L ∂ω = r 2 0 1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 (ω + B 1 mR) , α ′ n R = ∂L ∂q = q − B 1 r 2 0 1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 (k + B 1 q) , (3.12) giving r 2 0 ω = α ′ J 1 (1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 ) − B 1 r 2 0 mR , q = α ′ n R (1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 ) + r 2 0 B 1 k . (3.13) From the Virasoro constraint, we have r 2 0 ωk + qmR = 0, which becomes J 1 k + nm = 0 , (3.14) we get q 2 + r 2 0 ω 2 = m 2 R 2 1 + n 2 R 2 r 2 0 J 2 1 D 2 , D 2 ≡ 1 r 2 0 B 1 1 − α ′ B 1 J 1 mR r 2 0 − α ′ J 1 mR 2 , m 2 R 2 + r 2 0 k 2 = m 2 R 2 1 + n 2 R 2 r 2 0 J 2 1 . (3.15)</trash>

					<figDesc>The remaining Virasoro constraint gives the energy, which takes the form</figDesc>
					<trash>E 2 = κ 2 α ′ 2 = 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 m 2 R 2 α ′ 2 1 + n 2 R 2 r 2 0 J 2 1 (1 + D 2 ) . (3.16) From the equations (3.11), (3.12) we get J 2 1 r 4 0 = 1 α ′ 2 k − α ′ B 1 n R 2 = n 2 R 2 mR α ′ J 1 − B 1 2 , (3.17) which gives r 0 in terms of the (quantized) quantum numbers and B 1 (compare with (2.29)): r 2 0 = α ′ J 1 k 1 − α ′ n R B 1 = J 2 1 n R ( mR α ′ − B 1 J 1 ) (3.18) Substituting this value we get E = n R + mR α ′ − B 1 J 1 . (3.19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>This reproduces exactly the energy formula (3.5) of the quantum string spectrum for J 2 = 0.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.3">Classical solution for the BPS string using Nambu-Goto formalism</head>

				<p>Since we will be later interested in studying Dp branes, whose dynamics is governed by the Dirac- Born-Infeld (DBI) action, it is useful to reproduce the previous result in the Nambu-Goto formalism. We will see that the equations that we find for the Dp brane analog of the rotating circular BPS string are a simple generalization of the treatment described below.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The Nambu-Goto Lagrangian is given by L = 1 α ′ − det G αβ + 1 α ′ B µν ǫ αβ ∂ α X µ ∂ β X ν , G αβ = g µν ∂ α X µ ∂ β X ν , (3.20) where α, β = σ, τ .</trash>

					<figDesc>We will work in the gauge G στ = 0. By taking the same anstatz as in section 3.2 with r 1 = r 0 and r 2 = 0 (i.e. the string rotating in one plane one only) we get</figDesc>
					<trash>L = 1 α ′ Λ (κ 2 Λ − q 2 − r 2 0 ω 2 )(r 2 0 k 2 + m 2 R 2 ) + B 1 α ′ Λ r 2 0 (ωmR − qk) , (3.21) with Λ = 1 + B 2 1 r 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>0 . The energy, angular momentum J 1 in the plane r 1 , ϕ 1 and the linear momentum in y are obtained by</figDesc>
					<trash>E = ∂L ∂κ = 1 α ′ r 2 0 k 2 + m 2 R 2 Λ − U , J 1 = ∂L ∂ω = − r 2 0 ω α ′ κΛ r 2 0 k 2 + m 2 R 2 Λ − U + B 1 r 2 0 mR α ′ Λ , n R = ∂L ∂q = − q α ′ κΛ r 2 0 k 2 + m 2 R 2 Λ − U − B 1 r 2 0 k α ′ Λ , (3.22) where U = q 2 + r 2 0 ω 2 κ 2 . (3.23) The constraint equation G στ = 0 becomes kJ 1 + nm = 0 . (3.24) The equations (3.22) can be combined giving U Λ − U = 1 r 2 0 B 1 r 2 0 1 − α ′ B 1 J 1 mR − α ′ J 1 mR 2 ≡ D 2 , (3.25) or U = Λ D 2 1 + D 2 . (3.26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that D 2 is the same quantity seen in the previous subsection eq.(3.15). The energy square of the state becomes the same expression eq.(3.16), which we now write exhibiting the explicit r 0 dependence.</p>

				<p><formula>E 2 = m 2 R 2 α ′ 2 1 + n 2 R 2 r 2 0 J 2 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 1 + B 1 r 2 0 (1 − α ′ B 1 J 1 mR ) − α ′ J 1 mRr 4 0 2 . (3.27)</formula></p>

				<p>The Hamiltonian that arises after the gauge choice X 0 = κτ is (after substituting for q, ω their expressions in terms of</p>

				<p><formula>n R , J 1 ) H n/R, J 1 , r 0 = n R ∂y ∂τ + J 1 ∂ϕ 1 ∂τ − L = n R q + J 1 ω − L . (3.28)</formula></p>

				<p>Due to τ -scaling invariance of the Lagrangian we have H = −E. Therefore the equation for r 0 is ∂E ∂r0 = 0 and this is seen to give the same eq.(3.17) as in the previous subsection.</p>

				<p><formula>Therefore E = n R + mR α ′ − B 1 J 1 . (3.29)</formula></p>

				<p>In this way we recover the result (3.19) found by using the Polyakov formalism.</p>

				<p>The classical description reproduces the energy of the quantum string spectrum for large quantum numbers also in non-supersymmetric configurations. As an example, in the appendix we compute the classical energy of a rotating folded string.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Dp-branes interacting with a magnetic RR flux</head>

				<p>We consider the S-dual background to (3.2), which is given by</p>

				<p><formula>ds 2 = Λ 1 2 − dt 2 + dx 2 s + dr 2 1 + dr 2 2 + r 2 1 dϕ 2 1 + r 2 2 dϕ 2 2 , + Λ − 1 2 dy 2 − (B 1 r 2 1 dϕ 1 + B 2 r 2 2 dϕ 2 ) 2 , e 2(φ−φ0) = Λ , A 2 = e −φ0 Λ −1 (B 1 r 2 1 dϕ 1 + B 2 r 2 2 dϕ 2 ) ∧ dy . (4.1) where Λ = 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 + B 2 2 r 2 2 .</formula></p>

				<p>This represents a solution to the classical string equations to the leading order in α ′ . This background contains a flux which couples to a D string. In order to obtain magnetic flux backgrounds for the Dp brane, we perform T-duality transformations on x s coordinates. Using the usual rules (given in [20]) one finds</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = Λ 1 2 − dt 2 + dx 2 s + dr 2 1 + dr 2 2 + r 2 1 dϕ 2 1 + r 2 2 dϕ 2 2 + Λ − 1 2 dy 2 1 + ... + dy 2 p − (B 1 r 2 1 dϕ 1 + B 2 r 2 2 dϕ 2 ) 2 , e 2(φ−φ0) = Λ 3/2−p/2 , A p+1 = e −φ0 Λ −1 (B 1 r 2 1 dϕ 1 + B 2 r 2 2 dϕ 2 ) ∧ dy 1 ∧ dy 2 ∧ ... ∧ dy p . (4.2)</trash>

					<figDesc>Here s = p + 5, ..., 9.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>For simplicity, here we consider a Dp-brane with p ≥ 1 which rotates only on the 12 plane, lying at r 2 = 0. In this case the dependence on B 2 disappears. The projection of this Dp brane on the plane 12 describes a circle with radius r 1 = r 0 . The Dp brane also moves and winds on a p−dimensional torus in the compact space. The compact coordinates y i have periodicity y i ∼ y i + 2πR i , i = 1, · · · , p. It is convenient to formally describe the trajectory in the non-compact space r 1 , ϕ 1 in terms of another circular coordinate y 0 = r 0 ϕ 1 such that y 0 ∼ y 0 + 2πr 0 . The Dp brane action is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = 1 (2π) p dτ p l=1 2π 0 dσ l L , (4.3) where for this (r 2 = 0) Dp brane the Lagrangian L becomes L = µ p e −(φ−φ0) − det G αβ + µB 1 Λ r 1 det M , (4.4) where µ p = 1 g s l p+1 s , g s = e φ0 , l s = √ α ′ . (4.5) Here α, β = 0, 1, · · · , p and G αβ = g µν dX µ ds α dX ν ds β , (4.6) with ds α = (dτ, dσ 1 , · · · , dσ p ) and M αβ ≡ dy β ds α , (4.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with y β = (y 0 , y 1 , · · · , y p ). Note the dimension [B 1 ] = [1/R].</p>

				<p>We take the ansatz:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X 0 = κτ , r 1 = r 0 , r 2 = 0 , ϕ 1 = ωτ + k i σ i , y i = q i τ + ˜ m ij σ j . (4.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Using our compact notation, we write y 0 = q 0 τ + ˜ m 0j σ j with q 0 = r 0 ω and m 0j ≡ r 0 k j . Note that q α ≡ ˙ y α and the momenta are p yα =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∂L ∂ ˙ yα .</trash>

					<head>The constants of motions are:</head>

					<figDesc>• k i ;</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>• the compact windings m ij : ˜ m ij ≡ R i m ij (for y i ∼ y i + 2πR i ); • the momenta in the compactified directions p yi =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ni Ri = ∂L ∂qi ; • the angular momentum J 1 = ∂L ∂ω corresponding to the &quot; momentum &quot; p y0 = J1 r0 = ∂L ∂q0 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that k i , m ij , J 1 , n i are integer numbers.</p>

				<p>We take the gauge</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G 0j = g µν dX µ dτ dX µ dσ j = 0 , j = 1, · · · , p . (4.9) This can be rewritten as p α=0 q α ˜ m αj = 0 for each j = 1, · · · , p. Since ∂ det(M) ∂qα m αj = 0 for j = 1, · · · , p and ∂ √ − det G ∂qα ∼ q α , this implies p α=0 ∂L ∂q α ˜ m αj = p α=0 p yα m αj = J 1 k j + p i=1 n i m ij = 0 , j = 1, · · · , p . (4.10)</trash>

					<figDesc>Another consequence is that the product of the matrix M times its transpose, i.e. M · M T , is blockdiagonal and one gets det(M ) = q det(G ij ) with q ≡ p α=0 q 2 α . Also, note that G 00 = κ 2 Λ − q 2 .</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Therefore we can rewrite the Lagrangian in this gauge as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L = µ p Λ (κ 2 Λ − q 2 ) det(G ij ) + µ p B 1 r 0 Λ q det(G ij ) . (4.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Consider now, for fixed G ij , the vector q whose components are the dynamical variables q α = ˙ y α .</p>

				<p>We note that L is invariant under rotations of q . Therefore we can take a frame where q =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(q, 0, · · · , 0) getting p y ≡ p α=0 p 2 yα = ∂L ∂q = −q κ 2 Λ − q 2 µ p Λ det(G ij ) + µ p B 1 r 0 Λ det(G ij ) , (4.12) from which it follows that q 2 κ 2 = Λ D 2 1 + D 2 , D 2 ≡ Λ µ p (J 1 /r 0 ) 2 + p i=1 (n i /R i ) 2 det(G ij ) − B 1 r 0 2 . (4.13) By using the relations (4.10) one verifies the following identity: (J 1 /r 0 ) 2 + (n/R) 2 det(G ij ) = J 1 /r 0 ˜ m , ˜ m ≡ det( ˜ m ij ) , n R ≡ p i=1 n 2 i R 2 i . (4.14) We fix r 1 = r 0 by requiring ∂H ∂r0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>= 0 where H is the Hamiltonian. This Hamiltonian describing the dynamics of the space coordinates at fixed κ is obtained by substituting for q i , ω their expressions in terms of</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ni Ri , J 1 in the general formula H n i R i , J 1 , r 0 = p i=1 n i R i ∂y i ∂τ + J 1 ∂ϕ ∂τ − L = i n i R i q i + J 1 ω − L . (4.15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Due to τ -scaling invariance of the Lagrangian we have H = −E, where the energy of the state is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E ≡ ∂L ∂κ = µ p det(G ij ) Λ − q 2 /κ 2 = µ p det(G ij )(1 + D 2 ) Λ = µ p ˜ m 1 + n 2 R 2 r 2 0 J 2 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 0 1 + B 1 r 2 0 (1 − B 1 J 1 µ p ˜ m ) − J 1 µ p ˜ mr 4 0 2 . (4.16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the last step we have used the definitions and the identities (4.13) and (4.14). From now on, the calculation follows identical steps as in section 3.3. We find r 0 by the equation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∂E 2 ∂r 2 0 = 0. This gives again r 2 0 = J 2 1 n R | ˜ mµ p − B 1 J 1 | . (4.17)</trash>

					<figDesc>Substituting this value into the above expression for E we get</figDesc>
					<trash>E = n R + ˜ mµ p − B 1 J 1 = p i=1 n 2 i R 2 i + R 1 · R 2 · · · R p det(m ij )µ p − B 1 J 1 . (4.18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In terms of the tension of the Dp brane τ p = µ p /(2π) p and the volume of the torus T p this becomes</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E = p i=1 n 2 i R 2 i + τ p Vol(T p ) m − B 1 J 1 , (4.19) where m ≡ det(m ij ) = 1 Vol(T p ) dy 1 ∧ · · · ∧ dy p . (4.20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is the winding number of the Dp brane around the T p -torus. Note that the term τ p × Vol(T p ) × m is the expected contribution to the energy of the form tension × volume × winding. This term is O(1/g s ). Thus we find that the energy has the same form as the energy (3.19) of the circular BPS string (in the particular case J 2 = 0). This Dp brane solution is also supersymmetric as it is related by dualities to the circular BPS string. In the particular p = 2 and B 1 = B 2 = 0 case, it agrees with the energy formula for the analogous membrane BPS solution found in [21, 22] (see eq. (2.42) in [22]).</p>

				<p>Let us now consider some physical implications of the energy formula. We take R i ∼ l s . In the absence of magnetic fields and assuming g s ≪ 1 the energy of the brane is essentially given by the winding contribution</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E ∼ 1 g s l s m ≫ 1 l s . (4.21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Similarly to the case of the string, we find that there are Dp branes which become light when the magnetic flux gets to some value, B 1 J 1 ∼ τ p Vol(T p )m. These are states with large m, and with n i of order 1. The energy becomes</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>E ∼ p i=1 n 2 i R 2 i ≪ 1 g s l s m . (4.22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Strikingly, these Dp branes become macroscopic since r 0 (and in fact the proper distance) goes to infinity when B 1 approaches τ p Vol(T p )m/J 1 (see eq. (4.17)). In the absence of magnetic fields they have size r 0 ∼ J1 √ m l s √ g s , which is typically small in the perturbative regime, but it may be large by a suitable choice of quantum numbers (satisfying of course the constraint (4.10)).</p>

				<p>In the case of the model (2.1), the physical string spectrum is periodic in the magnetic field parameters. A very interesting open question is whether the full quantum spectrum of Dp brane states in the background (4.2) could also have some analogous periodicity.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Discussion</head>

				<p>To summarize, we have computed the energy of Dp branes in the presence of magnetic RR flux backgrounds and identified a family of BPS rotating Dp brane solutions which are invariant under four supersymmetry transformations. There are some potentially interesting applications. Since the solutions are BPS, the mass formula should be protected from quantum string theory corrections and therefore it should be possible to extrapolate it to strong coupling, where the gravitational field of the brane becomes important and these branes could become black holes, analogous to the black holes of [23], but moving in magnetic fields. Also, it may be possible to construct the Dp brane supergravity solution with the addition of the magnetic RR F p+2 flux by starting with a Dp&apos; brane background, adding magnetic parameters as in section 2 and perform several dualities, providing a model for AdS/CFT correspondence which might exhibit some interesting effects. We have seen that there are macroscopic string and Dp brane states which become light for some values of the magnetic field parameters B 1 , B 2 . In general, the presence of many light classical macroscopic states in a non-supersymmetric background could be a sign of potential instabilities. In the non-supersymmetric case, the quantum spectrum is known [3, 4] to contain tachyons in some range of the parameters B 1 , B 2 , R (see section 2). Such instabilities in principle can arise both from string modes or from supergravity modes. In the first case, like the model of section 2.1, where tachyons arise in the winding sector, the supergravity background is classically stable, but the string theory is unstable in some range of the parameters. In the second case, like the model of section 3.1, the supergravity background itself is classically unstable (which allows a study of tachyon instabilities in a field theory setting [5]). From the quantum spectrum (2.3) (see also appendix A), it can be seen that, when B 1 = B 2 , even states with N L = 0, N R = mn can become tachyonic (when B 1 = B 2 the mass squared of these states is manifestly positive definite). The energy of the corresponding classical solutions never becomes imaginary because, from the Virasoro constraint, E 2 is proportional to ( ˙ X i ˙ X j + X i ′ X j ′ )g ij ≥ 0 where g ij is the spatial part of the metric. The classical string may become light, but not tachyonic. Since the presence of fluxes in string-theory backgrounds are important for moduli stabilization, a very interesting question is whether instabilities could also arise for non-supersymmetric flux compactification models in some range of the parameters. If this is the case, this effect could constraint the number of stable vacua. A study in this direction was done in [24], looking for instabilities of the supergravity background.</p>

				<p>The reduction of the energy of a state originates due to the standard gyromagnetic interaction. This effect is universal and it is present for any quantum state with spin that moves in a magnetic field. In string theory, the effect can be stronger due to the existence of states with arbitrarily large values of the spin, for which the negative gyromagnetic coupling can be important even for weak magnetic fields (for example, there are magnetic string models which become unstable for infinitesimal values of the magnetic field, see sect. 6 in [3]). For strong magnetic fields, one needs to take into account O(B 2 ) effects where gravity gets into the game. Finding the full quantum spectrum in this case is in general highly complicated, but we have seen that the energy of quantum states with large spin can be obtained with a good accuracy by studying the classical dynamics.</p>

				<p>In non-supersymmetric backgrounds, this may signal potential instabilities by the presence of light states with large spin.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>

				<p>We would like to thank Jaume Garriga, Jaume Gomis and Paul Townsend for useful discussions. R.I. would like to thank the Departament ECM of U. Barcelona where this work was carried out for hospitality. This work is also supported by the European EC-RTN network MRTN-CT- 2004-005104. J.R. also acknowledges support by MCYT FPA 2004-04582-C02-01 and CIRIT GC 2005SGR-00564. J.L.C. is also supported by the Spanish&apos;s Ministerio de Educación y Ciencia, FPU fellowship (ref: AP2003-4193).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Appendix A Quantum spectrum</head>

				<p>Let us review the main points of the string quantization in the background (2.1). We refer to [3] for more details. The coordinate y satisfies the free equation ∂ + ∂ − y = 0. Write y = qτ + mRσ + y ′ , where y ′ is single-valued and define γ 1,2 = B 1,2 mR, taking 0 ≤ γ i &lt; 1. Introducing complex coordinates in the planes 1, 2:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z 1,2 = X 1,2 + iY 1,2 = r 1,2 e iϕ ′ 1,2 with ϕ ′ 1,2 = ϕ 1,2 + B 1,2 y, one gets Z i = Z iR (τ + σ) + Z iL (τ − σ) where 2 α ′ Z iR (s) = ia i0 e iγis + i ∞ k=1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>a i,k e i(k+γi)s + a i,−k e i(−k+γi)s . (A.1) Z iL (s) has the same expression with a ik → ˜ a ik and k + γ i → k − γ i , and similarly Z * i = X i − iY i in terms of a * i,k (R part) and a * i,k (L part). Note that Z iR,L (σ = 2π) = e i2πγi Z iR,L (σ = 0).</p>

				<p>One then introduces annihilation and creation operators by b i0 ≡</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>γi 2 a i0 , b † i0 ≡ γi 2 a * i0 and b ik− ≡ k + γ i 2 a i,k , b † ik− ≡ k + γ i 2 a * i,k , b ik+ ≡ k − γ i 2 a * i,−k , b † ik+ ≡ k − γ i 2 a i,−k , such that [b ik± , b † jk ′ ± ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>= δ ij δ kk ′ and similarly for the Left part. A similar construction holds for the fermionic coordinates. Here we will consider as an example the NS sector. In this case, the integer k is replaced by a half-integer number and therefore there is no fermionic zero mode. The angular momentum in the plane i is J i = J iR + J iL with</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>J iR = − 1 4 k (k + γ i )(a * ik a ik + a ik a * ik ) + J ψ iR = −b † i0 b i0 − 1 2 + k≥1 (b † ik+ b ik+ − b † ik− b ik− ) + J ψ iR , J iL = − 1 4 k (k − γ i )(a * ik a ik + a ik a * ik ) + J ψ iL = ˜ b † i0 b i0 + 1 2 + k≥1 ( ˜ b † ik+ b ik+ − ˜ b † ik− b ik− ) + J ψ iL , where J ψ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>iR,L are the contributions of the fermionic coordinates in the plane i. Note that there is no fermionic analog of b † i0 b i0 + 1 2 . The momentum in the y direction is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>n R = q + B 1 J 1 + B 2 J 2 . One sees that i k k + γ i 2 2 (a * ik a ik + a ik a * ik ) + 2N ′ R = 2N R − i 2γ i J iR , i k k − γ i 2 2 (˜ a * ik a ik + ˜ a ik a * ik ) + 2N ′ L = 2N L + i 2γ i J iL , where N ′</trash>

					<figDesc>R,L represent the contributions of the other coordinates and of the NS fermions before normal ordering, and N R,L are the usual flat spacetime number operators including the contribution of every coordinate and of the NS fermions: N R,L =: N R,L : −1/2. The GSO projection implies N R,L ≥ 0. From this we get</figDesc>
					<trash>α ′ M 2 = (mR) 2 α ′ + α ′ n R − B 1 J 1 − B 2 J 2 2 + 2(N R + N L ) − i 2γ i (J iR − J iL ) , (A.2) where J iR,L ≡ S iR,L ∓ (l iR,L + 1/2) and l iR = b † i0 b i0 , l iL = ˜ b † i0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>b i0 , representing the contributions of the Landau Levels in the plane i. Note the bounds l iR,L ≥ 0 , |S 1R,L ± S 2R,L | ≤ N R,L + 1 . (A.3)</p>

				<p>The bound for S iR,L can be saturated if in the plane 1 or 2 the fermionic modes 1/2+ or 1/2− are excited (and no other fermionic modes) plus possibly the modes 1+ or 1− (and no other bosonic modes). From (A.3) one can see that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α ′ M 2 ≥ (mR) 2 α ′ +α ′ n R −B 1 J 1 −B 2 J 2 2 +2(N R +N L ) 1− i γ i 2 −(γ 1 −γ 2 )(S 1R −S 2R −S 1L +S 2L )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Therefore M 2 ≥ 0 for γ 1 = γ 2 , i.e. when B 1 = B 2 .</p>

				<p>In general for B 1 = B 2 there can be tachyons. In particular, consider the case B 2 = 0. Eq</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. (A.2) can be written as α ′ M 2 = (mR) 2 α ′ + α ′ (mR) 2 (mn − γ 1 (S 1R + S 1L )) 2 + 2(N R + N L ) + 2γ 1 (l 1L + l 1R + 1) − 2γ 1 (S 1R − S 1L ) From (A.3) one have |S 1R,L | ≤ N R,L + 1 . Take, for example, n = 0, m = 1, R 2 = α ′ , N R = N L = 0, l 1L = l 1R = 0, S 1R = 1, S 1L = −1. We get α ′ M 2 = 1 − 2γ 1 &lt; 0 , for 1/2 &lt; γ 1 &lt; 1 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Another interesting tachyonic state, appearing at B 1 = B 2 in a certain range of the parameters, is a state with N L = 0. We take N R = nm, N L = 0, l 1,2L =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>l 1,2R = 0, S 1R = nm + 1, S 1L = −1, S 2R = 0, S 2L = 0, obtaining α ′ M 2 = mR √ α ′ + √ α ′ n R (1 − γ 1 ) 2 − 2(γ 1 − γ 2 ) . (A.4) It follows that M 2 can be negative only if (B 1 − B 2 ) &gt; mR 2α ′ . Setting, for instance, m = 1, γ 1 = 1 − 1/n 0 , B 2 = 0, R = √ α ′ , one finds that M 2 becomes negative for n 0 &gt; 1 + n + (n + 1) 2 + n 2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note the difference with the true BPS case which occurs for B 1 = B 2 , where M 2 in (A.4) becomes a perfect square.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Appendix B Rotating folded string</head>

				<p>Another class of widely studied quantum string states represents strings which are folded and rotate in the non-compact plane r 1 , ϕ 1 . In addition, we will consider the case when it is wrapped in the compact dimension y with winding m ≥ 0 and zero momentum n. The corresponding ansatz is t = κτ , r 1 = r 1 (σ) , ϕ 1 = ωτ , y = mRσ , (B.1) and r 2 = ϕ 2 = 0. We will consider this string in the model (3.2). It corresponds to a quantum state with N R =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N L = N , J 1R = J 1L = N , J 2R = J 2L = 0 , (B.2) which gives α ′ M 2 = 4N + α ′ mR α ′ − B 1 J 1 2 , (B.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we assume B 1 &gt; 0. We will now show that the classical energy of the solution (B.1) reproduces this formula.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The Nambu-Goto Action is S = 1 2π dτ dσL where the Lagrangian L is L = 1 α ′ Λ (κ 2 Λ − r 2 1 ω 2 ) (dr 1 /dσ) 2 Λ + m 2 R 2 + B 1 r 2 1 α ′ Λ ωmR . (B.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We can formally consider σ to play the role of &quot; time &quot; and solve for r 1 (σ) by using the Hamiltonian formalism, where we define a &quot; conjugate momentum &quot; and the &quot; Hamiltonian &quot; by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p(σ) = α ′ ∂L ∂(dr 1 /dσ) , H(p, r 1 ) = 1 α ′ p dr 1 dσ − L . (B.5) We call for short: f ≡ κ 2 + (κ 2 B 2 1 − ω 2 )r 2 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 , g ≡ m 2 R 2 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 , A ≡ −α ′ H(p, r 1 ) . (B.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The important point is that A is constant.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>We find p 2 = (dr 1 /dσ) 2 (dr 1 /dσ) 2 + g f , f g 2 (dr 1 /dσ) 2 + g = (f − p 2 )g = A − B 1 r 2 1 mR 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 ω , (B.7) giving dr 1 dσ 2 = g f g − A − B1r 2 1 mR 1+B 2 1 r 2 1 ω 2 A − B1r 2 1 mR 1+B 2 1 r 2 1 ω 2 . (B.8) Therefore f g − (A − B1r 2 1 mR 1+B 2 1 r 2 1 ω) 2 ≥ 0, which is satisfied if 0 ≤ r 2 1 ≤ r 2 M , r 2 M ≡ κ 2 m 2 R 2 − A 2 (mRω − AB 1 ) 2 . (B.9) Note that (B.7) holds for arbitrary r 1 and therefore it implies that A ≥ 0 , A − B 1 r 2 1 (mRω − AB 1 ) ≥ 0 , (B.10) so that A mRω − AB 1 − B 1 r 2 1 = A − B 1 r 2 1 (mRω − AB 1 ) |mRω − AB 1 | . (B.11) Some useful formulae, following from rewriting what said above, are: p = f − 1 g A − B 1 r 2 1 mRω 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 2 = |mRω − AB 1 | mR r 2 M − r 2 1 , (B.12) dr 1 dσ = ± mR r 2 M − r 2 1 | A mRω−AB1 − B 1 r 2 1 | . (B.13) The energy of the state is E = 1 2π dσ ∂L ∂κ = κ 2πα ′ dσ (dr 1 /dσ) 2 + g f = κ 2πα ′ dσ dr 1 dσ 1 p = 2nκ πα ′ mR |mRω − AB 1 | rM 0 dr 1 r 2 M − r 2 1 = nκ α ′ mR |mRω − AB 1 | . (B.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here we have used (B.13) with the + sign when r grows from 0 to r M and we have assumed that the string is folded n times; a factor 4 appears because for n = 1 any point r 1 of the string is obtained 4 times as σ goes from 0 to 2π.</p>

				<p>We have still to require,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>using (B.13) and (B.11), 2π = 2π 0 dσ = 4n |mRω − AB 1 | rM 0 dr 1 A − B 1 r 2 1 (mRω − AB 1 ) mR r 2 M − r 2 1 = 2πn mR A |mRω − AB 1 | − ǫB 1 r 2 M 2 , (B.15) where ǫ ≡ sign(mRω − AB 1 ). The formula (B.15) together with (B.9) gives κ 2 m 2 R 2 (mRω − AB 1 ) 2 = r 2 M + A 2 (mRω − AB 1 ) 2 = r 2 M + mR n + ǫ B 1 r 2 M 2 2 , (B.16) and therefore E = n α ′ r 2 M + mR n + ǫ B 1 r 2 M 2 2 . (B.17) Finally, one can express r 2 M in terms of the angular momentum J 1 : J 1 = 1 2π dσ ∂L ∂ω = 1 2πα ′ dσ −ω r 2 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 (dr 1 /dσ) 2 + g f + B 1 mRr 2 1 1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 = 4n 2πα ′ |mRω − AB 1 | rM 0 dr 1 −ωr 2 1 mR + B 1 r 2 1 A − B 1 r 2 1 (mRω − AB 1 ) (1 + B 2 1 r 2 1 ) r 2 M − r 2 1 = −ǫ n 2α ′ r 2 M . (B.18) Thus α ′ E 2 = 2n|J 1 | + α ′ mR α ′ − B 1 J 1 2 , (B.19) in agreement with (B.3).</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Flux compactification</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Douglas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Kachru</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Physics of string flux compactifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Denef</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Douglas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Kachru</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Magnetic flux tube models in superstring theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Russo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Tseytlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4619508068</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Magnetic backgrounds and tachyonic instabilities in closed superstring theory and M-theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Russo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Tseytlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">611</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">93</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Closed string tachyon condensation on twisted circles</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>David</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gutperle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Headrick</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Minwalla</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP 0202</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">041</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supersymmetric fluxbrane intersections and closed string tachyons</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Russo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Tseytlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">065</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relativistic minimal surfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Hoppe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Nicolai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">196</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">451</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Euler top dynamics of Nambu-Goto p-branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Axenides</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Floratos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">JHEP 0703</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page">093</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BPS states of strings in 3-form flux</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Grana</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Frey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">026008</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An open string landscape</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Gomis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Marchesano</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Mateos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">021</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supersymmetric D-branes and calibrations on general N = 1 backgrounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Martucci</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Smyth</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">048</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">D-branes in Melvin background</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Takayanagi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Uesugi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">036</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">D-branes in string theory Melvin backgrounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Dudas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Mourad</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">622</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">46</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orientifolds of string theory Melvin backgrounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Angelantonj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Dudas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Mourad</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">637</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">59</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonrenormalization of the Superstring Tension</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Dabholkar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Harvey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">478</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">kappa-symmetry, supersymmetry and intersecting branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Bergshoeff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Ortin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Papadopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5029705040</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supercurves</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Mateos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ng</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Townsend</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">538</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">366</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Super D-branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Bergshoeff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Townsend</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">490</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">145</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Path Integral Derivation of Quantum Duality in Nonlinear Sigma Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Buscher</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">201</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">466</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duality in the type II superstring effective action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Bergshoeff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Hull</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ortin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4519504081</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">547</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rotating toroidal branes in supermem- brane and matrix theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Axenides</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Floratos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Perivolaropoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">085006</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-perturbative states in type II superstring theory from classical spinning membranes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Brugues</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Rojo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Russo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">710</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">117</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extremal black holes and elementary string states</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mod. Phys. Lett. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109504147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2081</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributions of nonsupersymmetric flux vacua</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Denef</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Douglas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">JHEP 0503</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">061</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
