<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2007-10-27">27 Oct 2007 June, 2007</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">B</forename>
								<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
								<surname>Ward</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Baylor University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>76798-7316</postCode>
									<settlement>Waco</settlement>
									<region>Texas</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2007-10-27">27 Oct 2007 June, 2007</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>IR-Improved DGLAP-CS Theory: Kernels, Parton Distributions, Reduced Cross Sections †</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>It is shown that exact, amplitude-based resummation allows IR-improvement of the usual DGLAP-CS theory. This results in a new set of kernels, parton distributions and attendant reduced cross sections, so that the QCD perturbative result for the respective hadron-hadron or lepton-hadron cross section is unchanged order-by-order in α s at large squared-momentum transfers. We compare these new objects with their usual counterparts and illustrate the effects of the IR-improvement in some phenomenological cases of interest with an eye toward precision applications in LHC physics scenarios.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>With the impending start of the LHC, the era of precision QCD at the LHC, by which we mean 1% or better precision tags on the theoretical predictions, obtains. In this new era for perturbative QCD in high energy colliding beam physics, we have the extremely challenging task of proving that a given theoretical precision tag does in fact hold to that level. All aspects of the standard formula for hadron-hadron scattering in perturbative QCD have to be examined for possible sources of uncertainty in the physical and technical precision components of any claimed total theoretical precision tag. In this connection, we recall that, in Ref. [1], we have found that the resummation of large infrared (IR) effects in the kernels of the usual DGLAP-CS [2–5] theory results in their improved behavior in the respective IR limit. This improved behavior, for example, results in kernels that are integrable in the IR limit and which therefore are more amenable to realization by MC methods (our ultimate goal) to arbitrary precision.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we review the results in Ref. [1] and we show that the new IR-improved DGLAP-CS theory leads to a new set of parton distributions and reduced cross sections, so that the exact predictions from QCD for hadron-hadron and lepton-hadron processes are unaltered order-by-order in perturbation theory. The advantage is better control on the accuracy of a given fixedorder calculation throughout the entire phase space of the respective physical process, especially when the prediction is given by MC methods.</p>

				<p>The paper is organized as follows. In the next section, we recapitulate the new IRimproved DGLAP-CS theory, as it is not very familiar. In Section 3, we illustrate the use of the new IR-improved theory with some examples of phenomenological interest. In Section 4, we address the issue of what it does to the standard calculational apparatus for perturbative QCD predictions of hadron-hadron and lepton-hadron scattering processes at large squared momentum transfer. Section 5 contains some concluding remarks. Review of exact, amplitude-based resummation theory is presented in the Appendix.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>IR-Improved DGLAP-CS Theory Specifically, the motivation for the improvement which we develop can be seen already in the basic results in Refs. [5] for the kernels that determine the evolution of the structure functions by the attendant DGLAP-CS evolution of the corresponding parton densities by the standard methodology. Here, we already stress that the attendant evolution equations, under Mellin tranformation, are entirely implied by those of the Callan-Symanzik-type [2] analyzed in Refs. [3, 4] in their classic analysis of the deep inelastic scattering processes. Thus, henceforward, we shall refer to these equations as the DGLAP-CS equations. Consider the evolution of the non-singlet(NS) parton density function q N S (x), where x can be identified as Bjorken&apos;s variable as usual. The basic starting point of our analysis is the infrared divergence in the kernel that determines this evolution:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dq N S (x, t) dt = α s (t) 2π 1 x dy y q N S (y, t)P qq (x/y) (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the well-known result for the kernel P qq (z) is, for z &lt; 1,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P qq (z) = C F 1 + z 2 1 − z (2) when we set t = ln µ 2 /µ 2 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for some reference scale µ 0 with which we study evolution to the scale of interest µ.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 Here, C F = (N 2 c − 1)/(2N c</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is the quark color representation&apos;s quadratic Casimir invariant where N c is the number of colors and so that it is just 3. This kernel has an unintegrable IR singularity at z = 1, which is the point of zero energy gluon emission and this is as it should be. The standard treatment of this very physical effect is to regularize it by the replacement</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 (1 − z) → 1 (1 − z) + (3) with the distribution 1 (1−z) + defined so that for any suitable test function f (z) we have 1 0 dz f (z) (1 − z) + = 1 0 dz f (z) − f (1) (1 − z) . (4) A possible representation of 1/(1 − z) + is seen to be 1 (1 − z) + = 1 (1 − z) θ(1 − ǫ − z) + ln ǫ δ(1 − z) (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with the understanding that ǫ ↓ 0. We use the notation θ(x) for the step function from 0 for x &lt; 0 to 1 for x ≥ 0 and δ(x) is Dirac&apos;s delta function. The final result for P qq (z) is then obtained by imposing the physical requirement [5]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>that</figDesc>
					<trash>1 0 dzP qq (z) = 0, (6) which is satisfied by adding the effects of virtual corrections at z = 1 so that finally P qq (z) = C F 1 + z 2 (1 − z) + + 3 2 δ(1 − z) . (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The smooth behavior in the original real emission result from the Feynman rules, with a divergent 1/(1 − z) behavior as z → 1, has been replaced with a mathematical artifact: the regime 1 − ǫ &lt; z &lt; 1 now has no probability at all and at z = 1 we have a large negative integrable contribution so that we end-up finally with a finite (zero) value for the total integral of P qq (z). This mathematical artifact is what we wish to improve here; for, in the precision studies of Z physics [7–9] at LEP1, it has been found that such mathematical artifacts can indeed impair the precision tag which one can achieve with a given fixed order of perturbation theory. An analogous case is now well-known in the theory of QCD higher order corrections, where the FNAL data on p T spectra clearly show the need for improvement of fixed-order results by resumming large logs associated with soft gluons [10–12]. 2 For reference, note that at the LHC, 2 TeV partons are realistic so that z ∼ = 0.001 means ∼ 2 − 3 GeV soft gluons, which are clearly above the LHC detector thresholds, in complete analogy with the situation at LEP where z ∼ = 0.001 meant ∼ 100 MeV photons which were also above the LEP detector thresholds – just as resummation was necessary to describe this view of the LEP data, so too we may argue it will be necessary to describe the LHC data on the corresponding view. And, more importantly, why should we have to set P qq (z) to 0 for 1 − ǫ &lt; z &lt; 1 when it actually has its largest values in this very regime?</p>

				<p>By mathematical artifact we do not mean that there is an error in the computations that lead to it; indeed, it is well-known that this +-function behavior is exactly what one gets at O(α s ) for the bremsstrahlung process. The artifact is that the behavior of the differential spectrum of the process for z → 1 in O(α s ) is unintegrable and has to be cut-off and thus this spectrum is only poorly represented by the O(α s ) calculation; for, the resummation of the large soft higher order effects as we present below changes the z → 1 behavior non-trivially, as from our resummation we will find that the 1 1−z -behavior is modified to (1 − z) γ−1 , γ &gt; 0. This is a testable effect, as we have seen in its QED analogs in Z physics at LEP1 [7–9]: if the experimentalist measures the cross section for bremsstrahlung for gluons(photons) down to energy fraction ǫ 0 , ǫ 0 &gt; 0, in our new resummed theory presented below, the result will approach a finite value from below as −ǫ γ 0 whereas the O(α s ) +-function prediction would increase without limit as − ln ǫ 0 . The exponentiated result has been verified by the data at LEP1.</p>

				<p>The important point is that the traditional resummations in N-moment space for the DGLAP-CS kernels address only the short-distance contributions to their higher order corrections. The deep question we deal with in this paper concerns, then, how much of the complete soft limit of the DGLAP-CS kernels is contained in the anomalous dimensions of the leading twist operators in Wilson&apos;s expansion, an expansion which resides on the very tip of the light-cone? Are all of the effects of the very soft gluon emission, involving, as they most certainly do, arbitrarily long wavelength quanta, representable by the physics at the tip of the light-cone? The Heisenberg uncertainty principle surely tells us that answer can not be affirmative.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we calculate these long-wavelength gluon</p>

				<p><formula>¹ £ ¢ £ ¢ £ ¢ £ ¢ £ ¢ £ ¢ ½ ´ ½ µ ´ µ Ò ´ Ò µ Þ È £ ¢ £ ¢ £ ¢ ¹ £ ¢ £ ¢ £ ¢ ´Þµ Õ Õ È ½ È ½ ´´µ´µ</formula></p>

				<p>È ¾ ´½ Þµ È ¾ ´½ Þµ Figure 1: In (a), we show the usual process q → q(1 − z) + G(z); in (b), we show its multiple gluon improvement q → q(1 − z) + G 1 (ξ 1 ) + · · · + G n (ξ n ), z = j ξ j .</p>

				<p>effects on the DGLAP-CS kernels that are not included (see the discussion below) in the standard treatment of Wilson&apos;s expansion. We therefore do not contradict the results of the large N-moment space resummations such as that presented in Ref. [13] nor do we contradict the renormalon chain-type resummation as done in Ref. [14].</p>

				<p>We employ the exact re-arrangement of the Feynman series for QCD as it has been shown in Ref. [15, 16]. For completeness, as this QCD exponentiation theory is not generally familiar, we reproduce its essential aspects in our Appendix. The idea is to sum up the leading IR terms in the corrections to P qq with the goal that they will render integrable the IR singularity that we have in its lowest order form. This will remove the need for mathematical artifacts and exhibit more accurately the true predictions of the full QCD theory in terms of fully physical results.</p>

				<p>We apply the QCD exponentiation master formula in eq.(80) in our Appendix (see also Ref. [15]), following the analogous discussion then for QED in Refs. [8, 9], to the gluon emission transition that corresponds to P qq (z), i.e., to the squared amplitude for q → q(z) + G(1 − z) so that in the Appendix one replaces everywhere the squared amplitudes for the ¯ Q ′ Q → ¯ Q ′′′ Q ′′ processes with those for the former one plus its nG analoga with the attendant changes in the phase space and kinematics dictated by the standard methods; this implies that in eq.(53) of the first paper in Ref. [5] we have from eq.(80) the replacement ( see Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>)</figDesc>
					<trash>P BA = P 0 BA ≡ 1 2 z(1 − z) spins |V A→B+C | 2 p 2 ⊥ ⇒ P BA = 1 2 z(1 − z) spins |V A→B+C | 2 p 2 ⊥ z γq F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where A = q, B = G, C = q and V A→B+C is the lowest order amplitude for q → G(z) + q(1 − z), so that we get the un-normalized exponentiated result</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P qq (z) = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq 1 + z 2 1 − z (1 − z) γq (9) where [8, 9, 15, 16] γ q = C F α s π t = 4C F β 0 (10) δ q = γ q 2 + α s C F π ( π 2 3 − 1 2 ) (11) and F Y F S (γ q ) = e −C E γq Γ(1 + γ q ) . (12) Here, β 0 = 11 − 2 3 n f , where n f is the number of active quark flavors, C E = .5772 . . . is Euler&apos;s constant and Γ(w) is Euler&apos;s gamma function. The function F Y F S (z) was already introduced by Yennie, Frautschi and Suura [17]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in their analysis of the IR behavior of QED. We see immediately that the exponentiation has removed the unintegrable IR divergence at z = 1. For reference, we note that we have in (9) resummed the terms 3 O(ln k (1 − z)t ℓ α n s ), n ≥ ℓ ≥ k, which originate in the IR regime and which exponentiate. The important point is that we have not dropped outright the terms that do not exponentiate but have organized them into the residuals ¯ β m in the analog of eq.(80). The application of eq.(80) to obtain eq.(9) proceeds as follows. First, the exponent in the exponential factor in front of the expression on the RHS of eq.(80) is readily seen to be from eq.(77), using the well-known results for the respective real and virtual infrared functions from Refs. [15, 16],</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>SUM IR (QCD) = 2α s ReB QCD + 2α s ˜ B QCD (K max ) = 1 2 2C F α s π t ln K max E + C F α s 2π t + α s C F π ( π 2 3 − 1 2 ) (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where on the RHS of the last result we have already applied the DGLAP-CS synthesization procedure in the third paper in Ref. [15] to remove the collinear singularities, ln Λ</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2</head>

				<p>QCD /m 2 q − 1, in accordance with the standard QCD factorization theorems [18]. This means that, identifying the LHS of eq.(80) as the sum over final states and average over initial states of the respective process divided by the incident flux and replacing that incident flux by the respective initial state density according to the standard methods for the process q → q(1 − z) + G(z), occurring in the context of a hard scattering at scale Q as it is for eq.(53) in the first paper in Ref. [5], the soft gluon effects for energy fraction &lt; z ≡ K max /E give the result, from eq.(80), that, working through to the ¯ 1 β-level and using q 2 to represent the momentum conservation via the other degrees of freedom for the attendant hard process,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α s (t) 2π P BA dtdz = e SUM IR (QCD)(z) { ˜ ¯ β 0 d 4 y (2π) 4 e {iy·(p 1 −p 2 )+ R k&lt;Kmax d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k)[e −iy·k −1]} + d 3 k 1 k 1 ˜ ¯ β 1 (k 1 ) d 4 y (2π) 4 e {iy·(p 1 −p 2 −k 1 )+ R k&lt;Kmax d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k)[e −iy·k −1]} + · · · } d 3 p 2 p 0 2 d 3 q 2 q 0 2 = e SUM IR (QCD)(z) { ˜ ¯ β 0 ∞ −∞ dy (2π) e {iy·(E 1 −E 2 )+ R k&lt;Kmax d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k)[e −iyk −1]} + d 3 k 1 k 1 ˜ ¯ β 1 (k 1 ) ∞ −∞ dy (2π) e {iy·(E 1 −E 2 −k 0 1 )+ R k&lt;Kmax d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k)[e −iy·k −1]} + · · · } d 3 p 2 p 0 2 q 0 2 (14) where we set E i = p 0 i , i = 1, 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and the real infrared functioñ S QCD (k) is well-known as well: ˜ S QCD (k) = − α s C F 8π 2 p 1 kp 1 − p 2 kp 2 2 | DGLAP-CS synthesized (15) and we indicate as above that the DGLAP-CS synthesization procedure in Refs. [15] is to be applied to its evaluation to remove its collinear singularities; we are using the kinematics of the first paper in Ref. [5] in their computation of P BA (z) in their eq.(53), so that the relevant value of k 2 ⊥ is indeed Q 2 . It means that the computation can also be seen to correspond to computing the IR function for the standard t-channel kinematics and taking 1 2 of the result to match the single line emission in P Gq . The two important integrals needed in (14) were already studied in Ref. [17]:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I Y F S (zE, 0) = ∞ −∞ dy 2π e [iy(zE)+ R k&lt;zE d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k)(e −iyk −1)] = F Y F S (γ q ) γ q zE I Y F S (zE, k 1 ) = ∞ −∞ dy 2π e [iy(zE−k 1 )+ R k&lt;zE d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k)(e −iyk −1)] = ( zE zE − k 1 ) 1−γq I Y F S (zE, 0) (16) When we introduce the results in (16) into (14) we can identify the factor ¯ β 0 γ q zE + dk 1 k 1 dΩ 1 ˜ ¯ β 1 (k 1 )( zE zE − k 1 ) 1−γq γ q zE d 3 p 2 E 2 q 0 2 = dt α s (t) 2π P 0 BA dz + O(α 2 s ). (17) where P 0</trash>

					<figDesc>BA is the unexponentiated result in the first line of (8). This leads us finally to the exponentiated result in the second line of (8) by elementary differentiation:</figDesc>
					<trash>P BA = P 0 BA z γq F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq (18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let us stress the following.</p>

				<p>In this paper, we have retained for pedagogical reasons the dominant terms in the resummation which we use for the kernels. The result in the first line of (14) is exact and can be used to include all higher order resummation effects systematically as desired. Moreover, we have taken a one-loop representation of α s for illustration and have set it to a fixed-value on the RHS of (14), so that, thereby, we are dropping further possible subleading higher order effects, again for reasons of pedagogy. It is straight forward to include these effects as well [19].</p>

				<p>Here, we also may note how one can see that the terms we exponentiate are not included in the standard treatment of Wilson&apos;s expansion: From the standard method [20], the N-th moment of the invariants T i,ℓ , i = L, 2, 3, ℓ = q, G, of the forward Compton amplitude in DIS is projected by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P N ≡ q {µ 1 · · · q µ N } N! ∂ N ∂p µ 1 · · · ∂p µ N | p=0 (19) where x Bj = Q 2 /(2qp</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) in the standard DIS notation; this projects the coefficient of 1/(2x Bj ) N . For the dominant terms which we resum here, the characteristic behavior would correspond formally to γ q -dependent anomalous dimensions associated with the respective coefficient whereas by definition Wilson&apos;s expansion does not contain such. In more phenomenologically familiar language, it is well-known that the parton model used in this paper to calculate the large distance effects that improve the kernels contains such effects whereas Wilson&apos;s expansion does not: for example, the parton model can be used for Drell-Yan processes, Wilson&apos;s expansion can not. Similarly, any Wilsonexpansion guided procedure used to infer the kernels via inverse Mellin transformation, by calculating the coefficient of (1/z) n in Wilson&apos;s expansion, will necessarily omit the dominant IR terms which we resum. Here, we stress that we refer to the properties of the expansion of the invariant functions T i , not to the expansion of the kernels themselves, as the latter are related to the respective anomalous dimension matrix elements by inverse Mellin transformations. We need to emphasize that we are not saying that there is an error in the standard use of Wilson&apos;s expansion. We are saying that the IR improvement which we exhibit is not a property of that expansion as it is conventionally defined.</p>

				<p>The normalization condition in eq.(6) then gives us the final expression</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P qq (z) = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq 1 + z 2 1 − z (1 − z) γq − f q (γ q )δ(1 − z) (20) where f q (γ q ) = 2 γ q − 2 γ q + 1 + 1 γ q + 2 . (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The latter result is then our IR-improved kernel for NS DGLAP-CS evolution in QCD.</p>

				<p>We note that the appearance of the integrable function (1 − z) −1+γq in the place of 1 (1−z) + was already anticipated by Gribov and Lipatov in Refs. [5]. Here, we have calculated the value of γ q in a systematic rearrangement of the QCD perturbation theory that allows one to work to any exact order in the theory without dropping any part of the theory&apos;s perturbation series.</p>

				<p>The standard DGLAP-CS theory tells us that the kernel P Gq (z) is related to P qq (1−z) directly: for z &lt; 1, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P Gq (z) = P qq (1 − z) = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq 1 + (1 − z) 2 z z γq . (22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This then brings us to our first non-trivial check of the new IR-improved theory; for, the conservation of momentum tells us that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 0 dzz (P Gq (z) + P qq (z)) = 0. (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Using the new results in eqs.(20,22), we have to check that the following integral vanishes:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I = 1 0 dzz 1 + (1 − z) 2 z z γq + 1 + z 2 1 − z (1 − z) γq − f q (γ q )δ(1 − z) . (24) To see that it does, note that z 1 − z = z − 1 + 1 1 − z = −1 + 1 1 − z . (25) Introducing this result into eq.(24) we get I = 1 0 dz{(1 + (1 − z) 2 )z γq − (1 + z 2 )(1 − z) γq + 1 + z 2 1 − z (1 − z) γq − f q (γ q )δ(1 − z)}. (26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The integrals over the first two terms on the right-hand side (RHS) of (26) exactly cancel as one sees by using the change of variable z → 1 − z in one of them and the integral over the last two terms on the RHS of (26) vanishes from the normalization in eq.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(6). Thus we conclude that I = 0. (27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The quark momentum sum rule is indeed satisfied.</p>

				<p>Having improved the IR divergence properties of P qq (z) and P Gq (z), we now turn to P GG (z) and P qG (z). We first note that the standard formula for P qG (z),</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P qG (z) = 1 2 (z 2 + (1 − z) 2 ), (28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is already well-behaved (integrable) in the IR regime. Thus, we do not need to improve it here to make it integrable and we note that the singular contributions in the other kernels are expected to dominate the evolution effects in any case. We do not exclude improving it for the best precision [19] and we return to this point presently.</p>

				<p>This brings us then to P GG (z). Its lowest order form is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P GG (z) = 2C G ( 1 − z z + z 1 − z + z(1 − z)) (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which again exhibits unintegrable IR singularities at both z = 1 and z = 0. (Here, C G is the gluon quadratic Casimir invariant, so that it is just N c = 3.) If we repeat the QCD exponentiation calculation carried-out above by using the color representation for the gluon rather than that for the quarks, i.e., if we apply the exponentiation analysis in the Appendix to the squared amplitude for the process G →</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G(z) + G(1 − z), we get the exponentiated un-normalized result P GG (z) = 2C G F Y F S (γ G )e 1 2 δ G 1 − z z z γ G + z 1 − z (1 − z) γ G + 1 2 (z 1+γ G (1 − z) + z(1 − z) 1+γ G ) (30)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>wherein we obtain the γ G and δ G from the expressions for γ q and δ q by the substitution</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C F → C G : γ G = C G α s π t = 4C G β 0 (31) δ G = γ G 2 + α s C G π ( π 2 3 − 1 2 ). (32)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We see again that exponentiation has again made the singularities at z = 1 and z = 0 integrable.</p>

				<p>To normalize P GG , we take into account the virtual corrections such that the gluon momentum sum rule</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 0 dzz (2n f P qG (z) + P GG (z)) = 0 (33) is satisfied. This gives us finally the IR-improved result P GG (z) = 2C G F Y F S (γ G )e 1 2 δ G { 1 − z z z γ G + z 1 − z (1 − z) γ G + 1 2 (z 1+γ G (1 − z) + z(1 − z) 1+γ G ) − f G (γ G )δ(1 − z)} (34) where for f G (γ G ) we get f G (γ G ) = n f 6C G F Y F S (γ G ) e − 1 2 δ G + 2 γ G (1 + γ G )(2 + γ G ) + 1 (1 + γ G )(2 + γ G ) + 1 2(3 + γ G )(4 + γ G ) + 1 (2 + γ G )(3 + γ G )(4 + γ G ) . (35)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is these improved results in eqs.(20,22,34) for P qq (z), P Gq (z) and P GG (z) that we use together with the standard result in (29) for P qG (z) as the IR-improved DGLAP-CS theory.</p>

				<p>For clarity we summarize at this point the new IR-improved kernel set as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P exp qq (z) = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq 1 + z 2 1 − z (1 − z) γq − f q (γ q )δ(1 − z) , (36) P exp Gq (z) = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq 1 + (1 − z) 2 z z γq , (37) P exp GG (z) = 2C G F Y F S (γ G )e 1 2 δ G { 1 − z z z γ G + z 1 − z (1 − z) γ G + 1 2 (z 1+γ G (1 − z) + z(1 − z) 1+γ G ) − f G (γ G )δ(1 − z)}, (38) P qG (z) = 1 2 (z 2 + (1 − z) 2 ), (39)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have introduced the superscript exp to denote the exponentiated results hence- forth.</p>

				<p>Returning now to the improvement of P qG (z), let us record it as well for the sake of completeness and of providing better precision. Applying eq.(80) to the process G → q+ ¯ q, we get the exponentiated result</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P exp qG (z) = F Y F S (γ G )e 1 2 δ G 1 2 {z 2 (1 − z) γ G + (1 − z) 2 z γ G }. (40)</trash>

					<figDesc>The gluon momentum sum rule then gives the new normalization constant for the P</figDesc>
					<trash>exp GG via the result ¯ f G (γ G ) = n f C G 1 (1 + γ G )(2 + γ G )(3 + γ G ) + 2 γ G (1 + γ G )(2 + γ G ) + 1 (1 + γ G )(2 + γ G ) + 1 2(3 + γ G )(4 + γ G ) + 1 (2 + γ G )(3 + γ G )(4 + γ G ) . (41)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The constant ¯ f G should be substituted for f G in P exp GG whenever the exponentiated result in (40) is used. These results (39), (40), and (41) are our new improved DGLAP-CS kernel set, with the option exponentiating P qG as well.</p>

				<p>In the discussion so far, we have used the lowest order DGLAP-CS kernel set to illustrate how important the resummation which we present here can be. In the literature [21, 22], there are now exact results up to O(α 3 s ) for the DGLAP-CS kernels. The question naturally arises as to the relationship of our work to these fixed-order exact results . We stress first that we are presenting an improvement of the fixed-order results such that the singular pieces of the any exact fixed-order result, i.e., the 1 (1−z) + parts, are exponentiated so that they are replaced with integrable functions proportional to (1 − z)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>γ−1</head>

				<p>with γ positive as we have illustrated above. Since the series of logs which we resum to accomplish this has the structure α ℓ s t ℓ ln n (1 − z), ℓ ≥ n these terms are not already present in the results in Refs. [21, 22]. As we use the formula in eq.(80), there will be no double counting if we implement our IR-improvement of the exact fixed-order results in Refs. [21, 22]. The detailed discussion of the application of our theory to the results in Refs. [21, 22] will appear elsewhere [19]. For reference, we note that the higher order kernel corrections in Refs. [21, 22] are perturbatively related to the leading order kernels, so one can expect that the size of the exponentiation effects illustrated above and below will only be perturbatively modified by the higher order kernel corrections, leaving the same qualitative behavior in general.</p>

				<p>In the interest of specificness, let us illustrate the IR-improvement of P qq when calculated to three loops using the results in Refs. [21, 22]. Considering the non-singlet case for definiteness (a similar analysis holds for the singlet case) we write in the notation of the latter references</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>P + ns = P v qq + P v q ¯ q ≡ ∞ n=0 ( α s 4π ) n+1 P (n)+ ns (42) where at order O(α s ) we have P (0)+ ns (z) = 2C F { 1 + z 2 (1 − z) + + 3 2 δ(1 − z)} (43) which shows that P (0)+ ns (z</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) agrees with the unexponentiated result in (7) for P qq except for an overall factor of 2. We use this latter identification to connect our work with that in Refs. [21, 22] in the standard methodology. In Refs. [21, 22], exact results are given for P</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1)+ ns (z), and in Refs. [22]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>exact results are given for P</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(2)+ ns (z). When we apply the result in (80) to the squared amplitudes for the processes q → q + X, ¯ q → q + X ′ , we get the exponentiated result P +,exp ns (z) = ( α s 4π )2P exp qq (z) + F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq ( α s 4π ) 2 {(1 − z) γq ¯ P (1)+ ns (z) + ¯ B 2 δ(1 − z)} + ( α s 4π ) 3 {(1 − z) γq ¯ P (2)+ ns (z) + ¯ B 3 δ(1 − z)} (44) where P exp qq (z) is given in (39) and the resummed residuals ¯ P (i)+ ns , i = 1, 2 are related to the exact results for P (i)+ ns , i = 1, 2, as follows: ¯ P (i)+ ns (z) = P (i)+ ns (z) − B 1+i δ(1 − z) + ∆ (i)+ ns (z) (45) where ∆ (1)+ ns (z) = −4C F πδ 1 { 1 + z 2 1 − z − f q δ(1 − z)} ∆ (2)+ ns (z) = −4C F (πδ 1 ) 2 { 1 + z 2 1 − z − f q δ(1 − z)} − 2πδ 1 ¯ P (1)+ ns (z) (46) and ¯ B 2 = B 2 + 4C F πδ 1 f q ¯ B 3 = B 3 + 4C F (πδ 1 ) 2 f q − 2πδ 1 ¯ B 2 . (47)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, the constants B i , i = 2, 3 are given by the results in Refs. [21, 22] as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>B 2 = 4C G C F ( 17 24 + 11 3 ζ 2 − 3ζ 3 ) − 4C F n f ( 1 12 + 2 3 ζ 2 ) + 4C 2 F ( 3 8 − 3ζ 2 + 6ζ 3 ) B 3 = 16C G C F n f ( 5 4 − 167 54 ζ 2 + 1 20 ζ 2 2 + 25 18 ζ 3 ) + 16C G C 2 F ( 151 64 + ζ 2 ζ 3 − 205 24 ζ 2 − 247 60 ζ 2 2 + 211 12 ζ 3 + 15 2 ζ 5 ) + 16C 2 G C F (− 1657 576 + 281 27 ζ 2 − 1 8 ζ 2 2 − 97 9 ζ 3 + 5 2 ζ 5 ) + 16C F n 2 F (− 17 144 + 5 27 ζ 2 − 1 9 ζ 3 ) + 16C 2 F n F (− 23 16 + 5 12 ζ 2 + 29 30 ζ 2 2 − 17 6 ζ 3 ) + 16C 3 F ( 29 32 − 2ζ 2 ζ 3 + 9 8 ζ 2 + 18 5 ζ 2 2 + 17 4 ζ 3 − 15ζ 5 ), (48)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ζ n is the Riemann zeta function evaluated at argument n. The detailed phenomenological consequences of the fully exponentiated 2-and 3-loop DGLAP-CS kernel set will appear elsewhere [19]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Phenomenological Effects of IR-Improvement</head>

				<p>Let us now look into the effects of IR-improvement on the moments of the structure functions by discussing the corresponding effects on the moments of the parton distributions.</p>

				<p>In this section we work with the leading order results for definiteness of illustration.</p>

				<p>We know that moments of the kernels determine the exponents in the logarithmic variation [3–5] of the moments of the quark distributions and, thereby, of the moments of the structure functions themselves. To wit, in the non-singlet case, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dM N S n (t) dt = α s (t) 2π A N S n M N S n (t) (49) where M N S n (t) = 1 0 dzz n−1 q N S (z, t) (50) and the quantity A N S n is given (using (39)) by A N S n = 1 0 dzz n−1 P exp qq (z), = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2</trash>

					<figDesc>δq [B(n, γ q ) + B(n + 2, γ q ) − f q (γ q )] (51) where B(x, y) is the beta function given by B(x, y) = Γ(x)Γ(y)/Γ(x + y)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. This should be compared to the un-IR-improved result [3–5]:</p>

				<p><formula>A N S o n ≡ C F − 1 2 + 1 n(n + 1) − 2 n j=2 1 j . (52)</formula></p>

				<p>The asymptotic behavior for large n is now very different, as the IR-improved exponent approaches a constant, a multiple of −f q , as we would expect as n → ∞ because lim n→∞ z n−1 = 0 for 0 ≤ z &lt; 1 whereas, as it is well-known, the un-IR-improved result in (52) diverges as −2C F ln n as n → ∞. The two results are also different at finite n: for n = 2 we get, for example, for α s ∼ = .118 [23],</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A N S 2 = C F (−1.33) , un-IR-improved C F (−0.966) , IR-improved (53)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>so that the effects we have calculated are important for all n in general. For completeness, we note that the solution to (49) is given by the standard methods as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M N S n (t) = M N S n (t 0 )e R t t 0 dt ′ αs(t ′ ) 2π A NS n (t ′ ) = M N S n (t 0 )e ¯ an[Ei( 1 2 δ 1 αs(t 0 ))−Ei( 1 2 δ 1 αs(t))] =⇒ t,t 0 large with t&gt;&gt;t 0 M N S n (t 0 ) α s (t 0 ) α s (t) ¯ a ′ n (54) where Ei(x) = x −∞ dre r /r is the exponential integral function, ¯ a n = 2C F β 0 F Y F S (γ q )e γq 4 [B(n, γ q ) + B(n + 2, γ q ) − f q (γ q )] ¯ a ′ n = ¯ a n 1 + δ 1 2 (α s (t 0 ) − α s (t)) ln(α s (t 0 )/α s (t)) (55) with δ 1 = C F π π 2 3 − 1 2</trash>

					<figDesc>. We can compare with the un-IR-improved result in which the last line in eq.(54) holds exactly with ¯ a ′ n = 2A</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>N S o n /β 0 . Phenomenologically, for n = 2, taking Q 0 = 2GeV and evolving to Q = 100GeV, if we set Λ QCD ∼ = .2GeV and use n f = 5 for definiteness of illustration, we see from eqs. (54,55) that we get a shift of the respective evolved NS moment by ∼ 5%, which is of some interest in view of the expected HERA precision [24].</p>

				<p>We stress that the size of the exponent γ q is what one would expect from analogy with QED [25], where with Q = 100 GeV we have the analogous result γ e = (α EM /π)(ln Q 2 /m 2 e − 1) ∼ = 0.054 whereas here, with α s ∼ = .118, so that it is about 10 times α EM , we get a value for γ q that is about 10 times gamma e . There are no data that currently contradict the values we find for our γ j , = q, G. Evidently, from the exact result (14) we can consistently improve the values of the γ j as needed using more and more of the perturbative results for the functions SUM IR (QCD), ˜ S QCD , ˜ ¯ β n on the RHS accordingly, as we have noted.</p>

				<p>We give now the remaining elements of the leading anomalous dimension matrix in its &apos;best&apos; IR-improved form for completeness:</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>A</head>

				<figure>
					<trash>Gq n = 1 0 dzz n−1 P exp Gq (z) = C F F Y F S (γ q )e 1 2 δq 1 n + γ q − 1 + B(3, n + γ q − 1) , (56) A GG n = 1 0 dzz n−1 P exp GG (z) = 2C G F Y F S (γ G )e 1 2 δ G {B(n + 1, γ G ) + B(n + γ G − 1, 2) + 1 2 (B(n + 1, γ G + 2) + B(n + γ G + 1, 2)) − ¯ f (γ G )}, (57) 2n f A qG n = 2n f 1 0 dzz n−1 P exp qG (z) = 2T (F )F Y F S (γ G )e 1 2 δ G (B(n + 2, 1 + γ G ) + B(n + γ G , 3)) , (58) where T (F ) = 1 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>n f . We note that the un-exponentiated value of the last result in eq.(58) is a well-known one [3–5]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, 2T (F ) 2+n+n 2 n(n+1)(n+2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, and it would be used whenever we do not choose to exponentiate P qG . We will investigate the further implications of these IR-improved results for LHC physics elsewhere [19]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Impact of IR-Improvement on the Standard Method- ology</head>

				<p>In sum, we have used exact re-arrangement of the QCD Feynman series to isolate and resum the leading IR contributions to the physical processes that generate the evolution kernels in DGLAP-CS theory. In this way, we have obviated the need to employ artificial mathematical regularization of the attendant IR singularities as the theory&apos;s higher order corrections naturally tame these singularities. The resulting IR-improved anomalous dimension matrix behaves more physically for large n and receives significant effects at finite n from the exponentiation.</p>

				<p>We in principle can make contact with the moment-space resummation results in Ref. [26] but we stress that these results have necessarily been obtained after making a Mellin transform of the mathematical artifact which we address in this paper. Thus, the results in Ref. [26] do not in any way contradict the analysis in this paper.</p>

				<p>We note that the program of improvement of the hadron cross section calculations for LHC physics advanced herein should be distinguished from the results in Refs. [10,27,28].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Indeed, recalling the standard hadron cross section formula</figDesc>
					<trash>σ = i,j dx 1 dx 2 F i (x 1 )F j (x 2 )ˆ σ(x 1 x 2 s) (59)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where {F ℓ (x)} are the respective parton densities and σ(x 1 x 2 s) is the respective reduced hard parton cross section, the resummation results in Refs. [27, 28] address, by summing the large logs in Mellin transform space, the x 1 x 2 → 1 limit of σ(x 1 x 2 s) whereas the results above address the improvement, by resummation in x-space, of the calculation of the parton densities {F i (x)} for all values of x. Thus, the program of improvement presented above is entirely complementary to that in Refs. [27, 28] and both programs of improvement are useful for precision LHC physics. The situation can be illustrated by comparing the results in Refs. [29] with our results herein. The key observation can already be made from eq.(2.1) in the latter paper, wherein it is made manifest that the resummation carried out therein, as an application of the methods in Refs. [27, 28], is a resummation for the large N-Mellin space limit of the Mellin transform of the hard scattering coefficient function so that all of the IR effects in the parton densities are not included in this resummation. What we deal with here is however resummation of the IR effects in the kernels which generate exactly these IR effects in these parton densities directly in configuration space so that we work on a complementary aspect the formula (59) and this we do directly in x-space rather than in N-Mellin space. There is then no contradiction or repetition between our results and those in Ref. [29]. Refs. [27, 28] have stressed that the IR singularities of the parton densities are not addressed by their analysis. If we wanted to include the results in Refs. [27, 28], as we have discussed in Refs. [15], we would make an inverse Mellin transform of their results and apply them to our resummation calculus for the hard cross section σ(x 1 x 2 s) as it is illustrated in the Appendix; by construction, this would not affect the IR singularities for the evolution of the initial parton densities analyzed in this paper.</p>

				<p>Similarly, the analysis of the P T distribution resummation in Ref. [10] deals with the hard scattering coefficient response to soft-gluon emission. The initial parton densities are input to this analysis. Evidently, as we work with the x-space initial parton density evolution in which any P T has been integrated out, the analysis in Ref. [10] is entirely complementary to our work in this paper.</p>

				<p>Finally, we address the issue of the relationship between the re-arrangement that we have made of the exact leading-logs in the QCD perturbation theory and the usual treatment in the non-exponentiated DGLAP-CS theory. If one expands out the exponentiated kernels, using the distribution identity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1 − z) a−1 = 1 a δ(1 − z) + 1 (1 − z) + + ∞ j=1 a j j! ln j (1 − z) 1 − z + , (60)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>one can see that for example P qq and P exp qq agree to leading order, so that the leading log series which they generate for the respective NS parton distributions also agree through leading order in αs π L where L is the respective big log in momentum-space. At higher orders then, we have a different result for the {F i }, let us denote them by {F ′ i }, and a different result for the reduced cross section, let us denote it by σ ′ , such that we get the same perturbative QCD cross section,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>σ = i,j dx 1 dx 2 F i (x 1 )F j (x 2 )ˆ σ(x 1 x 2 s) = i,j dx 1 dx 2 F ′ i (x 1 )F ′ j (x 2 )ˆ σ ′ (x 1 x 2 s) (61)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>order by order in perturbation theory. The exponentiated kernels are used to factorize the mass singularities from the unfactorized reduced cross section and this generates σ ′ instead of the usuaî σ whose factorized form is generated using the usual DGLAP-CS kernels. For example, from (7), (39) and (60), we see that, starting at order O(α 2 s ), when one factorizes the mass singularities using P exp qq one makes a different subtraction from the respective fixed-order unfactorized hard cross section compared to what one would subtract if the factorization were done with the unexponentiated P qq , resulting in a different reduced cross section, ˆ σ ′ ; but, the convloution of this different reduced cross section with the respective {F ′ i } that result from solving the DGLAP-CS equation with the IR-improved kernels would then give the same result for the hadron-hadron scattering cross section as one would get with the un-improved set {F i , ˆ σ}, order by order in perturbation theory.</p>

				<p>The entirely analogous statement holds for the structure functions in deep inelastic scattering. They are represented as a sum over products of the parton distributions and the attendant hard scattering cross sections. Again, if we use exponentiated kernels to generate the respective parton distributions, we use these kernels to isolate the respective factorized hard scattering cross sections, giving the same perturbative QCD prediction order by order in perturbation theory for the respective deep inelastic structure functions.</p>

				<p>We thus have the same leading log series for σ as does the usual calculation with un-exponentiated DGLAP-CS kernels. We have an important advantage: the lack of +-functions in the generation of the configuration space functions {F ′ i , ˆ σ ′ } means that these functions lend themselves more readily to Monte Carlo realization to arbitrarily soft radiative effects, both for the generation of the parton shower associated to the {F ′ i } and for the attendant remaining radiative effects in σ ′ .</p>

				<p>We stress that, as on can see from our analysis above, unlike the standard MS unexponentiated kernels, our exponentiated kernels contain powers of the product α s L, as these describe the large IR effects which we resum. These effects are then beyond the standard Wilson expansion, as they cause non-trivial modification of the moments of the exponentiated kernels relative to the moments of the MS kernels and it is the latter which correspond to the respective anomalous dimensions of the operators in Wilson&apos;s expansion when this expansion exists. We exchange the naive connection between the moments of the kernels and these anomalous dimensions for the improved IR behavior of the exponentiated kernels. We do this with an eye toward MC methods.</p>

				<p>The use of the new IR-improved kernels may seem as though one is over counting effects; after all, it is well-known [30] that the response of the DGLAP-CS equation for a delta-function at z = 1 for an initial value t = t 0 in the NS case is indeed a solution which exhibits exactly (1 − z) γq−1 type behavior for the respective distribution that we have found for our NS exponentiated kernel. We are not over-counting this effect. For, consider the sequential application of the kernel P exp qq (z) so that, first, a quark, q(1), splits via its action to a quark q(z) and gluons {G i (ξ i )}, with i ξ i = 1 − z in the standard notation, and, second, the latter quark, q(z), splits via the second application of P</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>exp qq (z ′ ) to a quark q(zz ′ ) and gluons {G j (ξ ′ j )}, with j ξ ′ j = (1 − z ′ )z.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the first action, the quantum transition was for q(1) → q(z) on the quark Hilbert space while in the second it was for q(z) → q(zz ′ ), a completely different quantum transition on the quark Hilbert space. The two transitions are completely independent in the leading log and using P exp qq to effect them does not over-count anything; it simply makes the description of each transition more accurate.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have developed a new approach to precision QCD predictions for high energy colliding beam physics scenarios such as that afforded us by the impending turn-on of the LHC. We do not contradict any aspect of the traditional approach. We gain the advantages of improved IR behavior for the respective kernels, parton distributions and reduced cross sections, which should facilitate realization by multiple gluon MC methods. Such realizations for LHC physics will appear elsewhere. [19]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>
					<trash>❅ ❅ ❅ ■ ✓ ✓ ✂✁ ❅ ❅ ❅ ❅ ❅ ❅ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✂✁ ✂✁ ✒ ✠ ✏ ✏ ✏ ✁ ✁ ✄ ✂ ✄ ✂ ❘ ✒ ✒ ✄ ✁ ✒ ❅ ❅ ❅ ❘ ¯ Q ′ ¯ Q ′′′ −p 1 −p 2 G 1 k 1 q 1 q 2 Q Q ′′ G n k n</trash>

					<head>Figure 2:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The process ¯ Q ′ Q → ¯ Q ′′′ + Q ′′ + n(G). The four–momenta are indicated in the</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>standard manner: q 1 is the four–momentum of the incoming Q, q 2 is the four–momentum of the outgoing Q ′′ , etc., and Q = u, d, s, c, b, G.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>

				<p>We thank Prof. S. Jadach for useful discussions and Prof. W. Hollik for the kind hospitality of the Max-Planck-Institut, Munich, wherein a part of this work was completed.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Appendix</head>

				<p>In this Appendix I, we present the new QCD exponentiation theory which has been developed in Refs. [15, 16] as it is not generally familiar. The goal is to make the current paper self-contained.</p>

				<p>For definiteness, we will use the process in Fig. 2</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, ¯ Q ′ (p 1 )Q(q 1 ) → ¯ Q ′′′ (p 2 )Q ′′ (q 2 ) + G 1 (k 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) · · · G n (k n ), as the proto-typical process, where we have written the kinematics as it is illustrated in the figure. This process, which dominates processes such as t ¯ t production at FNAL, contains all of the theoretical issues that we must face at the parton level to establish , as an extension of the original ideas of Yennie, Frautschi and Suura (YFS) [17], QCD soft exponentiation by MC methods – applicability to other related processes will be immediate. For reference, let us also note that, in what follows, we use the GPS conventions of Ref. [31] for spinors {u, v, u} and the attendant photon and gluon polarization vectors that follow therefrom:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(ǫ µ σ (β)) * = ¯ u σ (k)γ µ u σ (β) √ 2 ¯ u −σ (k)u σ (β) , (ǫ µ σ (ζ)) * = ¯ u σ (k)γ µ u σ (ζ) √ 2 ¯ u −σ (k)u σ (ζ) , (62) with β 2 = 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and ζ defined in Ref. [31], so that all phase information is strictly known in our amplitudes. This means that, although we shall use the older EEX realization of YFS MC exponentiation as defined in Ref. [32], the realization of our results via the the newer CEEX realization of YFS exponentiation in Ref. [32] is also possible and is in progress [19].</p>

				<p>Specifically, the authors in Refs. [16] have analyzed how in the special case of Born level color exchange one applies the YFS theory to QCD by extending the respective YFS IR singularity analysis to QCD to all orders in α s . Here, unlike what was emphasized in Refs. [16], we focus on the YFS theory as a general re-arrangement of renormalized perturbation theory based on its IR behavior, just as the renormalization group is a general property of renormalized perturbation theory based on its UV(ultra-violet) behavior. We will thus keep our arguments entirely general from the outset, so that it will be immediate that our result applies to any renormalized perturbation theory in which the cross section under study is finite.</p>

				<p>Let the amplitude for the emission of n real gluons in our proto-typical subprocess, Q α + ¯ Q ′ ¯ α → Q ′′ γ ¯ Q ′′′ ¯ γ + n(G), where α, ¯ α, γ, and ¯ γ are color indices, be represented by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M (n)α ¯ α γ¯ γ = ℓ M (n)α ¯ α γ¯ γℓ , (63) M (n) ℓ is the contribution to M (n) from Feynman diagrams with ℓ virtual loops. Symmetrization yields M (n) ℓ = 1 ℓ! ℓ j=1 d 4 k j (2π) 4 (k 2 j − λ 2 + iǫ) ρ (n) ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ ), (64) where this last equation defines ρ (n) ℓ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>as a symmetric function of its arguments arguments k 1 , ..., k ℓ . λ will be our infrared gluon regulator mass for IR singularities; n-dimensional regularization of the &apos;t Hooft-Veltman [33] type is also possible as we shall see.</p>

				<p>We now define the virtual IR emission factor S QCD (k) for a gluon of 4-momentum k, for the k → 0 regime of the respective 4-dimensional loop integration as in (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>64), such that lim k→0 k 2 ρ (n)α ¯ α γ¯ γ1 (k)| leading Casimir contribution − S QCD (k)ρ (n)α ¯ α γ¯ γ0 = 0, (65)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we have now introduced the restriction to the leading color Casimir terms at one- loop 4 so that in the expression for the respective one-loop correction ρ (n) 1 and in that for for S QCD (k) given in Refs. [16], only the terms proportional to C F should be retained here as we focus on the f ¯ f→f ¯ f case, where f denotes a fermion. (Henceforth, when we refer to k → 0 gluons we are always referring for virtual gluons to the corresponding regime of the 4-dimensional loop integration in the computation of M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(n) ℓ .) In Ref. [16]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, the respective authors have calculated S QCD (k) using the running quark masses to regulate its collinear mass singularities, for example; n-dimensional regularization of the &apos;t Hooft-Veltman type is also possible for these mass singularities and we will also illustrate this presently.</p>

				<p>We stress that S QCD (k) has a freedom in it corresponding to the fact that any function ∆S QCD (k) which has the property that lim k→0 k 2 ∆S QCD (k)ρ (n) 0 = 0 may be added to it.</p>

				<p>Since the virtual gluons in ρ (n) ℓ are all on equal footing by the symmetry of this function, if we look at gluon ℓ, for example, we may write , for k ℓ → (0, 0, 0, 0) ≡ O while the remaining k i are fixed away from O, the representation</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>ρ</head>

				<figure>
					<trash>(n) ℓ = S QCD (k ℓ ) * ρ (n) ℓ−1 (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−1 ) + β 1 ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−1 ; k ℓ ) (66)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the residual amplitude β 1 ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−1 ; k ℓ ) will now be taken as defined by this last equation. It has two nice properties: • it is symmetric in its first ℓ − 1 arguments • the IR singularities for gluon ℓ that are contained in S QCD (k ℓ ) are no longer contained in it.</p>

				<p>We do not at this point discuss the extent to which there are any further remaining IR singularities for gluon ℓ in β 1 ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−1 ; k ℓ ). In an Abelian gauge theory like QED, as has been shown by Yennie, Frautschi and Suura in Ref. [17], there would not be any further such singularities; for a non-Abelian gauge theory like QCD, this point requires further discussion and we will come back to this point presently.</p>

				<p>We rather now stress that if we apply the representation (66) again we may write</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ρ (n) ℓ = S QCD (k ℓ )S QCD (k ℓ−1 ) * ρ (n) ℓ−2 (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−2 ) +S QCD (k ℓ )β 1 ℓ−1 (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−2 ; k ℓ−1 ) +S QCD (k ℓ−1 )β 1 ℓ−1 (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−2 ; k ℓ ) +β 2 ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−2 ; k ℓ−1 , k ℓ ), (67)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where this last equation serves to define the function β 2 ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ−2 ; k ℓ−1 , k ℓ ). It has two nice properties: • it is symmetric in its first ℓ − 2 arguments and in its last two arguments k ℓ−1 , k ℓ • the infrared singularities for gluons ℓ − 1 and ℓ that are contained in S QCD (k ℓ−1 ) and S QCD (k ℓ ) are no longer contained in it.</p>

				<p>Continuing in this way, with repeated application of (66), we get finally the rigorous, exact rearrangement of the contributions to ρ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(n) ℓ as ρ (n) ℓ = S QCD (k 1 ) · · · S QCD (k ℓ )β 0 0 + ℓ i=1 j =i S QCD (k j )β 1 1 (k i ) + · · · +β ℓ ℓ (k 1 , · · · , k ℓ ), (68)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the virtual gluon residuals β i i (k ′ 1 , · · · , k ′ i ) have two nice properties: • they are symmetric functions of their arguments • they do not contain any of the IR singularities which are contained in the product S QCD (k ′ 1 ) · · · S QCD (k ′ i ).</p>

				<p>Henceforth, we denote β i i as the function β i for reasons of pedagogy. We can not stress too much that (68) is an exact rearrangement of the contributions of the Feynman diagrams which contribute to ρ (n) ℓ ; it involves no approximations. Here also we note that the question of the absolute convergence of these Feynman diagrams from the standpoint of constructive field theory remains open as usual. Yennie, Frautschi and Suura [17] have already stressed that Feynman diagrammatic perturbation theory is non-rigorous from this standpoint. What we do claim is that the relationship between the YFS expansion and the usual perturbative Feynman diagrammatic expansion is itself rigorous even though neither of the two expansions themselves is rigorous.</p>

				<p>Introducing (68) into (63) yields a representation similar to that of YFS, and we will call it a &quot; YFS representation &quot; ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M (n) = e αsB QCD ∞ j=0 m (n) j , (69) where we have defined α s (Q)B QCD = d 4 k (k 2 − λ 2 + iǫ) S QCD (k) (70) and m (n) j = 1 j! j i=1 d 4 k i k 2 i − λ 2 + iǫ β j (k 1 , · · · , k j ). (71)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We say that (69) is similar to the respective result of Yennie, Frautschi and Suura in Ref. [17] and is not identical to it because we have not proved that the functions β i (k 1 , ..., k i ) are completely free of virtual IR singularities. What have shown is that they do not contain the IR singularities in the product S QCD (k 1 ) · · · S QCD (k i ) so that m (n) j does not contain the virtual IR divergences generated by this product when it is integrated over the respective 4j-dimensional j-virtual gluon phase space. In an Abelian gauge theory, there are no other possible virtual IR divergences; in the non-Abelian gauge theory that we treat here, such additional IR divergences are possible and are expected; but, the result (69) does have an improved IR divergence structure over (63) in that all of the IR singularities associated with S QCD (k) are explicitly removed from the sum over the virtual IR improved loop contributions m (n) j to all orders in α s (Q).</p>

				<p>Turning now to the analogous rearrangement of the real IR singularities in the differential cross section associated with the M (n) , we first note that we may write this cross section as follows according to the standard methods</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dê 2αsReB QCD n! n m=1 d 3 k m (k 2 m + λ 2 ) 1/2 δ(p 1 + q 1 − p 2 − q 2 − n i=1 k i ) ¯ ρ (n) (p 1 , q 1 , p 2 , q 2 , k 1 , · · · , k n ) d 3 p 2 d 3 q 2 p 0 2 q 0 2 , (72) where we have defined ¯ ρ (n) (p 1 , q 1 , p 2 , q 2 , k 1 , · · · , k n ) = color,spin ∞ j=0 m (n) j 2 (73)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in the incoming Q ¯ Q&apos; cms system and we have absorbed the remaining kinematical factors for the initial state flux, spin and color averages into the normalization of the amplitudes M (n) for reasons of pedagogy so that the ¯ ρ (n) are averaged over initial spins and colors and summed over final spins and colors. We now proceed in complete analogy with the discussion of ρ (n) ℓ above.</p>

				<p>Specifically, for the functions ¯ ρ (n) (p 1 , q 1 , p 2 , q 2 , k 1 , · · · , k n ) ≡ ¯ ρ (n) (k 1 , · · · , k n ) which are symmetric functions of their arguments k 1 , · · · , k n , we define first, for n =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1, lim | k|→0 k 2 ¯ ρ (1) (k)| leading Casimir contribution − ˜ S QCD (k)¯ ρ (0) = 0, (74)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the real infrared functioñ S QCD (k) is rigorously defined by this last equation and is explicitly computed in Refs. [16], wherein we retain here only the terms proportional to C F from the result in Ref. [16] ; like its virtual counterpart S QCD (k) it has a freedom in it in that any function ∆ ˜ S QCD (k) with the property that lim | k|→0 k 2 ∆ ˜ S QCD (k) = 0 may be added to it without affecting the defining relation (74).</p>

				<p>We can again repeat the analogous arguments of Ref. [17], following the corresponding steps in (66)-(71) above for S QCD to get the &quot; YFS-like &quot; result</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dêxp = n dê SUM IR (QCD) ∞ n=0 n j=1 d 3 k j k 0 j d 4 y (2π) 4 e iy·(p 1 +q 1 −p 2 −q 2 − P k j )+D QCD * ¯ β n (k 1 , . . . , k n ) d 3 p 2 p 0 2 d 3 q 2 q 0 2 (75) with SU M IR (QCD) = 2α s ReB QCD + 2α s ˜ B QCD (K max ), 2α s ˜ B QCD (K max ) = d 3 k k 0 ˜ S QCD (k)θ(K max − k), D QCD = d 3 k k ˜ S QCD (k) e −iy·k − θ(K max − k) , (76) 1 2 ¯ β 0 = dσ (1−loop) − 2α s ReB QCD dσ B , 1 2 ¯ β 1 = dσ B1 − ˜ S QCD (k)dσ B , . . . (77)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the ¯ β n are the QCD hard gluon residuals defined above; they are the non-Abelian analogs of the hard photon residuals defined by YFS. Here, for illustration, we have recorded the relationship between the ¯ β n , n = 0, 1 through O(α s ) and the exact one-loop and single bremsstrahlung cross sections, dσ (1−loop) , dσ B1 , respectively, where the latter may be taken from Ref. [35] We stress two things about the right-hand side of (75) :</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>•</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>It does not depend on the dummy parameter K max which has been introduced for cancellation of the infrared divergences in SU M IR (QCD) to all orders in α s (Q) where Q is the hard scale in the parton scattering process under study here.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>• Its analog can also be derived in our new CEEX [32] format.</p>

				<p>We now return to the property of (75) that distinguishes it from the Abelian result derived by Yennie, Frautschi and Suura – namely, the fact that, owing to its non-Abelian gauge theory origins, it is in general expected that there are infrared divergences in the ¯ β n which were not removed into the S QCD , ˜ S QCD when these infrared functions were isolated in our derivation of (75).</p>

				<p>More precisely, the left-hand side of (75) is the fundamental reduced parton cross section and it should be infrared finite or else the entire QCD parton model has to be abandoned.</p>

				<p>There is an observation in the literature [36] that unless we use the approximation of massless incoming quarks, the reduced parton cross section on the left-hand side of (75) diverges in the infrared regime at O(α 2 s (Q)). We do not go into this issue here but either use the quark masses strictly as collinear limit regulators so that they are set to zero in the numerators of all Feynman diagrams in such a way that the limit lim m 2 q /E 2 q →0 , where E q is the quark energy, is taken everywhere that it is finite or, alternatively, we use n-dimensional methods to regulate such divergences while setting the quark masses to zero as that is an excellent approximation for the light quarks at FNAL and LHC energies – we take this issue up elsewhere.</p>

				<p>From the infrared finiteness of the left-hand side of (75) and the infrared finiteness of SUM IR (QCD), it follows that the quantity d ¯ ˆ σ exp ≡ e −SUM IR (QCD) dêxp must also be infrared finite to all orders in α s .</p>

				<p>As we assume the QCD theory makes sense in some neighborhood of the origin for α s , we conclude that each order in α s must make an infrared finite contribution to d ¯ ˆ σ exp .</p>

				<p>At O(α 0 s (Q)) , the only contribution to d ¯ ˆ σ exp is the respective Born cross section given by ¯ β (0) 0 in (75) and it is obviously infrared finite, where we use henceforth the notation ¯ β (ℓ) n to denote the O(α ℓ s (Q)) part of ¯ β n . Thus, we conclude that the lowest hard gluon residual ¯ β (0) 0 is infrared finite. Let us now define the left-over non-Abelian infrared divergence part of each contribution ¯ β</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(ℓ) n via ¯ β (ℓ) n = ˜ ¯ β (ℓ) n + D ¯ β (ℓ) n where the new functioñ ¯ β (ℓ)</trash>

					<figDesc>n is now completely free of any infrared divergences and the function D ¯ β (ℓ)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>n contains all left-over infrared divergences in ¯ β (ℓ) n which are of non-Abelian origin and is normalized to vanish in the Abelian limit f abc → 0 where f abc are the group structure constants.</p>

				<p>Further, we define D ¯ β (ℓ) n by a minimal subtraction of the respective IR divergences in it so that it only contains the actual pole and transcendental constants, 1/ǫ − C E for ǫ = 2 − d/2, where d is the dimension of space-time, in dimensional regularization or ln λ 2 in the gluon mass regularization. Here, C E is Euler&apos;s constant.</p>

				<p>For definiteness, we write this out explicitly as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dP h D ¯ β (ℓ) n ≡ n+ℓ i=1 d n,ℓ i ln i (λ 2 ) where the coefficient functions d n,ℓ i</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are independent of λ for λ → 0 and dP h is the respective n-gluon Lorentz invariant phase space.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>At O(α n s (Q)), the IR finiteness of the contribution to d ¯ ˆ σ exp then requires the contri- bution d ¯ ˆ σ (n) exp ≡ n ℓ=0 1 ℓ! ℓ j=1 k j ≥Kmax d 3 k j k j ˜ S QCD (k j ) n−ℓ i=0 1 i! ℓ+i j=ℓ+1 d 3 k j k 0 j ¯ β (n−ℓ−i) i (k ℓ+1 , . . . , k ℓ+i ) d 3 p 2 p 0 2 d 3 q 2 q 0 2 (78) to be finite. From this it follows that Dd ¯ ˆ σ (n) exp ≡ n ℓ=0 1 ℓ! ℓ j=1 k j ≥Kmax d 3 k j k j ˜ S QCD (k j ) n−ℓ i=0 1 i! ℓ+i j=ℓ+1 d 3 k j k 0 j D ¯ β (n−ℓ−i) i (k ℓ+1 , . . . , k ℓ+i ) d 3 p 2 p 0 2 d 3 q 2 q 0 2</trash>

					<figDesc>(79) is finite. Since the integration region for the final particles is arbitrary, the independent powers of the IR regulator ln(λ 2 ) in this last equation must give vanishing contributions.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>This means that we can drop the D ¯ β (ℓ) n from our result (75) because they do not make a net contribution to the final parton cross section σ exp . We thus finally arrive at the new rigorous result</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dêxp = n dê SUM IR (QCD) ∞ n=0 n j=1 d 3 k j k j d 4 y (2π) 4 e iy·(p 1 +q 1 −p 2 −q 2 − P k j )+D QCD * ˜ ¯ β n (k 1 , . . . , k n ) d 3 p 2 p 0 2 d 3 q 2 q 0 2 (80) where now the hard gluon residuals ¯ β n (k 1 , . . . , k n ) defined by ˜ ¯ β n (k 1 , . . . , k n = ∞ ℓ=0 ¯ β (ℓ) n (k 1 , . . . , k n ) (81)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are free of all infrared divergences to all orders in α s (Q). This is a basic result of this Appendix.</p>

				<p>We note here that, contrary to what was claimed in the Appendix of the first paper in Refs. [16] and consistent with what is explained in the third reference in [16], the arguments in the first paper in Refs. [16] are not sufficient to derive the respective analog of eq.(80); for, they did not really expose the compensation between the left over genuine non-Abelian IR virtual and real singularities between dP h ¯ β n and dP h ¯ β n+1 respectively that really distinguishes QCD from QED, where no such compensation occurs in the ¯ β n residuals for QED.</p>

				<p>We point-out that the general non-Abelian exponentiation of the eikonal cross sections in QCD has been proven formally in Ref. [34]. The contact between Ref. [34] and our result (80) is that, in the language of Ref. [34], our exponential factor corresponds to the N=1 term in the exponent of eq.(10) of the latter reference. One also sees immediately the fundamental difference between what we derive in (80) and the eikonal formula in Ref. [34]: our result (80) is an exact re-arrangement of the complete cross section whereas the result in eq.(10) of Ref. [34] is an approximation to the complete cross section in which all terms that could not be eikonalized and exponentiated have been dropped.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">† Work partly supported by US DOE grant DE-FG02-05ER41399 and by NATO grant PST.CLG.980342.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We will generally follow Ref. [6] and set µ 0 = Λ QCD without loss of content since dt = dt ′ when t = ln µ 2 /Λ 2 QCD , t ′ = ln µ 2 /µ 2 0 for fixed values of Λ QCD , µ 0 .</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Note that we do not address p T resummation effects herein; we use this example to illustrate the point that, whenever the phase space for radiation is restricted in a given variable, soft gluon radiation will result in large logs that need to be resummed, altough the methods to make this resummation may vary in detail.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Following the standard LEP Yellow Book [7] convention, we do not include the order of the first nonzero term in counting the order of its higher order corrections.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> These correspond with maximally non-Abelian terms in Ref. [34] but computed exactly rather than in the eikonal approximation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Callan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jr</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Symanzik, Commun. Math. Phys Springer Tracts in Modern Physics</title>
		<editor>G. Hoehler</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1541" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Georgi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Politzer</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Gross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Wilczek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="980" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">B126 (1977) 298</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Altarelli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Parisi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nucl</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L N</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yad</forename>
				<surname>Lipatov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Fiz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Gribov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sov</forename>
				<surname>Lipatov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Yu. L. Dokshitzer, Sov. Phys. JETP J. Nucl. Phys. J.C. Collins and J. Qiu, Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">938</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="1398" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>for. an alternative discussion of the lowest order DGLAP-CS theory</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Applications of Perturbative QCD</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Field</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley Publ. Co., Inc, Redwood City</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Z Line Shape</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Berends</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>G.</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Altarelli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Kleiss</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Verzegnassi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CERN, Geneva, 1989) p. 89, and references therein</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">D47 (1993) 3733; Phys. Lett.B257 (1991) 173; in &quot; Z o Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Skrzypek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L S</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. XXVth Rencontre de Moriond</title>
		<editor>J. Tran Thanh Van</editor>
		<meeting>. XXVth Rencontre de Moriond<address><addrLine>Les Arcs, France ; Editions Frontieres, Gif-Sur-Yvette</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="2669" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Tpju</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Brighton Workshop</title>
		<editor>N. Dombey and F. Boudjema</editor>
		<meeting>. Brighton Workshop<address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Plenum</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page">325</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Collins</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Soper</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Sterman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Nucl. Phys.B250 (1985) 199, and references therein</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Balazs</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">637</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">235</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Acosta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CDF Collaboration)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">022003</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Albino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Ball</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">513</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">93</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Mikhailov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page">431</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">B33 (2002) 1543 Amsterdam, 2003 ) p. 275</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Acta</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Mod</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Delaney</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. DPF 2004</title>
		<editor>Proc. ICHEP2002, ed. S. Bentvelsen et al.,( North Holland C. Glosser, S. Jadach, B.F.L. Ward and S.A.,Mod B.F.L. Ward, C. Glosser, S. Jadach and S.A. Yost</editor>
		<meeting>. DPF 2004</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>A20</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ICHEP04 Singapore, 2005) p. 588; B.F.L. Ward and S. Yost, preprint BU-HEPP-05-05, and references therein</title>
		<editor>H. Chen et al.</editor>
		<meeting>. ICHEP04 Singapore, 2005) p. 588; B.F.L. Ward and S. Yost, preprint BU-HEPP-05-05, and references therein</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Sci. Publ. Co</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">D52 (1995) 108; Phys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Delaney</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">239</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="342" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Yennie</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Frautschi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Suura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Phys. Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">329</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>379. ; see also K. T. Mahanthappa. related. analysis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">B78 (1978) 281; Nucl.Phys. B152 (1979) 285</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. Phys. Rev</title>
		<editor>29</editor>
		<editor>S. Libby and G. Sterman</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3252</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3705. . [19] B.F.L. Ward, to appear</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Gorishnii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Larin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Tkachov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<editor>217</editor>
		<editor>S. G. Gorishnii and S.A. Larin</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">B129(1977) 66;ibid.B139(1978) 545; ibid</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Floratos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ross</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Sachrajda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">B152</title>
		<editor>A. Gonzalez-Arroyo, C. Lopez and F.J. Yndurain</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">493</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>B153</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Curci</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Furmanski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nucl</forename>
				<surname>Petronzio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Furmanski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Petronzio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Floratos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kounnas</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lacaze</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>161</editor>
		<editor>A. Gonzalez-Arroyo and C. Lopez, Nucl. Phys. B166 R. Hamberg and W. Van Neerven</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="97" />
			<pubPlace>Nucl. Phys</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A M</forename>
				<surname>Vermaseren</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Vogt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="688" to="691" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bethke</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Suppl</title>
		<meeting>. Suppl</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">345</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Carli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. HERA-LHC Workshop</title>
		<editor>A. De Roeck and H. Jung</editor>
		<meeting>. HERA-LHC Workshop<address><addrLine>Geneva</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CERN</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">78</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rev D38 (1988) 2897; ibid. D39 (1989) 1471; ibid) 351; Phys</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Phys. Commun.Lett. Comput. Phys. Commun. Phys.Lett. Phys.Rev. Phys. Rev</title>
		<editor>S. Jadach, W. Placzek and B.F.L. Ward</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>S</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3582102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">298</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4056" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1206" />
			<publisher>S</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Was</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Comp. Phys. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">432</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Corcella</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Magnea</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Cern-Ph-Th</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-06-15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Sterman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys.B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">281</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">310</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Catani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Trentadue</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys.B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">353</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">183</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Moch</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A M</forename>
				<surname>Vermaseren</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Vogt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">726</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">317</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Comp</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Skrzypek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Jezabek, Acta Phys. Pol. B27 and references therein</title>
		<editor>J. Blumlein and H. Kawamura</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Acta Phys. Polon. B33</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="1309" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Was</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Eur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="423" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Jadach</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F L</forename>
				<surname>Ward</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
				<surname>Was</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">63</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Veltman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">318</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">50</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. refer- ences therein</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G M</forename>
				<surname>Gatherall</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Ellis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Sexton</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="445" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Di</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Lieto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Gendron</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Christopher</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Halliday</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sachrajda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">357</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">37</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and. references therein</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
