<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Entropy of Pairs of Dual Attractors in Six and Seven Dimensions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2008-07-14">14 Jul 2008</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">El</forename>
								<forename type="middle">Hassan</forename>
								<surname>Saidi</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Faculté des Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lab/UFR-Physique des Hautes Energies</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Rabat</settlement>
									<country key="MA">Morocco</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Antonio</forename>
								<surname>Segui</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Departamento de Fisica Teorica</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Zaragoza</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>50009-Zaragoza</addrLine>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Entropy of Pairs of Dual Attractors in Six and Seven Dimensions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2008-07-14">14 Jul 2008</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Preprint typeset in JHEP style -HYPER VERSION Lab/UFR-HEP/0804-rev, GNPHE/0804-rev</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We study the attractor mechanism of dual pairs of black brane bounds in N = 2 supergravity in six and seven dimensions. First, we consider the effective potentials of the 6D and 7D black branes as well as their entropies. The contribution coming from the SO (1, 1) factor of the moduli spaces M 6D and M 7D of these theories is carefully analyzed and it is used to motivate the study of the dual black branes bounds; which in turn allow to fix the critical value of the dilaton at horizon. The attractor eqs of the black branes and the bound pairs are derived by combining the criticality conditions of the corresponding effective potentials and the Lagrange multiplier method capturing constraints eqs on the fields moduli. Keywords: 6D/7D black branes, attractor mechanism, electric/magnetic duality, BPS and non BPS states, entropy. * College SPC, Academie Hassan II des Sciences et Techniques, Rabat, Morocco</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<figure>
					<trash>Contents 1. Introduction 2 2. General tools 5 2.1 Effective potential 6 2.2 Criticality condition 7 3. Duality symmetry and entropy 8 3.1 6D and 7D black attractors 9 3.2 Dyonic attractors in 6D supergravity 11 3.3 Entropy of 6D black attractors 14 4. Black string 16 4.1 Entropy of the black string 16 4.2 Regular and singular representations 18 4.3 Electric/magnetic duality 20 5. Attractor eqs and Lagrange multiplier method 21 5.1 Effective potential V BH 21 5.1.1 Potential of the BH 21 5.1.2 Implementing the Lagrange multiplier 23 5.1.3 Attractor eqs and their solutions 24 5.2 Effective potential V BM 25 5.2.1 Black membrane attractor equations 28 5.2.2 Solving eq(5.55) 29 6. Entropy of the pair BH-BM 32 6.1 Attractor eqs for the dyonic DP 34 6.2 Extremums of V DP 36 6.2.1 Solving eqs(6.33-6.34-6.35) 37 6.2.2 Solving eq(6.40) 39 7. Conclusion and discussion 40 8. Appendix: On effective potential in 6D and 7D 43 8.1 6D N = 2 supergravity 45 8.2 7D N=2 supergravity 49</trash>


				</figure>

			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Supersymmetric and non supersymmetric black attractors have received an increasing interest in the framework of supergravity theories [1]-[8]; especially in the case of those supergravity models embedded in 10D superstrings and 11D M-theory compactifications [9]-[27]. New solutions to the attractor equations describing BPS and non-BPS states have been obtained and many results concerning supergravity theories in four and higher dimensional space times have been derived [28]-[40]. For reviews, see for instance [41]-[46].</p>

				<p>In this paper, we contribute to this matter by studying the attractor mechanism and the entropy S of the two following 6D/7D black brane systems: 1) the first system we consider concerns generic Electrically charged Black Branes (EBB for short) in N = 2 supergravity theory in six and seven dimensional space times. If most of the basic properties of these EBBs with electric charges</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>q Λ = 0 , Λ = 1, ... , (1.1) but no magnetic charges g Λ = 0 , Λ = 1, ... , (1.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are quite known; there are nevertheless some specific properties that need more studies. Here, we would like to shed more light on the EBB entropy and the electric/magnetic duality which, as we will show, turn out to be strongly related: a) Concerning the entropy S EBB =S EBB (q) of the EBB black attractors in 6D and 7D, it turns out that it takes a very remarkable value 1 namely,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S EBB = 0 . (1.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This degenerate value will be analyzed in details throughout this study by using the criticality method; but to fix the ideas think about it as given by the g Λ → 0 limit of the following relation to be explicitly derived in this work,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S EBB = 1 2 lim g Λ →0 |q 2 g 2 | = 0, (1.4) with q 2 = Λ q Λ q Λ and g 2 = Λ g Λ g Λ .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In an attempt to analyze what kind of information we can extract from the classical relation S EBB (q) = 0, we ended with the conclusion that this degenerate value could be interpreted as a singular limit of a bound state of the following pair of dual black attractor</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>EBB-MBB , (1.5) 1 Black holes</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>could be either small or large depending on whether the corresponding classical horizon area is zero or non zero [47, 48, 49, 12]. If we naively apply the Bekenstein-Hawking entropy-area formula to the small black holes, their entropy vanishes and the expected quantum degrees of freedom seem to totally disappear. This discrepancy comes from the fact that the general relativity is only a classical effective theory of quantum gravity opening then a way to deal with small black holes in connection with R 2 corrections and supersymmetry enhancement in near horizon geometry [50, 48, 49, 12, 51]. Small black holes exist also in higher dimensions. In 5D, an explicit study of small black holes in N = 2 and N = 4 supergravity can be found in [52] and refs therein. – 2 – where MBB stands for the magnetic dual of EBB. The black attractor bound state EBB-MBB will be introduced and commented succinctly below; see the point (2) of this motivating presentation. But explicit details and extensive comments will be given in the section 6 of this work. b) Concerning the electric/magnetic duality, it is used to deal with the Magnetically charged Black Branes (MBB). Roughly, this duality exchanges the charges of the EBB and the corresponding MBB dual along the standard correspondence,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>EBB electric/magnetic duality ←−−−−−−−−−−−−−−−→ MBB . (1.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this study, we will show that electric/magnetic duality is in fact a universal symmetry of EBB and MBB attractors. It exchanges not only the electric {q Λ } and magnetic {g Λ } charges (q Λ ↔ g Λ ); but also the effective scalar potentials V EBB and V M BB as well as the corresponding entropies S EBB and S M BB as illustrated below,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>EBB electric/magnetic duality ←−−−−−−−−−−−−−−−→ MBB q Λ ←→ g Λ V EBB ←→ V M BB S EBB ←→ S M BB .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From this correspondence, we immediately conclude that the entropy S M BB = S M BB (g) of the magnetically charged black brane MBB should be identically zero; in agreement with eq(1.4). The relation S M BB = 0 will be rigourously derived in sub-section 5.2. We also learn that the scalar potentials V EBB and V M BB are intimately related as it will be explicitly shown in section 5. 2) the second system that we want to study in this paper concerns precisely generic Dual Black Brane Pairs ( dual pairs DP for short). A DP attractor can defined as a bound state consisting of an electrically charged brane EBB and its magnetic dual MBB. Formally, we can represent a generic DP bound state either as in eq(1.5) or roughly, by using group theory representation language, like a doublet</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>DP ∼ EBB MBB . (1.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this set up, the EBB attractor considered in point (1), with the degenerate entropy S EBB = 0, can be thought of as corresponding to the singular limit</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>DP g Λ → 0 −−−−→ EBB 0 , (1.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>describing a singular geometry where the horizon area A M BB of the MBB attractor shrinks to a singular point (A M BB → 0).</p>

				<p>The same picture is valid for the dual MBB attractor which corresponds to the degenerate limit,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>DP q Λ → 0 −−−−→ 0 M BB , (1.9) – 3 – describing</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the electric/magnetic dual of eq(1.8). Before proceeding ahead, we would like to notice that the results we will derive below for the DP attractors apply as well to: i) the dyonic Black String (BS for short) of the 6D N = 2 supergravity, ii) the DP brane bounds in all supergravity theories with scalar manifolds of the form SO (1, 1) × (G/H).</p>

				<p>Regarding the 6D black string BS, it can be viewed as a particular representation of the electric magnetic duality group. The BS is a pure singlet while DP is based on the pair (1.7). Moreover, it is interesting to have in mind that, despite their geometric differences, the BS and DP entropy formulas are also comparable. This feature can be explicitly checked by comparing the S DP formula (1.4) and the BS entropy relation S BS to be derived in section 4 eq(4.13), and which we recall below,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BS = |q 0 g 0 | 2 = 1 2 q 2 0 g 2 0 , (1.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with q 0 and g 0 being respectively the electric and magnetic charges of the 6D black string. As we see, the above S BS expression and the S DP relation (1.4) have more a less the same charge dependence structure.</p>

				<p>Concerning the second feature; it has been pointed out in [46, 55, 56], that supergravity theories with scalar manifolds having an SO (1, 1) factor would have zero entropies. The result S EBB = 0 of eq(1.3) and, up on using electric/magnetic duality S MBB = 0 , (1.11) should be then thought of as special relations that are valid as well for supergravity theories beyond those embedded in 10D type IIA superstring and 11D M-theory on K3 we are considering in this work. On the other hand, we will also take the opportunity of the use of the criticality condition of the black branes effective potentials to develop a tricky approach to get the BPS and non BPS states solutions by using an adapted Lagrange multiplier method. Details on this issue will be given in section 5 of this study. BPS and non BPS black holes as well as black membranes are distinguished by the values (5.26-5.28,5.45) of the Lagrange multipliers at the minimum of the effective potential. The Lagrange multipliers λ ΛΣ given by eq(4.35) capture the constraint eqs(5.8,5.14) on the fields coordinates {L ΛΣ } (4.36) that are used to parameterize the moduli space of the theory.</p>

				<p>The organization of this paper is as follows: In section 2, we describe briefly some useful tools; in particular the derivation of the singular value (1.3). In section 3, we study the EBB and MBB attractors as well as the DP black attractor bounds in 6D and 7D N = 2 supergravity theories. In section 4, we consider with details the 6D black string. We show, amongst others, that its entropy is invariant under electric/magnetic duality and conclude with a general result on dyonic duals pairs of black branes. In section 5, we study the BPS and non BPS black attractors in 6D by using a new method. This approach is based on combining the criticality of the effective potential and the Lagrange multiplier method capturing constraint eqs on the field moduli. Using this approach we derive the attractors eqs of the 6D black hole BH and 6D black membrane BM. We also give the explicit solutions as well as their entropies. In section 6, we derive the effective potential V DP of the dyonic dual pair bound DP ≡ BH-BM. Then we study the attractor mechanism for the dyonic DP and derive the general formula for its entropy S DP . This result obtains for the 6D apply as well to the dyonic black hole-black 3-brane (BH-B3B) and the (BS-BM ) bound state of the 7D theory. In section 7, we give the conclusion and discussion and in section 8, we give an appendix.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">General tools</head>

				<p>To exhibit explicitly the particular features</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S 6D EBB = 0 , S 7D EBB = 0 , S 6D MBB = 0 , S 7D MBB = 0 , (2.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>of the entropies of the electrically charged EBB and the magnetically charged MBB in six and seven space time dimensions, it is interesting to start by describing briefly some useful results. We begin by recalling that the moduli space M N =2 6D of the 6D N = 2 supergravity theory embedded in 10D type IIA superstring on K3 is given by the following Lie group coset</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M N =2 6D = SO (1, 1) × G 6 , G 6 = SO(4,20) SO(4)×SO(20) . (2.2) A quite similar factorization holds for the scalar manifold M N =2 7D of the N = 2 supergravity theory in 7D space time embedded in 11D M-theory on K3. It reads as follows M 7 = SO (1, 1) × G 7 , G 7 = SO(3,19) SO(3)×SO(19) . (2.3) As we see, the two scalar manifolds M N =2 6D and M N =2 7D are given by the product of two factors namely SO (1, 1) and G n with n = 6, 7. The real one dimensional factor SO (1, 1) is parameterized by a real field variable σ, to be interpreted as the 6D (resp. 7D ) dilaton σ = σ (x). The factor G 6 is real 80 dimensional manifold parameterized by the real field coordinates, φ aI (x) ≃ (4, 20) , (2.4) transforming in the bi-fundamental of the SO (4) × SO (20) isotropy symmetry with a = 1, ..., 4 and I = 1, ..., 20. The factor G 7 is real 57 dimensional manifold parameterized by the field coordinates ξ αi (x) ≃ (3, 19) , (2.5) transforming in the bi-fundamental of the SO (3) × SO (19) isotropy symmetry with α = 1, 2, 3 and i = 1, ..., 19. As the technical analysis of eqs(2.2) and (2.3) is quite similar, we will focus our attention mainly on the 6D theory and just give the results for the 7D case. – 5 – 2.1 Effective potential</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The effective potential V of black attractors in generic space time D-dimensional extended supergravity, including 6D N = 2, have been studied in [46]; see also [55] as well as the appendix of this paper. The general form of this potential reads formally, in terms of the geometric Z geo and the matter Z matter central charges, as follows</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V (φ) ∼ |Z geo (φ)| 2 + |Z matter (φ)| 2 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that Z geo has contributions coming from the physical charges of the various gauge fields of the gravity supermultiplet while Z matter has contributions coming from the gauge fields in the matter sector.</p>

				<p>In the case of 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity, we have the following gauge field strengths,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>gravity multiplet : H 3 = dB 2 , F a 2 = dA a 1 , matter multiplets : F I 2 = dA I 1 , (2.6) together with their magnetic duals G 3 , G a 4 and G I 4 . So Z 6D,N =2 geo and Z 6D,N =2 matter have contributions from the charges of (H 3 , G 3 ) , F a 2 , F I 2 and G a 4 , G I 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>; and then the full effective potential V 6D,N =2 involves three blocks namely V black string , V black hole and V black membrane .</p>

				<p>Notice also that in eq(2.6), B 2 = 1 2 dx µ dx ν B [µν] is the usual NS-NS B µν -field in 6D, the gauge fields A a µ stand for the four graviphotons and A I µ for the twenty Maxwell fields of the non chiral 6D supergravity embedded in type IIA superstring on K3, see eqs(3.29-3.30) to fix the ideas. Following [46] and [55], we can compute explicitly the various contributions V black string , V black hole and V black membrane by using the following generic relations,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V black string ∼ Z BS geo 2 + Z BS matter 2 , V black hole ∼ Z BH geo 2 + Z BH matter 2 , V black membrane ∼ Z BM geo 2 + Z BM matter 2 . These contributions, which are respectively associated with (H 3 , G 3 ) , F a 2 , F I 2 and G a 4 , G I 4</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, will be studied later on; they are given by eqs(4.2), (5.2), (5.37). With these relations in mind, we turn now to study some specific properties of these potentials. One of the consequences of the factorization (2.2) of the manifold M</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N =2 6D is that the EBB (resp. MBB) effective scalar potential V SBB 6D = V SBB 6D (σ, φ) , (2.7) where the upper index SBB stands either for EBB or MBB, factorizes as well like V SBB 6D = V SO(1,1) × V G 6 . (2.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The term in the right hand of the above relation,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V SO(1,1) = V dil (σ) , (2.9) – 6 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is the dilaton contribution to eq(2.8); it has no dependence in the local field coordinates φ aI ; that is no dependence in the matter fields of the Maxwell sector of the theory,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∂V SO(1,1) ∂φ aI = 0. (2.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We will see later on that this contribution is given by the typical remarkable relation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V SO(1,1) (σ) ≃ exp (nσ) , (2.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the number n depends on the type of the black brane we are dealing with. More precisely, we have the following values [55, 56],</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>6D black string : n = ±4 , 6D black hole : n = −2 , 6D black membrane : n = +2 . (2.12) The factor V G 6 of (2.8) has no dependence in the dilaton V G 6 = V G 6 (φ) , ∂V G 6 ∂σ = 0 , (2.13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>it describes the contribution of the matter fields φ aI in the Maxwell sector of the 6D N = 2 supergravity theory. The explicit field expression of V G 6 in terms of the φ aI will be given later on.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.2">Criticality condition</head>

				<p>First we study the electrically (resp. magnetically) charged black brane EBB (resp. MBB). Then we consider the case of the dyonic black string BS. The critical values (σ, φ) = (σ c , φ c ) of the effective scalar potential V SBB</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>6D (2.7-2.8) are obtained by solving the constraint equations ∂V SBB 6D ∂σ = 0 , ∂V SBB 6D ∂φ aI = 0 , (2.14) which, due to the factorization property (2.8), simplify like, ∂V SO(1,1) ∂σ = 0 , ∂V G 6 ∂φ aI = 0 . (2.15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The critical value σ c of the dilaton that extremize the potential V</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>SO(1,1) , and then V SBB 6D , is obtained by computing ∂V SO(1,1) ∂σ ≃ ∂ [e nσ ] ∂σ = ne nσ = 0 , (2.16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>from which we learn that the critical point corresponds to the following infinite value,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>nσ c −→ −∞. (2.17) – 7 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For n &gt; 0, σ c −→ −∞ and for n &lt; 0, σ c −→ +∞.</p>

				<p>Putting this value back into V SO(1,1) eq(2.11), we see that the value of the potential V SO(1,1) at the critical point vanishes identically; i.e,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V SO(1,1) σ=σc = 0 . (2.18) Because of the factorization (2.8), we also have V SBB 6D σ=σc = 0 , (2.19) leading as well to the zero entropy relation, S SBB 6D = 0 , (2.20) in agreement with eq(1.3).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For the dyonic 6D black string, the situation is different. The form of the corresponding effective potential V BS has the following field moduli factorization,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V BS = V SO(1,1) (σ) × V 6 (φ) + V SO(1,1) (−σ) × ˜ V 6 (φ) , (2.21) where V 6</trash>

					<figDesc>(φ) stands for the contribution coming from the electric charge and V 6 (φ) the contribution coming from the magnetic charge.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>As we will see in details later, it turns out that the solving of the criticality condition of V BS leads to a finite critical value of the dilaton</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>|σ c | &lt; ∞ . (2.22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Substituting this value back into V BS , we obtain a positive definite value of the effective potential at the minimum, [</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>V BS (σ)] σ=σc &gt; 0 , (2.23) leading in turn to a on a zero value of the entropy S BS for the dyonic 6D black string. The value of S BS is given by eq(1.10); it will be computed explicitly later on, see eq(4.13).</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Duality symmetry and entropy</head>

				<p>First, we describe some useful aspects on: (1) the 6D and7D attractors and the dual pairs, (2) the gauge invariant n-forms in generic d-dimensions; in particular the electric/magnetic duality [57, 58, 59] and the fluxes used to define the various electric and magnetic charges. Then, we study the &quot; dyonic &quot; attractors in 6D and 7D. We will distinguish the two following cases: (a) the 6D Black String BS ; behaving as a singlet under electric/magnetic duality</p>

				<p><formula>(BS) . (3.1) – 8 –</formula></p>

				<p>No analogous object exists in 7D. (b) Bound states of dual EBB and MBB behaving as pairs under electric magnetic duality EBB M BB . (3.2)</p>

				<p>The possible candidates for these bound pairs are: (i) the 6D Black Hole -Black Membrane (BH-BM ), (ii) the 7D Black Hole -Black 3-Brane (BH-B3B), (iii) the 7D Black String -Black Membrane (BS-BM ). Below, we shall focus our attention in a first step on the special 6D dyonic string BS and its entropy S BS .</p>

				<p>Then, we study the basic properties of the BH and BM black attractors separately. This study can be viewed as a prelude to BH-BM bound.</p>

				<p>More details on the dual pair BH-BM in six dimensions and its analogues in 7D will be considered in section 6 and the discussion section.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.1">6D and 7D black attractors</head>

				<p>Electric/magnetic duality permutes electrically charged objects and their magnetic charged duals. In 10D type II superstrings and 11D M-theory compactifications down to d-dimensions, this discrete symmetry relates those pairs of p 1 -and p 2 -dimensional black objects with the condition</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>p 1 + p 2 = d − 4 , d ≥ 4 . (3.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From this relation, one recognizes: (1) the 4D dyonic black hole corresponding to p 1 + p 2 = 0. (2) the 6D dyonic black string corresponding to p 1 + p 2 = 2. (3) the 8D dyonic black membrane corresponding to p 1 + p 2 = 4.</p>

				<p>In six and seven dimensions we are interested in we have the following:</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>6D case</head>

				<p>In the non chiral 6D N = 2 supergravity theory embedded in 10D type IIA superstring on K3, the relation (3.3) reads as, p 1 + p 2 = 2 , (3.4) and can be solved in three ways like: (a) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (1, 1) describing a dyonic black string (BS ). The 6D BS attractor carries both an electric charge q 0 and a magnetic charge g 0 associated with the gauge invariant 3-form field strength</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H 3 = dB 2 , (3.5) of the N = 2 supergravity multiplet. (b) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (0, 2) describing a magnetic black hole (BH ). – 9 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In 6D, the BH attractor carries 24 magnetic charges g BH Λ (g Λ for short) associated with the gauge invariant fields strengths</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F Λ 2 = dA Λ 1 , (3.6) of the N = 2 supergravity theory. The 6D BH hole has no electric charge, q BH Λ = 0. (3.7) (c) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (2, 0) describing an electric 6D black membrane (BM ) carrying 24 electric charges q BM Λ (q Λ for short) related to g BH Λ under electric magnetic duality. The 6D black membrane has no magnetic charge g BM Λ = 0. (3.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The above BH and the BM attractors are related by electric/magnetic duality in six dimensions. As such, the bound state made of the 6D black hole BH and the 6D black membrane BM 6D : BH-BM ≡ BH BM , (3.9) form a dyonic pair of black attractors with 24 electric and 24 magnetic charges {q Λ , g Λ } , Λ = 1, ..., 24. (3.10) Viewed as a single entity, the composite state BH-BM should, ` a priori, share the basic features of the dyonic black string BS ; in particular sharing aspects of the effective potentials and their entropies. We will study these features details later on.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>7D case</head>

				<p>In the case of 7D N = 2 supergravity theory embedded in 11D M-theory on K3, the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>relation (3.3) becomes p 1 + p 2 = 3 (3.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and it is solved in four manners as follows: (a) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (0, 3) describing a magnetic 7D black hole (BH ), (b) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (3, 0) describing an electric 7D black 3-brane (B3B), dual to the black hole.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(c) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (1, 2) describing a magnetic 7D black string (BS ). (d) the case (p 1 , p 2 ) = (2, 1) describing an electric 7D black 2-brane (BM ), dual to the black string. The 7D N = 2 supergravity theory embedded in 11D M-theory on K3 has the following abelian gauge symmetry, U N S (1) × U 3 (1) × U 19 (1) . (3.12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The 7D black hole BH and black 3-brane B3B are charged under the U 22 (1) gauge symmetry of the supergravity theory while the 7D black string BS and black membrane BM are charged under the gauge invariant 3-form and its dual 4-form.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>– 10 –</head>

				<p>Notice that in 7D N = 2 supergravity theory, we have no dyonic singlet; but rather two kinds of dyonic pairs: (i) the pair</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>BH-B3B ≡ BH B3B , (3.13) carrying 22 electric charges {q 1 , ..., q 22 } and 22 magnetic ones {g 1 , ..., g 22 }. (ii) the pair BS-BM ≡ BS BM , (3.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>carrying an electric charge q 0 and a magnetic charge g 0 .</p>

				<p>Notice also that there is a correspondence between the attractors in 6D and 7D space time dimensions. We have, 6D : BS ←→ 7D : BS-BM , 6D : BH-BM ←→ 7D : BH-B3B . (3.15)</p>

				<p>This property is a consequence following from the relation between 11D M-theory and 10D type IIA superstring; which after compactification on K3, descends to the 6D and the 7D space times.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.2">Dyonic attractors in 6D supergravity</head>

				<p>To start recall that in the d-dimensional space time, a gauge invariant (p + 2)-form field strength (p ≤ d −</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2), F p+2 = 1 (p+2)! dx µ p+2 . . . dx µ 1 F µ 1 ...µ p+2 , (3.16) with a (p + 1)-form gauge connection A p+1 = 1 (p+1)! dx µ p+1 . . . dx µ 1 A µ 1 ...µ p+1 , (3.17) has a Poincaré (magnetic) dual given by G d−p−2 = ⋆ F p+2 . (3.18) with the usual property * G d−p−2 = − (−) (p+2)(d−p−2) F p+2 . (3.19) Expanding G d−p−2 , G d−p−2 = 1 (p+2)!(d−p−2)! dx µ D · · · dx µ p+3 G µ p+3 ...µ d , (3.20) we also have G µ p+3 ...µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p><formula>d = F µ 1 ...µ p+2 ε µ 1 ...µ p+2 µ p+3 ...µ d , (3.21) – 11 – with ε µ 1 .</formula></p>

				<p>..µ p+2 µ p+3 ...µ d being the d-dimensional completely antisymmetric tensor.</p>

				<p>The magnetic charge g (resp electric charge q) associated with the field strength F p+2</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(resp. G d−p−2 ) can be defined as g = S p+2 F p+2 , q = S d−p−2 G d−p−2 . (3.22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Using the normalized n-volume form Ω n of the real n-sphere S n ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S n Ω n = 1 , n = p + 2 or d − p − 2 , (3.23) we can also express the gauge invariant field strengths as follows, F p+2 = g Ω p+2 , G d−p−2 = q Ω d−p−2 , (3.24) with Ω p+2 ∧ Ω d−p−2 ≃ V d . (3.25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where V d is the volume real d-form of the space time. We also have F p+2 ∧ G d−p−2 ≃ gqV d , (3.26) with the following quantization condition relating electric and magnetic sectors, gq = 2πk , k integer . (3.27)</p>

				<p>Seen that the analysis for 6D and the analysis for 7D are quite similar, we shall fix our attention in what follows on the 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity theory; too particularly on the case of 6D supergravity models embedded in 10D type IIA superstring on K3. There, the field theory spectrum following from the compactification of 10D type IIA superstring on K3, involves the two supersymmetric multiplets namely the gravity supermultiplet and the Maxwell supermultiplets: (1) the gravity supermultiplet This supermultiplet contains, in addition to fermions, the following bosonic fields:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(i) the 6D gravity field : g µν = g µν (x) , µ, ν = 0, ..., 5 , (ii) the NS-NS B-field : B µν = B µν (x) , (iii) four U (1) gauge fields : A a µ = A a µ (x) , a = 1, ..., 4 , (iv) the 6D dilaton : σ = σ (x) . (2) the Maxwell gauge sector This sector involves twenty Maxwell supermultiplets with the following bosons: (i) twenty abelian gauge fields : A I µ = A I µ (x) , I = 1, ..., 20, (ii) twenty quartets of scalars : φ aI = φ aI (x) . – 12 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The abelian gauge symmetry group of the 6D N = 2 supergravity theory that we are considering here can be cast as follows</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>U N S (1) × U 4 (1) × U 20 (1) . (3.28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The U N S (1) factor is the abelian gauge symmetry associated with the NS-NS gauge field B µν and field strength F 3 that we have denoted earlier as H 3 .</p>

				<p>The abelian factor U 4 (1) is the gauge symmetry with the four gauge fields A a µ and the field strengths F a 2 of the supergravity multiplet.</p>

				<p>The factor U 20 (1) is associated with A I µ and the field strength F I 2 of the Maxwell-matter sector.</p>

				<p>Along with the gauge invariant fields strengths</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F 3 , F a 2 , F I 2 . (3.29) We also have their Poincare duals namely G 3 , G a 4 , G I 4 . (3.30) The (1 + 24</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) electric charges and the (1 + 24) magnetic charges associated with these gauge invariant field strengths are as follows: (a) dyonic black string BS : The 6D dyonic BS has an electric charge q 0 and a magnetic charge g 0 with the following quantization condition q 0 g 0 = 2πk 0 , (3.31) where k 0 is an integer (k 0 ∈ Z). (b) 6D black hole BH : The six dimensional BH has magnetic charges 2 under the gauge symmetry U 24 (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1). g Λ , Λ = 1, ..., 24 . (3.32) (c) 6D black membrane BM :</trash>

					<figDesc>The six dimensional BM is the dual of the black hole and is electrically charged under the U 24 (1) gauge symmetry: q Λ , Λ = 1, ..., 24 . (3.33)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The electric and magnetic charges of the 6D black hole and the 6D black membrane are related by the quantization condition,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>q Λ g Λ = 2πk Λ , k Λ ∈ Z . (3.34) 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For a geometric derivation of the explicit relation between the bare charge gΛ and the physical charges (ma, mI ), see [56] – 13 –</p>

				<p>In the brane language of 10D type IIA superstring on Calabi-Yau manifolds, the electric and/or the magnetic charges are associated with branes wrapping cycles of Calabi-Yau manifold (CY). In the 6D case we are considering, the CY manifold in question is given by K3 with a homology containing, in addition to the 0-cycle C 0 (K3 points) and the real 4-cycle C 4 , real twenty-two 2-cycles C I 2 . We also have the following features 6D black attractors : electric/magnetic near horizon geometry</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Entropy dyonic black string : q 0 , g 0 AdS 3 × S 3 R 3 H 1 G − 3 4 N black hole : (0, g Λ ) AdS 2 × S 4 R 4 H 2 G −1 N black membrane : q Λ , 0 AdS 4 × S 2 R 2 H 3 G − 1 2</trash>

					<figDesc>N</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>where the last column stands for the 6D generalized Bekenstein-Hawking entropy formula expressed in terms of the 6D Newton constant G N and the radius of the horizon geometry.</p>

				<p>In the case of black string for instance, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S entropy BF S ∼ G − 3 4</trash>

					<figDesc>N × A ha ,</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>where A ha is the 3d-horizon &quot; hyper-area &quot; in agreement with dimensional arguments and black object thermodynamics laws. Notice in passing that the 6D black hole BH is made of: -D0 branes, -D2 brane wrapping the twenty-two 2-cycles of K3, and -D4 wrapping K3. The dual black membrane BM is made of: -D2 branes, -D4 brane wrapping the 2-cycles of K3, and -D6 brane wrapping K3. These 6D black objects have different AdS p+2 × S 4−p near horizon geometries; they are schematically represented on the figure 1.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.3">Entropy of 6D black attractors</head>

				<p>Using dimensional arguments and the near horizon geometry, the entropy formula S p of the black p-brane attractor in six space time dimensions, that describes the analogue of the Hawking Bekenstein entropy of the 4D black hole, can be written by as follows</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S p = R 4−p H 1 G − 4−p 4 N , p = 0, 1, 2 . (3.35) Here G N ∼ l 4 Planck is the 6D Newton constant scaling as (lenght) 4 and where R 2 H 1 , R 3 H 2 and R 4 H 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>stand respectively for the horizon &quot; hyper-areas &quot; of the black hole BH (p = 0), – 14 – Figure 1: This figure represents the black attractors in 6D N=2 supergravity. Dashed loops refer to the near horizon geometries: (i) On top: we represent a black string with near horizon geometry AdS 3 × S 3 . (ii) Bottom-left: a BH with its near horizon AdS 2 × S 4 . (iii) Bottom-right: a black membrane with AdS 4 × S 2 geometry . the dyonic black string BS (p = 1), and the black membrane BM (p = 2). The entropy S p is completely specified by the electric q and magnetic g charges of the black attractor, S p = S p (q, g) . (3.36)</p>

				<p>In the next sections, we will first show that the entropies</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BH = S 0 (g Λ ) , S BS = S 1 (q 0 , g 0 ) , S BM = S 2 (q Λ ) , (3.37)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>are indeed specified by the appropriate electric q 0 and q Λ as well as the corresponding magnetic g 0 and g Λ ones. Then we use this result to check explicitly that, at supergravity level, the entropy S 1 (q 0 , g 0 ) of the 6D black string is invariant under electric/magnetic duality. This property is also used to conjecture that the invariance of S BS under the electric/magnetic duality is a general feature of dyonic objects including black brane bound states. As such, invariance under electric/magnetic duality should holds also for the entropy</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S EBB−M BB = S DP (q Λ , g Λ ) , (3.38) of the dual pair bounds DP ≡ (EBB-MBB) given by eqs(3.9,3.13,3.14). By using this natural conjecture, it follows that under the dual change q A → q ′ A = g A , g A → g ′ A = q A , (3.39) we should also have S EBB (q A ) ↔ S M BB g A , (3.40) – 15 – where</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>S EBB and S M BB stand respectively for the entropies of an electrically charged black brane EBB and its magnetic dual MBB.</p>

				<p>In this view, invariance of the entropy S 1 of the dyonic black string BS under the change (3.39) as well as of the dual pair bounds DP,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S 1 (q ′ 0 , g ′ 0 ) = S 1 (q 0 , g 0 ) , S DP (q ′ Λ , g ′ Λ ) = S DP (q Λ , g Λ ) , (3.41) follows straightforwardly.</trash>

					<figDesc>The result for the case S DP (q Λ , g Λ ) will be explicitly derived in section 6. The case of the 6D black string BS will be studied below.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Black string</head>

				<p>The six dimensional black string is a dyonic black attractor solution of the N = 2 non chiral supergravity with near horizon geometry AdS 3 × S 3 . The magnetic charge m = g 0 and the electric charge e = q 0 carried by the BS are those of the gauge invariant 3-form field strengths F 3 and G 3 = ⋆ F 3 . The ⋆ conjugation stands for the usual six dimensional Hodge duality interchanging n-forms with (6 − n) ones.</p>

				<p>The field strengths F 3 and G 3 are associated with the NS-NS 2-form B µν fields in six dimensions.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Using eqs(3.22), we have g 0 = S 3 F 3 , q 0 = S 3 G 3 . (4.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The electric q 0 and magnetic g 0 charges obey the quantization condition (3.31).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4.1">Entropy of the black string</head>

				<p>The effective potential V BS = V BS (σ, g 0 , q 0 ) of the BS is given by the the 6D extension of the 4D Weinhold relation [46, 53, 54]. It reads in terms of the dilaton field σ = σ (x) of the 6D N = 2 supergravity multiplet and the electric/magnetic charges like [55]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>,</figDesc>
					<trash>V BS = g 2 0 2 exp (−4σ) + q 2 0 2 exp (4σ) . (4.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In addition to the exponential behavior, the potential V BS has the remarkable invariance under the following change,</figDesc>
					<trash>σ → −σ and g 0 ↔ q 0 . (4.3) At the horizon r = R BS horizon of the dyonic BS, the above potential V BS is at its minimum. The value of the dilaton at horizon σ 1 = σ r = R BS horizon , (4.4) is obtained by solving the following constraint equation dV BS (σ) dσ = 0, (4.5) – 16 – which in turns leads to, 2q 2 0 exp (4σ) − 2g 2 0 exp (−4σ) = 0 . (4.6) The critical value σ 1 of the dilaton at the horizon R BS horizon is given by exp (4σ 1 ) = ± g 0 q 0 &gt; 0 , (4.7) or equivalently σ 1 = 1 4 ln g 0 q 0 . (4.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From this solution, we learn two interesting information: The first information, noted previously in [56], concerns the electric/magnetic duality. The latter requires interchanging the electric q 0 and magnetic g 0 charges; but also performing the change σ → −σ (4.9) in the moduli space. This property is manifestly exhibited by eqs(4.3-4.6). The second information we learn concerns the critical value σ 1 of the dilaton at the horizon of the black string eq(4.8). Finite critical values σ 1 of the dilaton requires that both the electric q 0 and the magnetic g 0 charges have to be non zero,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>i.e q 0 g 0 = 0 , (4.10) or equivalently by using eq(3.31) k 0 = 0 . (4.11)</trash>

					<figDesc>We will see later that this is a general property valid also for of the 6D dyonic pair BH-BM. Moreover, the value V min BS of the BS potential V BS (σ) at the minimum of the black string potential is</figDesc>
					<trash>V min BF S (σ 1 ) = |q 0 g 0 | &gt; 0 , (4.12) and so the BS entropy reads as S 1 = |q 0 g 0 | 4 . (4.13) Up on using eq(3.31), S 1 can be also expressed as S 1 = π |k 0 | 2 . (4.14) where k</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>0 is an integer. Notice that because of the constraint eq(4.10), the entropy S 1 given by the above eqs is necessarily positive definite. Below, we want to discuss what happens to the entropy S 1 if we try to go beyond the constraint eq(</p>

				<p><formula>4.10). – 17 –</formula></p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4.2">Regular and singular representations</head>

				<p>For later use, we make two comments concerning the effective potential of the dyonic black string. The first comment concerns the generic case where k 0 = 0 and the second deals with the singular case k 0 = 0. (1) case k 0 = 0: This case corresponds to the dyonic black string of the 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity we have been studding. In fact it is interesting to distinguish two situations:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(a) Regular representation: g 0 = 0, q 0 = 0 Here, the extremum of the black string potential at σ 1 = 1 4 ln g 0 q 0 , (4.15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is well defined and is precisely a minimum. Since g 0 and q 0 are related as in eq(3.31), we can be expressed σ 1 either as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>σ 1 = 1 4 ln 2πk 0 q 2 0 , (4.16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>by using the electric charge q 0 and the integer k 0 , or equivalently by using the magnetic charge g 0 like</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>σ 1 = 1 4 ln g 2 0 2πk 0 . (4.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The value of the potential at the minimum depends remarkably on the integer k 0 as shown below,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V min BF S (σ 1 ) = 2π |k 0 | &gt; 0 . (4.18)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is an interesting property that let understand that a non zero entropy value seems to need dyonic charged black branes since if taking for example g 0 = 0 and finite but q 0 = 0, eq(4.18) vanishes identically. (b) Singular representation Notice that, strictly speaking, the condition k 0 = 0 corresponds to g 0 q 0 = 0. But this condition could be solved in general in two ways: First by using regular finite charges g 0 = 0 and q 0 = 0 as just discussed above.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Second by considering the singular situation where we have an infinite number of electric charges and no magnetic charge; i.e</figDesc>
					<trash>q 0 → ∞ and g 0 → 0, (4.19) together with the constraint g 0 = k 0 q 0 . We can also have the symmetric case where we do have an infinite number of magnetic charges and no electric charge: q 0 → 0 and g 0 → ∞. (4.20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>These particular and singular configurations are in some sense formal; but very suggestive. They will be used later on to approach the dyonic pair BH-BM.</figDesc>
					<trash>– 18 – (2) Case k 0 = 0: Using eq(3.31), this case is solved as g 0 = 0 , q 0 = 0. (4.21) or like g 0 = 0 , q 0 = 0. (4.22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>They can be also associated with the (self dual and anti-self dual part) black string of the 6D N = (2, 0) chiral supergravity. There, the NS-NS B-field field B [µν] splits into a self dual part B + [µν] , (4.23) and anti-self dual part B − [µν] . (4.24)</p>

				<p>The strength H + [λµν] associated with the self dual part B + [µν]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, H + 3 = dB + 2 , (4.25) is in the gravity supermultiplet while the field strength H − λµν of the anti-self dual part B − [µν] , H − 3 = dB − 2 , (4.26)</trash>

					<figDesc>together with the field σ, are in the tensor multiplet. The minimum V min BS (σ 1 ) of the black string potential is at infinity; that is either at</figDesc>
					<trash>σ 1 → +∞ , (4.27) or at σ 1 → −∞ .</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In both cases, V min BS (σ 1 ) takes a zero value in agreement with eq(4.18). For illustration; we give in figure 2 the general behavior of the black string potential in terms of the dilaton σ.</figDesc>
					<head>Figure 2:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Variation of the effective potential with to the dilaton field. (a) Case of black string in</figDesc>
					<trash>6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity. (b/c) black string in 6D N = (2, 0) chiral supergravity. – 19 – 4.3 Electric/magnetic duality</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The key property of the above dyonic black string entropy relation (4.13) is that S BS is invariant under the following electric-magnetic change</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>q 0 → q ′ 0 = g 0 , g 0 → g ′ 0 = q 0 , (4.28) with S BS (q 0 , g 0 ) → S BS (q ′ 0 , g ′ 0 ) = S BS (q 0 , g 0 ) . (4.29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This property, which can be explicitly checked on previous eqs, was expected since we are dealing with a dyonic object. Moreover, using the discussion of sub-section 4.2 (singular representation), the relation (4.29) can be extended to the 6D dyonic pair BH-BM.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Black hole/black membrane</head>

				<p>Denoting by S BH the entropy of magnetically charged black hole BH ; i.e S BH = S BH (g Λ ) , (4.30) and by S BM the entropy of the electrically charged black membrane BM ; i.e</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BM = S BM (q Λ ) . (4.31) Then performing the electric/magnetic duality (4.28), the entropies S BH (g Λ ) and S BM (q Λ ) are interchanged as follows S BH (g Λ ) → S BH (g ′ Λ ) = S BM (q Λ ) , S BM (q Λ ) → S BM (q ′ Λ ) = S BH (g Λ ) . (4.32)</trash>

					<figDesc>From these relations we learn that, like for the dyonic BS singlet, the entropy S DP = S BH−BM (g Λ , q Λ ) , (4.33) of the dyonic pair DP ≡ BH-BM obeys the same identity as eq(4.29). It is invariant under electric/magnetic duality transformation.</figDesc>
					<trash>S DP (g Λ , q Λ ) = S DP (g ′ Λ , q ′ Λ ) . (4.34)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In what follows, we want to prove this statement by computing explicitly the expressions of S DP (g Λ , q Λ ) and S DP (g ′ Λ , q ′ Λ ). But before that we need to study the effective potentials and the attractor eqs of the following: (a) the BPS and non BPS black holes in 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity (b) the BPS and non BPS black membranes in 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity (c) the BPS and non BPS dyonic pairs DP ≡ (BH-BM).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>The effective potential and the attractor mechanism of the 6D black string BS has been explicitly studied in [55]. We will then just give the results.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>– 20 –</head>

				<p>We also take this opportunity to develop a new method to deal with the computation of the critical values of the effective potentials of the BH and the BM in six dimensions. This new method relies on enlarging the moduli space of the 6D N = 2 supergravity by including Lagrange multipliers, λ ΛΣ = λ ΣΛ , (4.35) capturing the constraint eqs on the field matrix</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L ΛΣ = L ΛΣ (x) , (4.36) used to parameterize the SO (4, 20) orthogonal group manifold involved in the moduli space SO(4,20) SO(4)×SO(20) . 5. Attractor eqs and Lagrange multiplier method</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We first describe the effective potential V BH of the 6D black hole. Then, we use the electric/magnetic duality and results from [56] to determine the effective potential V BM of the black membrane. After that, we study the attractor eqs and their solutions by combining the approach of the criticality of the potential and the Lagrange multiplier method.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5.1">Effective potential V BH</head>

				<p>In the 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity embedded in 10D type IIA superstring on K3, the black hole BH is magnetically charged under the U</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>4 (1) × U 20 (1) gauge group symmetry. The bare magnetic charges g Λ are given by, g Λ = S 2 F Λ 2 , Λ = 1, ..., 24 . (5.1)</trash>

					<figDesc>The magnetic charges g Λ form a charge vector the group SO (4, 20) with signature 4 (+) and 20 (−) captured by the diagonal flat metric η ΛΣ of the tangent space R (4,20) . 5.1.1 Potential of the BH The effective scalar potential V BH of the black hole is given by the Weinhold relation, expressed in the flat coordinate frame,</figDesc>
					<trash>V BH = 4 a=1 δ ab Z a Z b + 20 I=1 δ IJ Z I Z J . (5.2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this relation, the central charges Z a and Z I are respectively the dressed charges describing respectively the physical charges of the four Maxwell fields in the gravity supermultiplet and the twenty Maxwell fields of the matter sector. The dressing of the charges is given by the following linear combination,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z a = 24 Λ=1 U aΛ g Λ , Z I = 24 Λ=1 U IΛ g Λ , (5.3) – 21 – where U ΣΛ parameterize the moduli space M N =2 6D of 10D type IIA superstring on K3, M N =2 6D = SO (1, 1) × G 6 , G 6 = SO(4,20) SO(4)×SO(20) . (5.4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that the real matrix U ΛΣ obeys a set of constraint relations that can be used to put U ΛΣ in a more convenient form. We have the following properties: (i) the factorization property which allows to factorize U ΛΣ as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>U ΛΣ = e −σ L ΛΣ , U −1 ΛΣ = e σ L −1 ΛΣ , L −1 = ηL t η . (5.5) Here e −σ parameterizes the factor SO (1, 1) of M N =2 6D</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and L ΛΣ defines G 6 . Multiplying this equation by the magnetic charge vector g Σ , we obtain the dressed magnetic charge vector Z Λ = (Z a , Z I ),</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z a = 24 Σ=1 U aΣ g Σ = e −σ 24 Σ=1 L aΣ g Σ , Z I = 24 Σ=1 U IΣ g Σ = e −σ 24 Σ=1 L IΣ g Σ . (5.6) (ii</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) the orthogonality property of the elements of the SO (4, 20) group which requires that the real 24 × 24 matrices L ΛΣ should obey the orthogonality condition:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>4 c,d=1 δ cd L cΛ L dΣ − 20 K,L=1 δ KL L KΛ L LΣ = η ΛΣ , (5.7) with Λ and Σ = 1, · · · , 24. This relation can be also rewritten as L t ηL ΛΣ = 24 Υ,Γ=1 L Υ Λ η ΥΓ L Γ Σ = η ΛΣ . (5.8)</trash>

					<figDesc>Multiplying both sides of this equation by g Λ g Σ , we obtain the following constraint eq</figDesc>
					<trash>4 a,b=1 δ ab Z a Z b − 20 I,J=1 δ IJ Z I Z J = e −2σ g 2 , (5.9) with 24 Λ,Σ=1 g Λ η ΛΣ g Σ = g 2 . (5.10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>This relation expresses the orthogonality condition in terms of the magnetic charges. We will refer to it as the &quot; magnetic orthogonality &quot;</figDesc>
					<trash>relation. (iii) the isotropy invariance under SO (4) × SO (20) which acts on the matrix L ΛΣ ∈ SO (4, 20) as a gauge group symmetry, L = hLh −1 , (5.11) where h ∈ SO (4) × SO (20), the maximal compact subgroup of SO (4, 20). – 22 – 5.1.2 Implementing the Lagrange multiplier</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that the matrix variable L ΛΣ has 24 × 24 real parameters which is much larger that the 80 moduli required by (5.4). The properties (ii) and (iii) are then constraint eqs on L ΛΣ which is convenient to cast as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L ΛΣ = L ab L aJ L Ib L IJ . (5.12)</trash>

					<figDesc>To deal with the undesired degrees of freedom in L ΛΣ , we proceed as follows: (1) we fix the SO (4) × SO (20) gauge symmetry by working in the gauge where the submatrices L ab and L IJ are taken symmetric:</figDesc>
					<trash>L ab = L ba , L IJ = L JI . (5.13) (2) the orthogonality property eq(5.8) L t ηL ΛΣ = η ΛΣ (5.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>will be imposed by using the Lagrange multiplier method. This method should be understood as an alternative way to the usual Maurer-Cartan equation generally used to deal with this matter [46]. Eq(5.8) suggests that the Lagrange multipliers should be a symmetric matrix field λ ΛΣ like in eq(4.35); but the equivalent reduced form eq(5.9) of the constraints suggests that it is more convenient to take the Lagrange parameters λ ΛΣ as follows,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ ΛΣ = λg Λ g Σ , (5.15)</trash>

					<figDesc>where now we have only one Lagrange multiplier λ. Therefore the previous expression of the effective scalar potential V BH of the black hole potential can be put into the following form V BH (σ, Z, λ) = Z a Z a + Z I Z</figDesc>
					<trash>I + λ Z a Z a − Z I Z I − e −2σ g 2 , (5.16) where we have set Z a Z a = 4 a,b=1 δ ab Z a Z b , Z I Z I = 20 I,J=1 δ IJ Z I Z J . (5.17)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this relation, we have an extra dependence on the Lagrange multiplier λ. Moreover, setting Z a = e −σ R a ,</p>

				<p><formula>Z I = e −σ R I , (5.18) with R a = L aΛ g Λ , R I = L IΛ g Λ , (5.19) – 23 –</formula></p>

				<p>we can factorize out the dilaton field dependence in the effective potential. We have: V BH (σ, R, λ) = e −2σ V 0 (R, λ, g)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(5.20) with V 0 (R, λ, g), V 0 (R, λ, g) = R a R a + R I R I + λ R a R a − R I R I − g 2 , (5.21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>being the potential of the black hole at σ = 0. The factor V 0 has no dependence in the dilaton field.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5.1.3">Attractor eqs and their solutions</head>

				<p>Because of the structure of the effective black hole potential V BH (Z, λ) = V BH (σ, R, λ) , (5.22) with Z = Z (σ, R) , R = R (L ΛΣ ) , (5.23) the attractor eqs for the six dimensional magnetic black hole can be written in different, but equivalent manners depending of the variables we use.</p>

				<p>For example, the attractor eqs can stated by using as variables the dilaton σ, the dressed charges R a and R I and obviously the Lagrange multiplier λ. Then we have,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δ e V BH δσ = 0 , δ e V BH δR = 0 , δ e V BH δλ = 0 . (5.24)</trash>

					<figDesc>They can be also expressed by using as variables the dressed central charges Z a = e −σ R a and Z I = e −σ R I and the Lagrange multiplier as follows,</figDesc>
					<trash>(1 + λ) Z a = 0 , (1 − λ) Z I = 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>, R a R a − R I R I = g 2 , (5.25) where now the dilaton has been absorbed in the Z&apos;s. There are three kinds of solutions of the eqs(5.25). These solutions are given by: solution (1) : Z a = 0 , Z I = 0 , λ = ±1 ,</figDesc>
					<trash>(5.26) solution (2) : Z a = 0 , Z I = 0 , λ = +1 , (5.27) solution (3) : Z a = 0 , Z I = 0 , λ = −1 . (5.28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The first one is a singular degenerate solution; while the two others describe respectively a non BPS and a BPS black hole.</p>

				<p>Moreover, since the dressed magnetic charge Z is given by the product e −σ R, the vanishing of the product</p>

				<p><formula>e −σ R = 0 , (5.29) – 24 –</formula></p>

				<p>can, in addition to the singular case e −σ = 0 = R, be solved as well by taking e −σ = 0 , R = 0 (5.30) or e −σ = 0 , R = 0. (5.31) Then, we have to distinguish the two following solutions: (a) case 1 : σ 0 → ∞ In this case, the value of the minimum of the potential at the critical point is given by,</p>

				<p><formula>V min BH = e −2σ 0 g 2 = 0. (5.32)</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>So the entropy S BH of the black hole is zero,</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>S BH = 0. (5.33)</formula></p>

				<p>This configuration corresponds to the solution (5.26). (b) case 2 : σ = σ 0 &lt; ∞. Here the value of the dilaton at horizon σ (r horizon ) = σ 0 is given by a finite number (σ 0 &lt; ∞). The two solutions (5.27-5.28) read as follows case (2a) : R a = 0 , R I = 0 , λ = 1 , case (2b) : R a = 0 , R I = 0 , λ = −1</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>. (5.34) The corresponding values of the 6D black potential V min BH at the minimum are case (2a) : V min BH = −e −2σ 0 g 2 &gt; 0 , g 2 &lt; 0 , case (2b) : V min BH = +e −2σ 0 g 2 &gt; 0 , g 2 &gt; 0 . (5.35)</trash>

					<figDesc>In these relations, σ 0 is a free parameter. To fix it, we need an extra constraint. We will see later on that σ 0 can be indeed fixed in the case of the dyonic pair DP ≡ BH-BM. Before that let us complete this analysis by considering also the effective potential V BM of the black membrane and its entropy S BM . 5.2 Effective potential V BM The electrically charged black membrane BM is the dual of the magnetic black hole BH considered above. Its effective scalar potential V BM depends on the electric charges q Λ and the field variables of the moduli space (5.4). The 24 bare electric charges q Λ are given by, q Λ =</figDesc>
					<trash>S 4 F Λ 4 , F Λ 4 = ⋆ F Λ 2 . (5.36)</trash>

					<head>The q</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Λ &apos;s with Λ = 1, ..., 24, form a 24-vector charge of the group SO (4, 20). The explicit expression of potential V BM of the black membrane can be read like</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>V BM = W a W a + W I W I , (5.37) – 25 –</formula></p>

				<p>where now W a and W I are respectively the dressed electric charges of the bare ones q Λ .</p>

				<p>These dressed charges can be expressed as linear combination as follows,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>W a = 24 Λ=1 q Λ P Λa , W I = 24 Λ=1 q Λ P ΛI , (5.38)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where, like for U ΛΣ of eq(5.3), the field matrix P ΛΣ parameterizes the moduli space (5.4).</p>

				<p>The matrices P ΛΣ and U ΛΣ are then related to each other. To obtain this relation, we use the electric/magnetic duality exchanging the black hole and the black membrane charges.</p>

				<p>Formally, the electric/magnetic duality can be stated at the level of the effective scalar potentials V BH and V BM like</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g Λ ↔ q Λ , V BH ↔ V BM , (5.39) and then R a ↔ W a , R I ↔ W I . (5.40) Extending the electric/magnetic duality relation eqs(3.33), which we rewrite as follows, 24 Λ=1 q Λ g Λ = 2πk , 24 Λ=1 k Λ = k ∈ Z , (5.41) to the dressed charges, 24 Λ=1 W Λ Z Λ = k , (5.42)</trash>

					<figDesc>we can determine the relation between U ΛΣ and P ΛΣ matrices. Indeed putting</figDesc>
					<trash>W Λ = Σ P ΛΣ q Σ , (5.43) and Z Λ = Υ g Υ L ΥΛ , (5.44) back into</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>above relation, we find that the matrix P ΥΛ is just the inverse of the matrix U ΣΥ .</p>

				<p>Therefore, electric/magnetic duality mapping the black hole BH to the black membrane BM is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>– 26 – black hole BH electric/magnetic ← −−−−−−−−−− → black membrane BM g Λ ↔ q Λ U ΣΥ ↔ P ΥΛ = (U ΣΥ ) −1 Z Λ ↔ W Λ λ ↔ ξ (5.45)</trash>

					<figDesc>Notice that, like for the matrix U ΛΣ , we also have the following properties: (i) the factorization of the moduli space (5.4) as SO (1, 1) ×</figDesc>
					<trash>SO(4,20) SO(4)×SO(20) allows to factorize P ΛΣ like, P ΛΣ = e +σ L −1 ΛΣ . (5.46)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Multiplying both sides of this equation by q Σ , we obtain the dressed central charges W Σ = W a , W I W a = q Λ P Λa , W I = q Λ P ΛI . (5.47)</p>

				<p>As in the case of 6D black hole eq(5.18), these charges factorize as well like</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>W a = e +σ T a , W I = e +σ T I , (5.48) with T a = q Λ L −1 Λa , T I = q Λ L −1 ΛI . (5.49)</trash>

					<figDesc>The dressed charges T a and T I are the dual of the R a and R I . (ii) the orthogonality property of the non compact SO (4, 20) group, which we can be written as</figDesc>
					<trash>4 a=1 L −1 aΛ L −1 aΣ − 20 K=1 L −1 KΛ L −1 KΣ = η ΛΣ , (5.50)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>allows to get more information on the dressed electric charges. Multiplying both sides of this algebraic constraint equation by q Λ q Σ , we obtain</figDesc>
					<trash>W a W a − W I W I = e +2σ q 2 , (5.51) with q 2 = q Λ η ΛΣ q Σ = 4 a=1 q 2 a − 20 I=1 q 2 I . (5.52) – 27 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is the electric analogue of the constraint relation (5.9) concerning the dressed magnetic charges of the black hole. This condition will be implemented in the effective potential V BM eq(5.37) by using a Lagrange multiplier ξ. The auxiliary field ξ should be thought as the analogue of the Lagrange multiplier λ used in the black hole case; see also table (5.45). Combining eq(5.37) with eq(5.51), we end with the following generalized effective scalar potential for the black membrane,</p>

				<p><formula>V BM = W a W a + W I W I + ξ W a W a − W I W I − e +2σ q 2 . (5.53)</formula></p>

				<p>Notice that lowering and rising indices of SO (4) and SO (20) are done with the usual Kronecker metric, that is W a = W a and W I = W I . Those of SO (4, 20) are done with the metric η ΛΣ .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5.2.1">Black membrane attractor equations</head>

				<p>The effective scalar potential of the 6D black membrane can be also put in the form V BM = (1 + ξ) W a W</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a + (1 − ξ) W I W I − ξe +2σ q 2 . (5.54)</trash>

					<figDesc>The variation of V BM with respect to ξ gives precisely the condition (5.51); while the variation with respect to W a and W I give constraint eqs on the field moduli,</figDesc>
					<trash>δ e V BM δW a = (1 + ξ) W a , δ e V BM δW I = (1 − ξ) W I , δ e V BM δξ = W a W a − W I W I − e +2σ q 2 . (5.55)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The attractor eqs for the black membrane corresponds to the extremum (minimum) of this potential. These eqs read as follows</figDesc>
					<trash>(1 + ξ) W a = 0 , (5.56) (1 − ξ) W I = 0 , (5.57) W a W a − W I W I − e +2σ q 2 = 0 . (5.58)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Like for the black hole, there are three solutions extremizing the effective scalar potential V BM . These solutions, which are classified by the sign of the semi-norm of the electric charge vector q Λ , are listed below: (1) first solution (</figDesc>
					<trash>q 2 = 0): W a = 0 , W I = 0 , ξ = ±1 . (5.59) This is a singular solution. (2) second solution (q 2 &lt; 0): W a = 0 , W I = 0 , ξ = +1 . (5.60) – 28 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This solution corresponds to non BPS black membrane. (3) third solution (q 2 &gt; 0):</p>

				<p><formula>W a = 0 , W I = 0 , ξ = −1 . (5.61)</formula></p>

				<p>This solution corresponds to BPS black membrane.</p>

				<p>Putting these solutions back into (5.54), we can determine the value V min BM of the effective potential at the extremum. For the three solutions, the extremal values can be combined altogether in a unique form given by:</p>

				<p><formula>V min BM = −ξe +2σ q 2 . (5.62)</formula></p>

				<p>Notice that due to the constraint eq(5.58) which requires q 2 = 0 for W a = W I = 0, the potential at the first extremum ( first solution) should vanish:</p>

				<p><formula>(1) : V min BM = 0 . (5.63)</formula></p>

				<p>For the two other cases (2) and (3) with q 2 = 0, the values of the effective potential at the corresponding extremum read as follows:</p>

				<p><formula>V min BM = e +2σ q 2 &gt; 0 , (5.64)</formula></p>

				<p>where the dependence into the Lagrange parameter ξ has been also fixed as ξ = ±1. Notice that ξ = +1 corresponds to the non BPS black membrane while ξ = 1 is a BPS state. Notice also that the value of the effective potential at the extremums depends on the factor e +2σ which, like in the case of the black hole, is an unfixed modulus.</p>

				<p>Below, we give more details concerning the above solutions; in particular those solutions with V</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>min BM &gt; 0 . (5.65)</trash>

					<figDesc>Then, we turn to study the free factor e ±2σ and show how it can be fixed in the case of the dyonic attractor pair BH-BM.</figDesc>
					<trash>5.2.2 Solving eq(5.55)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Recall that W a and W I depend, in addition to L −1 ΛΣ , on the dilaton σ in the following manner eq(</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>5.48), W a = e +σ T a , W I = e +σ T I , (5.66) with T a = q Λ L −1 Λa , T I = q Λ L −1 ΛI . (5.67)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Using this factorization, we will show that there are various ways to solve the attractor eqs of the black membrane.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>– 29 –</head>

				<p>Among these solutions, we have the degenerate one associated with W a = 0 = W I and leading to V min BM = 0. (5.68)</p>

				<p>This solution will be ignored hereafter.</p>

				<p>The two other solutions are those associated with eqs(5.60-5.61). We have: A. case: W a = 0 , W I = 0 , ξ = 1.</p>

				<p>Since the W &apos;s depends on the moduli and the bare charges; i.</p>

				<p><formula>e, W = W (σ, L, q) , (5.69)</formula></p>

				<p>the conditions W a = 0 and W I = 0 allows then to give the relation between the field moduli of (5.4) and electric charges q Λ of the black membrane.</p>

				<p>Substituting W a and W I in terms of T a and T I , we have W a = e +σ T a = 0 , W I = e +σ T I = 0 . (5.70)</p>

				<p>Obviously, the solutions of the above relations should satisfy the constraint equation</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>W a W a − W I W I = e +2σ q 2 , (5.71) which, by substituting W a = 0, reduces to 20 I=1 W I W I = 20 I=1 W 2 I = −e +2σ q 2 &gt; 0 . (5.72) As we see, definite positivity of the norm 20 I=1 W 2 I requires q 2 = − q 2 &lt; 0 . (5.73) Eq(5</trash>

					<figDesc>.70) can be solved in two basic ways as follows: (a) either by taking σ → −∞ whatever the values of T a ; in particular T a = 0. But this solution should be ruled out since we should have W I = e +σ T I = 0 , (5.74) which violates eq(5.72). (b) or by taking σ = σ 2 , an arbitrary but a finite number (say σ 2 &lt; ∞), and T a = 0 but T I = 0. A solution for T a = 0 depends of the value of q 2 = q Λ η ΛΣ q Σ and can, a priori, be split into two situations (i) and (ii) corresponding respectively to: (i) a light like charge vector q 2 = 0</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>We already know that this case should be ruled out; but it is interesting to see the explicit relation between the field moduli L ΛΣ of (5.4) and the electric charges of the black membrane. We have L −1 Λa = # q Λ q a</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, T a = # q 2 q a = 0 . (5.75) – 30 – However, because of eq(5.72) which requires 20 I=1 W I W I = e +2σ 2 20 I=1 T I T I = −e +2σ 2 q 2 , (5.76) we get 20 I=1 T I T I = 0 ⇒ T I = 0 . (5.77)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This solution should be then ruled out since T I = 0. (ii) a non zero semi-norm q 2 = 0 We have the following:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L −1 Λa = (q Λ q a −q 2 η Λa ) q 2 , T a = (q 2 q a −q 2 q a ) q 2 = 0 . (5.78)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This solution is acceptable provided q 2 &lt; 0 since eq(5.72) requires</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>20 I=1 T I T I = − q 2 &gt; 0 . (5.79) From this relation we can determine T I ; i.e T I = q I −q 2 20 J=1 q 2 J , I = 1, ..., 20 , (5.80) which leads in turns to L −1 ΛJ = q Λ q J −q 2 q 2 20 I=1 q 2 I , I = 1, ..., 20 . (5.81)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this case, the values of the effective scalar potential V BM at the minimum is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V min BM = −e +2σ 2 q 2 = e +2σ 2 q 2 &gt; 0 . (5.82)</trash>

					<figDesc>It depends on the electric charges. but it has a free dependence in the value σ 2 of the dilaton.</figDesc>
					<trash>B. case : W a = 0 , W I = 0 , ξ = −1 We have to solve W a = e +σ T a = 0 , W I = e +σ T I = 0 , ξ = −1 , (5.83) with the constraint relation 4 a=1 W a W a = 4 a=1 W 2 a = e +2σ q 2 &gt; 0 . (5.84) – 31 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From this constraint relation we see that the electric charges of the black membrane should be q 2 &gt; 0. The method is quite similar to the one used for the black hole case. After some straightforward calculations, we end with the following</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>case (3) : V min BM = e +2σ 2 q 2 &gt; 0 , (5.85)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we still have the unfixed factor e +2σ 2 .</p>

				<p>6. Entropy of the pair BH-BM</p>

				<p>We start by recalling the various expressions of the effective scalar potentials of the 6D black attractors that have been obtained so far. These are collected in the following table</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>6D black attractors : effective scalar potential dyonic black string : V BS (σ) = q 2 0 2 e 4σ + g 2 0 2 e −4σ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>black hole : V BH (σ, R, λ) = e −2σ V 0 (R, λ) black 2-brane : V BM (σ, T, ξ) = e 2σ V 2 (T, ξ)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>(6.1)</head>

				<p>The entropy S BS of the dyonic 6D black string BS reads, in terms of the electric q 0 and magnetic g 0 charges of the 3-form field strength H 3 , as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BS = |g 0 q 0 | 4 , (6.2) or again like S BS = π 2 |k 0 | , k 0 ∈ Z * . (6.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For the entropies S BH and S BM of the 6D black hole BH and black membrane BM, the situation is a little bit different. Viewed separately, the corresponding entropies S BH and S BM are respectively given by:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BH = 1 4 e −2σ 0 g 2 , (6.4) and S BM = 1 4 e 2σ 2 q 2 , (6.5) with g 2 = 4 a=1 g 2 a − 20 I=1 g 2 I , q 2 = 4 a=1 q 2 a − 20 I=1 q 2 I . (6.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In these relations σ 0 and σ 2 stand respectively for the value of the dilaton field at the horizon of the black hole BH and the black membrane BM : σ 0 = σ (r bh ) , r bh = black hole horizon , σ 2 = σ (r bm ) , r bm = black 2-brane horizon .</p>

				<p><formula>(6.7) – 32 –</formula></p>

				<p>As we have noted before, σ 0 and σ 2 might also take finite values but unfortunately cannot be fixed if dealing with BH and BM as independent objects. A way to see why the effective potentials V BH = V BH (σ, R, λ) ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(6.8) and V BM = V BM (σ, T, ξ) , (6.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>cannot fix the dilaton at their extremum is to note the following: (i) First the scalar potentials V BH and V BM are eigenfunctions of the operator</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>d dσ : dV BH dσ = −2V BH , dV BM dσ = +2V BM . (6.10) (ii</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) the zeros of the effective potentials V BH and V BM can be obtained in three ways.</p>

				<p>In the case of the black hole BH, the zeros are given by,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V BH = e −2σ 0 V 0 (R, λ) = 0 ⇒      (1) : e −2σ 0 = 0, V 0 (R, λ) = 0 (2) : e −2σ 0 = 0, V 0 (R, λ) = 0 (3) : e −2σ 0 = 0, V 0 (R, λ) = 0 (6.11)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For the configurations (1) and (2), the value σ 0 of the dilaton at the critical point is σ 0 → +∞ . (6.12)</p>

				<p>They lead to the degenerate relations (1.3-2.20). However, for the third configuration, the critical value of the dilaton is unfixed and can be any arbitrary; but finite, value. This is the case we are interested in here.</p>

				<p>In the case of the black membrane BM, we have</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V BM = e +2σ 2 V 2 (T, ξ) = 0 ⇒      (1) : e +2σ 2 = 0, V 2 (T, ξ) = 0 (2) : e +2σ 2 = 0, V 2 (T, ξ) = 0 (3) : e +2σ 2 = 0, V 2 (T, ξ) = 0 (6.13) The configurations (1) and (2) imply σ 2 → −∞ , (6.14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>while for the third configuration leaves σ 2 an arbitrary finite number. Notice that eq(6.11) and (6.13) exhibit very remarkable properties; in particular the two following: (a) They are exchanged under electric/magnetic duality. At the black hole and the black membrane horizons, we then have</p>

				<p><formula>±σ 0 ↔ ∓σ 2 , g Λ ↔ q Λ . (6.15) – 33 – (b)</formula></p>

				<p>The above relation (6.15) should be associated with eq(4.3) of the dyonic black string. This property shows that σ 2 = −σ 0 , (6.16) ending then with one unknown quantity; say σ 0 , which remains unfixed. Moreover, eq(6.15) teaches us that the black hole potential (5.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>20-5.21) V BH = e −2σ V 0 , (6.17) and the black membrane potential (5.37-6.1) V BM = e +2σ V 2 , (6.18)</trash>

					<figDesc>as two limits of the potential of the dyonic black pair DP ≡ BM-BH.</figDesc>
					<trash>V DP ≃ e −2σ V 0 + e +2σ V 2 . (6.19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the limit σ → −∞, the potential V DP of the dyonic pair reduces as V DP → V BH , (6.20) and in the limit σ → +∞, it behaves like, V DP → V BM . (6.21)</p>

				<p>To get the explicit expression of σ 0 , we have to study the attractor mechanism of the dyonic attractor DP ≡ BM-BH.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>6.1</head>

				<p>Attractor eqs for the dyonic DP</p>

				<p>To begin, notice that the general moduli dependence of the effective scalar potential V DP of the dyonic black attractor pair is given by, V DP = V (σ; R, T ; λ, ξ, ζ; q, g) . (6.22)</p>

				<p>The set of parameters {σ, R, T, λ, ξ, ζ, q, g} is the general set of the possible moduli in which may depend the effective scalar potential and which are supposed to describe the attractor eqs of the DP dyonic pair. They are as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(a) the R&apos;s and the T &apos;s are the dressed charges as in eqs(5.18-5.19) and (5.48-5.49); (b) λ and ξ are the Lagrange multipliers given by eqs(5.15-5.16) and (5.53); (c) q = (q Λ ) and g = (g Λ ) are the electric and magnetic charges given by eqs(3.31,3.32,3.33,3.34)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>(d) the variable ζ is an extra Lagrange multiplier that will be described below. Notice also that, like for the dyonic black string BS, the potential V DP of the dyonic pair should be also invariant under the electric/magnetic duality (6.15). Expression of V DP The explicit expression of V DP is given by the sum of: (i) the effective scalar potential of the black hole (5.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>20-5.21), V BH = V BH (σ, R, λ, g Λ ) . (6.23) – 34 – (ii</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) the effective scalar potential of the black membrane (5.37) which is dual to V BH , V BM = V BM (σ, T, ξ, q Λ ) . (6.24) (iii) an extra term depending on the dressed electric and magnetic charges Z and W . This term is given by the constraint eq(5.42)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C = C (Z, W ) , (6.25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>capturing the electric/magnetic duality between the dressed charges of the black hole and the black membrane. It may be interpreted as the interaction term. Then, we have V DP = V BH + V BM + ζC , (6.26) where ζ is a Lagrange multiplier used to implement the constraint (5.42) in the effective scalar potential of the DP dyonic pair.</p>

				<p>In addition to the various electric and magnetic bare charges q Λ and g Λ , the dyonic potential V DP depends on the eighty one field variables (σ, L ΛΣ ) of the moduli space; and on the three Lagrange multipliers λ, ξ and ζ.</p>

				<p>While the dilaton appears in V DP as e ±2σ , the eighty field moduli L ΛΣ are involved in the game through the dressed charges,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R a = R a (L ΛΣ ) , R I = R I (L ΛΣ ) , (6.27) and T a = T a L −1 ΛΣ , T I = T I L −1 ΛΣ . (6.28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>By substituting V BH and V BM by their explicit expression, we can put the DP effective scalar potential V DP in the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V DP = e −2σ V 0 + e +2σ V 2 + ζC , (6.29) where we have set V 0 = (1 + λ) a R a R a + (1 − λ) I R I R I −λg 2 , (6.30) and V 2 = (1 + ξ) a T a T a + (1 − ξ) I T I T I −ξq 2 , (6.31) as well as C = −   1 − 24 Λ,Σ=1 η ΛΣ Z Λ W Σ   = −   1 − 24 Λ,Σ=1 η ΛΣ R Λ T Σ   . (6.32)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The equations defining the extremum (minimum) of the scalar potential V DP are then given by the four following systems of eqs:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δV DP δR a = 0 , δV DP δR I = 0 , δV DP δλ = 0 , (6.33) – 35 – and δV DP δT a = 0 , δV DP δT I = 0 , δV DP δξ = 0 , (6.34) as well as δV DP δζ = 0 (6.35) and finally δV DP δσ = 0. (6.36) Eqs(6.33</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) give relative extremums (minimums) associated with the black hole BH contri- bution. Eqs(6.34) define relative extremums (minimums) associated with the black membrane BM. Eq(6.35) captures the duality relation between the black hole BH and the black membrane BM. Eq(6.36) is in some sense special; it gives the values of σ 0 and σ 2 we are after. Below, we give the details on the solutions of these eqs.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>6.2</head>

				<p>Extremums of V DP</p>

				<p>Here we study the extremums (minimums) of the potential (6.29). Since V DP is multivariables function, we shall proceed by steps in order to get these minimums: (1) First we solve successively the eq(6.33), eq(6.34) and (6.35). These solutions fix the critical values of the field moduli and the Lagrange multipliers in terms of the electric and magnetic charges q 0 , g 0 , q a , g a and q I , g I ;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R min = R (q, g) , T min = T (q, g) , λ min = λ (q, g) , ξ min = ξ (q, g) , ζ min = ζ (q, g) . (6.37) (2)</trash>

					<figDesc>Then, we substitute the obtained solutions back into eq(6.29) to get the new effective potential V DP namely</figDesc>
					<trash>V DP = e −2σ V min 0 + e +2σ V min 2 + (ζC) min , (6.38) where now V min 0 = V 0 R min , T min , λ min , ζ min , V min 2 = V 2 T min , R min , ξ min , ζ min . (6.39) (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>After that, we solve the attractor equation given by the minimization of (</p>

				<p><formula>6.38), i.e δ V DP δσ = 0 , (6.40)</formula></p>

				<p>in order to determine the critical values of σ at the extremums.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>– 36 – 6.2.1 Solving eqs(6.33-6.34-6.35)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A) solution of eqs(6.33): By substituting eq(6.29) and (6.30), we can be put eqs(6.33) in the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(1 + λ) R a + ζT a = 0 , (1 − λ) R I − ζT I = 0 , R a R a − R I R I = g 2 . (6.41)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These equations have three types of solutions which can be classified according to whether the sign of g 2 ; that is g 2 = 0, g 2 &gt; 0 or g 2 &lt; 0. Case A1 (g 2 = 0): In this case, the solution reads as:</p>

				<p><formula>R min a = 0 , R min I = 0 , λ min = −1 , ζ min = 0 , (6.42)</formula></p>

				<p>and all remaining other moduli are free. Case A2 (g 2 &gt; 0): Here the solution reads as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R min a = g a |g 2 | 4 b=1 g 2 b − 1 2 , (R a R a ) min = g 2 , R min I = 0, , λ min = −1 , ζ min = 0 , (6.43) and all remaining other moduli are free. Case A3 (g 2 &lt; 0):</trash>

					<figDesc>In this case the solution is given by:</figDesc>
					<trash>R min I = g I |g 2 | 20 J=1 g 2 J − 1 2 , R I R I min = −g 2 , R min a = 0 , λ min = +1 , ζ min = 0 , (6.44) and all remaining other moduli are free. In all cases A1, A2 and A3 (g 2 = 0, g 2 &gt; 0 and g 2 &lt; 0), we have V min 0 = R I R I min = g 2 . (6.45) B) Solution of eqs(6.34): Using eq(6.29) and (6.30), we can be put eqs(6.34) in the form (1 + ξ) T a + ζR a = 0 , (1 − ξ) T I − ζR I = 0 , T a T a − T I T I = q 2 . (6.46) – 37 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here also we have three kinds of solutions depending on the signs of q 2 . The solutions are quite similar to the previous cases; they are given by: Case B1 (q 2 = 0):</p>

				<p>In this case the solution reads as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T min a = 0 , T min I = 0 , ξ min = −1 , ζ min = 0 , (6.47) and all remaining moduli are free. Case B2 (q 2 &gt; 0): Here the solution is given by: T min a = q a |q 2 | 4 b=1 q 2 b − 1 2 , (T a T a ) min = q 2 , T min I = 0 , ξ min = −1 , ζ min = 0 , (6.48) and all remaining other moduli are free. Case B3 (q 2 &lt; 0): In this case the solution reads as: T min I = q I −q 2 20 J=1 q 2 J − 1 2 , T I T I min = −q 2 , T min a = 0 , ξ min = +1 , ζ min = 0 , (6.49) and all remaining moduli are free. In all cases B1, B2 and B3 (q 2 = 0, q 2 &gt; 0 and q 2 &lt; 0), we have V min 2 = (T a T a ) min = q 2 . (6.50) C. solution of eqs(6.35): Eq(6.35) gives T a R a − T I R I = 4 a=1 (T a R a ) − 20 I=1 (T I R I ) = k, (6.51) and is solved as:</trash>

					<head>Case C1 :</head>

					<figDesc>In this case, the solution corresponds to</figDesc>
					<trash>T a R a = k , T I R I = 0 , (6.52) – 38 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and requires that T a R a = 0 and T a = 0. Consistency with the solutions of eqs(6.33-6.34) implies:</p>

				<p><formula>T min a = kR min a 4 b=1 (R b R b ) min −1 , T min I = 0 , R min I = 0 . (6.53)</formula></p>

				<p>Moreover equating the expression of T min a given by case B2 with the expression of T min a which we obtain by substituting R min a by its value given by case A2, we get the following</p>

				<p><formula>identity 4 b=1 T min b T min b 4 b=1 R min b R min b = k 2 . (6.54)</formula></p>

				<p>Using eq(6.48) and eq(6.43), we can obtain the following electric and magnetic duality relation q 2 .g 2 = k 2 , q 2 &gt; 0, g 2 &gt; 0. (6.55)</p>

				<p>This electric/magnetic duality relation involves the squares of the vector charges q Λ and g Λ . Case C2 : In this case, the solution is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T a R a = 0 , T I R I = −k , (6.56) and corresponds to: T min I = −kR min I 20 J=1 (R J R J ) min −1 , T min a = 0 , R min a = 0 . (6.57) Substituting the solution of T min I given by case B3 and R min I given by case A3, we get the following identity 20 I=1 T min I T I min 20 I=1 R min I R I min = k 2 , (6.58)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which corresponds to the electric/magnetic duality q 2 .g 2 = k 2 ; but now with q 2 &lt; 0 and g 2 &lt; 0.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>6.2.2 Solving eq(6.40) Substituting V min 0 , V min 2 and (ζC) min by their expressions, we get the following effective scalar potential for the dilaton field V DP (σ) = e −2σ g 2 + e +2σ q 2 . (6.59) This is as positive definite effective dyonic potential V DP (σ) &gt; 0 , (6.60) – 39 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>that depends, in addition to the dilaton σ, on the semi-norms q 2 and g 2 of the bare electric and magnetic charges of the dyonic pair DP.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Since the second derivative d 2 V DP dσ 2 ≥ 0 , (6.61) the minimum of eq(6.59) is obtained by solving e +2σ q 2 − e −2σ g 2 = 0. (6.62)</trash>

					<figDesc>The critical value σ c of the dilaton solving this constraint relation is</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>e +2σc = |g 2 | |q 2 | , σ c = 1 4 ln g 2 − ln q 2 . (6.63)</formula></p>

				<p>Putting this solution back into eq(6.62), we get V min BH−BM = 2 |g 2 q 2 | . (6.64)</p>

				<p>This relation should be compared with eqs(4.13-4.14).</p>

				<p>In the end, we would like to add that the analysis given in this section extends directly to the the dyonic pairs DP ≡ BH-B3B,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(6.65) and DP ≡ BS-BM, (6.66) of (3.13-3.14</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) of the 7D N = 2 supergravity embedded in 11D M-theory on K3.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="7">Conclusion and discussion</head>

				<p>In this paper, we have studied the extremal black brane attractors in the 6D (resp. 7D ) N = 2 supergravity limit of the 10D type IIA superstring (resp. 11D M-theory) on K3. In these limits, the classical entropy of electrically charge black branes EBB (resp. magnetically charged branes MBB) have degenerate values; see eqs(1.3,1.11,2.20,5.33).</p>

				<p>In trying to understand this classical degeneracy, we have been lead to make a proposal where the degenerate value of the 6D black hole BH entropy</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S entropy BH = 0 , (7.1) and the entropy of black membrane BM S entropy BM = 0 , (7.2) appear as two singular limits of the classical entropy S entropy BH−BM ≡ S entropy DP (7.3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>of the bound state dual pair (BH-BM) 6D ≡ DP . This result applies as well for the 6D dyonic black string (BS) 6D and for the dual pair attractors (BH-B3B) 7D and (BS-BM) 7D – 40 – of the N = 2 7D supergravity theory.</p>

				<p>In analyzing the degeneracy of S</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>entropy EBB</head>

				<p>= S entropy M BB = 0, we have also found that electric/magnetic duality is a universal symmetry playing a central in the physics of 6D/7D black attractors. Among our results, we mention the following: First, by using the electric/magnetic duality (e/m symmetry for short), we have given a refined classification of the black attractors in 6D and 7D. These black branes are classified into two representations of the e/m symmetry: dyonic singlets and pairs as follows: (1) Six dimensions In 6D non chiral supergravity theory with sixteen supercharges, we have: (a) An attractor singlet, corresponding to the dyonic black string denoted as (BS). This dyonic attractor carries an electric charge q 0 = * S 3 F 3 and a magnetic charge g 0 = S 3 F 3 with F 3 being the field strength of the NS-NS B µν -field. (b) An attractor pair describing the dual pair</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>DP ≡ BH-BM ≡ BH BM , (7.4) carrying 24 electric and 24 magnetic charges {q Λ , g Λ }. The black hole BH carry 24 magnetic charge g Λ = S 4 F Λ 4 and corresponds to the singular limit σ → +∞ , e −σ → 0 , (7.5) of the SO (1, 1) factor of the moduli space SO (1, 1) × SO(4,20)</trash>

					<figDesc>SO(4)×SO(20) . This singular limit may be formally stated as,</figDesc>
					<trash>DP σ → +∞ − −−−−− → BH 0 . (7.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The same feature is valid for the electrically charged black membrane BM carrying 24 electric charges {q Λ }. The BM, which is e/m dual to BH, corresponds to the singular limit</figDesc>
					<trash>σ → −∞ , e +σ → 0 , (7.7) in the moduli space. We also have DP σ → −∞ − −−−−− → 0 BM . (7.8) (2) Seven dimensions</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the 7D N = 2 supergravity theory we have no attractor singlet; but two pairs (DP ) 1 and (DP ) 2 : The first pair is given by the bound state BH-B3B carrying 22 electric and 22 magnetic charge {q Λ , g Λ }.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(DP ) 1 ≡ BH-B3B ≡ BH B3B , (7.9) – 41 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The second attractor pair is given by the dual pair (DP ) 2 ≡ BS-BM ≡ BS BM . (7.10)</p>

				<p>This pair carries an electric charge q 0 and a magnetic one g 0 ; it should compared with the 6D black string (BS) 6D .</p>

				<p>Notice that the black hole (BH) 7D (resp. B3B) with the 22 magnetic charges g Λ (resp. 22 electric charges q Λ ) follows as the singular limit σ → +∞ (resp. σ → +∞) of (DP ) 1 .</p>

				<p>The same property holds for the 7D black string (BS) 7D and the black membrane (BM) 7D .</p>

				<p>They are singular limits of the (DP ) 2 pair.</p>

				<p>Then we have considered the question of computing the entropies S black−brane of the above 6D and 7D black attractors. For the dyonic 6D black string (BS) 6D with an electric charge q 0 and a magnetic charge g 0 , the entropy S 6D BS is given by eqs(4.13-4.14) namely,</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>S 6D</head>

				<p>BS = 1 2 g 0 q 0 &gt; 0, (7.11) which, for later use, we prefer to rewrite as follows</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S 6D BS = 1 2 g 2 0 q 2 0 &gt; 0. (7.12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Clearly S 6D BS is invariant under e/m symmetry. For the case of 6D black hole (BH) 6D and the 6D black membrane (BM) 6D , the corresponding entropies S 6D BH and S 6D BM take degenerate values as in eqs(7.1-7.2).</p>

				<p>Recall that this property of the classical entropy has been point out in literature many years ago [46]; see also [55, 56]. It is due to the specific structure of the scalar manifolds M N =2 6D and M N =2 7D of these the 6D and 7D theories which contain an ambiguous SO (1, 1) factor as shown below,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M N =2 6D = SO (1, 1) × SO(4,20) SO(4)×SO(20) , M N =2 7D = SO (1, 1) × SO(3,19) SO(3)×SO(19) . (7.13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The SO (1, 1) factor, which is associated with the dilaton, puts a very restrictive constraint on the critical value of the effective scalar potential and on the entropy. Moreover, by freezing the dilaton to a some constant value; say σ = σ BH for the BH and σ = σ BM for the black membrane, the corresponding entropies are no longer zero; but they depend on these free constant parameters.</p>

				<p>To overcome this difficulty, we have proposed that, classically, the black hole BH and the black membrane BM of the 6D space time should be thought of as an attractor bound state with the singular limits (7.6,7.8). In this view, all the difficulties are overcome and e/m duality appears as a universal symmetry.</p>

				<p>Entropy of dual pair DP With the attractor bound state picture in mind, we have studied the attractor mechanism – 42 – of the 6D dual pair DP ≡ BH-BM and we have found, amongst others, the following: (i) the values σ BH and σ BM of the dilaton at the horizons of (BH) 6D and (BM) 7D are as follows σ BH = −σ BM , (7.14) in agreement with e/m duality. Moreover we have been able to compute σ BH which is given by</p>

				<p><formula>σ BH = 1 4 ln g 2 − 1 4 ln q 2 , (7.15) with g 2 = g Λ η ΛΣ g Σ , q 2 = q Λ η ΛΣ q Σ , (7.16)</formula></p>

				<p>where η ΛΣ is the metric of the tangent space R 4,20 . (ii) the entropy of the six space-time dimension DP dual pair is given by S DP = 1 2 |g 2 q 2 | , (7.17)</p>

				<p>Notice that the relation (7.17) of the entropy S DP is quite similar to the relation (7.12) giving the entropy of the 6D black string.</p>

				<p>At the end, we would like to add the two following: First, the explicit analysis we have made for 6D applies as well for the black pairs (7.9-7.10) in 7D N = 2 supergravity embedded in 11D M-theory on K3. The entropy of the attractor bounds (DP ) 1 and (DP ) 1 have similar expression as in eqs(7.17-7.16) with η ΛΣ being the metric of the flat space R 3,19 .</p>

				<p>Second, the Lagrange multiplier method we have developed in section 5 seems to be the appropriate way to deal with the study of the critical points of the black branes effective potentials.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>

				<p>EHS would like to thank M. Assorey, L. Boya, L. R. Cortes for scientific discussions and Departemento di Fisica Teorica, Universidad Zaragoza for kind hospitality. He also thanks A. Belhaj, L.B Drissi, H. Jehjouh for collaboration in this direction. AS has been supported by MCYT ( Spain) under grant FPA 2003-02948, CICYT (grant FPA-2006-02315) and DGIID-DGA (grant 2007-E24/2), Spain. This research work is supported by &quot; Fisica de altas energias: Particulas, Cuerdas y Cosmologia, A 9335/07 &quot; and the program Protars D12/25/CNRST. 8. Appendix: On effective potential in 6D and 7D</p>

				<p>We begin by recalling that, with the exception of D = 4, N = 1, 2 and D = 5, N = 2, all supergravity theories contain scalar fields whose kinetic Lagrangian is described by σmodels of the form G/H. The symmetry group G is a non compact group acting as an</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>– 43 –</head>

				<p>isometry group on the scalar manifold and H is the isotropy subgroup having the form H = H aut ⊗ H matter . The subsymmetry H aut is the automorphism group of the extended supersymmetric algebra and H matter is related to the matter supermultiplets. For the list of the coset manifolds G/H and the automorphism groups of the various supergravity theories for any dimension D and number N , see [60, 61]. For D = 6, N = 2 and D = 7, N = 2, these are given by eqs(2.2) and (2.3). We aso recall that generic D supergravity theories with moduli space G/H have several specific properties shared by most of these theories. Amongst these features, we quote the three following: (1) the group G acts linearly on the (p + 2)-forms field strengths F a 1··· a p+2 corresponding to the various (p + 1)-forms A a 1··· a p+1 appearing in the gravitational and matter multiplets. (2) the properties of a given supergravity theory with fixed D and N are completely specified by the geometry of G/H, in particular in terms of the coset representatives L = L ΛΣ satisfying the gauge symmetry relation L ξ ′ = gL (ξ) h (g, ξ) , g ∈ G, h ∈ H, ξ ′ = ξ ′ (ξ) , with ξ being the coordinates of the coset G/H. In particular, the matrix N ΛΣ capturing the field coupling metric of the (p + 2)-forms F Λ a 1··· a p+2 in the supergravity Lagrangian density is fixed in terms of L. The physical field strengths T Λ a 1··· a p+2 of the interacting theories are also dressed with scalar fields as explicitly developed in the literature; especially in a series of papers by Ferrara and collaborators; see for instance sections 3 and 5 of the study [46] and [62]-[65] for a geometrical approach dealing with the so called F 4 supergravity containing the 6D N = 2 superalgebra as a subsymmetry; see also the appendix B of [36]. (3) Like in 4D N = 2 theory, higher dimensional supergravity exhibits as well two kinds of central charges: Z geo coming from gravity multiplet (geometry) and Z matter arising from the matter sector. The dressing property allows to write down the central charges Z geo ≡ Z a 1 ···ap associated to the (p + 1)-forms A gravity a 1··· a p+1 in the gravitational multiplet in terms of the geometrical structure of the moduli space. The matter (p + 1)-forms A matter a 1··· a p+1 of the matter multiplets give rise to charges that are closely related to the central charges. Notice in passing that when p &gt; 1, the central charges do not appear in the usual supersymmetry algebra, but in its extended version containing the central generators Z a 1 ···ap associated to p-dimensional extended objects. Notice also that besides the fact that they satisfy differential relations of Maurer-Cartan type, the central charges Z satisfy as well sum rules quite analogous to those for the N = 2 special geometry case [66]. These sum rules, which define in particular the effective potential,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V ef f ∼ |Z geo | 2 + |Z matter | 2 . (8.1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>have been analyzed in details in [46]. Our main goal below is to write down the explicit form of the dressed charges Z geo , Z matter in the 6D/7D supergravity cases and then V 6D/7D ef f</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>.</head>

				<p>We also give some useful relations between Z geo and Z matter which are analogous the familiar D = 4, N = 2 supergravity using special geometry relations [66]. For concreetness, we shall first focus on N = 2 supergravity in 6D and then move to 7D.</p>

				<p>– 44 – These theories have respectively 81 (58 ) scalars distributed as follows: (i) the dilaton σ belonging to the 6D (7D) N = 2 gravity multiplet. (ii) the eighty (fifty seven) other moduli φ aI (ρ aI ) belonging to the 6D (7D) N = 2 Maxwell multiplets.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="8.1">6D</head>

				<p>N = 2 supergravity</p>

				<p>The effective scalar potential V ef f of the 6D black objects is given by the so called Weinhold potential (8.1) expressed as quadratics of the dressed charges [67, 68, 69, 70],</p>

				<p><formula>(Z + , Z − , Z a , Z I ) , a = 1, ..., 4, I = 1, ..., 20. (8.2)</formula></p>

				<p>These charges appear in the supersymmetric transformations of the (fermionic) fields of the 6D supergravity theory. At the event horizon of the 6D black objects, the potential V ef f attains the minimum. The real (σ, φ aI ) moduli parameterizing SO(1,1)×SO(4,20) SO(4)×SO(20) are generally fixed by the charges g + , g − , g a , h I , q a , p I , (8.3) of the N = 2 6D supergravity gauge field strengths</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H + 3 , H − 3 , F a 2 , F I 2 , F 4a , F 4I .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The attractor equations of the 6D N = 2 black objects are obtained from the minimization of the (V ef f ) black . Notice that from the field spectrum of the 6D N = 2 non chiral supergravity, one learns that two basic situations should be distinguished: (1) 6D black string (BS ) with near horizon geometry AdS 3 × S 3 . This is a 6D dyonic black F-string solution. The electric/magnetic charges involved here are those of the gauge invariant 3-form field strengths</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H + 3 = 1 2 (H 3 + ⋆ H 3 ) , H − 3 = 1 2</trash>

					<figDesc>(H 3 − ⋆ H 3 ) , associated with the usual 2-form antisymmetric B ± µν fields in 6D. The ⋆ conjugation stands for the usual Poincaré duality interchanging n-forms with (6 − n) ones. (2) 6D black hole (BH ) and its black 2-brane (BM ) dual. The field strengths involved in these objects are related by the Poincaré duality in 6D space time which interchanges the 2-and 4-form field strengths. Below, we study briefly and separately these two configurations. Black string in 6D The BPS black object of the 6D N = 2 non chiral theory is a dyonic string charged under both the self dual H</figDesc>
					<trash>+ 3 and anti-self dual H − 3 field strengths of the NS-NS B ± -fields. Using the following bare magnetic/electric charges, g ± = S 3 H ± 3 , g ± = 1 2 (g ± e) , where g = S 3 H 3 and e = S 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>⋆ H 3 , one can write down the physical charges in terms of the dressed charges.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>– 45 – (a) Dressed charges The dressed charges play an important role in the study of supergravity theories [46]. They appear in the supersymmetric transformations of the Fermi fields (here gravitinos), and generally read like Z ± = X</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>± + g + + X ± − g − , (8.4) where the real 2 × 2 matrix X = X + + X + − X + − X + + , parameterizes the SO (1, 1</trash>

					<figDesc>) factor of the moduli space G. Taking the η rs flat metric as η = diag (1, −1), we can express all the four real parameters X ± − and X ± + in terms of the dilaton σ = σ (x) by solving the constraint eqs X t ηX = η which split into four constraint relations like X</figDesc>
					<trash>+ + X + + − X − + X − + = 1 , X − − X − − − X + − X + − = 1 , X + + X + − − X − + X − − = 0 , X + − X + + − X − − X − + = 0 . (8.5) These eqs can be solved by, X + + = X − − = cosh (2σ) , X − + = X + − = sinh (2σ) . (8.6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Putting these solutions back into the expressions of the central charges Z + and Z − (8.4), we get the following dilaton dependent quantities</figDesc>
					<trash>Z ± = 1 2 [g exp (−2σ) ± e exp (2σ)] . (8.7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Notice that these dressed charges have no dependence on the ω aI field moduli of the coset SO (4, 20) /SO (4) × SO (20). This is because the NS-NS B-fields is not charged under the isotropy group of the above coset manifold. (b) Black string potential With the dressed charges Z + and Z − , we can write down the gauge invariant effective scalar potential V BF S . It is given by the so called Weinhold potential,</figDesc>
					<trash>V BS = Z + 2 + Z − 2 . (8.8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Notice that, as far symmetries are concerned, one also have the other &quot; orthogonal &quot; combination namely (Z + ) 2 − (Z − ) 2 . This combination corresponds just to the electric/magnetic charge quantization condition. By substituting eq(8.4) into the relation (8.8), we get the following form of the potential,</figDesc>
					<trash>V BS = g + , g − M g + g − , with M = X + + 2 + X − + 2 2X + + X + − 2X − + X − − X − − 2 + X + − 2 . – 46 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>From this matrix and using the transformations given in [68], we can read the gauge field coupling metric N +− and N −+ that appear in the 6D N = 2 supergravity component field Lagrangian density</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L N =2 sugra 6D √ −g = R 6 1 + 1 2 N +− H + ∧ H − + 1 2 N −+ H − ∧ H + + · · ·</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In this eq, R 6 is the usual 6D scalar curvature and g = det (g µν ). By further using (8.7), we can put the potential V BF S into the following form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V BS (σ) = g 2 2 exp (−4σ) + e 2 2 exp (4σ) . (8.9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that the self and anti-self duality properties of the field strengths H + 3 and H − 3 imply that the corresponding magnetic/electric charges are related as g + = e + , g − = −e − . Using the quantization condition for the dyonic 6D black F-string namely (e + g + + g − e − ) = 2πk, k integer, one gets,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g + g + − g − g − = eg = 2πk. (8.10) Then the the quantity (Z + ) 2 − (Z − ) 2 becomes (Z + ) 2 − (Z − ) 2 = 2eg, being just the</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>quantization condition of the electric/magentic charges of the F-string in 6D space time. (2) 6D Black Hole Contrary to the dyonic BS, the 6D black hole is magnetically charged under the U 4 (1) × U 20 (1) gauge group symmetry generated by the gauge transformations of the (4 + 20) gauge fields of the 6D N = 2 gravity fields spectrum. Recall that in 6D, the electric charges are given, in terms of the field strength F 4a and F 4I , by, q a = S 4 F 4a , p I = S 4 F 4I .</p>

				<p>with a = 1, ..., 4 and .I = 1, ..., 20 The corresponding magnetic duals, which concern the black 2-brane, involve the 2-form field strengths F Λ 2 integrated over 2-sphere,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g a = S 2 F a 2 , h I = S 2 F I 2</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>.</head>

				<p>Like for black string, the charges Q Λ = (q a , p I ) are not the physical ones. The physical charges; to be denoted like Z a , Z I , appear dressed by the 6D scalar fields parameterizing the moduli space of the 10D type IIA superstring on K3. Recall that the charges Z a and Z I appear respectively in the supersymmetric transformations of the four graviphotinos/dilatinos and the twenty photinos of the U 20 (1) Maxwell multiplet of the gaugematter sector.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(a) Dressed charges The dressing of the twenty four electric charges q a , p I of the gauge fields A a µ , A I µ read as follows: Z a = e −σ Y ab q b + φ aJ p J , Z I = e −σ V Ib q b + Y IJ p J . (8.11) – 47 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Using the real 24 × 24 matrix M ΛΣ = e −σ × L ΛΣ , L ΛΣ = Y ab φ aJ V Ia Y IJ , that defines the moduli space G, the dressed charges Z Λ = (Z a , Z I ) can be put in the condensed form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z a = M aΣ Q Σ = e −σ L aΣ Q Σ , Z I = M IΣ Q Σ = e −σ L IΣ Q Σ . (8.12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Obviously not all the parameters carried by L ΛΣ are independent; the extra dependent degrees of freedom are fixed by imposing the SO (4, 20) orthogonality constraint eqs and requiring gauge invariance under SO (4) × SO (20). The factor e −σ of eq(8.11) is then associated with the non compact abelian factor SO (1, 1) considered previously.</p>

				<p>Taking the η ΛΣ flat metric of the non compact group SO (4, 20) as η ΛΣ = diag (4 (+) , 20 (−)), we can express all the 24 × 24 = 576 real parameters L ΛΣ in terms of eighty of them only; that is in terms of φ aJ . Notice moreover that setting,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z a = e −σ R a , R a = L aΣ Q Σ , Z I = e −σ R I , R I = L IΣ Q Σ , (8.13) as well as L Υ Σ · E Σ ̥ = L Υ a E a ̥ − L Υ I E I ̥ = δ Υ ̥ , one can compute a set of useful relations. In particular we have dL ̥Λ = L ΥΛ · dL Υ Σ · P Σ ̥ , ∇Z a = D H 1 Z a + Z a dσ , (8.14) ∇Z I = D H 2 Z I + Z I dσ , where D H 1 Z a = dZ a − Ω b a Z b , H 1 = O (4) , D H 2 Z I = dZ I − Ω J I Z J , H 2 = O (4) , (8.15) and where Ω b a and P I a are given by Ω b a = E Σ a · dL b Σ , P I a = E Σ a · dL I Σ , together with similar relation for Ω J I and P a I . Using (8.14), we can write down the Maurer- Cartan eqs for the dressed charge. They read as follows, ∇Z a = P I a Z I , ∇Z I = P a I Z a . (8.16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice in passing that Z I = 0 is a solution of ∇Z a = 0. The same property is valid for Z a = 0 which solves ∇Z I = 0. – 48 – (b) Effective black hole potential Using the dressed charges (8.11-8.12), we can write down the gauge invariant effective scalar potential V BH . Following [46, 69], V BH reads as,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V BH (σ, L) = (Z a Z a ) + Z I Z I , (8.17) which can be also put in the form V BH (σ, L) = e −2σ (R a R a ) + R I R I .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Clearly V BH , which is positive, is manifestly gauge invariant under both: (a) the U 4 (1) × U 20 (1) gauge transformations since the vectors Z a and Z I depend on the electric charges of the field strengths only which, as we know, are gauge invariant. (b) the gauge transformations of the SO (4) × SO (20) isotropy group of the moduli space. V BH is given by scalar products of the vectors Z a and Z a (resp Z I and Z I ). Using eqs(8.11), we can express the black hole potential as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V BH = e −2σ q a N ab q b + q a N aJ p J + p I N Ib q b + p I N IJ p J , or in a condensed manner like V BH = e −2σ Q Λ N ΛΣ Q Σ with N ΛΣ = N ab N aJ N aJ N IJ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that, like for BS, N ΛΣ has a 6D filed theoretical interpretation in terms of the gauge coupling of the gauge field strengths F Λ µν ; i.e a term like</p>

				<figure>
					<head>1 4</head>

					<figDesc>√ −gN ΛΣ F Λ µν F µνΣ appears in the component fields of the 6D N = 2 supergravity Lagrangian density.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="8.2">7D N=2 supergravity</head>

				<p>Here we discuss briefly the effective scalar potential of the black objects in 7D. This study is quite similar to the previous 6D analysis. Recall that the moduli space of this theory is given by</p>

			<note>SO(3,19)×SO(1,1) SO(3)×SO(19) .</note>

				<p>In 7D space time, the bosonic fields content of the N = 2 supergravity multiplet is given by g µν , B [µν]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, A a µ , σ , a = 1, 2, 3, µ, ν, ρ = 0, ..., 6, where B [µν]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is dual to a 3-form gauge field C [µνσ] . There is also nineteen U(1) Maxwell with the following 6D bosons:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A I µ , ρ aI , a = 1, 2, 3, I = 1, ..., 19, where ρ aI capture 3 × 19 degrees of freedom. The gauge invariant (p + 2)-forms of the 7D N = 2 supergravity are given by H 3 ∼ dB 2 , F a 2 ∼ dA a , F I 2 ∼ dA I . – 49 –</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Extending the above 6D study to the 7D case, one distinguishes: (i) 7D black 2-brane (black membrane BM). The effective scalar potential of the BM is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V 7D BM (σ) ∼ Z 2 = e −4σ g 2 , with g = S 3 H 3 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The extremum of this potential is given by σ = ∞. The value of the potential at the minimum is V 7D BM (∞) min = 0 and so the entropy vanishes identically. (ii) 7D black hole: The effective potential of this black hole is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V 7D BH (σ, L) = 3 a=1 Z a Z a + 19 I=1 Z I Z I , (8.18) where Z a = e −σ L aΛ g Λ , Z I = e −σ L aΛ g Λ , (8.19) satisfying the constraint relation, 3 a=1 Z a Z a − 19 I=1 Z I Z I = Q 2 , 3 a=1 q a q a − 19 I=1 p I p I = Q 2 and Q Λ = q a , p I with q a = S 2 F a 2 , p I = S 2 F I 2 , a = 1, 2, 3, I = 1, ..., 19. The real 22 × 22 matrix L aΛ = L ab ρ aI V Ia L IJ , (8.20) is associated with the group manifold SO (3, 19) /SO (3) × SO (19). It is an orthogonal matrix satisfying L t ηL = η with η = diag [3 (+) , 19 (−)] . The SO (3</trash>

					<figDesc>) × SO (19) symmetry can be used to choose L ab and L IJ matrices as L ab − L ba = 0, L IJ − L JI = 0. Putting the relations (8.19) back into (8.18), we get V 7D BH (σ, L) = e −2σ Q Λ N ΛΣ Q Σ where N ΛΣ = L aΛ L a Σ + L IΛ L I Σ .</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Extremal Black Holes</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5412</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9508072</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Extremal Black Holes</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Macroscopic Entropy of N = 2 Extremal Black Holes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page">9602111</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Attractors</forename>
				<surname>Supersymmetry</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1514" to="9602136" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bellucci</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Yeranyan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">d=4 Black Hole Attractors in N=2 Supergravity with Fayet-Iliopoulos Terms</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">First-order attractor flow equations for supersymmetric black rings in N=2</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yi-Xin</forename>
				<surname>Chen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yong-Qiang</forename>
				<surname>Wang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page">02052</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>D=5. supergravity</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Black Hole Attractors in Extended Supergravity</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Entropy Function and the Attractor Mechanism for Spherically Symmetric Extremal Black Holes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Rong-Gen</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Li-Ming</forename>
				<surname>Cao</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">064010</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">549603090</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1525</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Black Holes and Critical Points in Moduli Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Gibbons</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">500</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="9702103" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Goldstein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Iizuka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Jena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Trivedi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124021" to="0507096" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Topological BPS charges in 10 and 11-dimensional supergravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Andrew</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Callister</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Douglas</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Smith</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Macroscopic entropy formulae and non-holomorphic corrections for supersymmetric black holes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Gabriel</forename>
				<surname>Lopes Cardoso</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Bernard</forename>
				<surname>De Wit</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Thomas</forename>
				<surname>Mohaupt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5679906094</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Flux Vacua Attractors and Generalized Compactifications, ITP-UU-08-36, SPIN-08-27, e-Print:arXiv:0806</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Lilia</forename>
				<surname>Anguelova</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Topological Strings on Local Elliptic Curve and Non Planar 3-Vertex Formalism, arXiv:0712.4249, Generalized MacMahon G(q) as q-deformed CFT Correlation Function</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Lalla</forename>
				<surname>Btissam Drissi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Houda</forename>
				<surname>Jehjouh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hassan</forename>
				<surname>Saidi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Black Holes in Type IIA String on Calabi-Yau Threefolds with Affine ADE Geometries and q-Deformed 2d Quiver Gauge Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Laamara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Belhaj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Drissi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Saidi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">776</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topological string in harmonic space and correlation functions in Sˆ3 stringy cosmology</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hassan</forename>
				<surname>El</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Moulay</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Brahim</forename>
				<surname>Saidi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sedra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">748</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="457" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>gauge. theory on conifold, e-</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Eric</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Gimon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Finn</forename>
				<surname>Larsen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Joan</forename>
				<surname>Simon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Black Holes in Supergravity: the non-BPS Branch</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0710" to="4967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Edi</forename>
				<surname>Gava</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Kumar</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Narain</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename>
				<surname>Milanesi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Martin</forename>
				<forename type="middle">O</forename>
				<surname>Loughlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Half BPS states in AdS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exact Solutions and the Attractor Mechanism in Non-BPS Black Holes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Kyosuke</forename>
				<surname>Hotta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Takahiro</forename>
				<surname>Kubota</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the Moduli Space of non-BPS Attractors for N =2 Symmetric Manifolds</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">N=8 non-BPS Attractors, Fixed Scalars and Magic Supergravities</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Andrianopoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Trigiante</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Non-BPS Attractors in 5d and 6d Extended Supergravity</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Black Hole Attractors in Extended Supergravity, arXiv:0708.1268, [24] Renata Kallosh, Navin Sivanandam, Masoud Soroush, The Non-BPS Black Hole Attractor Equation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0603" to="060" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">51</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the Superstring Realization of the Yang Monopole</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Adil</forename>
				<surname>Belhaj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Pablo</forename>
				<surname>Diaz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Antonio</forename>
				<surname>Segui</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fluid of black holes at the beginning of the Universe</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Diaz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Per</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Segui</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.Phys.Conf.Ser</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exact Attractive Non-BPS STU Black Holes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Renata</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Navin</forename>
				<surname>Sivanandam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Masoud</forename>
				<surname>Soroush</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">065008</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0606263</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Eric</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Gimon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Finn</forename>
				<surname>Larsen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Joan</forename>
				<surname>Simon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Black Holes in Supergravity: the non-BPS Branch</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">5D Black Holes and Non-linear Sigma Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Micha</forename>
				<surname>Berkooz</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Boris</forename>
				<surname>Pioline</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Mohsen</forename>
				<surname>Alishahiha</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Farhad</forename>
				<surname>Ardalan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hajar</forename>
				<surname>Ebrahim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mohsen Alishahiha, On R2 Corrections for 5D Black Holes</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">String Theory Effects on Five-Dimensional Black Hole Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Alejandra</forename>
				<surname>Castro</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Joshua</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Davis</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Per</forename>
				<surname>Kraus</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Finn</forename>
				<surname>Larsen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Xi Yin, 5D Black Rings and 4D Black Holes, JHEP 0602 (2006) 023, arXiv:hep-th/0504126</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Davide</forename>
				<surname>Gaiotto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Andrew</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">34] D. Gaiotto, A. Strominger, X. Yin, New Connections Between 4D and 5D Black Holes, JHEP 0602</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="024" to="0503217" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Dijkgraaf</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Verlinde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Verlinde</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">5D Black Holes and Matrix Strings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">e-Print: arXiv:0803.0827, To appear in e-Print: arXiv:0806</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hassan</forename>
				<surname>El</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Saidi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">6D/7D N=2 Supergravity El Hassan Saidi, Computing the Scalar Field Couplings in 6D Supergravity 6D black string as a model of the AdS/CFT correspondence, Mod.Phys.Lett</title>
		<editor>37] Y.S. Myung, N.J. Kim, H.W. Lee</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="575" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonsingular 4d-flat branes in six-dimensional supergravities</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Nair</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Randjbar-Daemi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0503</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">049</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0408063</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Randjbar-Daemi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Sezgin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Scalar Potential and Dyonic Strings in 6D Gauged Supergravity</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="346" to="362" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Wit</forename>
				<surname>Bernard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Black</forename>
				<surname>Bps</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Holes</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Bellucci</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0711" to="4547" />
			<pubPlace>Extremal Black Hole and Flux Vacua Attractors, arXiv</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Boris Pioline, Lectures on on Black Holes, Topological Strings and Quantum Attractors</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="981" to="0607227" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Arithmetic and Attractors, arXiv:hep-th</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Gregory</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9807087</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Thomas</forename>
				<surname>Mohaupt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Supergravity and String Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3429" to="3482" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">52</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">U-Duality and Central Charges in Various Dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Andrianopoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int.J.Mod.Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="490" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Revisited</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">[arXiv:hep-th/9504147] How does a fundamental string stretch its horizon? Stretching the horizon of a higher dimensional small black hole</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extremal black holes and elementary string states JHEP 0505</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2081" to="059" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Gabriel</forename>
				<surname>Lopes Cardoso</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Bernard</forename>
				<surname>De Wit</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jü</forename>
				<surname>Kä</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Thomas</forename>
				<surname>Mohaupt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Stationary BPS solutions in N = 2 supergravity with R 2 -interactions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">12019</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A stringy cloak for a classical singularity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Atish</forename>
				<surname>Dabholkar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Renata</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Alexander</forename>
				<surname>Maloney</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="0410076" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Black hole entropy function and the attractor mechanism in higher derivative gravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0509</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">038</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Rong-Gen</forename>
				<surname>Cai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Chiang-Mei</forename>
				<surname>Chen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Kei-Ichi</forename>
				<surname>Maeda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nobuyoshi</forename>
				<surname>Ohta</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0712" to="4212" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Mohsen</forename>
				<surname>Alishahiha</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Farhad</forename>
				<surname>Ardalan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hajar</forename>
				<surname>Ebrahim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Black Holes and Critical Points in Moduli Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sergio</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Gary</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Gibbons</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Renata</forename>
				<surname>Kallosh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="9702103" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ceresole</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Trieste workshop on Mirror Symmetry and S–Duality</title>
		<meeting>the Trieste workshop on Mirror Symmetry and S–Duality<address><addrLine>Trieste ; Gava</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page">9509160</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Belhaj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Drissi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Saidi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Segui</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">N=2 Supersymmetric Black Attractors in Six and Seven Dimensions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="580" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Hassan</forename>
				<surname>El</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Saidi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Bps</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Bps 7d Black</forename>
				<surname>Non</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M-Theory</forename>
				<surname>Attractors</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>K3</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Issues in Electric-Magnetic Duality</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Xavier Bekaert</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="hep" to="th" />
			<date type="published" when="209169" />
			<publisher>Xavier Bekaert</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Deser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Gomberoff</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Henneaux</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Teitelboim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Brane Dyons and Electric-magnetic Duality</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="204" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electric-Magnetic Duality in Supergravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Wit</forename>
				<surname>Bernard</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl.Phys.Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">arXiv</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="171" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl. . 101</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supergravities in diverse Dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Salam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Sezgin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>A. Salam and E. Sezgin, North–Holland</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Supergravity and Superstrings: a Geometric Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Castellani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Fré</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<editor>62] Laura Andrianopoli, Riccardo D&apos;Auria and Silvia Vaula, Matter coupled F</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>gauged. supergravity Lagrangian</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Vaula</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0010</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">0006107</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Riccardo</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sergio</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Silvia</forename>
				<surname>Vaula</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0010</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">013</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Matter. coupled F 4 supergravity and the AdS 6 /CFT 5 correspondence</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">M A Lledo4-D gauged supergravity analysis of type IIB vacua on K3×T 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Andrianopoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page">044</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">53</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ceresole</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Duality and Mirror Symmetry, Nucl. Phys. (Proc. Supplements) B Non BPS Attractors in 5d and 6d Extended Supergravity</title>
		<editor>E. Gava, K. S. Narain, C. Vafa [67] L. Andrianopoli, S. Ferrara, A. Marrani, M. Trigiante</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>ArXiv</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page">07093488</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Central Charges in Various Dimensions Revisited, hep-th</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Laura</forename>
				<surname>Andrianopoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Riccardo</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sergio</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9608015</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sergio</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Alessio</forename>
				<surname>Marrani</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Black Hole Attractors in Extended Supergravity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0709" to="1268" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Andrianopoli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Auria</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Lledo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Horizon Geometry, Duality and Fixed Scalars in Six Dimensions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9802147</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">54</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
