<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">I = 2 Two-Pion Wave Function and Scattering Phase Shift</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2008-04-28">28 Apr 2008 (Dated: June 13, 2013)</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Kiyoshi</forename>
								<surname>Sasaki</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Center for Computational Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tsukuba</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>305-8577</postCode>
									<settlement>Tsukuba</settlement>
									<region>Ibaraki</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Naruhito</forename>
								<surname>Ishizuka</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Center for Computational Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tsukuba</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>305-8577</postCode>
									<settlement>Tsukuba</settlement>
									<region>Ibaraki</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Pure and Applied Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tsukuba</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>305-8571</postCode>
									<settlement>Tsukuba</settlement>
									<region>Ibaraki</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tokyo Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>152-8551</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">I = 2 Two-Pion Wave Function and Scattering Phase Shift</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2008-04-28">28 Apr 2008 (Dated: June 13, 2013)</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>PACS numbers: 12.38.Gc, 11.15.Ha * Present address : 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We calculate a two-pion wave function for the I = 2 S-wave two-pion system with a finite scattering momentum and estimate the interaction range between two pions, which allows us to examine the validity of a necessary condition for the finite size formula presented by Rummukainen and Gottlieb. We work in the quenched approximation employing the plaquette gauge action for gluons and the improved Wilson action for quarks at 1/a = 1.63 GeV on 32 3 × 120 lattice. The quark masses are chosen to give m π = 0.420, 0.488 and 0.587 GeV. We find that the energy dependence of the interaction range is small and the necessary condition is satisfied for our range of the quark mass and the scattering momentum, k ≤ 0.16 GeV. We also find that the scattering phase shift can be obtained with a smaller statistical error from the two-pion wave function than from the two-pion time correlator.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>INTRODUCTION</head>

				<p>Calculations of the scattering phase shift represent an important step for expanding our understanding of the strong interaction based on lattice QCD to dynamical aspects of hadrons. For the simplest case of the I = 2 S-wave two-pion system, several calculations have been reported in Refs. [1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6]. These calculations employ the finite size formula presented by Lüscher [7] and the extension to the system with a non-zero total momentum by Rummukainen and Gottlieb [8], in which the scattering phase shift is related to the energy eigenvalue on a finite volume. In previous applications of the formula the energy was calculated from an asymptotic time behavior of the two-pion time correlator.</p>

				<p>The derivation of the finite size formula assumes a condition R &lt; L/2 for the twopion interaction range R and the lattice size L, so that the boundary condition does not distort the shape of the two-pion interaction. It is important to examine the validity of this necessary condition for reliable results of the scattering phase shift. The CP-PACS collaboration calculated the two-pion wave function for the ground state of the I = 2 Swave two-pion system and estimated the interaction range from it [9]. In their case the scattering momentum is highly small, thus their work is an examination of the condition for the scattering length. They found that the interaction range is R ∼ 1.3 − 1.6 fm for the pion mass m π = 0.520 − 0.860 GeV. They also evaluated the scattering length and found it can be given with a smaller statistical error from the wave function than from the two-pion time correlator.</p>

				<p>In the present work we extend their work of the necessary condition for the scattering length (the scattering momentum k ∼ 0) to that for the scattering phase shift (k = 0) for the I = 2 S-wave two-pion system. In order to set a finite momentum for the ground state, we consider a system having the total momentum P = (2π/L)e x . We calculate the two-pion wave function and evaluate the scattering phase shift from it, as carried out by the CP-PACS collaboration for the scattering length. This article is organized as follows. In Sec. II we briefly review the derivation of the finite size formula presented by Rummukainen and Gottlieb [8], with emphasis on the role of the condition for the interaction range. The calculation method of the wave function and the simulation parameters are given in Sec. III. In Sec. IV A we present our results of the wave function and estimate the interaction range. The scattering phase shift from the wave function is provided and compared to those with the two-pion time correlator in Sec. IV B. Our results of the scattering length and the scattering phase shift at the physical quark mass are presented in Sec. IV C. Our conclusions are given in Sec. V. Preliminary reports of the present work were presented in Ref. [10]. The calculation was carried out on VPP5000/80 at the Academic Computing and Communications Center of University of Tsukuba.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>II. FINITE SIZE FORMULA</head>

				<p>We briefly review the derivation of the finite size formula presented by Rummukainen and Gottlieb [8], with emphasis on the role of the condition for the interaction range. We restrict ourselves the formula for the I = 2 S-wave two-pion system, but the generalization can be easily carried out. The formula has also been derived from another approaches in Ref. [11] and [12]. We follow, however, the original derivation in Ref. [8]. First we consider a wave function in the infinite volume in the Minkowski space defined by Ψ(x 1 ;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x 2 ) = 0|π + (x 1 )π + (x 2 )|π + (p 1 ), π + (p 2 ); in , (1) in the space like region, (x 1 − x 2 ) 2 &lt; 0. The state |π + (p 1 ), π + (p 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>); in is an asymptotic two-pion state with the four-dimensional momenta p 1 and p 2 . π + (x) is an interpolating operator for π + at the four-dimensional position x = (x 0 , x). We assume that the two-pion interaction range R is finite and the wave function satisfies</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>( j + m 2 π )Ψ(x 1 ; x 2 ) = 0 for j = 1, 2 , (2) for −(x 1 − x 2 ) 2 &gt; R 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, where j is the d&apos;Alembertian with respect to the coordinate x j .</p>

				<p>In order to remove a trivial dependence of the center of mass coordinate X = (x 1 + x 2 )/2, we introduce a relative wave function defined by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ(x) = Ψ(x 1 ; x 2 ) · e iP ·X , (3) where x = x 1 − x 2 is the relative coordinate and P = p 1 + p 2 = (E, P) is the total fourdimensional momentum. From (2) φ(x) satisfies ( − k 2 )φ(x) = 0 , (4) P · ∂φ(x) = 0 , (5) for −x 2 &gt; R 2 , where k 2 is the scattering momentum defined by k 2 = P 2 /4 − m 2 π = (E 2 − P 2 )/4 − m 2 π . (6) (4) and (5) also yield ∇ 2 − (P · ∇) 2 /E 2 + k 2 φ(x) = 0 . (7) We can obtain a relation between the wave function and the scattering phase shift by introducing a center of mass frame. The wave function in the center of mass frame φ CM (x CM ) is related from that in the original frame φ(x) by the Lorentz transformation, φ CM (x CM ) = φ(x) . (8) x CM is the coordinate in the center of mass frame given by x 0 CM = γ(x 0 − v · x) , (9) x CM = ˆ γ[x − vx 0 ] , (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where v is the velocity v = P/E and γ is the Lorentz boost factor γ = 1/ √ 1 − v 2 = E/ √ P 2 .</p>

				<p>The operation γ[x] is defined by ˆ γ[x] = γx + x ⊥ , (11) where x and x ⊥ are components of x parallel and perpendicular to the velocity v, i.e., x = v(x · v)/v 2 and x ⊥ = x − x .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>From (4) and (5), φ CM (x) satisfies ( − k 2 )φ CM (x) = 0 , (12) ∂ ∂x 0 φ CM (x) = 0 , (13) for −x 2 &gt; R 2 . Thus, φ CM (x 0 , x) is independent of x 0 and φ(0, x) = φ CM (−γ(v · x), ˆ γ[x]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) = φ CM (0, ˆ γ[x]) for |x| &gt; R . (14) In the following we always consider the wave function at x 0 = 0 and omit the argument for the relative time, for example φ(x) = φ CM (ˆ γ[x]) for (14). We also know that the Helmholtz equation is satisfied :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(∇ 2 + k 2 )φ CM (x) = 0 for |x| &gt; R . (15) We can expand φ CM (x) in terms of the spherical Bessel j l (x) and the Neumann function n l (x) as φ CM (x) = ∞ l=0 l m=−l b lm (k) · Y lm (Ω) α l (k) · j l (k|x|) + β l (k) · n l (k|x|) , (16)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with some constant b lm (k), where Ω is the spherical coordinate for x. The conventions of j l (x), n l (x) and Y lm (Ω) agree with those of Ref. [13]. The coefficients α l (k) and β l (k) yield the scattering phase shift as tan δ l (k) = β l (k)/α l (k). Next we consider a wave function on a periodic box L 3 in the Euclidian space ( on the lattice ), which is defined by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ψ L (x 1 , τ ; x 2 , τ ) = 0|π + (x 1 , τ )π + (x 2 , τ )|π + π + ; E, P , (17) where |π + π</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>+ ; E, P is an eigenstate with the total energy E and momentum P on the lattice. The wave function is periodic with respect to the position of either of the pions :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Ψ L (x 1 + n 1 L, τ ; x 2 + n 2 L, τ ) = Ψ L (x 1 , τ ; x 2 , τ ) for n 1 , n 2 ∈ Z 3 . (18) We introduce a relative wave function like as in the Minkowski space by φ L (x) = Ψ L (x 1 , τ ; x 2 , τ ) · e Eτ −iP·X , (19) with x = x 1 − x 2 and X = (x 1 + x 2 )/2. (18) and (19) yield φ L (x) = (−1) L/(2π)P·n · φ L (x + nL) for n ∈ Z 3 . (20)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the derivation of the finite size formula, it is assumed that the two-pion interaction range R is smaller than one-half the lattice extent, so that the boundary condition does not distort the shape of the two-pion interaction. With this assumption, φ L (x) satisfies the same equation as for φ(x) :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>∇ 2 − (P · ∇) 2 /E 2 + k 2 φ L (x) = 0 for R &lt; |ˆ1 )</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The finite size formula is given by solving (21) under the boundary condition (20). It is convenient to change the variable from x to y = ˆ γ[x] and define a new function by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ L CM (y) = φ L (x) , (22) to solve the differential equation (21). φ L CM (x) satisfies ∇ 2 + k 2 φ L CM (x) = 0 for R &lt; |x| &lt; L/2 , (23) φ L CM (x) = (−1) L/(2π)P·n · φ L CM (x + ˆ γ[n]L) for n ∈ Z 3 . (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that (22) is not the Lorentz transformation on the lattice, but it is merely a definition of the function with the change of the variable from x to y = ˆ γ[x] to solve (21).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The general solution of (23) under (24) can be written by φ L CM (x) = ∞ l=0 l m=−l v lm (k) · G lm (x; k) , (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with some constant v lm (k). G lm (x; k) is given from the periodic Green function :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G(x; k) = 1 γL 3 q∈Γ P 1 q 2 − k 2 e iq·x , (26) Γ P = q q = ˆ γ −1 2π L n + P/2 , n ∈ Z 3 , (27) as G lm (x; k) = Y lm (∇)G(x; k) , (28) where Y lm (x) = |x| l · Y lm (Ω) with the spherical coordinate Ω for x. The expansion of G(x; k) in terms of j l (x) and n l (x) is given by G(x; k) = k 4π n 0 (k|x|) + ∞ l=0 l m=−l g lm (k; 1) · Y lm (Ω)j l (k|x|) . (29) The function g lm (k; 1) is an analytic continuation of g lm (k; z) = i k l 4π γL 3 q∈Γ P Y lm (q) · (q 2 − k 2 ) −z , (30)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is defined for Re(z) &gt; (l + 3)/2, where the region Γ P is defined by (27). The explicit expansion for G lm (x; k) with general l and m is not needed. Note, however, that G lm (x; k) contains j l ′ (k|x|) for a whole range of l ′ and n l ′ (k|x|) with only l ′ = l as known from (28) and (29). The wave function in the Euclidian space is related to that in the Minkowski space by the analytic continuation of the relative time ix</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0 → x 4 . It seems that φ L (x) = φ(x) at x 0 = x 4 = 0 and φ L CM (x) = φ CM (x) , (31) from (14) and (22).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>But this is not true, because the degeneracies of the energy eigenstate in the infinite and the finite volume are different. (31) should be changed to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>φ L CM (x) = ∞ l=0 l m=−l C lm (k) · Y lm (Ω)φ (lm) CM (|x|) , (32)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with some constant C lm (k), where Ω is the spherical coordinate for x. φ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(lm) CM (|x|) is the lm component of φ CM (x) defined by φ (lm) CM (|x|) = dΩ Y * lm (Ω)φ CM (x) . (33) Substituting (16) and (25) into (32), we obtain φ L CM (x) = ∞ l=0 l m=−l v lm (k) · G lm (x; k) = ∞ l=0 l m=−l D lm (k) · Y lm (Ω) α l (k) · j l (k|x|) + β l (k) · n l (k|x|) , (34) where D lm (k) = C lm (k)b lm (k).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the present work we consider only the two-pion state in the A + 1 representation of the rotational group on the lattice, which equals to S-wave up to angular momentum l = 2. If the scattering phase shift for l ≥ 2 is very small in the energy range under consideration, β l (k) ∼ 0 for l ≥ 2 in (34). This also means that v lm (k) ∼ 0 for l ≥ 2, because G lm (x; k) contains n l (k|x|) as discussed before. This expectation is supported by our numerical simulation as shown later. We use the expansion form of G(x; k) in (29) to determine the allowed values of k, D lm (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>k) and v 00 (k) in (34). Comparing the coefficients of j 0 (k|x|) and n 0 (k|x|) of both lines of (34), we find D 00 (k) · α 0 (k) = v 00 (k) · 1 √ 4π g 00 (k; 1) , (35) D 00 (k) · β 0 (k) = v 00 (k) · k 4π , (36) where g 00 (k; 1) is defined from (30). Finally we obtain the finite size formula by taking the ratio of (35) and (36) : α 0 (k) β 0 (k) = 1 tan δ 0 (k) = √ 4π k g 00 (k; 1) . (37)</trash>

					<figDesc>The other components of (34) give only information for D lm (k). In the case of P = 0, this formula turns to be the formula presented by Lüscher in Ref. [7]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>III. METHOD OF CALCULATIONS</head>

				<p>A.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Calculation of wave function</head>

				<p>In the present work we consider the ground state of the I = 2 S-wave two-pion system with the total momentum P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . When the interaction between two pions is turned off, the scattering momentum k defined by (6) takes</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>k = 0 for P = 0 , k = π/(γL) for P = (2π/L)e x . (38)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These values of k are changed by the two-pion interaction.</p>

				<p>In order to calculate the wave function we construct the correlation function :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F ππ (x, τ, τ s ) = 0|Ω(x, τ ) ¯ Ω(P, τ s )|0 . (39) The operator Ω(x, τ ) is defined by Ω(x, τ ) = ˆ R 1 L 3 X e iP·X π + (X + ˆ R[x], τ )π + (X, τ ) , (40) where π + (x</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, τ ) is an interpolating operator for π + at the position (x, τ ). The operation R represents an element of the cubic group (O h ) for P = 0 and the tetragonal group (D 4h ) for P = (2π/L)e x . The summation over R projects out A + 1 representation of these groups, which equals to the S-wave state up to the angular momentum l = 4 for P = 0 and l = 2 for P = (2π/L)e x .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>The operator Ω(P, τ s ) in (39) is defined by Ω(P, τ s ) = 1 N R N R j=1 π + (P, τ s ; ξ j )π + (0, τ s ; η j ) † , (41) where π + (P, τ s ; ξ j ) = 1 L 3 x e iP·x ¯ d(x, τ s )ξ * j (x) γ 5 y u(y, τ s )ξ j (y) . (42) The operator π + (P, τ s ; η j ) is defined as π + (P, τ s ; ξ j ) by changing ξ j (x) to η j (x). The functions ξ j (x) and η j (x) are U(1) noise whose property is lim N R →∞ 1 N R N R j=1 ξ * j (x)ξ j (y) = δ 3 (x − y) . (43)</trash>

					<figDesc>In the present work we set N R = 2. Neglecting the contributions from excited states, we can extract the wave function by</figDesc>
					<trash>φ L (x) = F ππ (x, τ 0 , τ s ) F ππ (x 0 , τ 0 , τ s ) , (44) in the large τ 0 region, introducing a reference position x 0 . We note that φ L (x) at all positions x are not independent. The number of independent positions is (L + 2)(L + 4)(L + 6)/48 for P = 0 and (L + 2) 2 (L + 4)/16 for P = (2π/L)e x , owing to the boundary condition (20) and the rotational symmetry on the lattice, φ L (x) = φ L ( ˆ R[x]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>).</p>

				<p>In the present work we attempt to extract the energy of the two-pion system and the scattering phase shift from the wave function. For a comparison, we also evaluate them from the two-pion time correlator :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G ππ (τ, τ s ) = 1 L 3 x F ππ (x, τ, τ s ) , (45)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>as done in the previous works of the scattering phase shift. We also calculate the time correlator for the pion and the ρ meson,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>G π (τ, τ s ) = 1 N R N R j=1 1 L 3 x 0|π + (x, τ ) π + (0, τ s ; ξ j ) † |0 , (46) G ρ (τ, τ s ) = 1 N R N R j=1 1 L 3 x a=1,2,3 0|ρ a (x, τ ) ρ a (0, τ s ; ξ j ) † |0 , (47)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which are used to extract the masses. In (47) ρ a (x, τ ) is an interpolating operator for the ρ meson with the polarization a at the position (x, τ ) and ρ a (0, τ s ; ξ j ) is given by substituting γ a for γ 5 in (42).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B. Simulation parameters</head>

				<p>Our simulation is carried out in the quenched approximation with the plaquette gauge action at β = 5.9. Gauge configurations are generated with the 5-hit pseudo-heat-bath algorithm and the over-relaxation algorithm mixed in the ratio of 1 : 4. This combination is called a sweep and the physical quantities are measured every 200 sweeps after 2000 sweeps for the thermalization. We use the improved Wilson action for quarks [14]. The clover coefficient C SW is chosen to the mean-field improved value defined by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>C SW = U −3/4 = (1 − 2/β) −3/4 = 1.364 , (48) where U is the 1 × 1</trash>

					<figDesc>Wilson loop which is evaluated in one-loop perturbation theory. The quark propagators are calculated with the Dirichlet boundary condition imposed in the time direction and the periodic boundary condition in the spatial one. The source operator Ω(P, τ s ) in (39) is set at τ s = 20 to avoid effects from the time boundary. The lattice cutoff is estimated as 1/a = 1.631(45) GeV (a = 0.1208(33) fm) from m ρ . The lattice size is 32 3 × 120, which corresponds to the spatial extent 3.87 fm in the physical unit. We choose three quark masses to give m π = 0.420, 0.488 and 0.587 GeV . The numbers of configurations are 400, 212 and 212 for each quark mass, which are generated independently. The masses of the pion and ρ meson calculated from the time correlator are listed in Table I.</figDesc>
					<trash>IV. RESULTS A. Wave functions</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>We obtain the wave function φ L (x) by (44) and transform it to φ L CM (x) = φ L (ˆ γ −1 [x]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>). In the transformation we calculate the Lorentz boost factor by γ = √ E 2 − P 2 with the energy E extracted from the two-pion time correlator. In Fig. 1 we show φ L CM (x) at m π = 0.420 GeV for the total momentum P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . Here we set the reference position x 0 = (7, 5, 2) and τ 0 − τ s = 40 in (44), confirming that the wave function does not depend on the choice of τ 0 for τ 0 − τ s &gt; 32. In the figure the left and right panels for each momentum show the wave functions on xy-plane at z = 0 and yz-plane at x = 0. While the boundary conditions for P = 0 are the periodic conditions in all directions, those for P = (2π/L)e x are anti-periodic in the x direction and periodic in the other directions as known from (24). These features are clearly shown in the figure. We consider the two-pion interaction from the ratio :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V L CM (y) = ∇ 2 y φ L CM (y) φ L CM (y) = 1 φ L (x) ∇ 2 − (P · ∇) 2 /E 2 φ L (x) , (49) where y = ˆ γ[x]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>and ∇ 2 y is the Laplacian with respect to y. Away from the two-pion interaction range, we expect that V L CM (x) is independent of x and equals to −k 2 . In the calculation of the ratio, we rewrite (49) by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V L CM (y) = 1 φ L (x) 1 γ 2 ∂ 2 ∂x 2 1 + ∂ 2 ∂x 2 2 + ∂ 2 ∂x 2 3 φ L (x) , (50) and adopt the naive numerical derivative, ∂ 2 ∂x 2 i f (x) = f (x + ˆ i) + f (x − ˆ i) − 2f (x) , (51)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the Lorentz boost factor γ is calculated with E extracted from the two-pion time correlator. In Fig.2 V L CM (x) is plotted for the same parameters as for Fig. 1. We find that the ratio is almost constant for |x| &gt; 10 both for P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . We also observe a strong repulsive interaction near the origin consistent with the negative scattering phase of the I = 2 two-pion system.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Here, we note a physical meaning of V L CM (x) in (49). It seems that V L CM (x) equals to the corresponding ratio in the Minkowski space defined by</figDesc>
					<trash>V CM (x) = ∇ 2 φ CM (x) φ CM (x) , (52)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which approximately takes the potential of the two-pion interaction in the non-relativistic limit. This, however, is not true for P = 0 in the interaction region |x| &lt; R.</p>

				<p>Ignoring the difference of the degeneracy of the energy eigenstate in the infinite and the finite volume, the wave function in the Euclidian space, which is calculated in the present work, is related to that in the Minkowski space by the analytic continuation as φ L (x) = φ(x) at the relative time x 0 = 0. But a relation between φ L CM (x) and φ CM (x) is φ L CM (ˆ γ[x]) = φ L (x) = φ(x) = φ CM (−γ(v · x), ˆ γ[x]) , (53) which is not a relation at x 0 = 0. Thus, there is no simple relation between V</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>L</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>CM (x) in (49) and V CM (x) in (52) for P = 0. Only for the region |x| &gt; R, we give a simple relation : V L CM (x) = V CM (x) = −k 2</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>, due to the x 0 -independence of the wave function, φ CM (x 0 , x) = φ CM (0, x).</p>

				<p>We now consider the two-pion interaction range R. In the quantum field theory the wave function does not strictly satisfy the Helmholtz equation (23), even for the large |x| region. Hence, with k obtained from the two-pion time correlator, V</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>L</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>CM (x) + k 2 shows a small tail at large |x|. We may take the wave function as satisfying the Helmholtz equation, if V</figDesc>
					<trash>L CM (x)+k 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is sufficiently small compared with k 2 . In the present work we take an operational definition of the range R as the scale, where</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>U L CM (x) = V L CM (x) + k 2 k 2 = (∇ 2 + k 2 )φ L CM (x) k 2 φ L CM (x) , (54)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is small enough compared with the statistical error. With this definition we expect that the systematic error of the scattering phase shift from the interaction tail is smaller than the statistical error of the scattering phase shift.</p>

				<figure>
					<head>We show U L</head>

					<figDesc>CM (x) as the function of |x| in Fig. 3</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. We find R &lt; L/2(= 16) in all cases. This means that the necessary condition for the finite size formula is satisfied on the 32 3 lattice for our range of the quark mass m π = 0.420 − 0.587 GeV and the momentum k ∼ 0 − π/(γL)(∼ 0.16 GeV) with the current statistics of the simulations.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B.</head>

				<p>Scattering phase shift from wave function</p>

				<p>We attempt to calculate the scattering phase shift by substituting the momentum k obtained with three methods into the finite size formula (37). First method is the conventional one, where we calculate the momentum k by (6) with the energy of the two-pion system E extracted from the two-pion time correlator. Our results of k and the scattering phase shift δ 0 (k) are tabulated in Table II</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>for P = 0 and Table III for P = (2π/L)e x (labeled &quot; from T &quot; ).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>In the second method, we extract k by fitting the wave function φ L (x) to the Green function (26) with the form, φ L (x) = C · G(ˆ γ[x]; k) , (55) taking k and an overall constant C as free parameters. This method was introduced by the CP-PACS collaboration in Ref. [9] for the evaluation of the scattering length, where they found that the statistical error can be reduced with this method. The numerical evaluation of G(ˆ γ[x]; k) and an explicit procedure of the fitting are discussed in Appendix A. We choose the fitting range |x| ≥ x m with x m tabulated in Table II and III. An example of the fitting is shown in Fig. 4 at m π = 0.420 GeV, where the data points are shown with open circles and the values for the fits with cross symbols. We find that the fit works well both for P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . These mean that the contribution of G lm (x; k) with l ≥ 2 are negligible as expected. Our results of k and δ 0 (k) are tabulated in Table II and III (labeled &quot; from φ &quot; ). These are consistent with those of the conventional method ( &quot; from T &quot; ). We also find that the statistical errors is reduced. Thus the method with the wave function is also efficient for the evaluation of the scattering phase shift.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>As discussed in Sec. IV A, the ratio V L CM (x) in (49) equals to −k 2 away from the interaction range. For simplicity we write the ratio by</figDesc>
					<trash>V (x; γ) ≡ V L CM (ˆ γ[x]) = 1 φ L (x) 1 γ 2 ∂ 2 ∂x 2 1 + ∂ 2 ∂x 2 2 + ∂ 2 ∂x 2 3 φ L (x) , (56) with (50). We extract k by minimizing the chi-square : χ 2 (k) = |x|≥xm V (x; γ) + k 2 δV (x; γ) 2 , (57)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>taking k as a free parameter, where δV (x; γ) is the statistical error at fixed γ. This method is an extension of that introduced by the CP-PACS collaboration in Ref. [9] for P = 0 to the system with P = 0. As known in (56), V (x; γ) depends on k through γ. This fact makes the analysis difficult. We use a similar procedure as for fitting the wave function (see in Appendix B). We choose the same fitting range x m for fitting the wave function. Our results of k and δ 0 (k) are tabulated in Table II and III (labeled &quot; from V &quot; ). As shown in the tables, the results are consistent with those from the two-pion time correlator ( &quot; from T &quot; ) and fitting the wave function ( &quot; from φ &quot; ). We also find that the statistical error is significantly reduced.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C.</head>

				<p>Scattering length and phase shift at physical quark mass For P = 0, the momentum k is very small as shown in Table II. Thus the scattering length a 0 can be calculated by a 0 = tan δ 0 (k) k . (58)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>In Fig. 5</head>

				<p>we plot the scattering length a 0 /m π obtained from three methods discussed in the previous section. They are consistent, but the statistical errors are significantly reduced by using the two methods with the wave function ( &quot; from φ &quot; and &quot; from V &quot; ). We carry out the chiral extrapolation with the fit form, a 0 /m π = A + B · m</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 π and obtain a 0 /m π = −2.211(77) GeV −2 , (59)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in the chiral limit, for the data of fitting V (x, γ) ( &quot; from V &quot; ). The result of chiral extrapolation is also plotted in the Fig. 5. We refer that the prediction from CHPT is a 0 /m π = −2.265(51) GeV −2 [15].</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>We obtain the scattering phase shift at the physical quark mass for the various momenta k from the scattering amplitude defined by A(m π , k) = tan δ 0 (k) k m 2 π + k 2 , (60) which is normalized as A(m π , k) = a 0 m π at k = 0. We show the results in Table II and III, and plot in Fig. 6</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. We fit these amplitudes with a fitting form :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A(m π , k) = A 10 · m 2 π + A 20 · m 4 π + A 01 · k 2 + A 11 · m 2 π k 2 . (61)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The results of the fitting are also plotted in Fig. 6 and summarized in Table IV. We find that A 10 (= a 0 /m π ) is consistent with (59). Finally, we estimate the scattering phase shift δ 0 (k) at the physical quark mass by putting m π = 0.140 GeV in (61). In Fig. 7 our results are plotted as a function of k 2 and compared with the experiments [16]. Our results are larger than the experiments. We consider that this disagreement arises from the effect of the finite lattice spacing. We must leave this issue to studies in the future.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>V. CONCLUSION</head>

				<p>We have calculated the two-pion wave function for the ground state of the I = 2 S-wave two-pion system both for P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . We have investigated the validity of the necessary condition for the finite size formula and found that it is satisfied on the 32 3 lattice for the quark mass range m π = 0.420 − 0.587 GeV and the scattering momentum k ≤ 0.16 GeV. We have also found that the scattering phase shift can be extracted from the wave function with a smaller statistical error than from the two-pion time correlator, which have been used in the studies to date.</p>

				<p>An implication of the present work is the feasibility to calculate the decay width of the ρ meson through studies of the I = 1 two-pion system. While the evaluation of the disconnected diagrams with a good precision has been a computational problem, our method, investigating the scattering system from the wave function in which the energy eigenvalue is extracted from the wave function at a single time slice, could lend a tactics that can be used to evaluate such complicated diagrams with a modest cost.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>APPENDIX A: FITTING WAVE FUNCTION TO GREEN FUNCTION We introduce ¯ k 2 = (ˆ γ −1 [P/2]) 2 , (A1) and expand the Green function around k 2 = ¯ k 2 as G(ˆ γ[x]; k) = ∞ j=0 (k 2 − ¯ k 2 ) j−1 · F (ˆ γ[x]; j, ¯ k) . (A2) The coefficient F (x; j, ¯ k) is defined by F (x; 0, ¯ k) = − 1 γL 3 q 2 = ¯ k 2 e iq·x , (A3) and F (x; j, ¯ k) = 1 γL 3 q 2 = ¯ k 2 1 (q 2 − ¯ k 2 ) j e iq·x , (A4) for j ≥ 1, where q ∈ Γ P (defined by (27)). We evaluate F (x; j, ¯ k) for j ≥ 1 from (γL 3 ) · F (x; j, ¯ k) = − 1 j! q 2 = ¯ k 2 e iq·x + j r=1 1 (j − r)! q 2 = ¯ k 2 e −(q 2 − ¯ k 2 ) (q 2 − ¯ k 2 ) r e iq·x + 2π 3/2 γ (j − 1)! 2π L −3 1 0 dη η 2j−4 e (η ¯ k) 2 · f (x; η) , (A5) where f (x; η) = n∈Z 3 (−1) L/(2π)P·n · e −(( x+ˆη )) 2 . (A6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(A5) is obtained by the same technique discussed in Ref. [9]. F (ˆ γ[x]; j, ¯ k) in the (A2) is depend on k through γ. This fact makes the fitting of the wave function difficult. In the present work, we adopt the following procedure: [1] We calculate γ 0 = E/ √ E 2 − P 2 with the energy E extracted from the two-pion time correlator and take it as the initial value of γ. [2] We fix ¯ k and F (ˆ γ[x]; j, ¯ k) in the (A2) with given γ and fit the wave function, taking k as the free parameter. [3] We update γ by γ = 1 + P 2 /[4(m 2 π + k 2 )] with k obtained in [2]. [4] We iterate the procedure [2] -[3], until the value of k becomes to be stable.</p>

				<p>It is expected that k rapidly converges in this procedure, because the dependence of γ on k is very small. We confirm that k is stable within the single precision after five iterations for all our simulation parameters. We carry out above procedure for the each jackknife bin and estimate the statistical error of k by the jackknife method.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>FIGURES (a) P = 0 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0 1.1 x y -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0 1.1 y z (b) P = (2π/L)e x -18 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 18 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -0.1 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0 1.1 1.2 1.3 1.4 1.5 x y -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16</trash>


				</figure>

				<p><formula>0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0 1.1 1.2 1.3 1.4 1.5 y z</formula></p>

				<p>FIG. 1: Two-pion wave functions φ L CM (x) at m π = 0.420 GeV for the total momentum P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . The left and right panels for each momentum show φ L CM (x) on xy-plane at z = 0 and yz-plane at x = 0.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(a) P = 0 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -0.1 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 x y -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -0.1 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 y z (b) P = (2π/L)e x -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -0.1 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 x y -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -16 -14 -12 -10 -8 -6 -4 -2 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 -0.1 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 y z FIG. 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>: V L CM (x) at m π = 0.420 GeV for the total momentum P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . The left and right panels for each momentum show V L CM (x) on xy-plane at z = 0 and yz-plane at x = 0.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(a) P = 0 (b) P = (2π/L)e x -2.00 -1.00 0.00 1.00 7.0 8.0 9.0 10.0 11.0 12.0 13.0 14.0 15.0 16.0 |x| m π = 0.420 GeV -2.00 -1.00 0.00 1.00 m π = 0.488 GeV -2.00 -1.00 0.00 1.00 2.00 m π = 0.587 GeV -0.60 -0.30 0.00 0.30 7.0 8.0 9.0 10.0 11.0 12.0 13.0 14.0 15.0 16.0 |x| m π = 0.420 GeV -0.60 -0.30 0.00 0.30 m π = 0.488 GeV -0.60 -0.30 0.00 0.30 0.60 m π = 0.587 GeV FIG. 3</trash>

					<figDesc>: U L CM (x) as the function of |x| for the total momentum P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x .</figDesc>
					<trash>(a) P = 0 1.00 1.01 1.02 1.03 1.04 1.05 1.06 1.07 1.08 1.09 8.0 10.0 12.0 14.0 16.0 18.0 20.0 22.0 24.0 26.0 28.0 φ L (x) |x| φ L (x) fitting (b) P = (2π/L)e x 0.20 0.40 0.60 0.80 1.00 1.20 1.40 1.60 8.0 10.0 12.0 14.0 16.0 18.0 20.0 22.0 24.0 26.0 28.0 φ L (x) |x| φ L (x) fitting</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>FIG. 4: Results of fitting the wave function φ L (x) to the Green function at m π = 0.420 GeV for the total momentum P = 0 and P = (2π/L)e x . Open circles refer to the data points and cross symbols to the results of the fitting.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>-2.4 -2.2 -2.0 -1.8 -1.6 -1.4 -1.2 -1.0 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 a 0 / m π (1/GeV 2 ) m π 2 (GeV 2 ) from T from φ from V</trash>

					<figDesc>FIG. 5: Scattering length a 0 /m π obtained from the two-pion time correlator ( &quot; from T &quot; ), fitting the wave function ( &quot; from φ &quot; ) and fitting V (x; γ) ( &quot; from V &quot; ). The result of chiral extrapolation for the data of &quot; from V &quot; is also plotted.</figDesc>
					<trash>-0.7 -0.6 -0.5 -0.4 -0.3 -0.2 -0.1 0.00 0.01 0.02 0.03 A( m π , k ) k 2 (GeV 2 ) m π = 0.420 GeV from T from φ from V 0.00 0.01 0.02 0.03 k 2 (GeV 2 ) m π = 0.488 GeV from T from φ from V 0.00 0.01 0.02 0.03 k 2 (GeV 2 ) m π = 0.587 GeV from T from φ from V</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>FIG. 6: Scattering amplitude A(m π , k) fore three quark masses obtained from the two-pion time correlator ( &quot; from T &quot; ), fitting the wave function ( &quot; from φ &quot; ) and fitting V (x; γ) ( &quot; from V &quot; ). The fit curves for the data of &quot; from V &quot; are also plotted.</figDesc>
					<trash>-10.0 -9.0 -8.0 -7.0 -6.0 -5.0 -4.0 -3.0 -2.0 -1.0 0.0 1.0 0.000 0.005 0.010 0.015 0.020 0.025 0.030 0.035 0.040 δ ( deg. ) k 2 (GeV 2 ) present work ACM(A) ACM(B)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>FIG. 7: Results of the scattering phase shift at the physical pion mass and the experiments in Ref. [16].</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>TABLES κ N conf. m π (GeV) m ρ (GeV) m π /m ρ 0.1413 400 0.41964(66) 0.837(12) 0.5012(71) 0.1410 212 0.48829(95) 0.8598(95) 0.5679(62) 0.1405 212 0.58749(74) 0.9007(67) 0.6522(48)</trash>

					<figDesc>TABLE I: Masses of the pion and the ρ meson calculated from the time correlator.</figDesc>
					<trash>κ 0.1413 0.1410 0.1405 m π (GeV) 0.41964(66) 0.48829(95) 0.58749(74) x m 13.0 14.0 12.0 k (GeV) from T 0.0383(14) 0.0360(19) 0.0396(14) from φ 0.03760(91) 0.0363(12) 0.03810(92) from V 0.03762(46) 0.03750(57) 0.03875(33) δ 0 (k) (deg.) from T −1.71(18) −1.44(22) −1.88(18) from φ −1.63(11) −1.48(14) −1.70(11) from V −1.636(56) −1.621(69) −1.776(42) a 0 /m π (GeV −2 ) from T −1.86(12) −1.43(14) −1.415(87) from φ −1.808(79) −1.460(88) −1.322(58) from V −1.809(40) −1.546(42) −1.363(21) A(m π , k) from T −0.330(22) −0.343(34) −0.489(30) from φ −0.320(14) −0.349(21) −0.457(20) from V −0.3198(70) −0.370(10) −0.4709(72)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>TABLE II: Results for the total momentum P = 0 from two-pion time correlator ( &quot; from T &quot; ), fitting wave function ( &quot; from φ &quot; ) and fitting V (x; γ) ( &quot; from V &quot; ).</figDesc>
					<trash>κ 0.1413 0.1410 0.140 m π (GeV) 0.41964(66) 0.48829(95) 0.58749(74) x m 10.0 11.0 12.0 k (GeV) from T 0.1610(14) 0.1594(21) 0.1634(12) from φ 0.16015(96) 0.16117(82) 0.16369(54) from V 0.15956(40) 0.16197(38) 0.16394(28) γ from T 1.06159(22) 1.04749(23) 1.033921(92) from φ 1.06168(19) 1.04739(17) 1.033944(82) from V 1.06173(17) 1.04734(16) 1.033937(82) δ 0 (k) (deg.) from T −8.4(12) −5.5(17) −7.20(98) from φ −7.69(78) −6.92(69) −7.46(46) from V −7.21(33) −7.59(31) −7.67(24) A(m π , k) from T −0.412(55) −0.308(94) −0.472(62) from φ −0.379(37) −0.387(37) −0.488(29) from V −0.356(15) −0.423(17) −0.501(15)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>TABLE III: Results for the total momentum P = (2π/L)e x from two-pion time correlator ( &quot; from T &quot; ), fitting wave function ( &quot; from φ &quot; ) and fitting V (x; γ) ( &quot; from V &quot; ).</figDesc>
					<trash>A 10 (GeV −2 ) A 20 (GeV −4 ) A 01 (GeV −2 ) A 11 (GeV −4 ) from T −2.10(27) 2.02(92) −7.7(56) 26(22) from φ −2.17(17) 2.52(59) −3.2(34) 6(12) from V −2.187(80) 2.42(26) −2.3(15) 3.2(56)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>TABLE IV: Results of the coefficients A ij in (61).</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* Present address : Department of Physics, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Tokyo 152-8551, Japan</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<head>Acknowledgments</head>
				<p>We acknowledge to Y.Namekawa for helping us to develop a solver program. The numerical calculations have been performed on VPP5000/80 at the Academic Computing and Communications Center of University of Tsukuba.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">B: FITTING V (x; γ)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The fit of V (x; γ) is performed by the similar procedure as for fitting the wave function discussed in Appendix A</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">P 2 with the energy E extracted from the two-pion time correlator and take it as the initial value of γ</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We fix V (x; γ) with given γ and search k that gives the least number of χ 2 (k) in (57)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<editor>γ = 1 + P 2</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>with. k obtained in [2]</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We iterate the procedure [2] -[3], until the value of k becomes to be stable</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">It is expected that k in this procedure rapidly converges, because the dependence of γ on k is very small. We confirm that k is stable within the single precision after five iterations as for the fitting the wave function. We carry out above procedure for the each jackknife bin and estimate the statistical error of k by the jackknife method</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Aoki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CP-PACS Collaboration) Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="014502" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Suppl.)</title>
		<meeting>. Suppl.)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="381" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">RIKEN-BNL-Columbia Collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Yamazaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Sci., LAT2006</title>
		<meeting>. Sci., LAT2006</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">JHEP 0706 (2007) 053</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">X</forename>
				<surname>Li</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CLQCD Collaboration) Proc. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2007" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Yamazaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CP-PACS Collaboration) Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">074513</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Beane</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NPLQCD Collaboration) Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="054503" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Lü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys. Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="354" to="531" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Rummukainen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Gottlieb</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">397</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">450</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Aoki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CP-PACS Collaboration) Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="094504" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Sasaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Ishizuka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Sci., LAT2007</title>
		<meeting>. Sci., LAT2007</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Sachrajda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Sharpe</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">218</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">727</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Christ</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Kim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Yamazaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="114506" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum mechanics, Vols. I, II ( North-Holland</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Messiah</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Sheikholeslami</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Wohlert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">259</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">572</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Gasser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Leutwyler</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Bijnens</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Colangelo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Ecker</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">E</forename>
				<surname>Gasser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Sainio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Ann. Phys. Nucl. Phys</title>
		<editor>G. Colangelo, J. Gasser and H. Leutwyler</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="374" to="603" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Hoogland</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">126</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
