<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">22:31 WSPC/INSTRUCTION FILE Final Do subleading corrections to Bekenstein-Hawking entropy hold the key to quantum gravity?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2008-03-29">29 May 2008 February 21, 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">S</forename>
								<surname>Shankaranarayanan</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cosmology and Gravitation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Portsmouth</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Mercantile House</addrLine>
									<postCode>P01 2EG</postCode>
									<settlement>Portsmouth</settlement>
									<country key="GB">U.K</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">22:31 WSPC/INSTRUCTION FILE Final Do subleading corrections to Bekenstein-Hawking entropy hold the key to quantum gravity?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2008-03-29">29 May 2008 February 21, 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Black hole entropy</term>
					<term>Entanglement 
 PACS nos: 0460-m</term>
					<term>0470-s</term>
					<term>0470Dy</term>
					<term>0365Ud</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Black-holes are considered to be theoretical laboratories for testing models of quantum gravity. It is usually believed that any candidate for quantum gravity must explain the microscopic origin of the Bekenstein-Hawking (S BH) entropy. In this letter, we argue (i) the requirement for a candidate approach to go beyond S BH and provide generic subleading corrections, and (ii) the importance to disentangle and identify the degrees of freedom leading to S BH and its subleading corrections. Using the approach of entan-glement of modes across the horizon, we show that the microscopic degrees of freedom that lead to S BH and subleading corrections are different. We further show, using micro-canonical and canonical ensemble approaches, that the quantum entanglement predicts generic power-law corrections to S BH and that the corrections can be identified with the kinematical properties of the event-horizon. In any physical theory, entropy takes an unique position among other physical quantities. This is due to the fact that the entropy relates the macroscopic and microscopic structure of a system through the Boltzmann relation S = k B ln Ω (where Ω is the total number of accessible states) 1. The entropy of black-hole is unique and distinct from that of other physical systems and, hence, is not a surprise that entropy has taken a pivotal role in understanding black-hole properties: (i) Black-hole entropy is not extensive unlike, for instance, the entropy of an ideal gas. Its leading order — Bekenstein-Hawking entropy S BH — is proportional to the area of the event horizon (A H) of the black-hole 2,3 i. e.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
				<p>In any physical theory, entropy takes an unique position among other physical quantities. This is due to the fact that the entropy relates the macroscopic and microscopic structure of a system through the Boltzmann relation S = k B ln Ω (where Ω is the total number of accessible states) 1 . The entropy of black-hole is unique and distinct from that of other physical systems and, hence, is not a surprise that entropy has taken a pivotal role in understanding black-hole properties: (i) Black-hole entropy is not extensive unlike, for instance, the entropy of an ideal gas.</p>

				<p>Its leading order — Bekenstein-Hawking entropy S BH — is proportional to the area of the event horizon (A H ) of the black-hole 2,3 i. e.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BH = k B 4 A H ℓ 2 Pl where ℓ Pl ≡ G c 3 is the Planck length . (1)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Unlike ideal gas, the finiteness of the black-hole entropy requires that the matter and(or) gravity have quantum description which is evident from Eq. (1). (ii) It is still unclear, what are the microscopic degrees of freedom (DOF) leading to black-hole entropy? Currently, there are several approaches starting from counting states (by assuming fundamental structures) 4,5,6 to Noether charge 7,8,9,10,11 . Although , none of these approaches can be considered to be complete; all of them — February 21, 2013 22:31 WSPC/INSTRUCTION FILE</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Final 2</head>

					<figDesc>Shankaranarayanan</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>within their domains of applicability — by counting certain microscopic states yield (1). This is in complete contrast to other physical systems, such as ideal gas, where quantum DOF are uniquely identified and lead to the classical thermodynamic entropy . This is one of the few areas of physics where the semi-classical result dictates and, help to, identify the quantum theory.</p>

				<p>The above discussion raises an important question: Is it sufficient for an approach to reproduce (1) or need to go beyond the Bekenstein-Hawking entropy? As we know, S BH is a semi-classical result and there are strong indications that Eq. (1) is valid for large black holes [i.e. A H ≫ ℓ Pl ]. However, it is not clear, whether this relation will continue to hold for the Planck-size black-holes. Besides, there is no reason to expect that S BH to be the whole answer for a correct theory of quantum gravity. In order to have a better understanding of black-hole entropy, it is imperative for any approach to go beyond S BH and identify the subleading corrections. This raises a related question: Are the quantum DOF that contribute to S BH and its subleading corrections, identical or different? In general, the quantum DOF can be different. However, several approaches in the literature 12,13,14,15 that do lead to subleading corrections either assume that the quantum DOF are identical or do not disentangle DOF contribution to S BH and the subleading corrections.</p>

				<p>In this letter, we show that the quantum DOF that contribute to the Bekenstein- Hawking entropy and its subleading corrections are different. Using the approach of entanglement, we show that it is possible to disentangle DOF contributions. To isolate different contributions and elucidate their role in black-hole entropy, we obtain entanglement entropy (S ent ) in two different statistical — microcanonical and canonical — ensembles. Using the Schrödinger representation of the quantum fields, we show that entanglement predicts generic power-law corrections to S BH .</p>

				<p>So, what is entanglement (entropy) and how can it possibly be the source of black-hole entropy? Given a joint quantum system {AB}, entanglement refers to the quantum correlation between the sub-systems A and B. Entanglement is quantified by the entropy, S ent , of the reduced density matrix ρ α of either of the subsystems defined as S ent = −Tr[ρ α ln(ρ α )]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>α ∈ {A, B} . (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The relation between S ent and black-hole entropy can be understood from the fact that both are (i) quantum effects with no classical analogues and (ii) associated with the existence of horizon 16 .</p>

				<p>Let us now go to the details and see how using entanglement we can identify DOF contributing to S BH and the power-law corrections. We consider a massless scalar field (ϕ) propagating in an asymptotically flat, four-dimensional black-hole background given by the Lemaˆtre line-element a :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ds 2 = −dτ 2 + [1 − f (r)]dξ 2 + r 2 dθ 2 + sin 2 θ dφ 2 , (3) a The motivation</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>for the choice of scalar fields is given in Ref. 16 .</p>

				<p>February 21, 2013 22:31 WSPC/INSTRUCTION FILE</p>

			<div>
				<head>Final</head>

				<p>Do subleading corrections to Bekenstein-Hawking entropy hold the key to quantum gravity? 3 where r is the radial coordinate in the Schwarzschild coordinate system and is related to (ξ, τ ) by the relation ξ − τ = dr/ 1 − f (r). The Hamiltonian of the scalar field propagating in the above line-element is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>H(τ ) = 1 2 ∞ τ dξ 1 r 2 1 − f (r) Π 2 lm + r 2 1 − f (r) (∂ ξ ϕ lm ) 2 + l(l + 1) 1 − f (r) ϕ 2 lm , (4) where</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>ϕ lm is the spherical decomposed field and Π lm is the canonical conjugate of ϕ lm . [For simplicity of the notation, we will suppress the subscripts (lm).] Although, the above Hamiltonian is time-dependent, there are several advantages of Lemaˆtre coordinate over the Schwarzschild coordinate: (i) the former is not singular at the horizon (r H ) as opposed to the latter, and (ii) ξ (or τ ) are space(or, time)-like everywhere while r is space-like only for r &gt; r H .</p>

				<p>Having obtained the Hamiltonian, the next step is quantization. We use Schrödinger representation since it provides a simple and intuitive description of vacuum states for time-dependent Hamiltonian 17 . Formally, we take the basis vector of the state vector space to be the eigenstate of the field operator ϕ(τ, ξ) on a fixed τ hypersurface, with eigenvalues ϕ(ξ) i. e. ˆ ϕ(τ, ξ)| ϕ(ξ), τ = ϕ(ξ)| ϕ(ξ), τ .</p>

				<p>The quantum states are explicit functions of time and are represented by wave functionals Ψ[ϕ(ξ), τ ] which satisfy the functional Schrödinger equation:</p>

				<p><formula>i ∂Ψ ∂τ = ∞ τ dξ H(τ ) Ψ[ϕ(ξ), τ ] . (5)</formula></p>

				<p>To proceed with the evaluation of S ent : (i) We assume that the Hamiltonian evolves adiabatically. Technically, this implies that the evolution of the late-time modes leading to Hawking particles are negligible. In the microcanonical ensemble [where the total energy is fixed], this assumption translates to the weak time-dependence of the functional (Ψ[ϕ(ξ), τ ]). In the canonical ensemble [where the temperature is fixed], this corresponds to black-hole in thermal equilibrium and Ψ[ϕ(</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>ξ), τ ] is approximated as a WKB functional. (ii) We then obtain ρ α by tracing the region enclosing the horizon [ξ → (r H , ∞)] and use Eq. (2) to determine S ent b . Microcanonical ensemble: The Hamiltonian (4) at a fixed Lemaˆtre time τ =</figDesc>
					<trash>τ 0 ≡ 0 reduces to 16 H F = 1 2 ∞ 0 dr π 2 (r) + r 2 ∂ ∂r ϕ(r) r 2 + l(l + 1) r 2 ϕ 2 (r) , (6)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where π is a canonical transformed variable given by, Π = r 1 − f (r) π. This is the Hamiltonian of a scalar field in flat space-time and is valid for any fixed Lemaitre time. ˆ ϕ are time-independent and Ψ[ϕ] satisfies the time-independent Scrödinger February 21, 2013 22:31 WSPC/INSTRUCTION FILE</p>

				<figure>
					<head>Final 4</head>

					<figDesc>Shankaranarayanan</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>equation (5). For simplicity, let us choose the wave-functional to be superposition 16 of the ground Ψ 0 [ϕ] and first-excited state Ψ 1 [ϕ], i. e., Ψ[ϕ(r)] = c 0 Ψ 0 [ϕ] + c 1 Ψ 1 [ϕ]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, (7) where c 0 , c 1 are constants satisfying |c 0 | 2 + |c 1 | 2 = 1, and Ψ 0 [ϕ] = k ω k π 1/4 exp − 1 16π 3 ϕ 2 (|k|) ; Ψ 1 [ϕ] = 2ω k1 (2π) 3 ϕ(k 1 )Ψ 0 [ϕ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. (8)</p>

				<p>Following the procedure discussed in the previous page, the numerical evaluation of the density matrix leads to following best fit for the microcanonical entanglement entropy</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>16 S mc ent = S BH 1 + a 1 A H ℓ 2 Pl −ν (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where a 1 ∝ |c 1 | and ν &gt; 0. This is the first result of this letter. It is instructive to stress the implications of the result: (i) S mc ent is obtained for a scalar field in a flat space-time. Thus, S BH and the subleading corrections can be uniquely identified with the correlation of the quantum states. (ii) For the pure vacuum wave-functional, a 1 = 0 and S mc ent is identical to Bekenstein- Hawking entropy. This clearly shows that the entanglement entropy of ground state leads to the area law and the excited states contribute to the power-law corrections. (iii) For large black-holes, power-law correction falls off rapidly and we recover S BH . However, for the small black-holes, the second term dominates and black-hole entropy is no more proportional to area. Physical interpretation of this result is immediately apparent. In the large black-hole (or low-energy) limit, it is difficult to excite the modes and hence, the ground state modes contribute significantly to S ent . However, in the small black-hole (or high-energy) limit, larger number of field modes can be excited and hence they contribute significantly to S ent .</p>

				<p>Having established that the quantum DOF that contribute to S BH are different from the one that contribute to the corrections, our next step is to identify the power-law contributions to the kinematical properties of the horizon. For this we obtain S ent in the canonical ensemble.</p>

				<p>Canonical ensemble: In the adiabatic limit, the ansatz for the wave-functional is Ψ[ϕ(ξ), τ ] = P [ϕ] exp i S[ϕ(ξ, τ )] (10) where S is the Hamilton-Jacobi corresponding to (4) and P [ϕ] is the 1-loop term.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Using the relation between ρ and partition function Z, ρ(β) = 1 2πi i∞ −i∞ Z(β) e βE dE (11) February 21, 2013 22:31 WSPC/INSTRUCTION FILE</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Final</head>

				<p>Do subleading corrections to Bekenstein-Hawking entropy hold the key to quantum gravity? 5 and following the procedure discussed earlier, we get</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>18 S c ent = S BH + F log A H ℓ 2 Pl , where F = − 1 60 f ′′ (r H ) r 2 H − 1 10 κ r H , (12)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>κ is surface gravity and f ′′ (r H ) is second derivative of metric at the horizon. This is the second key result of this letter regarding which we would like to stress a few points: (i) This is a master equation and gives the entropy corresponding to a general spherically symmetric black-hole space-time. The sub-leading corrections depend only on the kinematical properties of black-hole i. e. surface gravity and second deriviative of metric function. [It should be noted that this form is unique for all orders of the WKB approximation and does not depend on third and higher order derivatives of the metric 18 .] (ii) F is a constant — and hence, subleading corrections are purely logarithmic — only, if κ ∝ r −1 H and f ′′ (r H ) ∝ r −2 H . This uniquely corresponds to Schwarzschild space-time. For any other black-hole space-times like, for instance, Reissner- Nördstrom, Schwarzschild-(</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Anti)de Sitter, we have S c ent = S BH − π 1/2 15 ℓ Pl A H −1/2 log A H ℓ 2 Pl + Higher contributions (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(iii) As in the microcanonical ensemble, (a) in the large black-hole limit the powerlaw corrections fall off rapidly and we recover S BH (b) in the small black-hole limit, the second term dominates and the black-hole entropy is not proportional to area.</p>

				<p>In summary, we have emphasized the importance of the subleading corrections to S BH and their role in identifying the structure of the quantum theory. Using the approach of entanglement, we have shown that the quantum DOF that lead to S BH need not necessarily contribute significantly to subleading terms. Since entanglement is a quantum effect and should be present in any quantum theory, the results presented here do have implications beyond the semiclassical regime and hence, the subleading corrections do seem to hold the key to unlock the mysteries of quantum gravity. The author wishes to thank Saurya Das, Hubert Lampeitl, Sudipta Sarkar, L. Sriramkumar and Sourav Sur for discussions. The work is supported by the Marie Curie Incoming International Grant IIF-2006-039205.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">* Email: shanki.subramaniam@port.ac.uk</note>

			<note place="foot">b S ent is generally divergent in continuum theories. Therefore usually we assume an ultraviolet cutoff ℓ Pl to regulate the quantum field theory. Below we assume that this is just a technical issue and that we can always have such a regularization see Refs. 18,19 and references therein.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mod. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">221</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Bekenstein</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Nuovo</forename>
				<surname>Cim</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">737</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. D. Bekenstein, Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2333</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Vafa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="9601029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Ashtekar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">904</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9710007</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Carlip</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241301" to="0203001" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Hooft</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">256</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">727</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Bombelli</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">373</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="201322-02-21" />
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Shankaranarayanan</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Srednicki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">666</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9303048</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Wald</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3427</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9307038</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Das</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Shankaranarayanan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121701" to="0511066" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Carlip</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Class. Quant. Grav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">41750005017</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Das</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Class. Quant. Grav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2355</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Myers</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
				<surname>Simon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24340708" to="1270" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Das</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Shankaranarayanan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Sur</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">064013</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum field theory of point particles and strings</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Hatfield</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Redwood City, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>734. p. (Frontiers inphysics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Sarkar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Shankaranarayanan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Sriramkumar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">arXiv:0802.1588 [gr-qc</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Brout</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
