<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SUPERSYMMETRY, GENERAL RELATIVITY AND UNITY OF NATURE *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2009-02-18">18 Feb 2009 October, 2008 11-17 September 2008,</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Kazunari</forename>
								<surname>Shima</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Saitama Institute of Technology Fukaya</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>369-0293</postCode>
									<settlement>Varna</settlement>
									<region>Saitama</region>
									<country>Japan, Bulgaria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Motomu</forename>
								<surname>Tsuda</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Saitama Institute of Technology Fukaya</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>369-0293</postCode>
									<settlement>Varna</settlement>
									<region>Saitama</region>
									<country>Japan, Bulgaria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SUPERSYMMETRY, GENERAL RELATIVITY AND UNITY OF NATURE *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2009-02-18">18 Feb 2009 October, 2008 11-17 September 2008,</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>* Based on the talk given by K. Shima at EU RTN Workshop Constituents, Fundamental Forces and Symmetries of the Universe,</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The basic idea and some physical implications of nonlinear supersymmetric general relativity (NLSUSY GR) are presented. NLSUSY GR may give new insights into the origin of mass and the mysterious relations between the cosmology and the low energy particle physics, e.g. the spontaneous SUSY breaking scale, the cosmological constant, the (dark) energy density of the universe and the neutrino mass.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>The symmetry and its spontaneous breaking are important notions for the unified description of nature. Supersymmetry (SUSY) [1, 2, 3] is a profound notion related naturally to space-time symmetry, which is promissing for the unification of graviton with all other particles in the single irreducible representation of the symmetry group. Therefore, the evidences of SUSY and its spontaneous breakdown [4, 5, 6] should be studied not only in (low energy) particle physics but also in cosmology, i.e. in the framework necessarily accomodating graviton [7].</p>

				<p>Along these viewpoints, we have found by the group theoretical arguments that among all SO(N) super-Poincaré (SP) groups the SO(10) SP group with the decomposition of 10 supercharges as 10 = 5 + 5 * under SO(10) ⊃ SU(5) ⊃ SU(3) × SU(2) × U(1) may be a unique and minimal group which accomodates all observed particles, i.e. the standard model (SM) with just three generations of quarks and leptons including graviton are accomodated as SUSY eigenstates in a single irreducible representation of SO(10) SP group, which constitute a single SO(10) linear (L) SUSY supermultiplet [8]. (We remember that the relativistic hydrogen atom is solved by O(4) space-time symmetry.) Remarkably we have assigned 5 the same quantum numbers as those of 5 of SU(5) GUT [9]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, i.e. 5 = (3, 1; [ 1 3 . 1 3 , 1 3 ]) + (1, 2; [−1, 0]) (1) with respect to (SU(3), SU(2); [Q e ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>). Furthermore considering that the superchages (generators) in the SUSY algebra for the massless representation of SO(10) SP in the light-cone frame can be interpreted as the creation and annihilation operators for spin 1 2 particle, we are tempted to imagine that there may be a certain composite structure (far) beyond the SM. We have proposed the superon-quintet (SQ) hypothesis [10] corresponding to 5 as the fundamental spin 1 2 massless objects for all observed particles.</p>

				<p>The advocated difficulty for constructing non-trivial SO(N &gt; 8) SUSY (gravity) theory, the so called no-go theorem based on S-matrix argument [11, 12], can be circumvented by adopting the nonlinear (NL) representation of SUSY [13], i.e. the vacuum degeneracy of the fundamental action. The NL representation of SUSY gives the (unique) action describing the spontaneous breakdown of SUSY. Volkov- Akulov (VA) model [2] gives the NL representation of N = 1 SUSY describing the dynamics of spin</p>

				<figure>
					<head>1 2</head>


				</figure>

				<p>Nambu-Goldstone (NG) fermion accompanying the spontaneous SUSY breaking in flat space-time.</p>

				<p>Therefore the NLSUSY invariant generalization of the general relativity gives the fundamental theory of everything in our scenario, i.e. the ultimate shape of nature is unstable empty space-time described by the principle of the general relativity [14]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Nonlinear Supersymmetric General Relativity</head>

				<p>For simplicity we discuss N = 1 without the loss of the generality. The extension to N &gt; 1 is crucial for the realistic model building.</p>

				<p>The fundamental action (called nonlinear supersymmetric general relativity (NL- SUSY GR)) has been constructed by extending the geometric arguments of Einstein general relativity (EGR) on Riemann space-time to new space-time inspired by NL- SUSY, where tangent space-time is specified not only by the Minkowski coodinate x a of SO(1, 3) but also by the Grassmanian coordinate ψ α of the isomorphic SL(2C) for NLSUSY [15, 10], i.e. the coset parameters of</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>superGL(4R) GL(4R)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>interpreted as NG fermions associated with the spontaneous breaking of super-GL(4R) down to GL(4R). (The noncompact isomorphic groups SO(1, 3) and SL(2C) for tangent space-time symmetry on curved space-time can be regarded as the generalization of the compact isomorphic groups SU(2) and SO(3) for the gauge symmetry of &apos;t Hooft-Polyakov monopole on flat space-time.)</p>

				<p>The NLSUSY GR action [15, 10] is given by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L NLSUSYGR (w) = c 4 16πG |w|{Ω(w) − Λ}, (2) |w| = det w a µ = det{e a µ + t a µ (ψ)}, t a µ (ψ) = κ 2 2i ( ¯ ψγ a ∂ µ ψ − ∂ µ ¯ ψγ a ψ), (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where G is the Newton gravitational constant, Λ is a (small) cosmological term and κ is an arbitrary constant of NLSUSY with the dimemsion (mass)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−2 . w a µ (x) = e a µ +t a µ (ψ) and w µ a = e µ a −t µ a +t µ ρ t ρ a −t µ σ t σ ρ t ρ a +t µ κ t κ σ t σ ρ t ρ a which terminates at O(t 4 ) are the invertible unified vierbeins of new space-time. e a µ is the ordinary vierbein of EGR for the local SO(1, 3) and t a µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(ψ) is the stress-energy-momentum tensor (i.e. the mimic vierbein) of NG fermion ψ(x) for the local SL(2, C). (We call ψ(x) superon as the hypothetical fundamental spin 1/2 particle constituting (carrying) the supercharge of the supercurrent [16] of the global NLSUSY.) Ω(w) is the the unified scalar curvature of new space-time computed in terms of the unified vierbeins w a µ (x). Note that e a µ and t a µ (ψ) contribute equally to the curvature of space-time, which may be regarded as the Mach&apos;s principle in ultimate space-time. (The second index of mimic vierbein t,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e.g. µ of t a µ , means the derivative ∂ µ .) s µν ≡ w a µ η ab w b ν and s µν (x) ≡ w µ a (x)w νa (x) are unified metric tensors of new spacetime. NLSUSY GR action (2) possesses promissing large symmetries isomorphic to SO(N) (SO(10)) SP group [17, 18, 19]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>; namely, L NLSUSYGR (w) is invariant under [new NLSUSY]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>⊗ [local GL(4, R)] (4) ⊗[local Lorentz] ⊗ [local spinor translation] (5) for spacetime symmetries and [global SO(N)] ⊗ [local U(1) N ] (6) for internal symmetries in case of N superons ψ i , (i = 1, 2, · · · , N). For example, L NLSUSYGR (w) (2) is invariant under the following NLSUSY transfor- mations: δ N L ψ = 1 κ ζ − iκ ¯ ζγ µ ψ∂ µ ψ, δ N L e a µ = iκ ¯ ζγ ρ ψ∂ [µ e a ρ] , (7) where ζ is a constant spinor and ∂ [µ e a ρ] = ∂ µ e a ρ − ∂ ρ e a µ . In fact, (7) induce the following GL(4R) transformations on the unified vierbein w a µ δ ζ w a µ = ξ ν ∂ ν w a µ + ∂ µ ξ ν w a ν , δ ζ s µν = ξ κ ∂ κ s µν + ∂ µ ξ κ s κν + ∂ ν ξ κ s µκ , (8) where ξ µ = −iκ ¯ ζγ µ ψ. L NLSUSYGR (w) (2) is also invariant under the following local Lorentz transformation: on w a µ δ L w a µ = ǫ a b w b µ (9) or equivalently on ψ and e a µ δ L ψ = − i 2 ǫ ab σ ab ψ, δ L e a µ = ǫ a b e b µ − κ 2 4 ε abcd ¯ ψγ 5 γ d ψ∂ µ ǫ bc , (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with the local parameter ǫ ab = (1/2)ǫ [ab] (x). The local Lorentz transformation forms a closed algebra, for example, on e a µ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>[δ L 1 , δ L 2 ]e a µ = β a b e b µ − κ 2 4 ε abcd ¯ ψγ 5 γ d ψ∂ µ β bc , (11) where β ab = −β ba is defined by β ab = ǫ 2ac ǫ 1 c b − ǫ 2bc ǫ 1 c a . The commutators of two new NLSUSY transformations (7) on ψ and e a µ are GL(4R), i.e. new NLSUSY (7) is the square-root of GL(4R); [δ ζ 1 , δ ζ 2 ]ψ = Ξ µ ∂ µ ψ, [δ ζ 1 , δ ζ 2 ]e a µ = Ξ ρ ∂ ρ e a µ + e a ρ ∂ µ Ξ ρ , (12) where Ξ µ = 2i ¯ ζ 1 γ µ ζ 2 − ξ ρ 1 ξ σ 2 e a µ ∂ [ρ e a σ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The algebra closes. The ordinary local GL(4R) invariance is trivial by the construction. Note that the no-go theorem is overcome (circumvented) in a sense that the nontivial N-extended SUSY gravity theory with N &gt; 8 has been constructed in the NLSUSY invariant way.</p>

				<p>New empty space-time for everything described by NLSUSY GR L NLSUSYGR (w) of the vacuum EH type is unstable due to NLSUSY structure of tangent spacetime and decays (called Big Decay [19]) spontaneously to ordinary Riemann spacetime and superon (matter), which is described by the ordinary EH action with the cosmological constant Λ, NLSUSY action for N superon (NG fermion) and their gravitational interactions.</p>

				<p>The resulting action (called tentatively superon-graviton model (SGM) from the subsequent compositeness viewpoints) for N = 1, which ignites Big Bang of the present observed universe, is the following SGM action [20];</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L SGM (e, ψ) = − c 4 Λ 16πG e|w V A | + c 4 16πG e|w V A |R(e) − c 4 16πG e|w V A | 2t (µν) R µν (e) + 1 2 (g µν ∂ ρ ∂ ρ t (µν) − t (µν) ∂ ρ ∂ ρ g µν +g µν ∂ ρ t (µσ) ∂ σ g ρν − 2g µν ∂ ρ t (µν) ∂ σ g ρσ − g µν g ρσ ∂ κ t (ρσ) ∂ κ g µν ) +(t µ ρ t ρν + t ν ρ t ρµ + t µρ t ν ρ )R µν (e) −2t (µρ) t (ν ρ) R µν − t (µρ) t (νσ) R µνρσ (e) − 1 2 t (µν) (g ρσ ∂ µ ∂ ν t (ρσ) − g ρσ ∂ ρ ∂ µ t (σν) + · · ·) +O(t 3 ) + · · · , (13) where (ψ) n ≡ 0 (n ≥ 5 for N = 1), e = det e a µ , t (µν) = t µν +t νµ , t (µν) = t µν +t νµ , and |w V A | = det w a b = det(δ a b +t a b</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is the flat space NLSUSY action of VA [2] containing up to O(t 4 ) and R(e), R µν (e) and R µνρσ (e) are the ordinary scalar curvature, the Ricci tensor and the Riemann curvature tensor of GR. Remarkably we can observe that the first term reduces to NLSUSY action [2], i.e. the arbitrary constant κ of NLSUSY is now fixed to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>κ −2 = c 4 8πG Λ (14) in the Riemann-flat e a µ (x) → δ a µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>space-time and the second term contains the familiar EH action of GR. These expansions describe the complementary relation of graviton and superons (matter), i.e. Mach&apos;s principle is encoded. Note that NLSUSY GR (2) and SGM (13) possess different asymptotic flat space-time, i.e. SGM-flat w a µ (x) → δ a µ space-time and Riemann-flat e a µ (x) → δ a µ space-time, respectively.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L SGM (e, ψ) (13) can be rewritten as the following famlliar form L SGM (e, ψ) = c 4 16πG |e|{R(e) − Λ + ˜ T (e, ψ)}, (15) where R(e</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) is the scalar curvature of ordinary EH action in Riemann space-time and T (e, ψ) represents the kinetic term and the gravitational interaction of superons.</p>

				<p>We think that the geometric arguments of EGR principle has been generalized naturally, which accomodates geometrically spin 1/2 matter as NG fermion accompanying spontaneous SUSY breaking encoded on tangent space-time as NLSUSY. Therefore the black hole as a singularity of space-time in EGR is an interesting object to be studied in the picture of NLSUSY GR.</p>

				<p>We have shown qualitatively that NLSUSY GR may potentially describe a new paradigm (SGM) for the SUSY unification of space-time and matter, where particular SUSY composites composed of superons for all (observed) particles except the graviton emerges as an ultimate feature of nature behind the familiar LSUSY models (MSSM, SUSY GUTs) [10, 21] and SM as well. That is, all (observed) low energy particles may be eigenstates of SO(N) SP expressed uniquely as the SUSY composites (eigen states) of N superons. We examine these possibilities in the next section.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">NL/L SUSY Relation and Physical Implications</head>

				<p>Due to the high nonlinearity of the SGM action we have not yet succeeded in extracting directly (low energy) physical meanings of SGM on curved Riemann space-time.</p>

				<p>However, considering that the SGM action reduces essentially to the N-extended</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>NLSUSY action with κ 2 = ( c 4 Λ 8πG ) −1 in asymptotic Riemann-flat (e a µ → δ a µ ) space- time</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>, it is interesting from the viewpoint of the low energy physics on the local coordinate system to find the N-extended LSUSY theory equivalent (related) to the N-extended NLSUSY model. Through the linearization of the N-extended NLSUSY model, the relation between N LSUSY free theory for LSUSY supermultiplet and N NLSUSY VA model for N NG fermion is demonstrated by many authors for N = 1 [22, 23, 24, 25] and for N = 2 case [26] by heuristic arguments and by the systematic superfield arguments as well.</p>

				<p>We have shown explicitly by the heuristic arguments for simplicity in two spacetime dimensions (d = 2) [27, 28] that N = 2 LSUSY interacting QED is equivalent (related) to N = 2 NLSUSY model in a sense that analogous SUSY invariant relations hold, i.e. each field of LSUSY supermultiplet are expressed uniquely in terms of NLSUSY NG fermions by the arguments on SUSY transformation. Note that the minimal realistic SUSY QED in SGM composite scenario is given by N = 2 SUSY [26].</p>

				<p>In establishing NL/L SUSY relation each field of LSUSY supermultiplet is expressed uniqely as the composite of NG fermions of NLSUSY, which are called SUSY invariant relations. Consequently we are tempted to imagine some composite structure (far) behind the familiar LSUSY unified models, e.g. MSSM and SUSY GUT.</p>

				<p>In this paper we study explicitly the vacuum structure of N = 2 LSUSY QED in the SGM scenario in d = 2 [28].</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>N = 2 NLSUSY action for two superons (NG fermions) ψ i (i, j, · · · = 1, 2) in d = 2 is written as follows, L N =2NLSUSY = − 1 2κ 2 |w| = − 1 2κ 2 1 + t a a + 1 2! (t a a t b b − t a b t b a ) = − 1 2κ 2 1 − iκ 2 ¯ ψ i ∂ψ i − 1 2 κ 4 ( ¯ ψ i ∂ψ i ¯ ψ j ∂ψ j − ¯ ψ i γ a ∂ b ψ i ¯ ψ j γ b ∂ a ψ j ) (16) where κ is a constant whose dimension is (mass) −1 and |w| = det(w a b ) = det(δ a b + t a b ), t a b = −iκ 2 ¯ ψ i γ a ∂ b ψ i , which is invariant under N = 2 NLSUSY transformation, δ ζ ψ j = 1 κ ζ j − iκ ¯ ζ k γ a ψ k ∂ a ψ j . (17) While, the helicity states contained formally in (d = 2) N = 2 LSUSY QED are the vector supermultiplet containing U(1) gauge field    +1 + 1 2 , + 1 2 0    + [CPT conjugate], and the scalar supermultiplet for matter fields    + 1 2 0, 0 − 1 2    + [CPT conjugate]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<p>The most general N = 2 LSUSY QED action for the massless case in d = 2, is written as follows [28]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>, = − 1 4 (F ab ) 2 + i 2 ¯ λ i</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>∂λ i + 1 2 (∂ a A) 2 + 1 2 (∂ a φ) 2 + 1 2 D 2 − 1 κ ξD + i 2 ¯ χ ∂χ +</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 (∂ a B i ) 2 + i 2 ¯ ν ∂ν + 1 2 (F i ) 2 +f (A ¯ λ i λ i + ǫ ij φ ¯ λ i γ 5 λ j − A 2 D + φ 2 D + ǫ ab AφF ab ) +e iv a ¯ χγ a ν − ǫ ij v a B i ∂ a B j + ¯ λ i χB i + ǫ ij ¯ λ i νB j − 1 2 D(B i ) 2 + 1 2 ( ¯ χχ + ¯ νν)A − ¯ χγ 5 νφ + 1 2 e 2 (v a 2 − A 2 − φ 2 )(B i ) 2 , (18) where (v a , λ</trash>

					<figDesc>i , A, φ, D) (F ab = ∂ a v b − ∂ b v a ) is the off-shell vector supermultiplet containing v a for a U(1) vector field, λ i for doublet (Majorana) fermions A for a scalar field in addition to φ for another scalar field and D for an auxiliary scalar field, while (χ, B i , ν, F i ) is off-shell scalar supermultiplet containing (χ, ν) for two (Majorana ) fermions, B i for doublet scalar fields and F i for auxiliary scalar fields. The linear term of F is forbidden by the gauge invariance [28]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>. Also ξ is an arbitrary demensionless parameter giving a magnitude of SUSY breaking mass, and f and e are Yukawa and gauge coupling constants with the dimension (mass) 1 , respectively.</p>

				<p>N = 2 LSUSY QED action (18) is invariant under the following LSUSY transformations parametrized by ζ i ,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δ ζ v a = −iǫ ij ¯ ζ i γ a λ j , δ ζ λ i = (D − i ∂A)ζ i + 1 2 ǫ ab ǫ ij F ab γ 5 ζ j − iǫ ij γ 5 ∂φζ j , δ ζ A = ¯ ζ i λ i , δ ζ φ = −ǫ ij ¯ ζ i γ 5 λ j , δ ζ D = −i ¯ ζ i ∂λ i , (19) for the vector multiplet and δ ζ χ = (F i − i ∂B i )ζ i − eǫ ij V i B j , δ ζ B i = ¯ ζ i χ − ǫ ij ¯ ζ j ν, δ ζ ν = ǫ ij (F i + i ∂B i )ζ j + eV i B i , δ ζ F i = −i ¯ ζ i ∂χ − iǫ ij ¯ ζ j ∂ν −e{ǫ ij ¯ V j χ − ¯ V i ν + ( ¯ ζ i λ j + ¯ ζ j λ i )B j − ¯ ζ j λ j B i } (20) with V i = iv a γ a ζ i − ǫ ij Aζ j − φγ 5</trash>

					<figDesc>ζ i for the scalar multiplet. N = 2 LSUSY QED action (18) and (20) can be rewritten as the familiar manifestly covariant form in terms of the complex quantities defined by</figDesc>
					<trash>χ D = 1 √ 2 (χ + iν), B = 1 √ 2 (B 1 + iB 2 ), F = 1 √ 2 (F 1 − iF 2 ). (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The resulting action is manifestly invariant under the local U(1):</figDesc>
					<trash>(χ D , B, F ) → (χ ′ D , B ′ , F ′ )(x) = e iΩ(x) (χ D , B, F )(x), v a → v ′ a (x) = v a (x) + 1 e ∂ a Ω(x). (22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(For further details see ref.[28]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.) For extracting the low energy particle physics contents of N = 2 SGM (NLSUSY GR) we adopt Riemann-flat asymptotic space-time, where N = 2 SGM reduces to essentially N = 2 NLSUSY action which is related (equivalent) to N = 2 SUSY QED action, which we call NL/L SUSY relation, i.e. for e</figDesc>
					<trash>a µ → δ a µ L N =2SGM −→L N =2NLSUSY + [suface terms] = L N =2SUSYQED . (23)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The NL/L SUSY relation of the two theories are shown explicitly by substituting the following generalized SUSY invariant relations [28] into the LSUSY QED theory. The SUSY invariant relations for the vector supermultiplet (v a , λ i , A, φ, D) are</figDesc>
					<trash>v a = − i 2 ξκǫ ij ¯ ψ i γ a ψ j |w|, λ i = ξ ψ i |w| − i 2 κ 2 ∂ a {γ a ψ i ¯ ψ j ψ j |w|} , A = 1 2 ξκ ¯ ψ i ψ i |w|, φ = − 1 2 ξκǫ ij ¯ ψ i γ 5 ψ j |w|, D = ξ κ |w| − 1 8 ξκ 3 ∂ a ∂ a ( ¯ ψ i ψ i ¯ ψ j ψ j |w|), (24) while for the scalar supermultiplet (χ, B i , ν, F i ) the relaxed SUSY invariant relations are χ = ξ i ψ i |w| + i 2 κ 2 ∂ a {γ a ψ i ¯ ψ j ψ j |w|} , B i = −κ 1 2 ξ i ¯ ψ j ψ j − ξ j ¯ ψ i ψ j |w|, ν = ξ i ǫ ij ψ j |w| + i 2 κ 2 ∂ a {γ a ψ j ¯ ψ k ψ k |w|} , F i = 1 κ ξ i |w| + 1 8 κ 3 ∂ a ∂ a ( ¯ ψ j ψ j ¯ ψ k ψ k |w|) −iκξ j ∂ a ( ¯ ψ i γ a ψ j |w|) − 1 4 eκ 2 ξξ i ¯ ψ j ψ j ¯ ψ k ψ k |w|. (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>N = 2 SUSYQED action (18) is invariant under the variations of the LSUSY component fields of two supermultiplets, which are induced by the NLSUSY transformations of the superon ψ i contained in the modified SUSY invariant relations (24) and (25). Furthermore substituting these SUSY invariant relations into the N = 2 SUSYQED action (18) we can show directly that N = 2 SUSYQED action (18) is related (reduced) to N = 2 NLSUSY action provided ξ 2 − (ξ i ) 2 = 1. As for the LSUSY transformations (19) and (20), the SUSY invariant relations (24) reproduce the familiar LSUSY transformations (19) under the NLSUSY transformations on the contained superons ψ i . The equality in (23) and the SUSY invariant relations (24) and (25) are called NL/L SUSY relation.</p>

				<p>While the modified SUSY invariant relations (25) for the scalar supermultiplet mean that the familiar LSUSY transformations (20) on the above scalar supermultiplet are not reproduced by the NLSUSY transformations of the contained superons ψ i but modified by the (contact four-fermion) gauge interaction terms in the above heuristic arguments. It is interesting that the four-fermion self-interaction term appearing only in the auxiliary fields F i is the origin of the familiar local U(1) gauge symmetry of LSUSY theory, which makes apparently the SUSY invariant relations modified. The redefinitions and the generalizations of the auxiliary fields in the supermultiplet solve these unpleasant situations [29], i.e. by the systematic arguments of NL/L SUSY relations in terms of the superfields the familiar LSUSY transformations on the generalized scalar supermultiplet are reproduced and NL/L SUSY relation holds. Note that in the linearized theory the commutator algebra does not contain U(1) gauge transformation even for the vector U(1) gauge field [26].</p>

				<p>Now we study the vacuum structure of N = 2 SUSY QED action (18) [30]. The vacuum is determined by the minimum of the potential V (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>A, φ, B i , D), ‡ V (A, φ, B i , D) = − 1 2 D 2 + ξ κ + f (A 2 − φ 2 ) + 1 2 e(B i ) 2 D. (26)</trash>

					<figDesc>Substituting the solution of the equation of motion for the auxiliary field D we obtain</figDesc>
					<trash>V (A, φ, B i ) = 1 2 f 2 A 2 − φ 2 + e 2f (B i ) 2 + ξ f κ 2 ≥ 0. (27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The configurations of the fields corresponding to the vacua in (A, φ, B i )-space, which are SO(1, 3) or SO(3, 1) invariant, are classified according to the signatures of the ‡ The terms,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 2 e 2 (A 2 + φ 2 )(B i ) 2 , should be added to Eqs.(26) and (27) but they do not change the final results. parameters e, f, ξ, κ as follows: (I) For ef &lt; 0, ξ f κ &lt; 0 case, A 2 − φ 2 − ( ˜ B i ) 2 = k 2 . ˜ B i = −e 2f B i , k 2 = −ξ f κ (28) (II) For ef &gt; 0, ξ f κ &lt; 0 case, A 2 − φ 2 + ( ˜ B i ) 2 = k 2 . ˜ B i = e 2f B i , k 2 = −ξ f κ (29) (III) For ef &lt; 0, ξ f κ &gt; 0 case, −A 2 + φ 2 + ( ˜ B i ) 2 = k 2 . ˜ B i = −e 2f B i , k 2 = ξ f κ (30) (IV) For ef &gt; 0, ξ f κ &gt; 0 case, −A 2 + φ 2 − ( ˜ B i ) 2 = k 2 . ˜ B i = e 2f B i , k 2 = ξ f κ (31)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We find that the vacua (I) and (IV) with SO(1, 3) isometry in (A, φ, B i )-space are unphysical, for they produce the pathological wrong sign kinetic terms for the fields induced around the vacuum.</p>

				<p>As for the cases (II) and (III) we perform the similar arguments as shown below and find that two different physical vacua appear. The physical particle spectrum is obtained by expanding the field (A, φ, B i ) around the vacuum with SO(3, 1) isom- etry.</p>

				<p>For case (II), the following expressions (IIa) and (IIb) are considered: Case (IIa) A = (k + ρ) sin θ cosh ω φ = (k + ρ) sinh ω ˜ B 1 = (k + ρ) cos θ cos ϕ cosh ω ˜ B 2 = (k + ρ) cos θ sin ϕ cosh ω.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>and Case (IIb)</head>

				<p>A = −(k + ρ) cos θ cos ϕ cosh ω φ = (k + ρ) sinh ω ˜ B 1 = (k + ρ) sin θ cosh ω ˜ B 2 = (k + ρ) cos θ sin ϕ cosh ω Note that for the case (III) the arguments are the same by exchanging A and φ, which we call (IIIa) and (IIIb). Substituting these expressions into L N =2SUSYQED (A, φ, B i ) and expanding the action around the vacuum configuration we obtain the physical particle contents. For the cases (IIa) and (IIIa) we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L N =2SUSYQED = 1 2 {(∂ a ρ) 2 − 2(ef )k 2 ρ 2 } + 1 2 {(∂ a θ) 2 + (∂ a ω) 2 − 2(ef )k 2 (θ 2 + ω 2 )} + 1 2 (∂ a ϕ) 2 − 1 4 (F ab ) 2 + (ef )k 2 v 2 a + i 2 ¯ λ i ∂λ i + i 2 ¯ χ ∂χ + i 2 ¯ ν ∂ν + 2ef ( ¯ λ 1 χ − ¯ λ 2 ν) + · · · , (32) and the consequent mass genaration m 2 ρ = m 2 θ = m 2 ω = m 2 va = 2(ef )k 2 = − 2ξe κ , m λ i = m χ = m ν = m ϕ = 0. (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Note that ϕ is NG boson for the spontaneous breaking of U(1) symmetry, i.e. the U(1) phase of B, and totally gauged away by the Higgs-Kibble mechanism with Ω(x) = eκ/2ϕ(x) for U(1) gauge (22). The vacuum breaks both SUSY and the local U(1) spontaneously. All bosons have the same mass and remarkably all fermions remain massless. λ i transforming inhomogeneouly δλ i = ξ κ ζ i + · · · in the true vacuum are NG fermions for the spontaneous N = 2 SUSY breaking. The physical implication of the off-diagonal mass terms √ 2ef ( ¯ λ 1 χ − ¯ λ 2 ν) = √ 2ef ( ¯ χ D λ + ¯ λχ D ) for fermions is unclear (pathologocal?) and deserves further investigations, which would induce the mixings of fermions and/or the lepton (baryon) flavour violations.</p>

				<p>By the similar computations for (IIb) and (IIIb) we obtain</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L N =2SUSYQED = 1 2 {(∂ a ρ) 2 − 4f 2 k 2 ρ 2 } + 1 2 {(∂ a θ) 2 + (∂ a ϕ) 2 − e 2 k 2 (θ 2 + ϕ 2 )} + 1 2 (∂ a ω) 2 − 1 4 (F ab ) 2 + 1 2 (i ¯ λ i ∂λ i − 2f k ¯ λ i λ i ) + 1 2 {i( ¯ χ ∂χ + ¯ ν ∂ν) − ek( ¯ χχ + ¯ νν)} + · · · . (34)</trash>

					<figDesc>and the following mass spectrum which indicates the spontaneous breakdown of</figDesc>
					<trash>N = 2 SUSY; m 2 ρ = m 2 λ i = 4f 2 k 2 = −4ξf κ , m 2 θ = m 2 ϕ = m 2 χ = m 2 ν = e 2 k 2 = −ξe 2 κf , m va = m ω = 0, (35)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which can produce mass hierarchy by the factor e f . Interestingly all fermions acquire masses through the spontaneous SUSY breaking. The local U(1) gauge symmetry is not broken. The massless scalar ω is a NG boson for the degeneracy of the vacuum in (A, ˜ B 2 )-space, which is gauged away provided the local gauge symmetry between the vector and the scalar multiplet is introduced.</p>

				<p>From these arguments we conclude that N = 2 SUSY QED is equivalent (related) to N = 2 NLSUSY action, which is the matter sector of N = 2 SGM produced by Big Decay (phase transition) of N = 2 NLSUSY GR (new space-time). It possesses two different vacua, the type (a) and (b) in the SO(3, 1) isometry of (II) and (III).</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The resulting models describe; for the type (a); two charged chiral fermions (ψ L cj ∼ ( ˜ χ DL , ˜ ν DL )) (j = 1, 2), two neutral chiral fermions (λ L j ∼ ˜ λ j</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>DL ), one massive vector (v a ), one charged massive scalar (φ c ∼ θ + iω), and one massive scalar (φ 0 ∼ ρ), where (χ, ν, λ i ) are written by left-handed Dirac fields and for the type (b); one charged Dirac fermion (ψ D c ∼ χ + iν), one neutral (Dirac) fermion (λ D 0 ∼ λ 1 − iλ 2 ), one massless vector (a photon) (v a ), one charged scalar (φ c ∼ θ + iϕ) and one neutral complex scalar (φ 0c ∼ ρ + iω), which are the composites of superons. and spontaneously breaks down to Riemann space-time with superon (massless NG fermion) matter of (15), which may be the birth of the present universe (space-time and matter) by the quantum effect Big Decay in advance of the inflation and/or the Big Bang. The variation of (15) with respect to e a µ gives the equation of motion for e a µ recasted as follows;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>R µν (e) − 1 2 g µν R(e) = 8πG c 4 ˜ T µν (e, ψ) − g µν c 4 Λ 8πG , (36)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where T µν (e, ψ) abbreviates the stress-energy-momentum of superon (NG fermion) matter including the gravitational interactions. Note that − c 4 Λ 8πG can be interpreted as the negative energy density of empty spacetime, i.e. the dark energy density ρ D . (The negative sign determined uniquely and produces the correct kinetic term of superons in NLSUSY.)</p>

				<p>While, on tangent spacetime, the low energy theorem of the particle physics gives the following superon (massless NG fermion)-vacuum coupling</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>&lt; ψ j α (q)|J kµ β |0 &gt;= i c 4 Λ 8πG (γ µ ) αβ δ jk e iqx + · · · , (37) where J kµ = i c 4 Λ 8πG</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>γ µ ψ k + · · · (j, k = 1, 2) is the conserved supercurrent obtained by applying the Noether theorem [16] and c 4 Λ 8πG is the coupling constant g sv of superon with the vacuum via the supercurrent. Further we have seen in the preceding section that the right hand side of (36) for N = 2 is essentially N = 2 NLSUSY VA action. And it is equivalent to the broken N = 2 LSUSYQED action (18) with the vacuum expectation value of the auxiliary field (Fayet-Iliopoulos term). For the case (b) it gives the SUSY breaking masse,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>M SU SY 2 ∼&lt; D &gt;∼ c 4 Λ 8πG , (38)</trash>

					<figDesc>to the component fields of the (massless) LSUSY supermultiplet, provided −f ξ ∼ O(1). We find NLSUSY GR (SGM) scenario gives interesting relations among the important quantities of the cosmology and the low energy particle physics, i.e.</figDesc>
					<trash>ρ D ∼ c 4 Λ 8πG ∼&lt; D &gt; 2 ∼ g sv 2 , (39)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Suppose that in the (low energy) LSUSY supermultiplet the stable and the lightest massive particle retains the mass of the order of the spontaneous SUSY breaking. And if we identify the neutrino with such a particle and with λ i (x), i.e.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m ν 2 ∼ c 4 Λ 8πG , (40)</trash>

					<figDesc>then SGM predicts remarkably the observed value of the (dark) energy density of the universe and explains naturally the observed mysterious numerical relations between m ν and ρ</figDesc>
					<trash>obs D : ρ obs D ∼ (10 −12 GeV ) 4 ∼ m ν 4 (∼ g sv 2 ). (41)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The tiny neutrino mass is the direct evidence of SUSY (breaking), i.e. the spontaneous phase transition of SGM spacetime. The large mass scales and the non-abelian gauge symmetry necessary for building the realistic and interacting broken LSUSY model will appear by the extension to the large N SUSY and by the linearization of T µν (e, ψ) which contains the mass scale Λ −1 in the higher order with ψ [18]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusions</head>

				<p>We have proposed a new paradigm for describing the unity of nature, where the ultimate shape of nature is new uastable (empty) space-time described by L NLSUSYGR (w). L NLSUSYGR (w) decays spontaneously to ordinary Riemann space-time with massless superon (fermionic matter) and subsequently ignites the Big Bang and the inflation of the present universe. L NLSUSYGR (w) may be regarded as a realization of the Mach&apos;s principle on new space-time, for e a µ and t a µ contribute equally to the unified vierbein w a µ , i.e. to the whole geometry of space-time. We have shown that the cosmological constant in L NLSUSYGR (w) is the origin of everything (all matter) and that the the vacua of SGM created by the Big Decay of N-extended NLSUSY GR action possess rich structures promissing for the unified description of nature.</p>

				<p>In fact, we have shown explicitly by using NL/L SUSY relations that N = 2 LSUSY theory of the realistic U(1) gauge theory appears as the physical field configurations on the vacuum of N = 2 NLSUSY GR theory on Minkowski tangent space-time, which gives new insights into the origin of mass, the dark matter and the dark energy of the universe. The cosmological implications of the composite SGM scenario deserve further studies.</p>

				<p>Interestingly the physical particle states of N = 2 SUSY QED as a whole look the similar structure to the lepton and the Higgs sector of the SM with the local U(1) and the global SU(2) [26]. The neutral scalr field ρ(∼ m ν ) of the radial mode may be a candidate of the dark matter, provided the N = 2 LSUSY QED structure is preserved in the realistic large N SUSY GUT model. (Note that ω in (34) is a NG boson and disappears provided the corresponding local gauge symmetry is introduced as in the SM.) We anticipate that the physical cosequences obtained in d = 2 hold in d = 4 as well, for the both have the similar on-shell helicity states of N = 2 supermultiplet though scalar fields and off-shell (auxiliary field) structures are modified (extended) and though the similar investigations in d = 4 are urgent for the realistic model building based upon SUSY.</p>

				<p>Further investigations on the spontaneous symmetry breaking for N ≥ 2 SUSY remains to be studied for the realistic model buildings. The extension to large N, especially to N = 5 is important for superon quintet (SQ) hypothesis of SGM scenario. SQ model [8] predicts a (heavy?) lepton state L 2+ with double charges. N = 4 case may shed new light on the mathematical roles of LSUSY in the anomaly free non-trivial d = 4 field theory.</p>

				<p>We can anticipate that any N-extended LSUSY (broken) model can be related to N-extended NLSUSY model via the NL/L SUSY relation containing the SUSY invariant relations with the universal forms ∼ (ψ) n |w| as shown in (24) and (25), which is favourable to the composite SGM viewpoint [8, 10] of the NLSUSY GR theory.</p>

				<p>Also NLSUSY GR with extra space-time dimensions equipped with the Big Decay is an interesting problem, which can give the framework for describing all observed particles as elementary a la Kaluza-Klein.</p>

				<p>Linearizing N = 2 SGM action L SGM (e, ψ) on curved space-time, which elucidates the topological structure of space-time [31], is a challenge. The corresponding NL/L SUSY relation will give the supergravity (SUGRA) [32, 33] analogue with the vacuum breaking SUSY spontaneously.</p>

				<p>The physical and mathematical meanings of the black hole as a singularity of space-time and the role of the equivalence principle are to be studied in detail in NLSUSY GR and SGM scenario .</p>

				<p>Finally we just mention that NLSUSY GR and the subsequent SGM scenario for the spin 3 2 NG fermion [17, 34] is in the same scope.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Acknowledgements</head>

				<p>The author (K.S.) would like to thank the organizers, especially Professor V. Dobrev and Professor D. Luest for inviting him to the EU RTN workshop and for the worm hospitality during the workshop.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Cosmology of NLSUSY GR Now we discuss the cosmological implications of N = 2 NLSUSY GR (or N = 2 SGM from the composite viewpoints). NLSUSY GR space-time of (2) is unstable</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wess</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Zumino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">52</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">V</forename>
				<surname>Volkov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Akulov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">109</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yu</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Golfand</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Likhtman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Jetp</forename>
				<surname>Lett</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<biblScope unit="page">323</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Salam</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Strathdee</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">465</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Fayet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Iliopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">461</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>O &apos;raifeartaigh</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">331</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gell-Mann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of supergravity workshop at Stony Brook</title>
		<editor>P. van Nieuwenhuisen and D. Z. Freedman</editor>
		<meeting>supergravity workshop at Stony Brook<address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>North Holland</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Z</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">25</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Georgi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">167</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">European</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">341</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Coleman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Mandula</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">159</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1251</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Haag</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Lopuszanski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sohnius</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">257</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Wess</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Bagger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Supergravity</forename>
				<surname>Supersymmetry</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Talk given at Conference in Honor of C.N. Yang&apos;s 85th Birthday</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-11-02" />
			<pubPlace>Singapore</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>To. appear in the Proceedings</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">501</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">237</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">574</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">507</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">260</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Class. Quant. Grav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5101</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">PoS HEP2005</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">011</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">645</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">455</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Sgm</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Called</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Nonlinear</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Nlsugra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cho</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Sawaguchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Mod. Phys. E</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">539</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Ivanov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Kapustnikov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2375</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Roč</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">451</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Uematsu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">K</forename>
				<surname>Zachos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">201</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">250</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Tanii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">525</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">183</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Tanii</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">546</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">162</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Mod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1085</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Mod</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3027</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in. preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Tsuda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Lang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">659</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">741</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Shima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Kasuya</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">290</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<forename type="middle">Z</forename>
				<surname>Freedman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Van Nieuwenhuisen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Ferrara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3214</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Deser</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">B</forename>
				<surname>Zumino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">335</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">S</forename>
				<surname>Baaklini</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">335</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
