<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2010-06-07">7 Jun 2010</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2010-06-07">7 Jun 2010</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Relations between various algebras/groups as well as their subalgebras/subgroups played an important role in the Lie algebras/groups theory and its representation theory development. One of these relations is the well known Inönü-Wigner contraction [1] that was, besides its mathematical merits, an important tool in numerous physical applications. There is a variety of Inönü-Wigner Lie algebra contraction applications arising in various parts of Theoretical Physics. Just to mention a few ranging from contractions from the Poincaré algebra to the Galilean one, and from the Heisenberg algebras to the Abelian ones of the same dimensions (a symmetry background of a transition processes from relativistic and quantum mechanics to classical mechanics) to those of contractions in the Kaluza-Klein gauge theories framework, say from (Anti-)deSitter to the Poincaré algebra, and various cases involving the Virasoro and Kac-Moody algebras. For instance, our recent study of the Affine Gauge Gravity Theory in 5D [2] is heavily related to the sl(5, R) algebra contraction w.r.t. its so(1, 3) subalgebra, and the representations of the relevant algebras. In physical terms, the meaning of the Inónú-Wigner contraction is to relate, for instance, strong to weak coupling regimes of the corresponding theories, or geometrically curved to &quot; less curved&apos; and/or flat spaces.</p>

				<p>It is not so well known that there is an inverse to the Inönü-Wigner contraction called the Gell-Mann formula [3, 4, 5, 6]. This formula is a simple prescription designed to determine a deformation of a Lie algebra that is &quot; inverse &quot; to the Inönü-Wigner contraction. This formula relates elements of the starting algebra to the corresponding ones of the contracted algebra. Moreover, by its construction it relates also the representations of these two algebras. Since, by a rule, various properties of the contracted algebra are much easier to explore (e.g. construction of representations [7], decompositions of a direct product of representations [4], etc.), this formula found its place, as a useful and simple tool, even in some textbooks and in the mathematical encyclopedia [3].</p>

				<p>To emphasize its meaning, this formula is also referred to as the &quot; decontraction &quot; formula. This formula was introduced by Dothan and Ne&apos;eman (while working at Caltech on noncompact algebras and their representations ) [8] and advocated by Hermann who learned from Gell-Mann about this formula, named it after Gell-Mann, and made important contributions to the formula himself.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>GENERALIZATION OF THE GELL-MANN FORMULA</head>

				<p>In the general case the Gell-Mann formula construction goes as follows: Let A be a symmetric Lie algebra A = M + T with a subalgebra M such that: (1) [M, M ] ⊂ M, [M, T ] ⊂ T, [T, T ] ⊂ M.</p>

				<p>Further, let A ′ be its Inönü-Wigner contraction algebra w.r.t its subalgebra M, i.e. A ′ = M + U , where (2) [M, M ] ⊂ M, [M, U ] ⊂ U, [U, U ] = {0}.</p>

				<p>The Gell-Mann formula states that the elements T ∈ T can be in certain cases expressed in terms of the contracted algebra elements M ∈ M and U ∈ U by the following rather simple expression:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(3) T = i α √ U · U [C 2 (M), U ] + σU.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, C 2 (M) and U · U denote the second order Casimir operators of the M and A ′ algebras respectively, while α is a normalization constant and σ is an arbitrary parameter. For a mathematically strict definition, cf. [3].</p>

				<p>The main drawback of the Gell-Mann formula is its limited validity. There is a number of references dealing with the question when this formula is applicable [4, 5, 6, 9]. The formula is best studied in the case of (pseudo) orthogonal algebras so(m, n) contracted w.r.t. their so(m − 1, n) and/or so(m, n−1) subalgebras, i.e. in the corresponding group cases: SO</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(m, n) → R m+n−1 ∧ SO(m − 1, n) and/or SO(m, n) → R m+n−1 ∧ SO(m, n − 1), where, loosely speaking, the Gell-Mann formula works very well [10]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. Moreover, the case of (pseudo) orthogonal algebras is the only one where this formula is valid for (almost) all representations [11]. Recently, we studied the sl(n, R) cases where the Gel-Mann formula does not hold as a general operator expression and its validity depends heavily on the sl(n, R) algebra representation space. An exhaustive list of the cases for which the Gell-Mann formula for sl(n, R) algebras hold is obtained [9].</p>

				<p>There were some attempts to generalize the Gell-Mann formula for the &quot; decontracted &quot; algebra operators of the complex simple Lie algebras g with respect to decomposition g = k + ik = k c [12, 13], that resulted in a form of relatively complicated polynomial expressions.</p>

				<p>In this work we consider Gell-Mann&apos;s formula in the sl(n, R) algebra cases, where the contraction is performed w.r.t. their maximal compact so(n) subalgebras . The Gell-Mann formula in these cases is especially valuable as a tool in the problem of finding all unitary irreducible representations of the sl(n, R) algebras in the basis of the SO(n) and/or Spin(n) groups generated by their so(n) subalgebras. Finding representations in the basis of the I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 3 maximal compact subgroup SO(n) of the SL(n, R) group, is mathematically superior, and it suites well various physical applications in particular in nuclear physics, gravity, physics of p-branes [14] etc. As an example consider a gauge theory based on the Affine spacetime symmetry SA(n, R) = T n ∧ SL(n, R). The gauge covariant derivative, D µ , µ = 0, 1, . . . , n − 1, as acting on an Affine matter field Ψ(x), is given by,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>D µ Ψ(x) i = ∂ µ − iΓ ab µ (x) (Q ab ) j i Ψ(x) j , Q ab ∈ sl(n, R), where Γ ab µ</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(x) are the sl(n, R) connections, and i, j enumerate the matter field components. The matter–gravity vertices require the knowledge of the sl(n, R) operators matrix elements (Q ab ) j i in the Hilbert space of the matter field components {Ψ i (x)}. In particular, for a generic spinorial SL(n, R) matter field, en explicit form of the matrix elements of the sl(n, R) generators for infinite-dimensional representation corresponding to the Ψ field is required.</p>

				<p>Moreover, this framework opens up a possibility of finding, in a rather straightforward manner, all matrix elements of noncompact SL(n, R), i.e. SL(n, R) generators for all finite and infinite dimensional representations. Unfortunately, as stated above, the original Gell-Mann formula is of limited validity, and it can be applied in the classes of multiplicity free representations only. Recently we have demonstrated, by an explicit construction, that the Gell-Mann formula has a generalization that is valid for all irreducible representations of the sl(n, R), n = 3, 4 and 5 algebras [15]. These formulas, though comparatively simpler than the ones resulting from some other attempts to generalize the Gell-Mann formula, are still rather cumbersome taking a few rows.</p>

				<p>In this paper we present a generalization of the Gell-Mann formula that is almost as compact and simple as the original formula, which is valid for all representations of the sl(n, R) algebras for all n values.</p>

				<p>In our previous study of the Gell-Mann formula and its generalization for the sl(n, R), n = 3, 4, 5 algebras [15], we first extracted the generalized formula from the previously known generic expressions in the sl(3, R) and sl(4, R) cases which enabled us to obtain finally the generalized formula for the sl(5, R) algebra. A crucial ingredient in generalization of the Gell-Mann formula for the sl(n, R) algebras is a role of the &quot; left-rotation &quot; action of the Spin(n) subgroup of the corresponding SL(n, R) group, which manages the non trivial multiplicity of the maximal compact so(n) subalgebra representations for a generic sl(n, R) representation. In this work we show, by making use of the Cartesian basis, how to obtain the explicit form of the generalized Gell-Mann formula for an arbitrary sl(n, R) algebra with a left-rotations included properly and demonstrate the closure of the sl(n, R)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>GENERALIZATION OF THE GELL-MANN FORMULA</head>

				<p>algebra commutation relations. Moreover, we showed how to rewrite the expression of the generalized formula in a suitable basis (e.g. the Gel&apos;fand- Tsetlin basis) allowing us to directly write down matrix expressions of the sl(n, R), i.e. su(n), generators for an arbitrary irreducible representation in the basis of the Spin(n) group.</p>

				<p>Note that due to mutual relations between the sl(n, R) and su(n) algebras , one can convey the Gell-Mann formula results obtained for the sl(n, R) algebras to the corresponding ones of the su(n) algebras. Though, there are some subtleties in that process that are considered below. 2 sl(n, R) and SL(n, R) topology and representations consid- erations As already stated, the Gell-Mann formula, except in the cases of (pseudo) orthogonal algebras, is not generally valid by itself, and its validity depends on the representations of the algebra as well. Therefore, in the case of the SL(n, R) groups, i.e. their sl(n, R) algebras, one faces, in addition to the pure algebraic features, the matters that are relevant to the group/algebra representations theory as well: notably (i) the group topology properties, and (ii) the non trivial multiplicity of the SL(n, R), and sl(n, R) representations in the SO(n), and so(n) basis, respectively. Both features are rather subtle for n ≥ 3. Note that, in the case of the sl(n, R) algebras, due to a fact that the generalization of the Gell-Mann formula depends on the algebra irreducible representation features, the construction itself deviates from the standard Lie algebra deformation approach.</p>

				<p>The SL(n, R) group can be decomposed, as any semisimple Lie group, into the product of its maximal compact subgroup K = SO(n), an Abelian group A and a nilpotent group N . It is well known that only K is not guaranteed to be simply-connected. There exists a universal covering group K = SO(n) of K = SO(n), and thus also a universal covering of G =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>SL(n, R): SL(n, R) ≃ SO(n) × A × N . For n ≥ 3, SL(n, R) has double covering, defined by SO(n) ≃ Spin(n) the double-covering of the SO(n) subgroup. The universal</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>covering group G of a given group G is a group with the same Lie algebra and with a simply-connected group manifold. A finite dimensional covering, SL(n, R) exists provided one can embed SL(n, R) into a group of finite complex matrices that contain Spin(n) as a subgroup. A scan of the Cartan classical algebras points to the SL(n, C) groups as a natural candidate for the SL(n, R) groups covering. However, there is no match of the defining dimensionalities of the SL</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(n, C) and Spin(n) groups for n ≥ 3, dim(SL(n, C)) = n &lt; 2 [ n−1 I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 5 n = 8 case, one finds that the orthogonal subgroup of the SL(8, R) and SL(8, C) groups is SO(8) and not Spin(8).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>For a detailed account of the D = 4 case cf. [16]. Thus, we conclude that there are no covering groups of the SL(n, R), n ≥ 3 groups defined in finite-dimensional spaces. An explicit construction of all SL(3, R) irreducible representations, unitary and nonunitary multiplicity-free spinorial [17], and unitary non-multiplicity-free [18], shows that they are infinite-dimensional. The universal (double) covering groups, SL(n, R), n ≥ 3 of the SL(n, R), n ≥ 3 group are groups of infinite complex matrices. All their spinorial representations are infinite dimensional . In the reduction of this representations w.r.t. Spin(n) subgroups, one finds Spin(n) representations of unbounded spin values.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The SU (n) groups are compact, with a simply connected group manifold, thus being its own universal coverings. The SO(n) subgroups are embedded into the SU (n) groups as n-dimensional matrices, and this embedding does not allow nontrivial (double) covering of SO(n) within SU (n). As a consequence , in the reduction of the SU (n) unitary irreducible representations one finds the tensorial SO(n) representations only.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>An inspection of the unitary irreducible representations of the SL(n, R), n = 3, 4 groups [18, 19] shows that they have, as a rule, a nontrivial multiplicity of the Spin(n), n = 3, 4 subgroup representations. It is well known, already from the case of the SU (3) representations in the SO(3) subgroup basis, that the additional labels required to describe this nontrivial multiplicity cannot be solely related to the group generators themselves. An elegant solution, that provides the required additional labels, is to work in the group manifold of the SO(n) maximal compact subgroup, and to consider an action of the group both to the right and to the left. In this way one obtains, besides the maximal compact subgroup labels, an additional set of labels to describe the SO(n) subgroup multiplicity.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>3</head>

				<p>Inönü-Wigner contraction of sl(n, R) algebras The sl(n, R) algebra operators, i.e. the SL(n, R), SL(n, R) group generators, can be split into two subsets: M ab , a, b = 1, 2, ..., n operators of the maximal compact subalgebra so(n) (corresponding to the antisymmetric real n × n matrices, M ab = −M ba ), and the, so called, sheer operators T ab , a, b = 1, 2, ..., n (corresponding to the symmetric traceless real n × n matrices, T ab = T ba ). The sl(n, R) commutation relations, in this basis, read: [M ab , M cd ] = i(δ ac M bd + δ ad M cb − δ bc M ad − δ bd M ca ), (4) [M ab , T cd ] = i(δ ac T bd + δ ad T cb − δ bc T ad − δ bd T ca ), (5) [T ab , T cd ] = i(δ ac M db + δ ad M cb + δ bc M da + δ bd M ca ). (6)</p>

				<p>The su(n) algebra operators can be split likewise w.r.t. its so(n) subalgebra into M ab and T</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>su(n) ab , a, b = 1, 2, ..., n. The T su(n) ab and T ab operators are mutually related by T su(n) ab = i T ab , and the [T su(n) ab , T su(n) cd ]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>differs from (6) by having an overall plus sign on the right-hand side.</p>

				<p>The Inönü-Wigner contraction of sl(n, R) with respect to its maximal compact subalgebra so(n) is given by the limiting procedure:</p>

				<p><formula>(7) U ab ≡ lim ǫ→0 (ǫT ab ),</formula></p>

				<p>which leads to the following commutation relations: [M ab , M cd ] = i(δ ac M bd + δ ad M cb − δ bc M ad − δ bd M ca ) (8) [M ab , U cd ] = i(δ ac U bd + δ ad U cb − δ bc U ad − δ bd U ca )</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(9) [U ab , U cd ] = 0. (10) Therefore, the Inönü-Wigner contraction of sl(n, R) gives a semidirect sum r n(n+1) 2 −1 so(n) algebra, where r n(n+1) 2 −1 is an Abelian subalgebra (ideal) of &quot; translations &quot; in n(n+1) 2 − 1 dimensions. The Gell-Mann formula, a prescription to provide an &quot; inverse &quot; to the Inönü-Wigner contraction, (7), in this case reads: (11) T σ ab = iα √ U · U [C 2 (so(n)), U ab ] + σU ab , where C 2 (so(n)) denotes the second order Casimir operator of the so(n) subalgebra, 1 2</trash>

					<figDesc>M ab M ab , while σ is an arbitrary (complex) parameter and α is a (real) normalization constant that depends on n. This expression can also be written in an equivalent form:</figDesc>
					<trash>(12) T σ ′ ab = − 2α √ U · U c U c{a M b}c + σ ′ U ab ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where σ ′ differs from σ accordingly, and { } denotes symmetrization of the enclosed indices.</p>

				<p>In order to make use of the Gell-Mann formula to obtain the sl(n, R) representations , the first necessary step is to determine representation matrix elements of the contracted algebra operators. The corresponding contracted I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 7 group is a semidirect product of SO(n) and an Abelian group, and it is well known that the usual group induction method provides the complete set of all inequivalent irreducible representations [7]. Nevertheless, we will not pursue the induction approach here. Instead, we will rather proceed to work in the representation space of square integrable functions L 2 (Spin(n)) over the Spin(n) group (in accord with the SL(n, R) topological properties), with the standard invariant Haar measure. As for our final goal, this approach ensures certain advantages: (i) The generalized Gell-Mann formula is expressed in terms of tensor operators w.r.t. the maximal compact subgroup basis (instead w.r.t. the eigenvector basis of the Abelian subgroup), (ii) This representation space allows for all inequivalent irreducible representations of the contracted group (some of the irreducible representations are multiply contained, i.e. each such representation appears as many times as is the dimension of the corresponding little group representation and all of them, irrespectively of the corresponding stabilizer, can be treated in an unified manner), and (iii) this space is rich enough to contain all representatives from equivalence classes of the SL(n, R) group, i.e. sl(n, R) algebra representations [20]. The last feature provides the necessary requirement of a framework needed for generalization of the Gell-Mann formula, i.e. a unique framework providing for all sl(n, R) (unitary) irreducible representations.</p>

				<p>The generators of the contracted group are generically represented in this space as follows. The so(n) subalgebra operators act, in a standard way, via the group action to the right:</p>

				<p><formula>M ab |φ = −i d dt exp(itM ab ) t=0 |φ , g ′ |g = g ′ g , |φ ∈ L 2 (Spin(n)).</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The Abelian operators U ab act multiplicatively as Wigner&apos;s D-functions (the appropriate representation SO(n) group matrix elements as functions of the group parameters): (13) U ab → |u|D v(ab) (g −1 ) ≡ v g −1 ab , |u| being a constant norm, g(θ) being an SO(n) element, and in order to simplify notation we denote by (in a parallel to the Young tableaux) the symmetric second rank tensor representation of SO(n). The vector ab from the representation space is determined by the ab &quot; double &quot; index of U ab , whereas the vector v can be an arbitrary vector belonging to the</figDesc>
					<head>1 2</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>n(n + 1) − 1 dimensional representation (the choice of v is determined, in Wigner&apos;s terminology, by the little group of the obtained representation). Taking an inverse of g in (13) ensures the correct transformation properties. The form of the representation of the Abelian operators merely reflects the</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>GENERALIZATION OF THE GELL-MANN FORMULA</head>

				<p>fact that they transform as symmetric second rank tensor w.r.t so(n) (9) and that they mutually commute.</p>

				<p>A natural discrete orthonormal basis in the Spin(n) representation space is given by properly normalized functions of the Spin(n) representation matrix elements:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>{J} {k} {m} ≡ √ dim({J})D {J} {k}{m} (g(θ) −1 )dθ |g(θ) , (14) {J ′ } {J} {k ′ } {m ′ } {k} {m} = δ {J ′ }{J} δ {k ′ }{k} δ {m ′ }{m} , where dθ is an (normalized) invariant Haar measure, D {J} {k}{m} are the Spin(n) irreducible representation matrix elements, (15) D {J} {k}{m} (θ) ≡ {J} {k} R(θ) {J} {m} .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Here, {J} stands for a set of the Spin(n) irreducible representation labels, while {k} and {m} labels enumerate the dim(D {J} ) representation basis vectors.</p>

				<p>An action of the so(n) operators in this basis is well known, and it can be written in terms of the Clebsch-Gordan coefficients of the Spin(n) group as follows,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(16) {J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } M ab {J} {k} {m} = δ {J ′ }{J} √ C 2 ({J}) C {J} {J ′ } {m}(ab){m ′ }</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>.</head>

				<p>The matrix elements of the U ab operators in this basis are readily found to read:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>{J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } U v ab {J} {k} {m} = |u| {J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } D −1 v(ab) {J} {k} {m} = |u| √ dim({J ′ })dim({J}) D {J ′ } * {k ′ }{m ′ } (θ)D v(ab) (θ)D {J} {k}{m} (θ)dθ (17) = |u| dim({J }) dim({J ′ }) C {J} {J ′ } {k} v {k ′ } C {J} {J ′ } {m} (ab) {m ′ } .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A closed form of the matrix elements of the whole contracted algebra r n(n+1)</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">−1</head>

				<p>so(n) representations is thus explicitly given in this space by</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(16) and (17). I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 9</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">The generalized formula</head>

				<p>The Gell-Mann formula (11) expressed in terms of the Wigner&apos;s functions now reads:</p>

				<p><formula>(18) T σ</formula></p>

				<p>ab = iα[C 2 (so(n)), D v(ab) ] + σD v(ab) .</p>

				<p>However, the T ab operators, as given by this expression depending on the representation space, do not close upon the sl(n, R) commutation relations (6) in the whole representation space. Indeed, we have shown in [9] that this formula yields the sl(n, R)/so(n) generators only when the representation space is restricted to Spin(n)/(Spin(m)⊗Spin(n−m)), with v vector chosen to be invariant with respect to the Spin(m) ⊗ Spin(n − m), 1 ≤ m ≤ n − 1, while Spin(1) is here implied to be a trivial group.</p>

				<p>We have shown in [15] that the Gell-Mann formula can be generalized in the cases of the sl(n, R), n = 3, 4 and 5 algebras so that the commutation relations (6) hold for an arbitrary irreducible representation in whole Hilbert space over the Spin(n) group. This generalization was achieved by adding certain extra terms containing the generators of SO(n) subgroup action to the left. For example, the generalized formula in the sl(5, R) case reads:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(19) T σ 1 σ 2 δ 1 δ 2 j1j2 µ1µ2 = σ 1 D 11 00j1 j2 00µ1µ2 + i 1 5 [C 2 (so(5)), D 11 00j1 j2 00µ1µ2 ] +i σ 2 D 11 11j1 j2 00µ1µ2 + 1 2 [C 2 (so(4) K ), D 11 11j1 j2 00µ1µ2 ] −D 1 1 1 1 j1 j2 1−1µ1µ2 (δ 1 + K 10 10 00 − K 10 01 00 ) − D 1 1 1 1j1 j2 − 11µ1µ2 (δ 1 − K 10 10 00 + K 10 01 00 ) +D 11 11j1 j2 11µ1µ2 (δ 2 + K 10 10 00 + K 10 01 00 ) + D 1 1 1 1 j1 j2 − 1−1µ1µ2 (δ 2 − K 10 10 00 − K 10 01 00</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>) ,</head>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The left action generators K, that appear in the formula can be related to the M ab operators by the following expression: (20) K ab ≡ g (a ′′ b ′′ )(a ′ b ′ ) D (ab)(a ′′ b ′′ ) M a ′ b ′ ,</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>where g (a ′′ b ′′ )(a ′ b ′ ) is the Cartan metric tensor of SO(n). The K ab operators behave exactly as the rotation generators M ab , it is only that they act on the lower left-hand side indices of the basis (14):</p>

				<p><formula>(21) {J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } K ab {J} {k} {m} = δ {J ′ }{J} √ C 2 ({J}) C{J} {J ′ } {k}(ab){k ′ } .</formula></p>

				<p>GENERALIZATION OF THE GELL-MANN FORMULA Due to the fact that the mutually contragradient SO(n) representations are equivalent, the K ab operators are directly related to the &quot; left &quot; action of the SO(n) subgroup on L 2 (|g(θ)): g ′ |g = gg</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>′ −1</head>

				<p>. The K ab and M ab operators mutually commute, however, the corresponding Casimir operators match, i.e. K 2 ab = M 2 ab .</p>

				<p>The generalized Gell-Mann formulas for sl(3, R), sl(4, R) and sl(5, R) [15] are given by rather cumbersome expressions. However, when these formulas are expressed in the Cartesian basis (like formulas (4)-(6)) in terms of the K ab operators and anti-commutators rather than commutators the resulting expressions become extremely simple. Moreover, this form allows for an immediate generalization to the case of an arbitrary n.</p>

				<p>We prove below that the generalized Gell-Mann formula for any sl(n, R) algebra w.r.t its so(n) subalgebra takes the following form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(22) T σ 2 ...σn ab = i n c&gt;d {K cd , D (cd)(ab) } + i n c=2 σ c D (cc)(ab) ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where σ c is a set of n − 1 arbitrary parameters that essentially (up to some discrete parameters) label sl(n, R) irreducible representations. Note that the sum in the first term goes only over pairs (c, d) where c &gt; d i.e. it is not symmetric in c, d.</p>

				<p>Let us begin the proof that the expressions (22) satisfy the sl(n, R) commutation relation (6) by introducing operators:</p>

				<p><formula>(23) T [c]</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ab = i c−1 d=1 {K cd , D (cd)(ab) } + iσ c D (cc)(ab) , c = 2, . . . , n i.e. expressing the generalized expression (22) as: (24) T ab = n c=2 T [c]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>ab .</p>

				<p>A straightforward, but somewhat lengthy, calculation yields [T</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(c) ab , T (d) a ′ b ′ ] = [T [c]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>a ′ b ′ , T [d] ab ] for c = d, and thus we find:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(25) [T ab , T a ′ b ′ ] = c [T [c]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>ab , T [c]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a ′ b ′ ] = −i c,d,d ′ {K dd ′ , {D (cd)(ab) , D (cd ′ )(a ′ b ′ ) }}. By making use of the identity: c (D (cd)(ab) D (cd ′ )(a ′ b ′ ) − D (cd ′ )(ab) D (cd)(a ′ b ′ ) ) (26) = 1 I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 11</trash>

					<figDesc>and the fact that the M generators are given in terms of the K operators via the D operators (cf. (20)), one verifies the desired expression (6).</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>Note that the first equality in (25) implies that the overall sign of operators T [c] ab is inessential. Moreover, any left rotation (generated by the K operators) of the generalized formula (22) will preserve the [T, T ] commutator (6) and thus lead to another valid expression for the generalized Gell-Mann formula. The generalized formulas related in this way form an equivalence class of formulas that yield the same set of sl(n, R) irreducible representations. Besides this class there are a few alternative useful expressions of the generalized Gell-Mann formula. We point out explicitly two cases below.</p>

				<p>Let us consider operators:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(27) U (cd) ab ≡ D (cd)(ab)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>stressing that D (cd)(ab) is just a particular representation of the U ab operators (13), characterized by the choice of the vector v to be v = (cd) and |u| = 1. Then, by making use of the commutation relations to shift the K operators to the right in (22) we find :</p>

				<p><formula>(28) T ab = 2i n c&gt;d U (cd) ab K cd + i n c=2 σ ′ c U (cc) ab .</formula></p>

				<p>This expression for the generalized formula can now be directly compared to the original formula in the form (12). It is as simple as the original Gell-Mann formula, with a crucial advantage of being valid in the whole representation space over L 2 (Spin(n)). General validity of the new formula is reflected in the fact that there are now n − 1 free parameters, i.e. representation labels, matching the sl(n, R) algebra rank, compared to just one parameter of the original Gell-Mann formula.</p>

				<p>Another notable form of the generalized formula relies on the fact that the operators T [c] (23) can be written as:</p>

				<p><formula>(29) T [c]</formula></p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ab = i 2 [C 2 (so(c) K ), U (cc) ab ] + iσ c U (cc) ab , c = 2, . . . , n where C 2</trash>

					<figDesc>(so(c) K ) is the second order Casimir of the so(c) left action subalgebra , i.e. C 2 (so(c) K ) =</figDesc>
					<trash>1 2 c a,b=1 (K ab ) 2 . The generalized Gell-Mann formula can now be written as: (30) T σ 2 ...σn ab = i n c=2 1 2 [C 2 (so(c) K ), U (cc) ab ] + σ c U (cc) ab ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>which is to be compared with the original formula in the form (11). Again, the generalized formula matches, by simplicity of the expression, the original one. Besides, the very term when c = n is, essentially, the original Gell-Mann formula (since C 2 (so(n) K ) = C 2 (so(n) M )), whereas the rest of the terms can be seen as necessary corrections securing the formula validity in the entire representation space. The additional terms vanish for some representations yielding the original formula.</p>

				<p>The generalized Gell-Mann formula expression for the noncompact &quot; shear &quot; generators T ab holds for all cases of sl(n, R) irreducible representations, irrespective of their so(n) subalgebra multiplicity (multiplicity free of the original Gell-Mann formula, and nontrivial multiplicity) and whether they are tensorial or spinorial. The price paid is that the Generalized Gell-Mann formula is no longer solely a Lie algebra operator expression, but an expression in terms of representation dependant operators K ab and U (cd) ab .</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>5</head>

				<p>Direct application -matrix elements of SL(n, R) generators for all irreducible representations The generalized Gell-Mann formula, as given by (30), can be directly applied to yield all matrix elements of the SL(n, R) generators for all irreducible representations, characterized by a complete set of labels σ i , i = 2, 3, . . . , n (the invariant Casimir operators are analytic functions of solely these labels), in the basis of the maximal compact subgroup Spin(n). Note that there can be some additional discrete labels generally related to the finite SL(n, R) center group. Taking the matrix elements of (30) we get:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>{J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } T σ 2 ...σn ab {J} {k} {m} (31) = {J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } i n c=2 1 2 [C 2 (so(c) K ), U (cc) ab ] + σ c U (cc) ab {J} {k} {m} = i 2 n c=2 C 2 (so(c) {k ′ } ) − C 2 (so(c) {k} ) + σ c {J ′ } {k ′ }{m ′ } U (cc) ab {J} {k} {m} = i 2 dim({J }) dim({J ′ }) n c=2 C 2 (so(c) {k ′ } ) − C 2 (so(c) {k} ) + σ c C {J} {J ′ } {k} (cc) {k ′ } C {J} {J ′ } {m} (ab) {m ′ } ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where, in the last equality, the expression (17) for the matrix elements of the U operators is used. The second Clebsch-Gordan coefficient, that is merely reflecting the Wigner-Eckart theorem, can be evaluated in any suitable basis, not necessarily the Cartesian one, due to the fact that the expression is covariant with respect to the free index (ab). Note, that this I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 13 is not the case for the first Clebsch-Gordan coefficient – it is necessary in order to evaluate it to express the specific vector (cc) in some basis that spans the entire vector space over Spin(n).</p>

				<p>The final expression is simplified by choosing the indexes of the generalized Gell-Mann formula matrix elements to be given by labels of the Spin(n) ⊃ Spin(n − 1) ⊃ · · · ⊃ Spin(2) group chain representation labels.</p>

				<p>In this notation, the basis vectors of the Spin(n) irreducible representations are written as:</p>

				<p><formula>(32) {J} {m} = J Spin(n),1 J Spin(n),2 J Spin(n),3 . . . J Spin(n−1),1 J Spin(n−1),2 . . . . . . J Spin(2) .</formula></p>

				<p>Likewise, the set of indices {k} of (14) is thus given by the labels of the irreducible representations {J Spin(n−1),1 , J Spin(n−1),2 , · · · ; J Spin(n−2),1 , J Spin(n−2),2 , · · · ; . . . ; J Spin(2) } of the Spin(n) ⊃ Spin(n−1) ⊃ · · · ⊃ Spin(2) group chain.</p>

				<p>To express the vector (cc) in such a basis we notice first that it corresponds to a diagonal traceless n by n matrix of the form diag(−</p>

				<p><formula>1 n , . . . , − 1 n , n−1 n , − 1 n , . . . , − 1 n ), with n−1</formula></p>

				<p>n positioned at the c-th row and column. On the other hand, the diagonal traceless matrix 1 c(c−1) diag(−1, . . . , −1, c − 1, 0, . . . , 0), with first c − 1 occurrences of −1, corresponds to a vector that belongs to a second order symmetric tensor ( representation) with respect to Spin(c), Spin(c + 1), . . . , Spin(n) subgroups, and it is invariant under Spin(c − 1):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(33) { } Spin(n) · · · { } Spin(c) {0} Spin(c−1) · · · 0 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This vector has n − c + 1 double-boxes followed by c − 2 zeros underneath – in shorthand notation:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>{ } n−c+1 {0} c−2 . Somewhat peculiar is the matrix 1 2 diag(−1, 1, 0, 0, . . . ) that corresponds to: (34) { } n−1 {0} 0 ≡ 1 √ 2 { } Spin(n) · · · { } Spin(4) 2 2 + 1 √ 2 { } Spin(n) · · · { } Spin(4) 2 −2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>GENERALIZATION OF THE GELL-MANN FORMULA where the standard labelling for SO(n), n ≤ 3 is implied, in particular the representation corresponds to J Spin(3) = 2.</p>

				<p>By combining these facts we find:</p>

				<p><formula>(35) (cc) + 1 c n d=c+1 (dd) = c−1 c { } n−c+1 {0} c−2 .</formula></p>

				<p>However, when evaluating the U (cc) operators of (30) in this basis, only the first term on the left-hand side is relevant due to the fact that:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(36) d &gt; c ⇒ [C 2 (so(c) K ), U (dd) ab ] = 0.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Having this in mind, we make use of (35) to recast, in the first equality of (31), the U (cc) operators accordingly. Taking into account arbitrariness of the σ c coefficients and following the same steps as in (31), we finally obtain a rather simple expression for the shear generator matrix elements for an arbitrary sl(n, R) representation (labelled now by parameters σ c )</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>: (37) {J ′ } {k ′ } {m ′ } T {w} {J} {k} {m} = i 2 dim({J }) dim({J ′ }) C {J} {J ′ } {m}{w}{m ′ } × n c=2 c−1 c C 2 (so(c) {k ′ } ) − C 2 (so(c) {k} ) + ˜ σ c C {J}( ) n−c+1 {J ′ } {k} (0) c−2 {k ′ }</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>.</head>

				<p>The relation of the labelling of (37) and the one of (22), i.e. (30), is achieved provided σ c = ˜ σ c + c−1 d=2 σ d /d. The Clebsch-Gordan coefficient with indices {m}, {w}, {m ′ } in (37) can be evaluated in an arbitrary basis (which is stressed by denoting the appropriate index by w instead by ab). The other Clebsch-Gordan coefficient can be evaluated in any basis labelled according to the</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Spin(n) ⊃ Spin(n − 1) ⊃ · · · ⊃ Spin(2) subgroup chain (e.g. Gel&apos;fand-Tsetlin basis) and can be, nowadays, rather easily evaluated, at least numerically.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As already stated, the matrix elements of the sl(n, R)/so(n) operators, as given by the Generalized Gell-Mann formula, apply to all tensorial, spinorial, unitary, nonunitary (both finite a infinite-dimensional) sl(n, R) irreducible representations. In many physics applications one is interested in the unitary irreducible representations. The unitarity question goes beyond the scope of the present work, and it relates to the Hilbert space properties, i.e. the vector space scalar product. An efficient method to study unitarity is to start with a Hilbert space L 2 (</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Spin(n), κ) of square integrable functions with a scalar product in terms of an arbitrary kernel κ, and to impose the unitarity constraints both on the scalar products itself and on the sl(n, R)/so(n) operators matrix elements in that scalar product (cf. [18]</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I. SALOM, DJ. ˇ SIJA CKI 15</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To sum up, the expressions (16) and (37) fully determine the action of the sl(n, R) operators for an arbitrary irreducible representation given by the set of n − 1 invariant Casimir operators labels σ c . This action is given in terms of the basis vectors (14) of the representation spaces of the maximal compact subgroup Spin(n) of the SL(n, R) group. This result is general due to a Corollary of Harish-Chandra [20] that explicitly applies to the case of the sl(n, R) algebras.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Conclusion</head>

				<p>The Gell-Mann formula, as stated above, applies at the pure algebraic level, i.e. as an algebraic expression, only in the case of (pseudo) orthogonal algebras . One can formally write it in other Lie algebra cases. However, it turns out, by an explicit verification, that it is not generally valid, ie. that the closure of the commutation relations of the generators given by this formula is not granted generically. It turns out that certain successful applications of the Gell-Mann formula, beyond the orthogonal-like algebras, were actually carried out in a framework of particular algebra representation spaces. Thus, the Gell-Mann formula applicability can be broaden beyond the so(m, n) algebra cases, by utilizing it in other algebra cases provided some Lie algebra representation conditions are met. As for the sl(n, R) algebras, contracted w.r.t. their so(n) subalgebras, the algebraic expression of the Gel-Mann formula matters generally for the multiplicity free representations only. In a previous work, starting from the known generic noncompact generators representation expressions for sl(3, R) and sl(4, R), we found the generalization of the Gell-Mann formula for the sl(5, R) case. It is valid for all representation spaces irrespective of the so(5) sub-representations non-trivial multiplicity . An analysis of the structure of the generalized Gell-Mann formula in the sl(3, R), sl(4, R) and sl(5, R) cases, especially of the role played by the K ab operators that generate the SO(n) K , i.e. Spin(n) K group (acting to the left in the group manifold and characterize the SO(n) M , i.e. Spin(n) M representations multiplicity) paved a way for a successful generalization of the Gell-Mann formula for all sl(n, R) algebras. The generalized formula is given by expression (22). It can take alternative forms, such as (28) and (30), that suit better for certain mathematical or physical applications. The generalized Gell-Mann formula for the sl(n, R) and or su(n) algebras, considered w.r.t. their so(n) subalgebras (the maximal compact subalgebra of the sl(n, R) algebra) is compact and simple, and thus has a great potential for both further general consideration and various applications in mathematics and physics.</p>

				<p>Note that the generalized Gell-Mann formula for the sl(n, R) algebras, that is valid for all representation Hilbert spaces, is characterized precisely by a right number of n − 1 (algebra rank) parameters, i.e. representation labels. As a first and most precious application, based on the generalized formula, we obtained for the first time a closed form of the expressions of all matrix elements of the sl(n, R) noncompact generators for all irreducible representations. All representations meaning: finite, infinite, tensorial and spinorial. A distinct feature of our generalized Gell-Mann formula approach is that the generalized expression goes beyond the standard notion of deformation of the contracted algebra, as it depends on additional operators, K ab , not belonging, however directly related, to the contracted algebra. Due to this fact, our generalization of the Gell-Mann formula is remarkably simple (compared to complicated polynomial expressions appearing in some other approaches to generalize the Gell-Mann formula), nevertheless establishing a direct relation between representations of the contracted and original al- gebras.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>7</head>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:1006.1224v1 [math-ph] 7 Jun 2010</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<p>This work was supported in part by MNTR, Project-141036. One of us, I.S., would like to acknowledge hospitality and useful discussions at the Institute for Nuclear Research and Nuclear Energy in Sofia (Bulgaria) during his visit as early stage researcher supported by the FP6 Marie Curie Research Training Network &quot; Forces-Universe &quot; MRTN-CT-2004-005104.</p>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Inönü</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">P</forename>
				<surname>Wigner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci</title>
		<meeting>. Nat. Acad. Sci</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1953" />
			<biblScope unit="page">510</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R) fields in gravity and brane physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Salom</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sijač</forename>
				<surname>Dj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sfin</forename>
				<surname>Xxii A</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Sl</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Hazewinkel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Encyclopaedia of Mathematics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">269</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Supplement. I</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lie Groups for Physicists</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Hermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
			<publisher>W. A. Benjamin Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<surname>Hermann</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">155</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Berendt</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Acta</forename>
				<surname>Phys</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Austriaca</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">207</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Mackey</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Induced Representations of Groups and Quantum Mechanics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Salom</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Dj</forename>
				<forename type="middle">ˇ</forename>
				<surname>Sija</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Cki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Band Spectra Generated by Non- Compact Algebra CALT-68-41 preprint; reprinted in F. J. Dyson, Sym- metry Groups in Nuclear and Particle Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yossef</forename>
				<surname>Dothan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Yuval</forename>
				<surname>Ne &apos;eman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>Benjamin Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">I</forename>
				<surname>Salom</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sijač</forename>
				<surname>Dj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sankaranarayanan</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nuovo Cimento</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1441</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Weimar</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lettere Al Nuovo Cimento J. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1300</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>12. ] ˇ Stovič P</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Mukunda</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Phys. Class. Quant. Grav. Int. J. Geom. Met. Mod. Phys</title>
		<editor>15] Igor Salom and Djordjě Sijač</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1014</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="065009" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ˇ Sijač Dj</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Ne &apos;eman</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Sijač</forename>
				<surname>Dj</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Spinors in Physics and Geometry</title>
		<editor>A. Trautman and G. Furlan eds.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>World Scientific Pub</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1655" to="1872" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Harish-Chandra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. 37 170</title>
		<meeting>. Nat. Acad. Sci. 37 170</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1951" />
			<biblScope unit="page">691</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
