<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Exotic Higgs boson decay modes as a harbinger of S 3 flavor symmetry</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2011-01-03">3 Jan 2011</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Gautam</forename>
								<surname>Bhattacharyya</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Saha Institute of Nuclear Physics</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1/AF Bidhan Nagar</addrLine>
									<postCode>700064</postCode>
									<settlement>Kolkata</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">FakultätfürPhysik</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">TechnischeUniversitätDortmund</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>44221</postCode>
									<settlement>Dortmund</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Philipp</forename>
								<surname>Leser</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">FakultätfürPhysik</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">TechnischeUniversitätDortmund</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>44221</postCode>
									<settlement>Dortmund</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Heinrich</forename>
								<forename type="middle">P</forename>
							</persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Exotic Higgs boson decay modes as a harbinger of S 3 flavor symmetry</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2011-01-03">3 Jan 2011</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>SINP/TNP/2010/12, TH-DO 10/10</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords scheme="pacs">
					<term>Nos: 1480Ec</term>
					<term>1130Hv 
 Key Words: Higgs boson</term>
					<term>flavor symmetry</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Discrete symmetries employed to explain flavor mixing and mass hierarchies can be associated with an enlarged scalar sector which might lead to exotic Higgs decay modes. In this paper, we explore such a possibility in a scenario with S3 flavor symmetry which requires three scalar SU (2) doublets. The spectrum is fixed by minimizing the scalar potential, and we observe that the symmetry of the model leads to tantalizing Higgs decay modes potentially observable at the CERN Large Hadron Collider (LHC).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Flavor models based on discrete symmetries are often used to address issues like large/small mixing and mild/strong mass hierarchies in the lepton/quark sector (for reviews, see, e.g. [1]). The permutation group S 3 is an attractive such candidate which was introduced in [2] and explored further in [3, 4].</p>

				<p>In this paper we study the exciting prospect that such flavor models can predict enlarged Higgs sectors with non-standard couplings to fermions and gauge bosons, although such a nonsupersymmetric extension does not provide any additional stability to the potential. The main motivation here arises from flavor issues. Its supersymmetrization would indeed bring in quantum stability, but in this work we stick to a minimal nonsupersymmetric S 3 flavor scenario.</p>

				<p>The motivation for choosing S 3 is that it is the smallest non-abelian discrete symmetry group that contains a 2-dimensional irreducible representation which can connect two maximally mixed generations. It is the symmetry group of an equilateral triangle and has three irreducible representations: 1, 1 ′ and 2, with multiplication rules: 2×2 = 1+1 ′ +2 and 1 ′ × 1 ′ = 1. Besides facilitating maximal mixing through its doublet representation, S 3 provides two inequivalent singlet representations which play a crucial role in reproducing fermion masses and mixing. To accomplish the latter, three scalar SU (2) doublets are introduced, which couple to the fermions as dictated by S 3 symmetry. It so happens that large mixing among up-and down-type quarks cancel each other in the Cabibbo matrix. Neutrino masses are separately generated by a type-II see-saw mechanism using scalar SU (2) triplets [5], so that the mismatch between the large mixing of the charged leptons and the diagonal neutrino masses translates directly into the Pontecorvo-Maki-Nakagawa-Sakata matrix.</p>

				<p>In this paper we do not deal with those triplets, but explore the following avenues: (i) minimization of the scalar potential with three scalar SU (2) doublets, two of which form an S 3 doublet and the third an S 3 singlet, (ii) the gauge and Yukawa interactions of the neutral scalars, and (iii) different nonstandard production and decay modes of the neutral CP-even scalars leading to the possibility of their detection at the LHC.</p>

				<p>For definiteness, we study the S 3 model pursued in [4] to explain the leptonic flavor structure. We concentrate on the complementary aspects by exploring the scalar sector. The assignments of the fermion and scalar fields are as follows:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(L µ , L τ ) ∈ 2 L e , e c , µ c ∈ 1 τ c ∈ 1 ′ , (Q 2 , Q 3 ) ∈ 2 Q 1 , u c , c c , d c , s c ∈ 1 b c , t c ∈ 1 ′ , (1) (φ 1 , φ 2 ) ∈ 2 φ 3 ∈ 1 ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the notations are standard and self-explanatory. The vacuum expectation values (VEVs) of the three scalar doublets φ 1,2,3 induce spontaneous electroweak symmetry breaking (SSB).</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Scalar potential and spectrum</head>

				<p>The most general S 3 invariant scalar potential involving three scalar doublet fields is given by [4, 6]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>V = m 2 φ † 1 φ 1 + φ † 2 φ 2 + m 2 3 φ † 3 φ 3 + λ 1 2 φ † 1 φ 1 + φ † 2 φ 2 2 + λ 2 2 φ † 1 φ 1 − φ † 2 φ 2 2 + λ 3 φ † 1 φ 2 φ † 2 φ 1 + λ 4 2 φ † 3 φ 3 ) 2 + λ 5 φ † 3 φ 3 φ † 1 φ 1 + φ † 2 φ 2 + λ 6 φ † 3 φ 1 φ † 1 + φ 2 φ † 2 φ 3 + λ 7 φ † 3 φ 1 φ † 3 φ 2 + λ 8 φ † 3 φ 1 φ † 2 φ 1 + φ 2 φ † 1 φ 2 + h. c. . (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>After SSB, nine degrees of freedom are left: three neutral scalars, two neutral pseudoscalars and two charged scalars with two degrees of freedom each. We denote the VEVs of φ i by v i and assume the λ i &apos;s to be real. For the purpose of generating maximal mixing in the lepton sector, we choose the vacuum alignment v 1 = v 2 = v. Once we solve the tadpole equations, v 1 = v 2 turns out to be an extremal condition if the following relations are satisfied:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>−m 2 = (2λ 1 + λ 3 )v 2 + (λ 5 + λ 6 + λ 7 )v 2 3 + 3λ 8 vv 3 , −m 2 3 = λ 4 v 2 3 + 2(λ 5 + λ 6 + λ 7 )v 2 + 2λ 8 v 3 /v 3 . (3)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>To ensure that the chosen vacuum alignment actually corresponds to a minimum of the potential, we adjust parameters to make sure that the determinant of the Hessian matrix is positive. Just to recall, the Hessian is defined as the square matrix of second order partial derivatives of a function describing its local curvatures. In this case, the function is the scalar potential and the Hessian</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>is just the mass matrix of the scalars. The positivity of the eigenvalues – see later in Eq. (6)</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>– guarantees that the potential is minimized. We note that after SSB, the potential turns out to be a polynomial of order four, and its global stability in the asymptotic limit (i.e. φ i → ∞) is ensured by the following set of conditions:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>λ 1 + λ 2 &gt; 0, λ 1 + λ 3 &gt; λ 2 , λ 4 &gt; 0, λ 5 + λ 6 &gt; 0, λ 7 &gt; 0, λ 8 &gt; 0. (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We now set out to find the spectrum of the three CP-even neutral scalars. We insert the expansion φ 0 i = v i + h i in Eq. (2) to obtain the mass matrix. After its diagonalization the weak basis scalars h 1,2,3 are expressed in terms of the physical scalars h a,b,c as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>h 1 = U 1b h b + U 1c h c − 1 √ 2 h a , h 2 = U 2b h b + U 2c h c + 1 √ 2 h a , (5) h 3 = U 3b h b + U 3c h c ,</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where U ib and U ic are analytically tractable but complicated functions of λ i s, v and v 3 , which we do not display. The condition v 1 = v 2 immediately leads to U 1b = U 2b and U 1c = U 2c . The masses of the three CP-even neutral scalars are</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>m 2 a = 4λ 2 v 2 − 2λ 3 v 2 − v 3 (2λ 7 v 3 + 5λ 8 v) , m 2 b(c) = 1 2v 3 4λ 1 v 2 v 3 + 2λ 3 v 2 v 3 + 2λ 4 v 3 3 − 2λ 8 v 3 + 3λ 8 vv 2 3 ∓ ∆m 3 ; (6) where ∆m 3 = 8vv 3 2vv (i) Since φ 1,2,3 are all weak SU (2) doublets, their VEVs are related as: 2v 2 + v 2 3 = v 2 SM , where v SM ≈ 246 GeV. (ii</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) One of the physical scalars is given by h a = (h 2 − h 1 )/ √ 2, i.e. there is no dependence on λ {1,...,8} or on the VEVs. This happens because S 3 symmetry requires the scalar mass matrix to be of the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>  a b c b a c c c d   , which always yields (−1, 1, 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>) as one eigenvector, regardless of the values of a, b, c and d. (iii) We strictly follow Eq. (4) to ensure that the potential is bounded from below. We randomly vary the magnitude of the λ i &apos;s in the range [0, 1], although slightly larger (but &lt; 4π) values of |λ i | would have still kept the couplings perturbative. We accept a given set of {λ 1 , . . . , λ 8 , v} only if it satisfies the minimization conditions.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(iv) The difference m 2 c − m 2 b = ∆m 3 /v</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>3 is positive, and when v 3 → 0, i.e. v → v SM , the splitting grows enormously. Since the maximum value of m 2 c is controlled by λ i ≤ 1, m 2 b becomes tachyonic when v 3 → 0. It has been suggested in [4] that with order one Yukawa couplings, the ratio v 3 /v ∼ 0.1 reproduces the correct Cabibbo angle in the quark sector. We require v 3 /v ≥ 0.6 to ensure that m 2 b stays above the accepted limit. Since h b and h c have similar gauge and Yukawa properties, quite different from those of h a (see discussions later), we show the mass splitting (m c − m b ) against m b in Fig. 1</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>(a), and the relation between m b and m a in Fig. 1(b).</figDesc>
					<head>Figure 1:</head>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Results of a random search for allowed scalar masses for a fixed v3/v = 0.6. In the left panel (a), we exhibit the splitting (mc − m b ) for different choices of m b . In the right panel (b), we show the allowed range of ma.</figDesc>

				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Scalar couplings to gauge and matter fields</head>

				<p>The kinetic terms |D µ φ i | 2 (i = 1, 2, 3) yield the couplings of the symmetry basis h i to W ± and Z. Clearly, these couplings are modified by a factor of v i /v SM &lt; 1 compared to their SM expressions. In terms of the mass basis scalars, we observe the following: (i) The coupling of h b to W + W − (or, ZZ) is the corresponding SM coupling multiplied by (2vU 1b + v 3 U 3b ) /v SM and the corresponding factor for h c is (2vU 1c + v 3 U 3c ) /v SM . (ii) The scalar h a does not have h a ZZ or h a W W couplings, unlike the other two scalars. This can be understood as follows. The gauge couplings of h i arise from the linear expansion φ 0 i = v i + h i in the kinetic term. Since v 1 = v 2 = v, the combination (h 1 + h 2 ) will couple to gauge bosons as proportional to v. The orthogonal combination (h 2 − h 1 ) that represents the physical scalar h a – see Eq. (5) and point ii following Eq. (7) – will not have the usual scalar-gauge-gauge vertex. The four-point h 2 a ZZ and h 2 a W W couplings will, however, exist.</p>

				<p>The S 3 invariant Yukawa Lagrangian, where the neutral scalars and the charged leptons/quarks are in their weak basis, is given by (f i &apos;s are the leptonic and g</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>u/d i s are quark Yukawa couplings) L Yuk = f 4 ee c h 3 + f 5 eµ c h 3 + f 1 µ c (µh 2 + τ h 1 ) + f 2 τ c (−µh 2 + τ h 1 ) +g u 4 uu c h 3 + g u 5 uc c h 3 + g u 1 c c (ch 2 + th 1 ) + g u 2 t c (−ch 2 + th 1 ) (8) +g d 4 dd c h 3 + g d 5 ds c h 3 + g d 1 s c (sh 2 + bh 1 ) + g d 2 b c (−sh 2 + bh 1 ) + H. c.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The couplings of h b,c to the quarks and leptons depend on the parameters v, v 3 , λ i and f i (or, g u/d i ), while the couplings of h a to fermions depend only on f i (or, g</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>u/d i</trash>

					<figDesc>). The physical scalar couplings to the mass basis fermions are given by the following Yukawa matrices, displayed for the charged leptons as an example (the structures for the quark sector are similar modulo Cabibbo mixing):</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p><formula>Y ha =   0 0 Y a eLτR 0 0 Y a µLτR Y a τLeR Y a τLµR 0   , Y h b,c =   Y b,c eLeR Y b,c eLµR 0 Y b,c µLeR Y b,c µLµR 0 0 0 Y b,c τLτR   . (9)</formula></p>

				<p>The position of the zeros in the matrices deserves some attention. It turns out that h a,b,c have off-diagonal fermion couplings at tree level due to the absence of any natural flavor conservation [7]. The numerical entries of the Yukawa matrices are intimately tied to the successful reproduction of the quarks&apos; and leptons&apos; masses and mixings. We make three observations at this stage. (i) We admit that unless some S 3 breaking parameters are introduced a successful reproduction of V cb and V ts is problematic [8], and also domain walls will be formed. We do not intend to cover all flavor issues. We simply concentrate on the scalar sector whose Lagrangian is S 3 invariant to start with. (ii) h a couples only off-diagonally and one of the two fermions has to be from the third generation. (iii) h b,c couple diagonally as in the SM, but also possess small, numerically insignificant, off-diagonal couplings involving the first two generations.</p>

				<p>The last two points require further clarification. In a theory with more than one SU (2) Higgs doublet, tree level flavor changing neutral currents (FCNC) generally exist in the scalar sector. For example, they exist in the ordinary &apos;two Higgs doublet model (2HDM)&apos;, but in the supersymmetric standard model they are avoided by the arrangement that one doublet couples only to the up-type fermions and the other to only the down-types. In nonsupersymmetric scenarios, in the absence of any natural flavor conservation, symmetry arguments have been advanced in the context of multi-Higgs models to show that the off-diagonal Yukawa couplings of the neutral scalars are suppressed by their relation to the off-diagonal entries of the Cabibbo-Kobayashi-Maskawa (CKM) matrix [9].</p>

				<p>In the present case, S 3 symmetry, under which both scalars and fermions transform nontrivially, is instrumental in suppressing the off-diagonal couplings. To provide intuitive understanding, we take, as an example, only the two-flavor µ–τ sector together with two neutral scalars h 1 and h 2 . It is not difficult to see that the combination (h 2 − h 1 ), which corresponds to h a , couples only off-diagonally, as mentioned earlier. But the other combination (h 2 + h 1 ), which corresponds to h b,c following Eq. (5), couples only diagonally to physical µ or τ . When we consider the quark sector, µ and τ would be replaced by second and third generation quarks which will have CKM mixing. This will yield off-diagonal entries for h b,c couplings to quarks suppressed by the off-diagonal CKM elements. The same happens for off-diagonal couplings involving the first two generations as well. The tiny size of tree level FCNC rates in an S 3 flavor model has been noticed also earlier, where predictions for Br (τ → 3µ), Br (K L → 2e) and Br (B s → 2µ) have been given [10]. In some setups where the fermion transformations under S 3 are not appropriately adjusted, the off-diagonal Yukawa couplings may become order one which induce sizable neutral scalar mediated rare processes, like K L → µe or K L → 2π, at tree level. This requires those neutral scalars to lie beyond several TeV [6, 11]. But in our case, once we adjust the f i /g u,d i &apos;s to reproduce the fermion masses and mixing, the off-diagonal Yukawa couplings are determined too. The largest of them corresponds to ¯ c L t R h a , which is about 0.8. The second largest off-diagonal coupling is that for ¯ s L b R h a , and is about 0.02. The next in line is ¯ µ L τ R h a , whose coefficient is about 0.008. The others are orders of magnitude smaller, and are of no numerical significance. Although FCNC processes like B d – ¯ B d and B s – ¯ B s mixings proceed at tree level, the contributions are adequately suppressed even for light scalar mediators.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Collider signatures</head>

				<p>The perturbativity condition |λ i | ≤ 1 and the requirement m b/c ≥ 114 GeV (for which we set v 3 /v ≃ 0.6) yields m b in the neighbourhood of 120 GeV and m c within 400 GeV – see the scatter plots in Fig. 1. Both h b and h c would decay into the usual ZZ, W W , b ¯ b, γγ, · · · modes, but the dominant decay mode of h b (or h c ) for the case of m a &lt; m b /2 (or m a &lt; m c /2) would be into h a h a . Recall that the existing limits on the Higgs mass depend crucially on the gauge coupling of the Higgs. Since h a ZZ or h a W W couplings are nonexistent, the mass of h a is unconstrained, i.e. m a can be lower than 114 GeV or larger than 200 GeV. We numerically calculate the strength of the h b h a h a coupling from the set of acceptable parameters characterizing the potential, and introduce a parameter k which is the ratio of the h b h a h a coupling and the h b W W coupling. The magnitude of k depends on the choice of λ i and v 3 . Assuming m a = 50 GeV, we obtain k in the range of (5 − 30). Just to compare with a 2HDM [12] for illustration, the corresponding k value, when the heavier Higgs weighing around 400 GeV decays into two lighter Higgs weighing 114 GeV each, is about 10.</p>

				<p>In</p>

				<p>Fig. 2(a) we have plotted the branching ratio of h b → h a h a as a function of m b for two representative values m a = 50,75 GeV, and for k ∼ 5 and 30, which correspond to the smallest and largest k obtained from the set of accepted scalar parameters. We observe that till the W W or ZZ decay modes open up, the branching ratio h b → h a h a is almost 100%. To calculate the decay widths into the usual modes (other than h a h a ), we have used HDECAY [13] by appropriately modifying the gauge and Yukawa couplings.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>As Fig. 2</head>

				<p>(b) suggests, as long as m a &lt; m t , h a will dominantly decay into jets, and one of them can be identified as the b-jet. The branching ratio of h a → µ¯ τ is, nevertheless, not negligible (about 0.1). As shown in Fig. 2(c), for m a ≪ m t , the branching ratio of t → h a c is quite sizable, which falls with increasing m a . It may be possible to reconstruct h a from h a → µ¯ τ . In fact, a light h a would be copiously produced from the top decay at the LHC. On the other hand, if m a &gt; m t , as can be seen again from Fig. 2(b), h a decays to t¯ c with an almost 100% branching ratio.</p>

				<p>If k is large, then there is an interesting twist to the failed Higgs search at LEP-2. In this case, h b → h a h a would overwhelm h b → b ¯ b, and hence the conventional search for the SM-like scalar (h b , as the lighter between h b and h c ) would fail. This is similar to what happens in the next-to-minimal supersymmetric models, when the lightest scalar would dominantly decay into two pseudoscalars, and each pseudoscalar would then decay into 2b or 2τ final states. In view of these possible 4b or 4τ Higgs signals, LEP data have been reanalyzed putting constraints on the Higgs production cross section times the decay branching ratios [14, 15]. The possibility of the Higgs cascade decays into 4j (j = quark/gluon), 2j + 2 photons and 4 photons has been studied too [16, 17]. From a study of 4b final states, a limit m h &gt; 110 GeV (for a SM-like Higgs) has been obtained [16]. From all other cascade decays the limit on m h will be considerably weaker. Our h a has the special feature that it has only off-diagonal Yukawa couplings involving one third-family fermion. If h b is lighter than the top quark, it would decay as h b → h a h a → 2b + 2j, and into b + 1j + µ + τ , the latter constituting a spectacular signal with two different lepton flavors µ and τ . The standard 2b and cascade 4b decay searches are not sensitive to our final states, and so a value of m b much lighter than 110 GeV is not ruled out.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Conclusions</head>

				<p>The discrete flavor symmetry S 3 , besides successfully reproducing fermion masses and mixing, provides an extended Higgs sector having unconventional decay properties. We assume all the couplings to be real, and do not deal with the possibility of CP violation in this paper. The potential has been minimized requiring maximal mixing for the atmospheric neutrinos. In our setup, there are two scalars which are SM Higgs like, except that each of them can have a dominant decay into the third (h b,c → h a h a ). The latter, i.e. h a , has no h a V V -type gauge interactions, and has only flavor off-diagonal Yukawa couplings with one fermion from the third generation. It is not unlikely that by evading the conventional search strategies, both h b and h a are already buried in the existing LEP and Tevatron data. In this analysis we have not dealt with the two pseudoscalars, which we leave for a future study. We urge our experimental colleagues to look for our suggested signals at the LHC, and perhaps also reanalyze the existing collider data.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1 110 130 150 170 190 Γ b-&gt;aa / Γ tot m b [GeV] k 50 = 29.4 k 75 = 29.4 k 50 = 5.2 k 75 = 6.1 (a) m a = 50 GeV m a = 75 GeV 1e-06 1e-05 0.0001 0.001 0.01 0.1 1 50 100 150 200 250 300 Branching ratios for h a m a [GeV] (b) µτ c sb c ct c 0.01 0.1 1 20 60 100 140 Branching ratio for t → h a c m a [GeV]</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(c) Figure 2: (a) Branching ratio of h b → haha for two representative values of ma, and in each case for smallest / largest values of k in the set of accepted scalar parameters which compares the strength of the h b haha coupling to the strength of h b W W coupling; (b) branching ratios for the decay of ha, and (c) branching ratio of the top quark decay into ha and charm quark.</p>

				<p>IST-Lisbon, LPT-Orsay, and ICTP-Trieste, at different stages of this work. H.P. was supported by DFG Grant No. PA 803/6-1. P.L. and H.P. were also supported by the Physics at the Terascale Helmholtz Alliance Working Group: Neutrino masses and Lepton Flavor Violation at the LHC, and they acknowledge hospitality at the Saha Institute of Nuclear Physics, Kolkata, during a part of this collaboration.</p>

			</div>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> 3 2(λ 5 + λ 6 + λ 7 ) 2 − λ 4 (2λ 1 + λ 3 ) + 2λ 8 v 4 (2λ 1 + λ 3 ) − 3λ 4 λ 8 v 4 3 + 12λ 8 v 2 v 2 3 (λ 5 + λ 6 + λ 7 ) + 12λ 2 8 v 3 v 3 + 2v 2 v 3 (2λ 1 + λ 3 ) + 2λ 4 v 3 3 − 2λ 8 v 3 + 3λ 8 vv 2 3 2 1 2 . (7) A few things are worth noting at this stage:</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
				<figure>
					<head>Acknowledgments:</head>
					<figDesc>We thank M. Frigerio for useful discussions. This work was supported by DAAD-DST PPP Grant No. D/08/04933, and DST-DAAD project No. INT/DAAD/P-181/2008. G.B. acknowledges hospitality at T.U. Dortmund,</figDesc>
				</figure>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ma, arXiv:0705.0327 [hep-ph]; G. Altarelli and F. Feruglio</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Ishimori</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Kobayashi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Ohki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Shimizu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Okada</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Tanimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New J. Phys. Rev. Mod. Phys. Prog. Theor. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2701" to="1" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl. . 183. hep. -th]]</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pakvasa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Sugawara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">61</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">[arXiv:hep-ph</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Phys</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R N</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Mohap-Atra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Perez-Lorenzana</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>De Sousa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">F</forename>
				<surname>Pires</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<forename type="middle">G</forename>
				<surname>Har-Rison</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="middle">R N</forename>
				<surname>Scott</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Mohapatra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Nasri</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Yu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Grimus and L. Lavoura, JHEP 0508</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Ma</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="033012" to="2761" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>arXiv. :hep-ph/0605020]; S. Morisi and M. Picariello</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Chen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Frigerio</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Ma</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="073008" to="079905" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">R</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N</forename>
				<surname>Mohapatra</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<surname>Senjanovic</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">912</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kubo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Okada</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Sakamaki</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">036007</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Glashow</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Weinberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1958</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>Z. z. Xing, D. Yang and S. Zhou</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">690</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">304</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Botella</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">C</forename>
				<surname>Branco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">N C</forename>
				<surname>Rebelo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">W</forename>
				<surname>Branco</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Grimus</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Lavoura</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B Phys. Lett. B</title>
		<editor>A. S. Joshipura and S. D. Rindani</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">687</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">260</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">149</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kubo</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Mondragon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Mondragon</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Rodriguez-Jauregui</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Prog. Theor. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">287</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">795</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">Y</forename>
				<surname>Yamanaka</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Sugawara</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Pakvasa</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1895" to="2135" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Lopez-Val</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Sola</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">033003</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Djouadi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kalinowski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Spira</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Phys. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1089704448</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">56</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ALEPH Collaboration and DELPHI Collaboration and L3 Collaboration and OPAL Collaborations and LEP Working Group for Higgs Boson Searches]</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Schael</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">JHEP 1005</title>
		<editor>15] S. Schael et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">049</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>hep. -ex]]</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Chang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Fox</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<surname>Weiner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">068</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Chang</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Fox</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Weiner</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">111802</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
