<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:///home/joseph/Desktop/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/rng/Grobid.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Rolling tachyons for separated brane-antibrane systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2014-07-07">7 Jul 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Dan</forename>
								<surname>Israël</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institut d&apos;Astrophysique de Paris</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>98bis Bd Arago</addrLine>
									<postCode>75014</postCode>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName>
								<forename type="first">Flavien</forename>
								<surname>Kiefer</surname>
							</persName>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="department">Institut d&apos;Astrophysique de Paris</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>98bis Bd Arago</addrLine>
									<postCode>75014</postCode>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Normale Supéieure</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>24rueLhomond</addrLine>
									<postCode>75231, cedex05</postCode>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UnitémixtedeRecherche7095</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS–UniversitéPierreetMarieCurie</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">UnitémixtedeRechercheduCNRSetdel&apos;</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">UMR8549</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">EcoleNormaleSupérieureassociéèal&apos;UniversitéPierreetMarieCurie</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Rolling tachyons for separated brane-antibrane systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2014-07-07">7 Jul 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>†</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We consider tachyon condensation between a D-brane and an anti-D-brane in superstring theory, when they are separated in their common transverse directions. A simple rolling tachyon solution, that describes the time evolution of the process, is studied from the point of view of boundary conformal field theory. By computing the boundary beta-functions of the system, one finds that this theory is conformal, hence corresponds to an exact solution of the string theory equations of motion. By contrast, the time-reversal-symmetric rolling tachyon is not conformal. These results put constraints on the space-time effective actions for the system.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
			<div>
				<head n="1">Introduction</head>

				<p>Annihilation of D-branes of opposite Ramond-Ramond charge is one of the fundamental processes of string theory. Tachyon condensation on brane-antibrane systems has also important cosmological applications, either as a tractable model of a time-dependent process in string theory, or concretely in D-brane inflation models [1]. It also appears in holographic models of QCD, to describe chiral symmetry breaking [2]. Whenever the distance between the branes is smaller than the critical value r c , the ground state in the brane-antibrane open string sectors becomes tachyonic. It has been conjectured long ago that the condensation of this complex-valued tachyon leads to the closed string vacuum, corresponding to the minimum of the tachyon potential [3], and partially confirmed by string field theory computations [4].</p>

				<p>In the case where the brane and the anti-brane are coincident in their common transverse directions, this system has been thoroughly studied using background-independent string field theory (BSFT) [5, 6, 7]. In this approach, one considers the two-dimensional worldsheet conformal field theory on the disk with marginal and relevant boundary perturbations. It allows to compute the exact off-shell tree-level tachyon potential [8, 9].</p>

				<p>On-shell configurations corresponding to real-time tachyon condensation on unstable Dbranes are also of interest, especially whenever the boundary conformal field theory (BCFT) is known. For unstable D-branes, a first type of solution, known as the full S-brane was found by Sen and represents a time-reversal symmetric process [10]. The second type of solution, known as the half S-brane [11, 12], represents the more realistic case of a tachyon starting, from t → −∞, at the maximum of its potential. It is straightforward to extend these results to coincident brane-antibrane pairs. Although the gradient of the tachyon field on the rolling tachyon solutions is very large, it should make sense to consider a spacetime effective action that describes slowly varying perturbations thereof. Remarkably, as was shown by Kutasov and Niarchos [13], it is possible to find unambiguously the effective action for the tachyon and its first derivative asking only that (i) the rolling tachyon discussed above is a solution to its equations of motion and that (ii) the on-shell Lagrangian on this solution is equal to the disk partition function with the time-like zero mode unintegrated. Upon a simple field redefinition, it coincides also with the &quot; tachyon-DBI &quot; action that was earlier proposed by Garousi [14], 1 and is able to reproduce correctly N-point tachyon amplitudes [17]. 2 Surprisingly, not much of this program has been carried out for the system of a D-brane and an anti-D-brane at finite distance – letting aside the even more interesting and challenging case of brane-antibrane scattering. The brane separation is a modulus at tree-level, even though a brane-antibrane potential is generated at one string loop [19]. Hence, we can ask whether tachyon condensation at fixed separation is possible. One may expect different spacetime physics compared to the coincident case, especially in the limit where the absolute value of the tachyon mass is small in string units. With cubic string field theory, an approximation of the tachyon potential as a function of the fixed brane-antibrane separation r has been computed few years ago using level truncation at next-to-leading order in [20]. In BSFT, the framework for studying the T-dual configuration – a brane-antibrane pair compactified along a worldvolume direction, with a relative</p>

				<p>Wilson line – was set in the works [21] and [22]. There, the worldsheet action of the system, including the background spacetime gauge fields along with the complex tachyon, was set. Unfortunately, the Abelian gauge field T-dual to r was set to zero in order to simplify the path integral computation. 1 Finally, the &apos;half S-brane&apos; rolling tachyon solution describing condensation at fixed, finite distance is not really understood, let alone the effective action of which it should be a solution. In [20] this problem was studied using conformal perturbation theory, which is expected to be valid, in spacetime terms, for very early times at the onset of tachyon condensation.</p>

				<p>Surprisingly, it was found that the boundary interaction corresponding to the rolling tachyon ceases to be marginal for a countable set of values of |r| larger than r c / √ 2.</p>

				<p>In this note, we show that, taking in particular into account the effect of contact terms that are dictated by worldsheet supersymmetry, the rolling tachyon boundary interaction seems to be exactly marginal for all values of |r| below the critical separation. Study of betafunctions for the system illuminates the crucial role of the contact term. The latter is able to cancel the power-like short distance singularity that arises at second order in perturbation theory for |r| &gt; 1/2. At fourth order, it cancels all but one power-like singularity that is present for |r| &gt; √ 7/4, for which an higher-order contact term is needed. Nevertheless, the potentially dangerous logarithmic singularities, that could occur for certain values of |r|, vanish by themselves without the help of the contact term.</p>

				<p>We find that the beta-functions of the theory are zero to all orders for |r| &lt; √ 17/6, while for larger values of |r| they vanish at least up to order five in perturbation theory. Thus, we expect that the perturbative expansion in the boundary tachyon perturbations does not break conformal invariance on the boundary, for any sub-critical separation. Unexpectedly, we find that the &apos;full S-brane&apos; rolling tachyon is not a boundary conformal field theory, for any non-zero separation between the branes. In that case the beta-function for the distance-changing boundary operator does not vanish. It implies that the corresponding space-time tachyon profile is not a solution of the equations of motion. It seems nevertheless that a more general solution than the &apos;half S-brane&apos; exists, for which the tachyon starts from and comes back to the tachyon vacuum; its physical meaning is not obvious though, since the phase of the complex tachyon cannot stay constant. From these results we learn that there should exist a space-time effective action for the system, that is valid for any 0 |r| &lt; r c (to be more precise, the effective action for the tachyon and distance field should admit a solution where the distance is a constant). Effective actions were proposed in the past by Sen [24] and Garousi [25]. However its domain of validity is not clear. Indeed, it does not allow as a solution a tachyon condensation at fixed distance, even in the regime of small brane separation in string units.</p>

				<p>Imposing the existence of the &apos;half S-brane&apos; solution at fixed distance fixes the effective action up to second order in the tachyon field. In order to get the fully explicit effective action around this rolling tachyon at fixed distance without further hypothesis, we can proceed as in [13] and try to fix all the coefficients of a generic first-order Lagrangian expressed in power series. It fails to give a single answer for two reasons. First, as the &apos;full S-brane&apos; solution seems not be allowed, the constraints from the tachyon equations of motion are weaker. Second, we would need to compute the disk partition function, to all orders in the tachyon coupling; for a generic distance analytical results for the perturbative integrals seem out of reach, from the fourth order. This work is organized as follows. In section 2 we give some background on the braneantibrane worldsheet action on the disk, emphasizing the role of the Fermi multiplets that realize the Chan-Patton degrees of freedom. In section 3 we discuss the role of contact terms in canceling the divergences that arises when tachyon perturbations collide. In section 4 we examine the system from the point of view of boundary renormalization group flow, and obtain our main results about the marginality of the rolling tachyon profile. Finally in the discussion we give the implications of our results for space-time effective actions. Some lengthy computations are given in the appendices.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2">Brane-antibrane worldsheet action</head>

				<p>In this section we discuss in detail the boundary worldsheet action of the brane/antibrane system, and set our conventions.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="2.1">Superspace action on the disk</head>

				<p>As a starting point, one considers the worldsheet action for coincident D1-brane and anti-D1- brane wrapped around a circle in a compactified direction Y , T-dual to the system of interest. We set everywhere in the following α ′ = 1. The N = (1, 1) superspace action on the disk was written in [26, 21, 22], including the coupling to background gauge and tachyon fields. In the present context one considers nontrivial Wilson Lines along the circle, T-dual to the brane positions x 1 and x 2 along X, the T-dual of Y . They naturally appear in the form x (±) = x 1 ± x 2 .</p>

				<p>Setting aside the &apos;spectator&apos; dimensions, one considers a pair of N = (1, 1) superfields on the disk, one time-like (X 0 ) and the other compactified on a circle (Y), with e.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>g. X 0 = X 0 + i √ 2 (θψ 0 + ¯ θ ¯ ψ 0 ) + θ ¯ θF 0 .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The superspace coordinates are denoted as z = (z, θ, ¯ θ). At the boundary of the disk, the Grassmann coordinates satisfy the boundary condition θ = ± ¯ θ. The algebra of the Chan-Patton factors for the brane-antibrane system is conveniently implemented by the canonical quantization of boundary fermions [27], see below. These boundary fermions are the bottom components of Fermi superfields of the boundary N = 1 superspace. For the brane-antibrane system one needs a complex superfield</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ ± = η ± + θF ± . (1) with Γ − = (Γ + ) * .</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Then the worldsheet action on the disk 1 , including the tachyon background as well as Wilson lines around the circle, reads:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BCFT (λ + , λ − ) = 1 2π D 2 d 2 z d 2 θ −DX 0 ¯ DX 0 + DY ¯ DY + i S 1 du dθ x (+) 4π D u Y − S 1 du dθ Γ + D u + i x (−) 2π D u Y Γ − − Γ + T + − Γ − T − , (2)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with the measure d 2 θ = dθ d ¯ θ, the superspace holomorphic derivative D = ∂ θ + θ∂ and the superspace boundary derivative D u = ∂ θ + θ∂ u , with the boundary coordinate u on S 1 . 1 We consider simple rolling tachyon profiles of the form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T ± = λ ± 2π e ωX 0 , (3) with 0 &lt; ω 1 / √ 2.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In order to get a real action, one chooses (λ + ) * = λ − . These are actually the tachyons that we are expecting to be solutions of the spacetime effective action. It is understood in this expression that the superfield X is taken on the (super)boundary of the disk. The space-time gauge field A (−) = − x (−) 4π dy being locally pure gauge, its minimal coupling to the Fermi superfields can be absorbed by a &apos;gauge&apos; transformation. 2 One has to be careful with this transformation if Y-dependent insertions appear in the path-integral; a prescription must be chosen (see below).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ ± → Γ ± e ±i x (−) 2π Y . (4)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>After this field redefinition, the boundary Fermi superfields are free, with the propagator on the real axis:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Γ + (ˆ z)Γ − ( ˆ w) = ˆ ǫ(ˆ z − ˆ w) = ǫ(z − w) − 2 θ z θ w δ(z − w) , (5)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with the sign function ǫ(z) = Θ(z) − Θ(−z). This implies that ∆(Γ ± ) = 0, i.e. vanishing conformal dimension.</p>

				<p>In terms of these new variables the worldsheet action (2) reads:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BCF T (λ + , λ − ) = 1 2π D 2 d 2 z d 2 θ −DX 0 ¯ DX 0 + DY ¯ DY + i S 1 du dθ x (+) 4π D u Y − S 1 du dθ Γ + DΓ − − Γ + T + − Γ − T − (6) where the tachyon fields have now the expression: T ± = λ ± 2π e ±i x (−) 2π Y+ωX 0 . (7)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Conformal invariance of the action at leading order imposes then :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ω 2 + x (−) 2π 2 = 1 2 . (8)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is the standard mass-shell condition of an open string tachyon with U (1) × U (1) Wilson lines turned on. The world-sheet action that describes a system of separated brane and anti-brane is obtained from the previous one by a T-duality along y. In the bulk, the superfield Y is traded for the superfield X that has Dirichlet boundary conditions. Renaming Y as X, the tachyon interaction of interest reads</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T ± = λ ± 2π e ±i x (−) 2π X+ωX 0 . (9)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Action (6) will be our starting point. In the free theory, one has two different boundary conditions on the disk boundary, related to the distinct positions of the branes : X = x (1) or Y = x (2) . We introduce the notations</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x (−) = x (1) − x (2) = 2πr x (+) = x (1) + x (2) = 2x cm , (10)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where on the first line r is such that ω 2 + r 2 = 1/2. On the second line, x cm is simply the center of mass coordinate of the system.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>2.2</head>

				<p>Action in components, quantization of the Fermi superfields</p>

				<p>Starting from the action (6), renaming Y as X, and integrating over the fermionic coordinates one gets the action:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S BCFT (λ + , λ − ) = 1 2π D 2 d 2 z −∂X 0 ¯ ∂X 0 + ∂X ¯ ∂X + i S 1 du x (+) 4π ∂ u ˜ X + S 1 du η + ∂ u η − − λ + 2π η + ψ + T + − λ − 2π η − ψ − T − − S 1 du F + F − − F + T + − F − T − , (11) with: ψ ± = ±ir √ 2 ˜ ψ x + ω √ 2ψ 0 T ± = e ±ir X+ωX 0 . (12) Auxiliary fields F ± are then integrated to give: S BCFT (λ + , λ − ) = 1 2π D 2 d 2 z −∂X 0 ¯ ∂X 0 + ∂X ¯ ∂X + i S 1 du x (+) 4π ∂ u ˜ X + S 1 du η + ∂ u η − − λ + 2π η + ψ + T + − λ − 2π η − ψ − T − + ε 1−4r 2 λ + λ − 4π 2 T + T − . (13)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A contact term at the end of the second line shows up, with a UV cutoff ε. This term, that does not follow from the equations of motion contributes nevertheless to correlation functions when 1/2 &lt; |r| &lt; 1/ √ 2. Its role will be discussed in section 3.3.</p>

				<p>Finally, as the center-of-mass perturbation completely factorizes and commutes with any operators in (13), one can set x (+) = 0 without loss of generality.</p>

				<p>Upon quantizing canonically the boundary fermions η ± , one recovers the Chan-Patton algebra corresponding to the brane-antibrane system [22]. It leads to the following identifica- tions:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>η + ⇔ σ + = σ 1 + iσ 2 2 η − ⇔ σ − = σ 1 − iσ 2 2 η + η − (z) ⇔ [σ + , σ − ] 2 = σ 3 2 (14)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where now the prescription for the path integral is Z = Tr DX i Dψ i P e −S[X i ,ψ i ] , which includes a path ordering for the operator insertions and a trace over the CP factors. In this context the tachyon becomes a boundary changing operator; when inserted on the boundary of the disk, it interpolates between the two distinct boundary conditions corresponding to the brane and to the anti-brane. The worldsheet action on the disk takes finally the form</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = S bulk − S 1 du λ + 2π σ + ⊗ ψ + e ir X+ωX 0 + λ − 2π σ − ⊗ ψ − e −ir X+ωX 0 − λ + λ − 4π 2 ε 1−4r 2 e 2ωX 0 . (15)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3">Perturbative integrals and contact terms</head>

				<p>In this section we discuss in more detail the contact term, quadratic in the tachyon field, that appear in the action (6) after integrating out the auxiliary fields from the Fermi superfields Γ ± , and quantizing their fermionic components. As was discussed long ago by Green and Seiberg [28] for closed string correlation functions, contact terms, dictated by worldsheet supersymmetry, can cancel unphysical divergences in correlation functions. We shall see below that it indeed cancels the short-distance singularity when two tachyons perturbations collide in the perturbative expansion.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.1">Free field correlators</head>

				<p>In order to fix the conventions, we use the following Green functions on the upper half-plane H + for a free-field X with Dirichlet boundary conditions, and its T-dual field X:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>X(z 1 )X(z 2 ) = − η xx 2 ln |z 12 | 2 + η xx 2 ln |z 1 ¯ 2 | 2 ˜ X(z 1 ) ˜ X(z 2 ) = − η xx 2 ln |z 12 | 2 − η xx 2 ln |z 1 ¯ 2 | 2 X(z 1 ) ˜ X(z 2 ) = − η xx 2 ln z 12 z¯ 1 ¯ 2 − η xx 2 ln z 1 ¯ 2 z¯ 12 (16) with eg. z 12 = z 1 − z 2 and z 1 ¯ 2 = z 1 − ¯ z 2 . Finally, the two-point function for fermions with Dirichlet b.c. read: ψ x (z 1 )ψ x (z 2 ) = η xx z 1 − z 2 (17a) ¯ ψ x (¯ z 1 ) ¯ ψ x (¯ z 2 ) = η xx ¯ z 1 − ¯ z 2 (17b) ψ x (z 1 ) ¯ ψ x (¯ z 2 ) = − ζη xx z 1 − ¯ z 2 (17c)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where ζ = ±1 corresponds to the spin structure. It corresponds to the boundary conditions for the supercurrent G(z) − ζ ¯ G(¯ z)| z=¯ z = 0. For the Virasoro superfield G = G + θT , this is naturally associated with the superspace boundary (z, θ) = (¯ z, ζ ¯ θ).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>With Neumann b.c., eq. (17c) gets a minus sign on the RHS. Finally, the boundary Green function for a superfield X with Neumann boundary conditions reads: X(ˆ z 1 )X(ˆ z 2 ) ℑz=0,θ=ζ ¯ θ = −2η xx ln z 12 = −2η xx ln(z 12 − θ 1 θ 2 ) (18) while it vanishes with Dirichlet b.c.. 3.2 Contact term in the worldsheet action</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As has been explicited in section (2.2), upon integrating out the auxiliary fields F ± that appear in the Fermi multiplets Γ ± , one obtains a contact term for the tachyon in the worldsheet action.</p>

				<p>The auxiliary field has the two-point function F + (u)F − (v) = 2δ(u − v). It is regularized at short distances according to:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>F + (t)F − (s) = 2δ(t − s) → δ(|t − s| − ε) (19)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It was shown in [30] that this point-splitting regularization that we use preserves worldsheet supersymmetry (unless one consider bulk-boundary correlators for which more care is needed). Then the contact term is given by the following non-local interaction on the disk (with u = e it , v = e is )</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>: 1 2 2π 0 dt 2π 0 ds δ(|t − s| − ε) ⋆ ⋆ e ir X+ωX 0 (u) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ e −ir X+ωX 0 (v) ⋆ ⋆ = 1 2 2π 0 dt 2π 0 ds δ(|t − s| − ε) |u − v| 2(ω 2 −r 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ e ir X+ωX 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>(u) e −ir X+ωX 0 (v) ⋆ ⋆ = 1 2 2 sin ε 2 1−4r 2 2π 0 ds ⋆ ⋆ e ir X+ωX 0 (v+ε) e −ir X+ωX 0 (v)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>⋆ ⋆ + ⋆ ⋆ e ir X+ωX 0 (v) e −ir X+ωX 0 (v+ε) ⋆ ⋆ ε→0 ∼ ε 1−4r 2 S 1 du ⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (u) ⋆ ⋆ . (20) By ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>we denote the boundary normal ordering (see e.g. [29]). 1 This treatment of the contact term may seem a bit ad hoc, however we will find in the next section that the term (20) appears naturally when one considers the renormalisation of the worldsheet action, justifying a posteriori this presentation. We will use in a next section the contact term on the upper half plane. It is similarly written as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ε 1−4r 2 2 +∞ −∞ dv ⋆ ⋆ e ir X+ωX 0 (v + ε) e −ir X+ωX 0 (v) ⋆ ⋆ + ⋆ ⋆ e ir X+ωX 0 (v) e −ir X +ωX 0 (v + ε) ⋆ ⋆ ε→0 ∼ ε 1−4r 2 R dv ⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (v) ⋆ ⋆ (21)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In order to compute all the counterterms generated from this contact term one will need to work with its complete non-local expression, though the dominant term, here the only divergent one, in its Taylor expansion (in terms of local operators) is sufficient to compute most of them. Indeed, it is found that working directly with the dominant term, a local operator, seems to be equivalent to working with the complete non-local contact term.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>It may be explained by the fact that after Taylor expansion of T ± (x + ǫ) and commutation of the sum and the integral, all other terms in the series of integrated local operators vanish as ǫ goes to zero.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>One may object that we are forgetting sub-dominant terms, but, as the UV cut-off is an artifact signaling our lack of ability to manipulate infinite quantities; it is to be understood as being strictly equal to zero, from the very beginning. From this point of view, we expect that only the divergent terms in (21) do contribute. Then it should be equivalent to use either the dominant (local) term or the complete (non-local) contact term. This statement seems to be confirmed numerically in the fourth order computations of section 4. As one can see, in the limit ε → 0 when one takes the UV cut-off to infinity, the contact term vanishes when |r| &lt; 1/2. Therefore, the results of the computations made in [24], where the contact term was not taken into account, remain unchanged. 1 It can be seen also by working directly with the N = 1 boundary superspace amplitudes; the contact terms contributions from the Γ ± correlators vanish for |r| &lt; 1/2. However, the contact term diverges when |r| &gt; 1/2. This contact term may ensure that the amplitudes do not diverge for |r| &gt; 1/2. The divergence associated with the contact term, that arises from the fusion of two tachyon vertices, correspond to the unphysical integrated vertex operator du dθ θ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (u)⋆ ⋆ = du ⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (u)⋆ ⋆ , (22)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>that is not supersymmetric. Hence, as in [28], one can understand the contact term as necessary to preserve worldsheet superconformal invariance on the boundary, when |r| &gt; 1/2.</p>

				<p>In other words, divergences corresponding to integrated operators of the form (22) cannot occur for a consistent, hence super-BRST invariant, superstring worldsheet theory. We will discuss below higher-order divergences, coming from the fusion of more than two operators, for which the analysis is more involved.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="3.3">Boundary one-point function</head>

				<p>In order to illustrate more precisely the role of the contact term, we compute the one-point function on the disk for a tachyon boundary vertex operator. This one-point function does not have to vanish because of the rolling tachyon background, and contains potentially a divergence at first order, when the inserted tachyon vertex collides with the integrated tachyon coming from the perturbative expansion. We will find that the contact term cancels the twotachyon divergence for all values of r in the range 1/2 &lt; |r| 1/ √ 2. At first order in the couplings λ ± , the one-point function for one of the boundary tachyon vertex operators is given by the integrated correlator</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Tr σ ± ⊗ ψ ± e ±ir X+ωX 0 (e it 1 ) ∼ λ ∓ 2π Tr σ ± σ ∓ t 1 0 dt 2 ψ ± e ±ir X+ωX 0 (e it 1 ) ψ ∓ e ∓ir X+ωX 0 (e it 2 ) 0 + λ ∓ 2π Tr σ ∓ σ ± 2π t 1 dt 2 ψ ∓ e ∓ir X+ωX 0 (e it 2 ) ψ ± e ±ir X+ωX 0 (e it 1 ) 0 ∼ λ ∓ 2π 1 − 4r 2 t 1 +2π t 1 dt 2 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 2ω 2 −2r 2 −1 +∞ −∞ dx 0 e 2ωx 0 . (23) The integration over t 2 is not defined for |r| &gt; 1/2, nevertheless the result Tr σ ± ⊗ ψ ± e ±ir X+ωX 0 (e it 1 ) ∼ λ ∓ 2π 1 − 4r 2 2 1−4r 2 √ π Γ( 1 2 − 2r 2 ) Γ(1 − 2r 2 ) +∞ −∞ dx 0 e 2 1 2 −r 2 x 0 (24)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>is analytic for any r ∈ [0, 1/ √ 2] In order to show how the divergence for |r| &gt; 1/2 is canceled, we can compute directly this quantity in superspace, using the Fermi multiplets Γ ± . Letting aside for a moment the zero-mode integral over x 0 , one considers the superspace integral</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dθ 1 Γ ± e ±ir X+ωX 0 (ˆ z 1 ) ∼ − λ ∓ 2π dθ 1 dθ 2 dt 2 ǫ(ˆ z 1 − ˆ z 2 ) e ±ir X+ωX 0 (ˆ z 1 )e ∓ir X+ωX 0 (ˆ z 2 ) 0 ∼ − λ ∓ 2π e 2ωx 0 dθ 1 dθ 2 dt 2 [ǫ(t 1 − t 2 ) − 2θ 1 θ 2 δ(t 1 − t 2 )] × × 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 1−4r 2 − θ 1 θ 2 (1 − 4r 2 )ǫ(t 1 − t 2 ) 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 −4r 2 ∼ − λ ∓ 2π e 2ωx 0 dt 2 (1 − 4r 2 ) 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 −4r 2 + 2δ(t 1 − t 2 ) 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 1−4r 2 . (25)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Now we introduce a point splitting regularization, asking that |t 1 − t 2 | &gt; ε. As we wish to keep the contact term in the computation, it is natural to include this point splitting in the Θ and δ distributions that appear in the above integral, as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Θ(|t 1 − t 2 | − ε) = Θ(t 1 − t 2 − ε) + Θ(t 2 − t 1 − ε) δ(|t 1 − t 2 | − ε) = δ(t 1 − t 2 − ε) + δ(t 2 − t 1 − ε) . (26)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In other words, we &apos;spread&apos; the contact term at the boundary of the interval |t 1 − t 2 | &lt; ε. Then the contribution to the one point-function becomes:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− λ ∓ 2π dt 2 (1 − 4r 2 )Θ(|t 1 − t 2 | − ε) 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 −4r 2 + δ(|t 1 − t 2 | − ε) 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 1−4r 2 = − λ ∓ 2π (1 − 4r 2 ) t 1 −ε t 1 −2π+ε dt 2 2 sin t 1 − t 2 2 −4r 2 − 2 λ ∓ 2π 2 sin ε 2 1−4r 2 ∼ − λ ∓ 2π 1 − 4r 2 2 1−4r 2 √ π Γ( 1 2 − 2r 2 ) Γ(1 − 2r 2 ) + 2 λ ∓ 2π ε 1−4r 2 − 2 λ ∓ 2π 2 sin ε 2 1−4r 2 , (27)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where two first terms in the last line come from the expansion of the following function:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 − 4r 2 2 2−4r 2 cos ε 2 2 F 1 1 2 , 1 + 4r 2 2 , 3 2 , cos 2 ε 2 . (28)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The second term of eq. (27) is the only divergent one if 4r 2 &gt; 1. It simplifies to</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− λ ∓ 2π 1 − 4r 2 2 1−4r 2 √ π Γ( 1 2 − 2r 2 ) Γ(1 − 2r 2 ) + 2 λ ∓ 2π ε 1−4r 2 − 2 λ ∓ 2π ε 1−4r 2 . (29)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Divergences compensate correctly, so that we eventually have at first order:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Tr σ ± ⊗ ψ ± − F ± e ±ir X+ωX 0 (z 1 ) ∼ −λ ∓ Γ(2 − 4r 2 ) Γ 2 (1 − 2r 2 ) +∞ −∞ dx 0 e 2 1 2 −r 2 x 0 . (30)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This quantity is UV-finite, but has a IR divergence due to the zero-mode integral. This divergence, that appears when x 0 → ∞, simply signals the breakdown of perturbation theory in λ ± . Note that for the homogeneous rolling tachyon on a non-BPS brane, for which the all orders computation is doable, summing up the the whole perturbative expansion gives a finite zero-mode integral. 1</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4">Computation of beta-functions</head>

				<p>In this section, we argue that the theory defined in (6) is exactly conformal, with the rolling tachyon profile (9), for any value of |r| below r c = 1/ √ 2. This will imply that for the spacetime effective action of the brane-antibrane system there exists a &apos;half S-brane&apos; rolling tachyon solution at fixed separation of the equations of motion. This is an important point since the effective action proposed in [25] did not admit solution at fixed distance ; in fact, in this action, for non-vanishing tachyon the distance field has an attractive potential towards the origin. Our motivation for looking closely at this issue was in part due to the results of Bagchi and Sen [20]. They found that the boundary deformation corresponding to the tachyon (9) was only marginal in the range 0 |r| &lt; r c / √ 2. For r c / √ 2 |r| &lt; r c it was found that for an infinite but countable set of distances the theory was not conformal. This is puzzling as we expect that everything goes smoothly up to the critical separation r c . 1 If we Wick-rotate the theory to an Euclidean target space, for which perturbation theory is well-defined, the zero-mode integration gives δ(2ω) which is zero for any value of |r| &lt; 1/ √ 2.</p>

				<p>At the end of the day, the basic difference between those two approaches is the contact term, however the latter is not responsible for restoring marginality, since it cannot cancel the logarithmic divergences that could spoil conformal invariance as we shall see; rather, the actual computation of the possible conformal symmetry-violating terms in the path integral gives zero thanks to the different contributions that cancel among themselves at a given order. Nevertheless, the contact term is able, as expected, to cancel the power-like two-tachyon divergences in the perturbative integrals.</p>

				<p>The cleanest way to show that the action (6), with the rolling tachyon perturbation (7) is a boundary CFT is to compute the boundary β-functions for all the boundary couplings involved. On top of the coupling constants λ ± for the rolling tachyon perturbations, one needs to introduce in the computation a perturbation corresponding to the separation-changing boundary operator σ 3 ⊗ i∂ u X. 1 The brane-antibrane separation is classically fixed at some value r, but still in the quantum theory one has to check that the corresponding beta-function vanishes for any r, in other words that it is not &apos;sourced&apos; by terms in λ ± . On top of this, more operators need to be considered in the analysis as |r| increases.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4.1">Generalities about boundary beta-functions</head>

				<p>In order to compute the beta-functions for their boundary couplings, we follow mostly the clear presentation of [33]. One considers a conformal field theory on the upper half-plane H + = {z, Im z ≥ 0} perturbed by boundary operators that can be marginal or relevant. The action of the theory is defined to be</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S(λ µ ) = S bulk + µ ℓ −yµ λ µ dx φ µ (x) + S ct , (31)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>in terms of the renormalized dimensionless couplings {λ µ } and the anomalous dimensions y µ = 1 − h µ . The renormalization scale is denoted by ℓ. The last term S ct stands for boundary counterterms whenever they are necessary. The boundary fields φ µ are normalized</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>as 2 φ * µ (∞) φ µ (0) = 1 (32)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with φ * µ the conjugate field to φ µ . 3 At second order in perturbation theory, one encounters the integral (which lies inside a correlator with arbitrary other insertions)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>: 4 1 2 µ,ν ℓ hµ−hν −2 dx 1 dx 2 φ µ (x 1 )φ ν (x 2 )Θ(|x 1 − x 2 | − ε)Θ(L − |x 1 − x 2 |) (33)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This integral has been regularized by point-splitting with a UV cutoff ε , and with and an IR</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1</head>

				<p>To be exact we will have to add it in superspace as Γ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>+ Γ − DX 2 The Zamolodchikov correlators are defined as (φa(∞)|φ b (z b )) = limz→∞ z 2ha ¯ z 2 ¯ ha φa(z)φ b (z b ). 3</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the case of theories with several boundary conditions, one has to trace over the Chan-Patton factors, which would be here included inside the fields,</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>e.g. as Tr φ * µ (∞) φµ(0) = 1.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Considering deformations by boundary-changing operators, the CP factors induce selection rules. 4 We will use the convention that operators (with CP factors) are ordered from right to left with increasing boundary parameter; this is the opposite convention than in [33]</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>. cutoff L. In order to compute the integral one can use the boundary OPE</figDesc>
					<trash>φ µ (x 1 )φ ν (x 2 ) = ρ D ρ µν (x 1 − x 2 ) hµ+hν −hρ φ ρ (x 2 ) + · · · x 1 &gt; x 2 . (34) In this case, (33) is rewritten as: µ&lt;ν ℓ hµ−hν −2 y+L y+ǫ dx dy φ µ (x)φ ν (y) + y+L y+ǫ dx dy φ ν (x)φ µ (y) (35)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Minimal substraction scheme</head>

				<p>In this scheme, we aim to isolate the divergences that occur in the integral (33) when two perturbations collide. One has to consider separately two cases. The subset of boundary fields {φ ρ } such that y µ + y ν − y ρ &lt; 0 (which are all relevant), gives a divergent contribution to the action (31) of the form (after removing the IR cutoff)</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S d = 1 2 µ,ν,ρ D ρ µν y µ + y ν − y ρ ε yµ+yν −yρ ℓ yµ+yν λ µ λ ν dx φ ρ . (36)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the minimal substraction scheme, this divergence is canceled by a similar counter term S ct = −S d .</p>

				<p>The subset of boundary fields {φ τ } such that y µ +y ν −y τ = 0 gives logarithmic divergences, or resonances (cutting the integration at the renormalization scale ℓ):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S d = 1 2 µ,ν,τ D τ µν ln(ε/ℓ)ℓ −y τ λ µ λ ν dx φ τ (37)</trash>

					<figDesc>This divergent piece is again canceled by an appropriate counterterm S ct = −S d . Now equating the bare couplings to the two corresponding contributions from the renormalized action (31), one gets the beta-function at second order</figDesc>
					<trash>β ms ρ := ℓ dµ ρ dℓ = y ρ λ ρ − µ,ν|yµ+yν =yρ D ρ µν λ µ λ ν (38)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>So non-linear contributions at quadratic order occur only in the cases of resonances, if they exist. 1 One can show that, in the minimal substraction scheme, this property holds to all orders in perturbation theory. Note that there is a sign difference between the above result and what appears in [33]. This comes from their convention of using e S instead of e −S as we did. One could obtain the same definition by simply changing the sign of the couplings.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Wilsonian scheme</head>

				<p>In this scheme, we equate the renormalization scale ℓ with the UV scale ε, viewed as a fundamental high-energy scale. We demand that the renormalized theory does not depend on the UV cutoff scale, i.e. that ε∂ ε e −S bdy = 0. Then the renormalized boundary couplings depend on the UV scale ε (as the regularized perturbative integrals do). At second order, the corresponding beta-functions read:</p>

				<p><formula>β ws ρ := ε∂ ε µ ρ = y ρ λ ρ − µ,ν D ρ µν λ µ λ ν (39)</formula></p>

				<p>In contrast with the minimal substraction scheme, eq. (38), there is no restriction to &apos;resonant&apos; boundary couplings in the sum giving the quadratic term of the beta-function (39). 1 We will see below that both schemes are useful in the study of the rolling tachyon perturbations , when it comes to understand the role of the contact terms. 4.2 Beta-functions for the brane-antibrane system at second order</p>

				<p>Coming back to the brane-antibrane system, we consider the following worldsheet action on the upper half-plane, as a function of the boundary couplings. So now we take the boundary variable to be u ∈ R. For convenience, we rescale the coupling according to λ ± → 2πλ ± .</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S = S bulk − dx λ + σ + ⊗ ψ + e ir X+ωX 0 + λ − σ − ⊗ ψ − e −ir X+ωX 0 − i δr 2 σ 3 ⊗ ∂ u ˜ X (40)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We omitted for the moment the contact term, which will enter later on in the discussion.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Distance coupling</head>

				<p>Let us start by discussing the beta-function for the distance perturbation. According to the general discussion above, one has</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>β r = (1 − h r ) δr 2 − (D r +− + D r −+ )λ − λ + − D r r+ δr 2 λ + − D r r− δr 2 λ − . . . (41)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the ellipsis here stands for higher order terms. The first term on the RHS vanishes because the conformal dimension of the distance perturbation is one. All the second order, all the structure constants for the three boundary operators under study appear, since, being all of conformal dimension one, they lead potentially to resonances.</p>

				<p>Without much work, we have that D r ±∓ = 0. The fusion of the tachyon vertex operators T ± will never produce the current ∂ u X, as t he e ωX 0 factors just add up. The structure constants D r r± also have to vanish, since the fusion of T ± with the boundary current iσ 3 ∂ u ˜ X comes with the Chan-Patton factor σ ± σ 3 = ∓σ ± hence not σ 3 . However, this product participates to the beta-function of T ± as we will see. At higher orders in perturbation theory, we would find a similar behavior. Namely, the fusion of any number tachyon vertices cannot produce the distance-changing operator, hence the beta-function for δr does not get tachyon &apos;source terms&apos; (which would be proportional to (λ + λ − ) n at order 2n). In other words, the distance coupling does not run in the rolling tachyon background (9). We can also be less specific and consider, instead of (9), a more general tachyon profile of the form:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T ± = 1 2π e ±ir X λ ± e ωX 0 + ξ ± e −ωX 0 , (42) 1 The linear</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>term, as well as the resonant quadratic terms, that are common to both schemes, can be shown to be &apos;universal&apos;, i.e. independent of the scheme chosen for the computations. the hermiticity of the action imposing that λ − = λ + and ξ − = ξ + .</p>

				<p>The conclusion can be different, as the structure constants D r ±∓ do not have to vanish by similar arguments. To this end, we use the 0-picture tachyons OPE:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>σ + σ − ⊗ T + (0) (z)T − (0) (w) = 1 + σ 3 4 ⊗ . . . + ir ∂ u ˜ X z − w + . . . σ − σ + ⊗ T − (0) (z)T + (0) (w) = 1 − σ 3 4 ⊗ . . . − ir ∂ u ˜ X z − w + . . . (43)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we only highlighted the interesting term. It is not difficult then to obtain the secondorder beta-function for the distance coupling :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>β r = − λ + ξ − + λ − ξ + 4π 2 r = − 1 2π 2 Re λ + ξ + r (44)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The beta-function (44) is scheme-independent, as the divergence is logarithmic. If one introduces a real parameter µ, the most general solution of this equation is then:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T ± = λ ± 2π e ±ir X e ωX 0 ± iµ e −ωX 0 , µ ∈ R (45)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Notice that, so far, the marginality of this solution has been checked only at second order. The fourth order (and higher) beta-functions would be non-trivial to compute, and marginality at this order is a priori not obvious. In any case, the physical meaning of the general solution (45) is not clear. If, for instance, one chooses λ + real (which is always possible by a shift of X), it corresponds to a case where the real part of the tachyon condenses, while the imaginary part evolves in the opposite direction. There is no clear reason why the phase of the tachyon condensate has to change by π/2 during its evolution, as the constraints on the solution (45) suggests. By symmetry arguments, the tachyon potential of the effective action should depend only on its square modulus.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>i.e. of T (x 0 ) 2 = λ + λ − 4π 2 e 2ωx 0 + µ 2 e −2ωx 0 , (46) which, for non-zero µ, goes through a minimal value |T | 2 = µ λ + λ − 2π 2 at finite time.</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>If we consider instead the time-reversal-symmetric tachyon profile (&apos;full S-brane&apos;) as in the case of the non-BPS brane:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T ± = λ ± 2π e ±irX cosh ωX 0 , (47)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>the beta-function (44) indicates a RG running of the distance coupling, unless r = 0. This result has far-reaching consequences. Unlike the case of coincident brane-antibrane or of a non-BPS brane, the effective action of the brane-antibrane system at finite distance should be such that, while the &apos;half S-brane&apos; rolling tachyon is allowed as a solution of its equations of motion, the &apos;full S-brane&apos; should not.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Tachyon couplings at quadratic order</head>

				<p>We now compute the beta-functions for the tachyon couplings λ ± at order λ + λ − for the &apos;half S-brane&apos; profile. 1 The boundary OPEs to consider at quadratic order are the distance-tachyon OPE</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− iσ 3 ⊗ ∂ u ˜ X(x 1 ) σ ± ⊗ ψ ± e ωX 0 ±ir X (x 2 ) ∼ −2 x 1 − x 2 (±σ ± ) ⊗ (±r)ψ ± e ωX 0 ±ir X (x 2 ) + · · · (48) and the tachyon-tachyon OPE σ + ⊗ ⋆ ⋆ ψ + e ωX 0 +ir X (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ σ − ⊗ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − e ωX 0 −ir X (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ∼ − 1 0 0 0 (1 − 4r 2 ) 1 (x 1 − x 2 ) 4r 2 ⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ + · · · (49)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>both for x 1 &gt; x 2 . The ellipsis stands for less singular terms.</p>

				<p>Beta-function for |r| &lt; 1/2. Whenever |r| &lt; 1/2 the OPE (49) does not lead to singularities when integrated. Hence, in the minimal substraction scheme, no corresponding counterterm is needed. This reflects the fact that the contact term is zero in this range. 2 This extends to all orders in perturbation theory.</p>

				<p>The case of the OPE (48) is different, as it leads to a logarithmic divergence for any r = 0. From (38) the relevant β-functions are of the form 3 :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>β ± = (1 − h ± )λ ± + (D ± r± + D ± ±r ) δr 2 λ ± + . . . (50) We get at second order that β ± = 1 2 − r 2 − ω 2 − 2rδr λ ± . (51)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>this is valid in any scheme, as only universal quantities appear. If one keeps the distance perturbation to zero (δr = 0) then the rolling tachyon background is marginal at second order provided that the on-shell condition ω 2 + r 2 = 1/2, as expected. Otherwise, the marginality of the perturbation is restored, at this order, if we use instead the on-shell condition</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ω 2 + (r + δr) 2 = 1/2 (52)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This is compatible with the interpretation of the boundary perturbation σ 3 ⊗ i∂ u ˜ X, that changes the relative position of the D-brane and the anti D-brane. It is T-dual to the relative 1 Let us remark in passing that, by shifting the zero-mode of the time-like field X0 → X0 + α, there is a common rescaling of the couplings λ ± → λ ± e ωα . This is a common feature of Liouville-like theories. For this reason, the perturbative expansion in λ ± does strictly make sense only in the Euclidean theory obtained by X0 → iXe. 2 In the Wilsonian scheme the contact term is an irrelevant operator in this range. 3 The sign is opposite here since the sign in front of the tachyon perturbation in (40) is opposite.</p>

				<p>Wilson line that appears in the action (2). 1 One checks that the normalization of this coupling in (2) is compatible, through T-duality, with relation (52). This analysis shows that, at least at this order, the rolling tachyon perturbations T ± &apos;adjust themselves&apos; to a change of braneantibrane separation in order to stay marginal.</p>

				<p>Beta-functions for 1/2 &lt; |r| &lt; r c and contact term When 1/2 &lt; |r| &lt; r c the situation is different. The operator exp 2ωX 0 (that appears also in the contact term) becomes relevant, hence should be considered in the discussion. As stated earlier, this operator in unphysical from the superstring theory point of view (at zero superghost number). The corresponding boundary coupling is denoted by µ c . The tachyon-tachyon OPE (49) gives a singular perturbative integral at second order:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx 2 ⋆ ⋆ ψ + e ωX 0 +ir X (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − e ωX 0 −ir X (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ r =1/2 ∼ ε 1−4r 2 dx 1 ⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ , (53) after removing the IR cutoff (L → ∞ limit).</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In the minimal substraction scheme, the following local counterterm is needed at this order to cancel the divergence:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>S ct = λ + λ − ε 1−4r 2 dx ⋆ ⋆ e 2ωX 0 (x) ⋆ ⋆ . (54)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Naturally, it agrees precisely with the expression of the contact term in the action (15). Since this divergence is power-like, it does not add any non-linear term in the minimal scheme beta-function β ms c for the coupling µ c . Hence, the latter can be consistently set to zero in the renormalized theory at this order. For the distance |r| = 1/2, amplitudes are finite without the counterterm, so it is not strictly needed 2 , but it contributes nevertheless finitely to the amplitudes. In the Wilsonian scheme, the beta-function reads, at second order:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>β ws c = (1 − 4r 2 )µ c − 1 − 4r 2 λ + λ − (55)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>One sees here an interesting phenomenon. The operator exp 2ωX 0 is relevant at linear order, but the RG flow gives an IR fixed point for this coupling at quadratic order, for µ c = λ + λ − .</p>

				<p>Comparing the outcomes of both schemes, one gets the same results but the interpretation is different. In the minimal substraction scheme the contact term appears as a counterterm, but the corresponding renormalized coupling is consistently set to zero. On the contrary, in the Wilsonian scheme, the RG flow has a fixed point with non-zero renormalized coupling µ c .</p>

				<p>Both points of view are &apos;non-supersymmetric&apos;, as in the superspace formulation this term is present from the beginning and removes the divergence under discussion.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>1</head>

				<p>To be more correct, as auxiliary fields from the Fermi superfield couples to this perturbation, some</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>±i δr λ ± ψ x e ±ir X+ωX 0</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>correction should be included. We verify that it doesn&apos;t modify the β-function at quadratic order. Moreover, this term shows up naturally if we work directly with the superspace distance perturbation i δr Γ + Γ − DuX. 2 But partition function appears to be discontinuous at |r| = 1/2 without its contribution.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="4.3">Marginality beyond quadratic order</head>

				<p>Part of the quadratic order results generalizes immediately to higher orders. Indeed only the fusion of distance perturbations with, say, T + can produce T + itself (since the fusion of n tachyons goes as e nωX 0 , as far as the X 0 dependence is concerned). Hence, if we set δr = 0 from the very beginning, we expect that the beta-functions β ± vanish to all orders in perturbation theory. With the same reasoning, the operator exp(2ωX 0 ) that we had to consider for |r| &gt; 1/2 cannot receive higher-order contributions to its beta-function. However, study of the marginality at higher orders is quite messy when |r| is getting closer to the critical distance, as the fusion of tachyon vertex operators produces more and more relevant boundary operators. For a given value of r, these operators, of the form e 2nωX 0 with n ∈ Z + , become (superficially) relevant if n &lt; (2 − 4r 2 ) −1/2 , and are of dimension one when they saturate this bound. These resonances occur all for 1 /2 |r| &lt; 1 / √ 2; this range was excluded by Bagchi and Sen in their analysis [20] for this precise reason. A given operator e 2nωX 0 appears first at order 2n in the perturbative expansion in the tachyon perturbations, hence the beta-function β n for its coupling λ n is of the form:</p>

				<p><formula>β n = (1 − 4n 2 ω 2 )λ n + O (λ + λ − ) n (56)</formula></p>

				<p>It is easier then to work in the minimal substraction scheme, where one just has to worry about logarithmic divergences, i.e. resonances. As we emphasized above, if the fusion of (superficially) marginal operators produces a (superficially) marginal operator, it generates a source term in the corresponding minimal scheme beta-function. It is nevertheless interesting to consider whether power-like divergences are also present. At second order the potentially marginal operator is nothing but the contact term itself, e 2ωX 0 , for the distance |r| = 1/2. Fortunately, thanks to its fermionic part the OPE (49) vanishes, hence there is no logarithmic divergence to cancel.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Marginality for √ 7/4 &lt; |r| &lt; √ 17/6</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The next possible resonance occurs when the operator e 4ωX 0 becomes of dimension one, i.e. for ω = 1/4 (equivalently, |r| = √ 7/4). The potential logarithmic divergence would occur at fourth order in perturbation theory. In order to investigate this issue we compute below all the possible divergent terms that occur at order (λ + λ − ) 2 from the perturbative integrals, that involve both the tachyon and contact term vertex operators.</p>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>In the computations of this subsection, we use the full non-local contact term (21), as even the sub-leading terms contribute a priori to the divergences. The first contribution comes from two contact term insertions (symbolically CC). Using the notations a = 4ω 2 and T ± = e ±ir X+ωX 0 , it reads</figDesc>
					<trash>CC = 1 0 0 1 ε 2a−2 4 dx 1 x 1 −2ε x 1 −L+ε dx 2 ⋆ ⋆ T + (x 1 + ε)T − (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ + ⋆ ⋆ T − (x 1 + ε)T + (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ × ⋆ ⋆ T + (x 2 + ε)T − (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ + ⋆ ⋆ T − (x 2 + ε)T + (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ (57)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The contact term being multiplied by the Chan-Patton identity matrix. The short-distance regularization chosen here prevents any operator to approach another one at less that ε, before integration of the auxiliary fields. The most natural IR cutoff prescription is to constraint two ordered operators not to move away from each other by more that L, also before integration of auxiliary fields. One gets then</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>CC ∼ 1 0 0 1 1 2a + 1 L ε 2−2a − L ε 1−2a − 5 − 6a − (2a − 1)2 2a+2 2 F 1 (1 − a, −a − 1 2 ; −a + 1 2 ; 1 4 ) 4(2a + 1)(2a − 1) L ε 1−4a × L 4a−1 dx 1 ⋆ ⋆ e 4ω X 0 ⋆ ⋆ (x 1 ) . (58)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The second contribution, from two tachyons and a contact term, is more involved as one has to integrate over two operator positions, leading to various type of singularities. One has to be careful with path ordering of the contact term with the tachyon; we have to distinguish three contributions, symbolically noted CTT, TCT and TTC. One finds that the contributions of CTT and TTC are equal, but TCT is different. We have to sum these three contributions together. Using the notation C(x) =</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>⋆ ⋆ T + (x + ε)T − (x) ⋆ ⋆ + ⋆ ⋆ T − (x + ε)T + (x) ⋆ ⋆ , one has: CT T + T CT + T T C = − 1 0 0 0 ε a−1 2 dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L+ε dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 ⋆ ⋆ C(x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 3 ) ⋆ ⋆ + dx 1 x 1 −2ε x 1 −L dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L+ε dx 3 ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ C(x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 3 ) ⋆ ⋆ + dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx 2 x 2 −2ε x 2 −L dx 3 ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ C(x 3 ) ⋆ ⋆ (59)</trash>

					<figDesc>Here, the whole computation is multiplied by the upper part of the identity matrix, since T + and T − are themselves multiplied by σ + and σ − respectively. One should also take into account the permutated version of (59) which has ordering T − T + instead of T + T − . From symmetry of the OPE&apos;s under this permutation, it contributes the same result but multiplied by the lower part of the identity matrix. Thus, the computation of the divergent terms gives the result, see appendix A:</figDesc>
					<trash>CT T + T CT + T T C ∼ 1 0 0 1 − 2 1 + 2a L ε 2−2a + 1 a L ε 1−2a + 2(a − 1) 3a L ε 1−a 2 F 1 (−a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + 2 F 1 (−a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 − V (a) L ε 1−4a L 4a−1 dx 1 ⋆ ⋆ e 4ω X 0 ⋆ ⋆ (x 1 ) (60)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The coefficient V (a) is given by (we did not find a closed form for it):</figDesc>
					<trash>V (a) = (a−1) ∞ n=0 1 s=0 Γ(a) Γ(a − n)Γ(1 + n)(3a − s − n) 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a; 2 + n − 2a; −1) 1 + n − 2a + 2 F 1 (s − a, 1 + s − 2a; 2 + s − 2a; −1) 1 + s − 2a + 2 F 1 (n − a, s + n − 1 − 2a; s + n − 2a; −1) s + n − 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (s − a, n + s − 1 − 2a; n + s − 2a; −1) n + s − 1 − 2a +(a−1) ∞ n,p=0 Γ(a)Γ(a − 1) Γ(a − n)Γ(1 + n)Γ(a − 1 − p)Γ(1 + p) 2 F 1 (1 − a, n + p − 3a, n + p + 1 − 3a, −1) 3a − n − p × 2 F 1 (2 + p − a, n + p + 1 − 2a, n + p + 2 − 2a, −1) n + p + 1 − 2a + (a − 1) ∞ p=0 1 s,t=0 Γ(a − 1) Γ(a − 1 − p)Γ(1 + p)(3a − s − t − p) × 2 F 1 (2 + p − a, s + p + 1 − 2a, s + p + 2 − 2a, −1) s + p + 1 − 2a (61)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>Finally, one has to consider the contribution from four tachyon insertions in the path integral (TTTT). The method of computation of the multiple integral is explained in appendix B. After a lengthy computation one gets 1</figDesc>
					<trash>T T T T = 1 0 0 1 dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 x 3 −ε x 3 −L dx 4 ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 3 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 4 ) ⋆ ⋆ ∼ 1 0 0 1 1 2a + 1 L ε 2−2a + a − 1 a L ε 1−2a − 2(a − 1) 3a L ε 1−a 2 F 1 (−a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + 2 F 1 (−a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>1 The term with ordering T − T + T − T + contributes the same result thus the total computation is directly multiplied by the identity matrix as in (60).</figDesc>
					<trash>+ L ε 1−4a − 1 1 − 4a (a − 1) 2 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 2 − 3a, 3 − 3a, −1) 2 − 3a × 2 F 1 (−a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (−a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + 2(a − 1) 2 − 1 2 F 1 (1 − a, a, 1 + a, −1) a + 2 F 1 (1 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a × 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a, a + 1, −1) a + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 1 − 3a, 2 − 3a, −1) 1 − 3a + U (a) L ε 1−4a L 4a−1 dx 1 ⋆ ⋆ e 4ω X 0 ⋆ ⋆ (x 1 ) (62)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>with U (a) a numerical coefficient which is not singular at a = 1/4. As in the previous computation, the coefficient U (a) is known only as a series expansion</figDesc>
					<trash>U (a) = (a − 1) 2 4a − 1 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1; a; −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, −3a; 1 − 3a; −1) 3a × 2 F 1 (−a, 1 − 2a; 2 − 2a; −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (−a, a − 1; a; −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a; 2 − 2a; −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1; a + 2; −1) a + 1 + 2(a − 1) 2 − 1 4a − 1 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 1 − 3a; 2 − 3a; −1) 3a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a; a + 1; −1) a × 2 F 1 (1 − a, 1 − 2a; 2 − 2a; −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (1 − a, a; a + 1; −1) a + (a − 1) 2 ∞ n=0 Γ(a + 1) Γ(n + 1)Γ(a − n + 1)(a + n − 1)(3a − n) 2 F 1 (n − a, −2a + n + 1; −2a + n + 2; −1) −2a + n + 1 + 2 F 1 (n − a, −2a + n − 1; n − 2a; −1) −2a + n − 1 + (a − 1) 2 ∞ n=0 Γ(a − 1) Γ(n + 1)Γ(a − n − 1)(a + n + 1)(3a − n − 2) + 2 2(a − 1) 2 − 1 ∞ n=0 Γ(a) Γ(n + 1)Γ(a − n)(a + n)(3a − n − 1) 2 F 1 (−a + n + 1, −2a + n + 1; −2a + n + 2; −1) −2a + n + 1 (63)</trash>


				</figure>

				<figure>
					<figDesc>The last three sums are rapidly converging, thus U (a) is known with good accuracy, for any value of a 1/4 (or ω 1/4). Let us now investigate the possible logarithmic divergences, that can only occur from the T T T T integral. Since we have that</figDesc>
					<trash>L ε 1−4a − 1 1 − 4a a→1/4 → log L ε , (64)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>only the last but one term in (62) could lead to a logarithmic divergence at ω = 1/4. It turns out that, in this limit, the coefficient of this term vanishes exactly. Looking more closely at this computation, one sees that each multiple integral that one gets from the three different fermionic contractions – see eq. (109) – has a logarithmic term as expected, however the sum of them precisely cancels. Hence, the same occurs as at order two; the coefficient in front of the potentially resonant term in the beta-function vanishes. 1 In order to check whether power-like divergences remain at fourth order, one has to resum the three contributions obtained above. The full contribution at order (λ + λ − ) 2 is given by CC + CT T + T CT + T T C + T T T T . Comparing (57), (59) and (62), one sees that the coefficients in front of all divergent terms vanish exactly for any value of ω 1/4. Hence, in this range, if one includes the two-tachyon contact term dictated by worldsheet supersymmetry, perturbative expansion is finite. 2 As said before we were not able to compute the coefficient associated to the term of order ǫ 1−4a , which becomes divergent for ω &lt; 1/4 in a closed form. Using a numerical evaluation, we find that the sum of the contributions gives a non-zero coefficient for any ω &lt; 1/4. Hence, a power-like divergence remains in this range. By dimensional counting, this uncanceled divergence corresponds to four tachyon operators coming close together at the same point. It is not unexpected that this divergence is not canceled by the contact term, as the latter corresponds to a two-tachyon collision. Since this remaining divergence is non-logarithmic, it does not mean that the boundary theory is not conformal, but rather that it should be renormalized at quartic order. It should be possible to cancel this divergence with higherorder contact-term. They may correspond to additional non-linear terms in the superspace action (6) (a four-auxiliary field vertex is needed then).</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>T T T T = 1 0 0 1 4 dx1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx3 x 3 −ε x 3 −L dx4 ⋆ ⋆ ψ + e X 0 /4+ir X (x1) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − e X 0 /4−ir X (x2) ⋆ ⋆ × × ⋆ ⋆ ψ + e X 0 /4+ir X (x3) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − e X 0 /4−ir X (x4) ⋆ ⋆ ∼ 2 3 L ε 3/2 + 7 √ πΓ 5 4 3Γ 3 4 − α L ε 3/4 − 3 L ε 1/2 dx1 ⋆ ⋆ e X 0 (x1) ⋆ ⋆</trash>

					<figDesc>with α ≃ 1.24 . . .. Logarithmic divergences are again found to vanish. 2 Not considering into account possible operator renormalization if there are operator insertions in the path integral.</figDesc>

				</figure>

				<p>As mentioned in section 3.2, we also obtained an unexpected result. If we assume that the computations of CTT and CC type terms could be equivalently done with the use of the simple dominant term ε a−1 e 2ωX 0 in (21), then we get the following contribution</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>CC + CT T + T CT + T T C = 1 0 0 1 − 1 1 + 2a L ε 2−2a + 1 a L ε 1−2a + 2(a − 1) 3a L ε 1−a 2 F 1 (−a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + 2 F 1 (−a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 − L ε 1−4a 2 a − 1 3a 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a; 2 − 2a; −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (−a, 1 − 2a; 2 − 2a; −1) 1 − 2a − 2 F 1 (−a, −1 − 2a; −2a; −1) 1 + 2a + 1 2a + 1 L 4a−1 dx 1 ⋆ ⋆ e 4ω X 0 ⋆ ⋆ (x 1 ) (65)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>One recognizes the coefficients of the three first divergences; these are precisely the ones appearing in the sum of (57) and (59). Moreover, numerical comparison of the L ε 1−4a coefficients gives almost identical results; the tiny difference could reasonably originates from the approximated evaluation of the infinite sums. This seems to show the equivalence of the two computations – (65) being of course significantly easier to perform – and then of the two (local and non-local) expressions of the contact term.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>Marginality to all orders</head>

				<p>Computations become intractable for the next resonance, which occurs for ω = 1/6 (or equivalently |r| = √ 17/6), as we have to consider sixth order perturbation theory, with contributions from both counterterms found so far. However we assume that the same occurs; the coefficient in front of the logarithmic six-tachyon divergence should vanish as well.</p>

				<p>To summarize, we have found that, to all orders in perturbation theory, the theory defined by the boundary action (15) is a boundary conformal field theory when |r| &lt; √ 17/6. In the range √ 17/6 &lt; |r| &lt; 1/ √ 2, the theory is conformal at least up to order five. We naturally expect that the theory is conformal to all orders in this range as well. As a side remark, the theory defined by the limit r → r − c seems not well-defined. In this case, all the operators e 2nωX 0 are relevant, and by doing the perturbative expansion in the tachyon couplings we would need an infinite number of counter-terms. By contrast, the theory defined directly at r = r c = 1/ √ 2 seems fine. The boundary interaction (with T ± ∼ e ±iX/ √ 2 ) is similar to a boundary sine-Gordon theory, with additional CP factors. Other puzzling features of the r → r − c limit will be discussed in the next section.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="5">Discussion</head>

				<p>We argued in this work that, for all values of the brane-anti-brane distance below the critical value r c , the homogeneous rolling tachyon solution with a fixed separation is an exact boundary conformal field theory. Thus, a spacetime effective action that is valid around this particular solution should have such tachyon profile as a solution of its equations of motion . An effective action for the brane-anti-brane system was proposed by Garousi [25]. In a different parameterization of the tachyon field, 1 , it reads:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L g (T, ˙ T , r, 0) = − 2 cosh π|T | 1 + 4π 2 r 2 |T | 2 − | ˙ T | 2 − π 2 ˙ r 2 (66)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>One checks readily that, with ˙ r = 0, δ r L g = 0 for any non-zero separation. Hence, this Lagrangian cannot admit solutions with constant brane-antibrane separation. This is not to be unexpected, since it was obtained by a fermion number orbifold of the non-Abelian tachyon-DBI action for a pair of coincident non-BPS D-branes. Therefore it could only be valid for an infinitesimal brane separation. Since δ r L g is linear in r, it seems not even to be valid in this limit.</p>

				<p>In order to find the space-time effective action from first principles, we could proceed as in [13]. In this approach, one considers a generic spacetime Lagrangian of the D0-¯ D0 system, depending on the tachyon field τ , its first derivative, the distance field r and its first derivative. 2 Since, as we argued before, rolling tachyon solutions at constant separation exist, the effective Lagrangian describing nearby field configurations should satisfy the condition</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δL(τ, ˙ τ , r, ˙ r) δr ˙ r=0, ˙ τ =ωτ = 0 (67) where ω 2 = 1 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>− r 2 , as well as the equation of motion for the tachyon with a profile of the form τ = µ exp ωt.</p>

				<p>Solving these equations at quadratic order in the tachyon field, one obtains a unique result, if we ask that for r = 0 one should recover the known Lagrangian for the coincident case:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L(τ, ˙ τ , r, 0) = −2 + 1 − 2r 2 τ 2 2 + ˙ τ 2 1 − 2r 2 + · · · (68)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Unlike in the case of the non-BPS brane considered by Kutasov and Niarchos in [13], we did not impose above that the more generic profile τ = ζe ωt +ξe −ωt (with arbitrary coefficients ζ and ξ) is a solution, since it does not correspond to an exactly marginal deformation on the worldsheet as long as r = 0. A straightforward generalisation of the effective Lagrangian found by these authors exists for r = 0but should not be considered since, by construction, it allows the time-reversal-symmetric tachyon profile τ ∼ cosh ωt as a solution.</p>

				<p>Imposing only the &apos;half S-brane&apos; as a solution leads to an underconstrained (finite) system of equations and not to a single recurrence relation as in [13]. However, below eq. (44) we have shown that a solution of this form is marginal at second order, provided ξ = iµζ with µ real. Besides the necessity to prove its conformal invariance at all order (by going through an even more tedious analysis as we have done for the &apos;half S-brane&apos; solution), it would again lead to an underconstrained system. Indeed, this tachyon satisfies the identity | ˙ τ | 2 = ω 2 |τ | 2 .</p>

				<p>One can show that, as a consequence, the relation between the coefficients in the Lagrangian does not organize into a single recurrence relation, but rather separates into a system of independent equations which is underconstrained. Thus it does not lead to a unique effective Lagrangian at higher orders in the tachyon couplings. 1 The worldsheet theory contains more information about the tachyon effective action, besides imposing that the rolling tachyon background of interest should be a solution of its equations of motion. Following [13, 17], we expect to get the effective Lagrangian evaluated on-shell to be given by the disk partition function, with the time-like zero modes kept unintegrated:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>L τ,ωτ,r,0 (x 0 ) = −Z(r|x 0 ) disk (69)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>With this equation one can test whether any proposal for the effective Lagrangian of the system is sensible. At second order, one can compare the spacetime Lagrangian, given by eq. (68), with the partition function given in appendix C:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z(r|x 0 ) = 2 − Γ(2 − 4r 2 ) Γ 2 (1 − 2r 2 ) λ + λ − e 2ωx 0 + O (λ + λ − ) 2 (70)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In order to match these two computations, we see that a distance-dependent field redefinition of the tachyon field is necessary:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>τ (t) = 1 √ 1 − 2r 2 Γ(2 − 4r 2 ) Γ 2 (1 − 2r 2 ) 1/2 λ + e ωt (71)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As one can see, with this definition, the spacetime tachyon vanishes at the critical distance r = 1/ √ 2, for any finite value of the worldsheet coupling λ + . It could be the way string theory deals with the fact that, when r → r c , the tachyon becomes a light field, and we could wonder how a local action along the brane worldvolume dimensions – that is a priori well-defined as the tachyon is lighter than all string modes – would make sense, since the separation between the brane and the antibrane is significant in this regime.</p>

				<p>The validity of the field redefinition (71) should be tested beyond quadratic order. 2 For this one would have first to compute analytically the perturbative &apos;screening integrals&apos; at higher order which does not seem trivial. For the special value of the distance r = 1/2 the computation, up to order eight in the tachyon amplitude, is given in appendix C:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z( 1 2 |x 0 ) = 2 1 − λ + λ − e ωx 0 2π + 1 − π 2 6 λ + λ − e ωx 0 2π 2 − 1 − 128 3π 2 λ + λ − e ωx 0 2π 3 + 1 + 205 108 + 3575 162π 2 + π 2 2 + π 4 70 λ + λ − e ωx 0 2π 4 + O λ + λ − e ωx 0 2π 5 (72)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This does not seem to trace back to the Taylor expansion of a known function. Since the space-time effective action approach seems to have important limitations for branes-antibranes at finite separation, the boundary string field theory may be more appropriate in order to know the properties of the system. Even though it does not contain information about the dynamics of the system, it allows to find the exact tachyon potential (as well as the appearance of lower-dimensional branes), hence can illuminate the fate of the 1 Note on the other hand that (68) is still valid with (47) under the replacement τ</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 → |τ | 2 and ˙ τ 2 → | ˙ τ | 2 . 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>One can check already that plugging this redefinition in Garousi&apos;s Lagrangian (66) does not lead to a consistent effective Lagrangian. tachyon. These computations seem not to be out of reach. We plan to come back to these issues in the near future. A heuristic argument gives a good motivation for this study. Following [36, 37], one could describe the result of this condensation by studying the closed string emission from the time-dependent boundary state. It was found in [36] that, knowing the one-point function on the disk B(E) = e iEX 0 , one can compute the density of closed string states emitted by the decay of a non-BPS brane which goes as</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>ρ c ∼ N 1 E N D(N )|B(E N )| 2 (73)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where the asymptotic Hagedorn density of closed string states at level N has the form D(N ) ∼ N −α exp(4π √ N ), with α &gt; 0, and E N ∼ 2 √ N . The one-point function for an unstable non- BPS D-brane goes as |B(E)| 2 ∼ exp(−2πE). Therefore, in this case, the sum is governed by the sub-leading power-like corrections to the Hagedorn density and typically diverge, giving the so-called &apos;tachyon dust&apos; of massive closed strings. In the case of non-zero separation, by dimensional analysis we may expect that |B(E)| ∼ exp(− √ 2πE/|m tach (r)|). This would lead to a convergent closed string production when |m tach | &lt; 1/ √ 2 (i.e. for r = 0), signaling that the tachyon does not condense completely at finite distance.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head n="6">Acknowledgements</head>

				<p>We thank Vladimir Dotsenko, Matthias Gaberdiel, Costas Kounnas, Vasilis Niarchos and Jan Troost for stimulating discussions. This work is in part supported by the ANR grant STR-COSMO, ANR-09-BLAN-0157.</p>

				<p>A Computation of the divergences in CTT-type terms We give below one example of computation of the divergence occuring in an integral involving one contact operator insertion. We study here the CTT term. With a bit of care, one can compute them exactly. With the expression of C given in (21), the CTT term is</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>− ε a−1 2 dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L+ε dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 ⋆ ⋆ C(x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ T + (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ T − (x 3 ) ⋆ ⋆ = (a−1) ε a−1 2 dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L+ε dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 (x 1 −x 2 +ε)(x 1 −x 3 +ε) a−1 (x 1 −x 2 ) a−1 (x 1 −x 3 )(x 2 −x 3 ) a−2 + (x 1 − x 2 + ε) a−1 (x 1 − x 3 + ε)(x 1 − x 2 )(x 1 − x 3 ) a−1 (x 2 − x 3 ) a−2 (74)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with a = 4ω 2 . Note that the IR cut-off is chosen such that two ordered operator do not move away from each other more that L. Then, since C(x) ∼ T ± (x + ε)T ∓ (x) the cut-off for x 2 in relation to x 1 is L − ε. One can get read of the path ordering with the following change of variable :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>x 2 = −Lδ 1 + x 1 x 3 = −Lδ 2 + x 2 (75) such that it gives, introducing η = ε/L: (a − 1)L 4a−1 ε a−1 2 1−η η dδ 1 1 η dδ 2 (δ 1 + η)(δ 1 + δ 2 + η) a−1 δ a−1 1 (δ 1 + δ 2 )δ a−2 2 + (δ 1 + η) a−1 (δ 1 + δ 2 + η)δ 1 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−1 δ a−2 2 dx 1 e 4ωX 0 (x 1 ) (76)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The integral over δ i &apos;s can be done with the use of the series representation of (1 +</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>η δ 1 +δ 2 ) α since δ 1 + δ 2 &gt; η, and (1 + η δ 1 ) β since δ 1 &gt; η. These are given by: (1 + x) α = ∞ n=0 Γ(1 + α) x n Γ(1 + α − n)Γ(1 + n) with |x| &lt; 1 (77)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Convergence of the series all along the domain of integration allows us to commute integral and sum sign 1 , such that one has:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(a − 1) 1 s=0 ∞ n=0 Γ(a) Γ(a − n)Γ(1 + n) η a−1+s+n × 1−η η dδ 1 1 η dδ 2 δ a−s 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−n + δ a−n 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−s (78)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>As one can see, the two integral to compute are symmetric by permutation of s and n. We then only focus on the first one. There are two ways to proceed now. Integrate directly and exactly since it is possible, or use an indirect method that reintroduce some path ordering. We use the second and apparently more complicated method, because it is needed to compute TTTT integrals. Indeed, one will see that hypergeometric functions will receive argument z which has absolute value less than 1, much more easier to handle for approximations, since the series representation is known exactly. We separate the first integral of (78) into:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1−η η dδ 1 δ 1 η dδ 2 δ 2a−n−s 1 δ a−2 2 (1 + δ 2 δ 1 ) a−n + 1−η η dδ 1 1 δ 1 dδ 2 δ a−s 1 δ 2a−2−n 2 (1 + δ 1 δ 2 ) a−n = 1−η η dδ 1 δ 2a−n−s 1 δ a−1 2 a − 1 2 F 1 n − a, a − 1, a, − δ 2 δ 1 δ 1 η + 1−η η dδ 1 δ a−s 1 δ 2a−1−n 2 2a − 1 − n 2 F 1 n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, − δ 1 δ 2 1 δ 1 = 1−η η dδ 1 δ 3a−1−s−n 1 2 F 1 (n − a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −1) 1 + n − 2a − η a−1 a − 1 1−η η dδ 1 δ 2a−s−n 1 2 F 1 n − a, a − 1, a, − η δ 1 + 1 2a − 1 − n 1−η η dδ 1 δ a−s 1 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −δ 1 ) (79)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Let us remark at this stage that z argument in 2 F 1 (a, b, c, z) verifies |z| &lt; 1 in the above integrals. The first one is trivial and gives:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 1 = (1 − η) 3a−s−n − η 3a−s−n 3a − s − n 2 F 1 (n − a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −1) 1 + n − 2a = 1 − η 3a−s−n 3a − s − n 2 F 1 (n − a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −1) 1 + n − 2a + o(η) (80) The second one is a bit more involved I 2 = − η 3a−s−n a − 1 − δ s+n−1−2a 1 (a − 1) 3a − s − n 2 F 1 (n − a, a − 1, a, −δ 1 ) a − 1 − 2 F 1 (n − a, s + n − 1 − 2a, s + n − 2a, −δ 1 ) s + n − 1 − 2a 1 η 1−η = η 3a−s−n 3a − s − n 2 F 1 (n − a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 − 2 F 1 (n − a, s + n − 1 − 2a, s + n − 2a, −1) s + n − 1 − 2a − η a−1 (1 − η) −s−n+1+2a 3a − s − n   2 F 1 n − a, a − 1, a, − η 1−η a − 1 − 2 F 1 n − a, s + n − 1 − 2a, s + n − 2a, − η 1−η s + n − 1 − 2a   = η 3a−s−n 3a − s − n 2 F 1 (n − a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 − 2 F 1 (n − a, s + n − 1 − 2a, s + n − 2a, −1) s + n − 1 − 2a + η a−1 (a − 1)(s + n − 1 − 2a) + η a a − 1 1 + (a − n)(a − 1) a(s + n − 2a) + o(η a+1 ) (81)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>On the last line we used the series representation of 2 F 1 :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>2 F 1 (a, b, c, z) = ∞ k=0 (a) k (b) k z k (c) k k! (82) for |z| &lt; 1. In particular, for c = b + 1 we have: 2 F 1 (−a, b, b + 1, −z) = ∞ k=0 Γ(1 + a) b Γ(1 + a − k)Γ(1 + k)(b + k) z k (83) Finally, the third one is : I 3 = 1 2a − 1 − n − δ a+1−s 1 (1 + n − 2a) s + n − 3a 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −δ 1 ) 1 + n − 2a − 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + a − s, 2 + a − s, −δ 1 ) 1 + a − s 1−η η = (1 − δ 1 ) a+1−s s + n − 3a 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −1 + η) 1 + n − 2a − 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + a − s, 2 + a − s, −1 + η) 1 + a − s − o(η a+1−s ) = −1 3a − s − n 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −1) 1 + n − 2a − 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + a − s, 2 + a − s, −1) 1 + a − s + o(η a+1−s ) + o(η) (84)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Collecting these results one finally get the sum:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a − 1 2 1 s=0 ∞ n=0 Γ(a) Γ(a − n)Γ(1 + n) η a−1+s+n 1−η η dδ 1 1 η dδ 2 δ a−s 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 +δ 2 ) a−n +δ a−n 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 +δ 2 ) a−s = a − 1 2 1 s=0 ∞ n=0 Γ(a) Γ(a − n)Γ(1 + n) η a−1+s+n (I 1 + I 2 + I 3 + (s ↔ n)) ∼ − η 2a−2 2a + 1 + η 2a−1 2a − η a−1 a − 1 3a 2 F 1 (−a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + 2 F 1 (−a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 − ∞ n=0 1 s=0 Γ(a) Γ(a − n)Γ(1 + n)(3a − s − n) 2 F 1 (n − a, 1 + n − 2a, 2 + n − 2a, −1) 1 + n − 2a + 2 F 1 (s − a, 1 + s − 2a, 2 + s − 2a, −1) 1 + s − 2a + 2 F 1 (n − a, s + n − 1 − 2a, s + n − 2a, −1) s + n − 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (s − a, s + n − 1 − 2a, s + n − 2a, −1) s + n − 1 − 2a (85)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>A similar computation was done for the T CT and T T C terms, with the correct cut-off prescriptions. Note however that CT T = T T C.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>B Computation of the divergences in the TTTT term</head>

				<p>The computation of an amplitude with four tachyon insertions is clearly a lot more involved than the above one, since three integrations have to be done. The straightforward OPE of the four tachyons is doable and gives, from (</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>109) : dx 1 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 x 3 −ε x 3 −L dx 4 ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 1 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 2 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ + T + (x 3 ) ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ⋆ ψ − T − (x 4 ) ⋆ ⋆ = dx 1 e 4ωX 0 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 x 3 −ε x 3 −L dx 4 (a − 1) 2 (x 1 − x 2 ) a−2 (x 1 − x 3 )(x 1 − x 4 ) a−1 (x 2 − x 3 ) a−1 (x 2 − x 4 )(x 3 − x 4 ) a−2 − (x 1 − x 2 ) a−1 (x 1 − x 4 ) a−1 (x 2 − x 3 ) a−1 (x 3 − x 4 ) a−1 + (a − 1) 2 (x 1 − x 2 ) a−1 (x 1 − x 3 )(x 1 − x 4 ) a−2 (x 2 − x 3 ) a−2 (x 2 − x 4 )(x 3 − x 4 ) a−1 (86)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>This integrand is too much coupled in its variables and not analytically computable in this form. But one can show using the identity</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>(x 1 − x 2 )(x 3 − x 4 ) − (x 1 − x 3 )(x 2 − x 4 ) + (x 1 − x 4 )(x 2 − x 3 ) = 0 (87) that the integrand can be reexpressed as dx 1 e 4ωX 0 x 1 −ε x 1 −L dx 2 x 2 −ε x 2 −L dx 3 x 3 −ε x 3 −L dx 4 (a − 1) 2 (x 1 − x 2 ) a−2 (x 2 − x 3 ) a (x 3 − x 4 ) a−2 (x 1 − x 4 ) a + 2(a − 1) 2 − 1 (x 1 − x 2 ) a−1 (x 1 − x 4 ) a−1 (x 2 − x 3 ) a−1 (x 3 − x 4 ) a−1 + (a − 1) 2 (x 1 − x 2 ) a (x 2 − x 3 ) a−2 (x 3 − x 4 ) a (x 1 − x 4 ) a−2 (88) If we use the change of variable x 2 = −Lδ 1 + x 1 x 3 = −Lδ 2 + x 2 x 4 = −Lδ 3 + x 3 (89) the integral becomes: dx 1 e 4ωX 0 1 η dδ 1 1 η dδ 2 1 η dδ 3 (a − 1) 2 δ a−2 1 δ a 2 δ a−2 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 + δ 3 ) a + (a − 1) 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ a 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 + δ 3 ) a−2 + 2(a − 1) 2 − 1 δ a−1 1 δ a−1 2 δ a−1 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 + δ 3 ) a−1 (90)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>It is possible to extract the divergences by analytic integration but we need to be careful since we will need at some point to commute the integrals and sums. For this reason, the z-argument in the 2 F 1 (a, b, c, z) should satisfy |z| &lt; 1.</p>

				<p>We will not develop the whole computation, but give as an example one of the three integrals. Let us study the following one:</p>

				<p><formula>1 η dδ 1 1 η dδ 2 1 η dδ 3 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ a 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 + δ 3 ) a−2 (91)</formula></p>

				<p>Integration of δ 3 imposes to separate the domain of integration in three parts: δ 1 + δ 2 &gt; 1 and δ 3 ∈ [η; 1] &lt; δ 1 + δ 2 δ 1 + δ 2 &lt; 1 and δ 3 ∈ [η;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>δ 1 + δ 2 ] &lt; δ 1 + δ 2 δ 1 + δ 2 &lt; 1 and δ 3 ∈ [δ 1 + δ 2 ; 1] &gt; δ 1 + δ 2 (92) This makes three integrals: I 1 = 1 η dδ 1 1 1−δ 1 dδ 2 1 η dδ 3 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ a 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−2 (1 + δ 3 δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−2 I 2 = 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 δ 1 +δ 2 η dδ 3 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ a 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−2 (1 + δ 3 δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−2 I 3 = 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 1 δ 1 +δ 2 dδ 3 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ 2a−2 3 (1 + δ 1 + δ 2 δ 3 ) a−2 (93) which integrate to: I 1 = 1 η dδ 1 1 1−δ 1 dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−2 δ a+1 3 a + 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, − δ 3 δ 1 + δ 2 ) 1 η I 2 = 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) a−2 δ a+1 3 a + 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, − δ 3 δ 1 + δ 2 ) δ 1 +δ 2 η I 3 = 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ 2a−1 3 2a − 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, − δ 1 + δ 2 δ 3 ) 1 δ 1 +δ 2 (94)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We will not develop the computations for all the three integrals. Let us focus on the third, which is easier to present. The method is similar for the two other ones.</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 3 = 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 1 2a − 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −δ 1 − δ 2 ) − (δ 1 + δ 2 ) 2a−1 2a − 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) (95)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These are two different integrations to do. We have:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 1 3 = 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 1 2a − 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −δ 1 − δ 2 ) I 2 3 = − 1 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) 2a−1 2a − 1 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) (96)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Each of these separates again in three parts: δ 1 ∈ [η; 1 2 ] and δ 2 ∈ [η; δ 1 ] δ 1 ∈ [η; 1 2 ] and δ 2 ∈ [δ 1 ; 1 − δ 1 ] δ 1 ∈ [ 1 2 ; 1] and δ 2 ∈ [η; 1 − δ 1 ] (97)</p>

				<p>There is no known expression for the integration of I 1 3 , but it is not much of a problem since we only want to extract divergences. Because |δ 1 + δ 2 | &lt; 1, one can express 2 F 1 as its series expansion given in (83). Since the series is convergent everywhere in the integration domain, we can commute the sum and the integral, such that</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 1 3 = − ∞ n=0 Γ(a − 1) Γ(a − 1 − n)Γ(1 + n)(1 − 2a + n) × 1/2 η dδ 1 δ 1 η dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) n + 1/2 η dδ 1 1−δ 1 δ 1 dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) n + 1 1/2 dδ 1 1−δ 1 η dδ 2 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 (δ 1 + δ 2 ) n (98)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>These integrals are very similar to the ones studied in appendix A. Following the method presented there, and with a careful power analysis in η, we can obtain:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 1 3 = − ∞ n=0 Γ(a − 1) Γ(a − 1 − n)Γ(1 + n)(1 − 2a + n) × − 2 −a−1−n η a−1 (a + 1 + n)(a − 1) + o(1) + 2 −a−1−n − 1 η a−1 (a + 1 + n)(a − 1) = − η a−1 3a(a − 1) 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 2a − 1 + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + o(1) (99)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The computation of I 2 3 is less difficult. With method of appendix A and (97), it gives:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 2 3 = 1/2 η dδ 1 δ 4a−2 1 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 2 − 3a, 3 − 3a, −1) 2 − 3a × 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + η 4a−1 3a(a − 1)(4a − 1) 3a 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) + (a − 1) 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, −3a, 1 − 3a, −1) × 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + η a−1 3a 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) a − 1 + o(1) (100)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We do not integrate explicitely the first term so that the logarithm appears unambiguously at a = 1/4. This has to be compared to the second term which does not become a logarithm, since it is finite at a = 1/4. Indeed, for this precise value a − 1 = −3a and one gets</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>η 0 3a(a−1) . Finally, summing up I 1 3 with I 2 3 , one obtains: I 3 = 1/2 η dδ 1 δ 4a−2 1 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 2 − 3a, 3 − 3a, −1) 2 − 3a × 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + η 4a−1 3a(a − 1)(4a − 1) 3a 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) + (a − 1) 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, −3a, 1 − 3a, −1) × 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a − η a−1 3a 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + o(1) (101) Similarly one computes I 1 and I 2 , for which we obtain: I 1 = o(1) (102) and I 2 = 1/2 η dδ 1 δ 4a−2 1 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 2 − 3a, 3 − 3a, −1) 2 − 3a × 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + η 4a−1 3a(a − 1)(4a − 1) 3a 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) + (a − 1) 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, −3a, 1 − 3a, −1) × 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + η 4a−1 ∞ n=0 Γ(a − 1) Γ(n + 1)Γ(a − n − 1)(a + n + 1)(3a − n − 2) 2 F 1 (−2a + n + 1, −a + n + 2; −2a + n + 2; −1) −2a + n + 1 + 2 F 1 (−2a + n + 3, −a + n + 2; −2a + n + 4; −1) −2a + n + 3 − η a−1 3a 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + o(1) (103) One expresses then the whole integral (91) as 1 η dδ 1 1 η dδ 2 1 η dδ 3 δ a 1 δ a−2 2 δ a 3 (δ 1 + δ 2 + δ 3 ) a−2 ∼ 1/2 η dδ 1 δ 4a−2 1 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, 2 − 3a, 3 − 3a, −1) 2 − 3a × 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + η 4a−1 1 (4a − 1) 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, a − 1, a, −1) a − 1 + 2 F 1 (1 − 2a, −3a, 1 − 3a, −1) 3a × 2 F 1 (2 − a, 1 − 2a, 2 − 2a, −1) 1 − 2a + 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + ∞ n=0 Γ(a − 1) Γ(n + 1)Γ(a − n − 1)(a + n + 1)(3a − n − 2) 2 F 1 (−2a + n + 1, −a + n + 2; −2a + n + 2; −1) −2a + n + 1 + 2 F 1 (−2a + n + 3, −a + n + 2; −2a + n + 4; −1) −2a + n + 3 − 2 η a−1 3a 2 F 1 (2 − a, a + 1, a + 2, −1) a + 1 + o(1) (104)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>Similar techniques apply to the two other kinds of integrals.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>C Partition function to eighth order</head>

				<p>The disk partition function for the system, unintegrated over the time-like zero modes, can be expressed as a series:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z(r|x 0 ) = ∞ n=0 −λ + λ − e 2ωx 0 n I n (105)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>with I n a coefficient that is equal to the sum time-ordered integrals that appear at order n in the perturbative expansion. We can express it in a condensed form as :</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I n = [dt &gt; ] 2n 1 3 5 . . . 2n − 1 2 4 6 . . . 2n −4r 2 perm P (−1) P a 1 a 2 a 3 a 4 . . . a 2n−1 a 2n 1 − 4r 2 n 2 − 1 2 n i=1 (−1) a 2i−1 −a 2i (106) with the time-ordered measure [dt &gt; ] 2n = 2n i=1 dt i 2π 2n−1 i=1 Θ(t i − t i+1 ) (107)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We have also introduced convenient notations for the integrand, defined as:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>a 1 a 2 a 3 a 4 . . . a 2n−1 a 2n = n i=1 2n j=2i+1 S(a 2i−1 , a j )S(a 2i , a j ) , i 1 i 2 . . . i p j 1 j 2 . . . j n = p α=1 n a=1 S(i α , j a ) (108) where S(i, j) = 2 sin t i −t j 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>. The sum in (106) is done over all permutations within the set {1, 2, 3 . . . 2n}. 1 Up to n = 2, the partition function, for given |r| &lt;</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1/ √ 2, reads: Z(r|x 0 ) = 2 − 2 λ + λ − e 2ωx 0 [dt &gt; ] 2 1 2 −4r 2 1 − 4r 2 + 2 λ + λ − e 2ωx 0 2 [dt &gt; ] 4 1 3 2 4 −4r 2 1 − 4r 2 2 1 2 3 4 − 1 3 2 4 + 1 − 4r 2 2 1 4 2 3 + . . . (109) The computation at second order in T , for r ≤ 1/2, gives the result Z(r|x 0 ) = 2 − Γ(2 − 4r 2 ) Γ 2 (1 − 2r 2 ) λ + λ − e 2ωx 0 + O (λ + λ − ) 2 (110) where we used the Dyson integral [35]: 2π 0 n i=1 dt i 2π n i&lt;j e i t i − e i t j 2α = Γ(1 + nα) Γ n (1 + α) (111)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>We notice that the result (110) is analytic in r for all values below the critical distance r c = 1/ √ 2. The reason for this property should now be familiar to the reader. For |r| &lt; 1/2, the contact term vanishes, hence give no contribution to (110). The value r = 1/2 is particular. We see that the prefactor of the second order integral in (109) vanishes; at the same time, the contact term gives a finite contribution, ensuring the continuity of the result in (110). For any 1/2 &lt; |r| &lt; r c , the second-order integral in (110) is divergent. As we explained in subsec. 3.3, the divergence is canceled by the contribution from the contact term, that appear in the worldsheet action (15), where ε is chosen to be the same as the short distance cutoff in (109). The finite part that remains agrees precisely with (110). Hence, the presence of the contact term gives (at least at this order) a continuous result all the way to the critical distance.</p>

			</div>
			<div>
				<head>The r=1/2 case</head>

				<p>Finding the complete expression of the disk partition function at any |r| &lt; 1/ √ 2 seems to be out of reach, since integrals involve complicated highly coupled multidimensional integrals with path-ordering.</p>

				<p>For this reason we want to compute the partition function in the special case where ω = 1/2 which is tractable. We recall that the perturbative expansion of the worldsheet action is given by (6):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z(r, λ + , λ − ) = e −δS = e − λ + 2π d ˆ t Γ + T + ( ˆ t)− λ − 2π d ˆ t Γ − T − ( ˆ t) = ∞ n,p=0 (−1) n+p (λ + ) n n! (λ − ) p p! perm± [d ˆ t] n+p Γ ± ( ˆ t 1 ) . . . Γ ± ( ˆ t n+p ) × × T ± ( ˆ t 1 ) . . . T ± ( ˆ t n+p ) (112) with n and p of the same parity and T ± = e ±i X+ωX 0 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>.</p>

				<p>Due to the Fermi multiplets correlators, the only non-vanishing terms are the ones which have as much + as −. The correlator of the Fermi multiplets are easy to compute using Wick theorem and the Green function (5). It leads to one product of supersymmetric sign functions ǫ(2i, 2i + 1), which decomposes into a sum of 2(n!) 2 supersymmetric path orderings. One finds that these path orderings are all equivalent under permutations of T + &apos;s (T − &apos;s) with T + &apos;s (T − &apos;s) and permutations of integration variable. So one choose one path ordering, symbolically t 1 &gt; ˆ t 2 &gt; . . . &gt; ˆ t 2n multiplied by a factor 2(n!) 2 . We should then compute:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z(r, λ + , λ − ) = 2 ∞ n=0 (λ + λ − ) n [d ˆ t &gt; ] 2n T + ( ˆ t 1 )T − ( ˆ t 2 ) . . . T − ( ˆ t 2n ) = 2 ∞ n=0 (λ + λ − ) n e inx [d ˆ t &gt; ] 2n n i&lt;j S(2i, 2j) ˆ S(2i − 1, 2j − 1) = 2 ∞ n=0 (λ + λ − ) n e inx I n (113) with S(i, j) = |2 sin t i −t j 2</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>| − ǫ(i, j)θ i θ j .</p>

				<p>The computation of the integrals I n is as follows, using the notation of eq. (108). We have first I 1 = − 1 2π [dt]</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>1 = − 1 2π (114) Then I 2 which is still easy I 2 = 1 (2π) 2 [dt] 2 2! 1 2 2 1 − [dt] 4 4! = 1 (2π) 2 − 1 4! (115) and I 3 = 1 2π [dt] 5 5! C 5 1 1 2345 − 1 (2π) 3 [dt] 3 3! 1 23 2 13 3 12 = 2 12 4!(2π) 5 − 1 (2π) 3 = 16 3π 5 − 1 8π 3 (116)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>I 4 is a bit more complicated to compute, but in terms of integrals, we find:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>I 4 = [dt &gt; ] 8 13 57 24 68 − 1 (2π) 2 [dt] 6 6! C 6 2 1 2 2 1 12 3456 + 1 (2π) 4 [dt] 4 4! 1 234 2 134 3 124 4 123 = 1 1120 + 143 144π 6 − 55 192π 4 + 13 480π 2 − − 1001 2592π 6 − 175 432π 4 − 1 240π 2 + 1 16π 4 = 1 1120 + 3575 2592π 6 + 205 1728π 4 + 1 32π 2 + 1 16π 4 (117)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>where we introduced the totally antisymmetric form :</p>

			<note>ab . . . cd . . . = P (−1) P p(a)p(b) . . . p(c)p(d) . . . = ab . . . cd . . . − ac . . . bd . . . + ad . . . bc . . .</note>

				<figure>
					<trash>+ . . . (118) with the partially anti-symmetric form : abc . . . def . . . = ǫ(a, b)ǫ(a, c)ǫ(b, c) × . . . × ǫ(d, e)ǫ(d, f )ǫ(e, f ) × . . . × abc . . . def . . . (119)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>The bigger n is, the more complicated is the corresponding term in the partition function. This is because more and more contribution of the contact term appear and that the path ordering can&apos;t be always removed. For the special value r = 1/2 the contact term has indeed a non-zero, but finite contribution to the final result.</p>

				<p>We end up with the following expansion. The terms coming from pure &apos;non-contact&apos; contributions are underlined:</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z(x) 2 = 1 − λ + λ − e ix 2π + (λ + λ − ) 2 4π 2 e 2ix 1 − π 2 6 − (λ + λ − ) 3 8π 3 e 3ix 1 − 128 3π 2 + (λ + λ − ) 4 16π 4 e 4ix 1 + 175 27 + 1001 162π 2 + π 2 15 − 55 12 + 143 9π 2 + 13π 2 30 + π 4 70 . . . (120) where we recognize the trivial expansion : 1 − λ + λ − e ix 2π + λ + λ − 2 e 2ix 4π 2 − λ + λ − 3 e 3ix 8π 3 + . . . = 1 1 + λ + λ − 2π e ix (121)</trash>


				</figure>

				<p>In fact, this factorization is exact to all orders; by looking at the integrals I n , one can see that the maximal contact term is always present and has a standard form, which we recognize as a Vandermonde determinant. The remaining terms should come from a non-trivial function that multiplies (121):</p>

				<figure>
					<trash>Z(x) = 2 1 + λ + λ − 2π e ix 1 − λ + λ − 2π 2 π 2 6 e 2ix + 128 3π 2 − π 2 6 λ + λ − 2π 3 e 3ix + 205 108 + 10487 162π 2 + π 2 2 + π 4 70 λ + λ − 2π 4 e 4ix + . . . (122)</trash>


				</figure>

			</div>

			<note place="foot">arXiv:1108.5763v2 [hep-th] 7 Jul 2014</note>

			<note place="foot">† Email: israel@iap.fr,kiefer@iap.fr 1 Unité mixte de Recherche 7095, CNRS – Université Pierre et Marie Curie 2 Unité mixte de Recherche du CNRS et de l&apos; ´ Ecole Normale Supé associéè a l&apos;Université Pierre et Marie Curie, UMR 8549.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> RR-couplings were added to this action in [15, 16]. 2 A different an interesting approach to tachyon effective actions on brane-antibrane pairs was given in [18].</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Using these results, the spacetime effective action with non-zero gauge field profiles was conjectured in [23] as a plausible covariantization, however it was not derived from first principles.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Our convention is that any amplitude is computed with e −S .</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The boundary current superfield DuY is defined to be the boundary super-derivative of Y first taken to the boundary (where Y has Neumann boundary conditions). 2 This is a slight abuse of language, as this is not a gauge symmetry from the worldsheet perspective.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We added a 1 /2 normalization such that to take account for the factor 2 coming from the trace over the CP factor, since the contact term is multiplied by the identity matrix.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> As a side remark, for the rolling tachyon on a non-BPS D-brane, it was already noticed in [31] that the contact terms, that were absent in the original computation of the partition function performed in [32], did not contribute to the final result.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Notice that, if the boundary perturbations in (33) are superficially marginal, the resonances correspond to the appearance of a marginal operator in the boundary OPE.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> F 1 (−a + n + 2, −2a + n + 1; −2a + n + 2; −1) −2a + n + 1 + 2 F 1 (−a + n + 2, −2a + n + 3; −2a + n + 4; −1) −2a + n + 3</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> This is confirmed by a direct evaluation of the TTTT integral at ω = 1/4 (with Mathematica) which gives</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> This field redefinition was discussed in [13] for the r = 0 case. 2 We assume that, by the symmetries of the problem, only even powers of the fields and their derivative appear, i.e one has L(|τ | 2 , | ˙ τ | 2 , r 2 , ˙ r 2 ). Without loss of generality, as the phase of the tachyon for the &apos;half S-brane&apos; solution under study is constant, we take τ (t) real.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> It is true at least a fortiori from the convergence of the integrals and the series of the integrals. Note besides that we do not integrate over any pole.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> To be precise, we have P ({1, 2, 3 . . . 2n}) = {a1, a2, a3 . . . a2n}.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inflation from D -anti-D brane annihilation</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H S</forename>
				<surname>Alexander</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="023507" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low energy hadron physics in holographic QCD</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Sakai</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Sugimoto</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Prog. Theor. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="843" to="882" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tachyon condensation on the brane anti-brane system</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9808</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">012</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The tachyon potential in open Neveu-Schwarz string field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Berkovits</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">04</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">022</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On background independent open string field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5467" to="5473" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some computations in background independent off-shell string theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Witten</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3405" to="3410" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comment on the background independent open string theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Shatashvili</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">311</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Some exact results on tachyon condensation in string field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kutasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Marino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0010" to="045" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Remarks on tachyon condensation in super- string field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kutasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Marino</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">G</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W</forename>
				<surname>Moore</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rolling tachyon</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0204</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">048</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">L</forename>
				<surname>Karczmarek</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Maldacena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page">042</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Timelike boundary Liouville theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<surname>Gutperle</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Strominger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="126002" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tachyon effective actions in open string theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kutasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Niarchos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="666" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tachyon couplings on nonBPS D-branes and Dirac-Born-Infeld action</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Garousi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="584" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Wess-Zumino terms of Brane-Antibrane systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Garousi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Hatefi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="800" to="502" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">More on WZ action of non-BPS branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Garousi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">E</forename>
				<surname>Hatefi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0903" to="008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Notes on tachyon effective actions and Veneziano amplitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">V</forename>
				<surname>Niarchos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">69</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Erkal</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">D</forename>
				<surname>Kutasov</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<surname>Lunin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Brane-Antibrane Dynamics From the Tachyon DBI Action</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Brane -anti-brane forces</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Banks</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">L</forename>
				<surname>Susskind</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9511194</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tachyon Condensation on Separated Brane-Antibrane System</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Bagchi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page">010</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Boundary string field theory of the DD-bar system</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<surname>Kraus</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Larsen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">63</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Brane-antibrane action from boundary string field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Takayanagi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Terashima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">T</forename>
				<surname>Uesugi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="03" to="019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Improved brane anti-brane action from boundary super- string field theory and multivortex solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">T</forename>
				<surname>Jones</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<forename type="middle">H</forename>
				<surname>Tye</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0301" to="012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dirac-Born-Infeld action on the tachyon kink and vortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="066008" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">D-brane anti-D-brane effective action and brane interaction in open string channel</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Garousi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="01" to="029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Linear models of supersymmetric D-branes, hep-th</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">K</forename>
				<surname>Hori</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="12179" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group Theory from Quarks at the Ends of Strings</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Marcus</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Sagnotti</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys.Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">188</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">B</forename>
				<surname>Green</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<surname>Seiberg</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Contact interactions in superstring theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="559" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">String theory An introduction to the bosonic string</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Polchinski</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Univ. Pr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">402</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manifestly Supersymmetric RG Flows</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Gaberdiel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Hohenegger</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1002</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">052</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On open superstring partition function in inhomoge- neous rolling tachyon background</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Fotopoulos</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<forename type="middle">A</forename>
				<surname>Tseytlin</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0312" to="025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rolling tachyons and decaying branes</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">F</forename>
				<surname>Larsen</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Naqvi</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">S</forename>
				<surname>Terashima</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0302" to="039" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">M</forename>
				<forename type="middle">R</forename>
				<surname>Gaberdiel</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">A</forename>
				<surname>Konechny</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">C</forename>
				<surname>Schmidt-Colinet</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conformal perturbation theory beyond the leading order</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="105402" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proposal for the open string tachyon effective action in the linear dilaton background</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<surname>Kluson</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="0406" to="021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of the Selberg integral</title>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">P</forename>
				<forename type="middle">J</forename>
				<surname>Forrester</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">O</forename>
				<forename type="middle">W S</forename>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bull. Amer. Math. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="489" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">N</forename>
				<forename type="middle">D</forename>
				<surname>Lambert</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">H</forename>
				<surname>Liu</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName>
				<forename type="first">J</forename>
				<forename type="middle">M</forename>
				<surname>Maldacena</surname>
			</persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Closed strings from decaying D-branes, JHEP 0703</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page">014</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
