<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei>
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="1333124"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<front>
<lb/>
	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Differential Geometric Methods<lb/> in Theoretical Physics<lb/> Physics and Geometry<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>NATO ASI Series<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Advanced Science Institutes Series<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">A series presenting the results of activities sponsored by the NA TO Science Committee,<lb/> which aims at the dissemination of advanced scientific and technological knowledge,<lb/> with a view to strengthening links between scientific communities.<lb/> The series is published by an international board of publishers in conjunction with the<lb/> NATO Scientific Affairs Division<lb/> A<lb/> B<lb/> C<lb/> D<lb/> E<lb/> F<lb/> G<lb/> H<lb/></div>

	<keyword>Life Sciences<lb/> Physics<lb/> Mathematical<lb/> and Physical Sciences<lb/> Behavioral and Social Sciences<lb/> Applied Sciences<lb/> Computer and Systems Sciences<lb/> Ecological Sciences<lb/> Cell Biology<lb/> Plenum Publishing Corporation<lb/></keyword>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>New York and London<lb/> Kluwer Academic Publishers<lb/> Dordrecht, Boston, and London<lb/> Springer-Verlag<lb/> Berlin, Heidelberg, New York, London,<lb/> Paris, and Tokyo<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">Recent Volumes in this Series<lb/> Volume 238-Physics, Geometry, and Topology<lb/> edited by H. C. Lee<lb/> Volume 239-Kinetics of Ordering and Growth at Surfaces<lb/> edited by Max G. Lagally<lb/> Volume 240-Global Climate and Ecosystem Change<lb/> edited by Gordon J. MacDonald and Luigi Sertorio<lb/> Volume 241-Appl ied Laser Spectroscopy<lb/> edited by Wolfgang Demtr6der and Massimo Inguscio<lb/> Volume 242-Light, Lasers, and Synchrotron Radiation: A Health Risk Assessment<lb/> edited by</div>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>M. Grandolfo, A. Rindi, and D. H. Sliney<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Volume</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>243-0avydov&apos;s Soliton Revisited: Self-Trapping of<lb/> Vibrational Energy in Protein<lb/> edited by</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Peter L. Christiansen and Alwyn C. Scott<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Volume</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>244-Nonlinear Wave Processes in Excitable Media<lb/> edited by</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Arun V. Holden, Mario Markus, and Hans G. Othmer<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Volume</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>245-Differential Geometric Methods in Theoretical Physics:<lb/> Physics and Geometry<lb/> edited by Ling-Lie Chau and Werner Nahm<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<note type="other">Series B: Physics<lb/></note>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Differential Geometric Methods<lb/> in Theoretical Physics<lb/> Physics and Geometry<lb/> Edited by<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Ling-Lie Chau and Werner Nahm<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>University of California, Davis<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Davis, California<lb/></address>

	<note type="other">Springer Science+Business Media, LLC<lb/></note>

	<reference>Proceedings of the NATO Advanced Research Workshop<lb/> and the 18th International Conference on<lb/> Differential Geometric Methods in Theoretical Physics: Physics and Geometry,<lb/> held July 2-8, 1988,<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>at the University of California, Davis,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Davis, California<lb/></address>

	<note type="other">LIbrary of Congress Ca~aloging-in-Publica~lon Data<lb/></note>

	<reference>International Confe~ence on Differential Geometr1c Methods 1n<lb/> ,Theoretica1 PhysIcs, Physics and Geometry (18~h ,1988<lb/> University<lb/> of California, Davis)<lb/></reference>

	<div type="abstract">Differential geometric methods In theoretical physics--physlcs and<lb/> geometry I edited by Ling-Lie Chau and Werner Nah @BULLET.<lb/> p,<lb/> em. --(NATO ASI series. Series B, Physics; vol. 245)<lb/> ~Proceedlngs of the NATO Advanced Research Workshop and the 18th<lb/> International Conference on Differential Geo~etric Methods 1n<lb/> Theoretical Physics, Physics and Geometry, held July 2-8, 1988, at<lb/> the UniverSity of California. Davis. Davis, Californ1a~--T.p.<lb/> verso.<lb/> ~Publ1shed 1n cooperation with NATO Scientific Affairs Division. n<lb/> Includes bibliographical references and index.<lb/></div>

	<idno>ISBN 978-1</idno>

	<phone>-4684-9150-0<lb/> ISBN 978-1-4684-9148-7 (eBook)<lb/></phone>

	<idno>DOI 10.1007/978-1-4684-9148-7<lb/></idno>

	<div type="abstract">1. Geo~etry. 01fferenttal--Congresses. 2. Mathematical physics-<lb/>-Congresses. 3. Quantu~ f1eld theory--Congresses. 4. Str1ng<lb/> mode I s--Congresses. 5. Confor.a I 1 nvar I ants--Congresses.<lb/></div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>1. Chau,<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<reference>L1ng-Lie. II. Nahm. Werner. III. North Atlant1c Treaty<lb/> Organization. Sc1ent1fic Affairs Div1s1on.<lb/> IV. Title. V. Series:<lb/> NATO ASI ser1es. Sertes B. Physics; v. 245.<lb/> QC20.7.D52158 1988<lb/> 530.1&apos; 5636--dc20<lb/> 90-22720<lb/> © 1990 Springer Science+Business Media New York<lb/> Originally published by Plenum Press, New York in 1990.<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">Softcover reprint of the hardcover 1 st edition 1990<lb/> All rights reserved<lb/> CIP<lb/> No part of this book may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted<lb/> in any form or by any means, electronic, mechanical. photocopying, microfilming.<lb/> recording. or otherwise, without written permission from the Publisher<lb/></note>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>SPECIAL PROGRAM ON CHAOS, ORDER, AND PATTERNS<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<note type="other">This book contains the proceedings of a NATO Advanced Research Workshop<lb/> held within the program of activities of the NATO Special Program on<lb/> Chaos, Order, and Patterns.<lb/> Volume 20B-MEASURES OF COMPLEXITY AND CHAOS<lb/> edited by</note>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Neal B. Abraham, Alfonso M. Albano,<lb/> Anthony Passamante, and Paul E. Rapp<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">Volume 225-NONLINEAR EVOLUTION OF SPATIO-TEMPORAL STRUCTURES<lb/> IN DISSIPATIVE CONTINUOUS SYSTEMS<lb/> edited by F. H. Busse and L. Kramer<lb/> Volume 235-DISORDER AND FRACTURE<lb/> edited by J. C. Charmet, S. Roux, and E. Guyon<lb/> Volume 236-MICROSCOPIC SIMULATIONS OF COMPLEX FLOWS<lb/> edited by Michel Mareschal<lb/> Volume 240-GLOBAL CLIMATE AND ECOSYSTEM CHANGE<lb/> edited by</note>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Gordon J. MacDonald and Luigi Sertorio<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Volume 243-DAVYDOV&apos;S SOLITON REVISITED: Self-Trapping of Vibrational Energy<lb/> in Protein<lb/> edited by</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Peter L. Christiansen and Alwyn C. Scott<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Volume 244-NONLINEAR WAVE PROCESSES IN EXCITABLE MEDIA<lb/> edited by</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Arun V. Holden, Mario Markus, and Hans G. Othmer<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">Volume 245-DIFFERENTIAL GEOMETRIC METHODS IN THEORETICAL PHYSICS:<lb/> Physics and Geometry<lb/> edited by Ling-Lie Chau and Werner Nahm<lb/></note>

	<div type="abstract">PREFACE<lb/> After several decades of reduced contact, the interaction between physicists and<lb/> mathematicians in the front-line research of both fields recently became deep and fruit-<lb/>ful again. Many of the leading specialists of both fields became involved in this devel-<lb/>opment. This process even led to the discovery of previously unsuspected connections<lb/> between various subfields of physics and mathematics. In mathematics this concerns in<lb/> particular knots von Neumann algebras, Kac-Moody algebras, integrable non-linear<lb/> partial differential equations, and differential geometry in low dimensions, most im-<lb/>portantly in three and four dimensional spaces. In physics it concerns gravity, string<lb/> theory, integrable classical and quantum field theories, solitons and the statistical me-<lb/>chanics of surfaces. New discoveries in these fields are made at a rapid pace.<lb/> This conference brought together active researchers in these areas, reporting their<lb/> results and discussing with other participants to further develop thoughts in future new<lb/> directions. The conference was attended by SO participants from 15 nations. These<lb/> proceedings document the program and the talks at the conference. This conference<lb/> was preceded by a two-week summer school. Ten lecturers gave extended lectures on<lb/> related topics. The proceedings of the school will also be published in the NATO-AS[<lb/> volume by Plenum.<lb/> The Editors<lb/> vii<lb/> ACKNOWLEDGMENTS<lb/> We would like to thank the many people who have made the conference a success.<lb/> Furthermore, ·we appreciate the excellent talks. The active participation of everyone<lb/> present made the conference lively and stimulating. All of this made our efforts worth-<lb/>while.<lb/> The organization of the conference would have been impossible without the excel-<lb/>lent service provided by the staff members at the Physics Department of the University<lb/> of California at Davis (UCD):</div>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Mary Schenck, Tom Mezzanares, Nilda Muniz, Madelin<lb/> Cameron, Shanti Chitradurgam, and Lynn Rabena</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">. The running of the School and<lb/> Conference could not have gone so smoothly without the help of many participants,<lb/> in particular Evan Fletcher, Andrew Parkes and Itaru Yamanaka. It is also our plea-<lb/>sure to thank Mr. and Mrs. Parson and their staff, who have made the Granlibakken<lb/> Conference Center in Tahoe City an excellent place to have enjoyable meetings.<lb/> Of course, none of this would have happened without the financial support of our<lb/> sponsors: NATO, UCD (the Physics Department and the Dean&apos;s Office of Letters and<lb/> Science). We would like to thank Robert Shelton, Chair of the Physics Department,<lb/> and Giovanni Venturi of NATO Scientific Affairs for their encouragement and generous<lb/> support.<lb/> ix<lb/> CONTENTS<lb/> Introduction to the 18th Conference on &apos;Differential Geometrical<lb/> Methods in Theoretical</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Physics&apos; .................................... 1<lb/> K. Bleuler<lb/> (1) Integrable Systems<lb/> Baxterization .................................................................... 5<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>V.F.R. Jones<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Geometric Classification of Commutative Algebras of<lb/> Ordinary Differential Operators .................................. 13<lb/> M. Mulase<lb/> Geometrical Aspects of Solvable Two Dimensional Models .. ...................... 29<lb/> K. Tanaka<lb/> Explicit Soliton-Generating Backlund Transformations ........................... 41<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>H.-C. Yen and J.C. Shaw<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">Integrability Conditions: Recent results in the theory<lb/> of integrable models</note>

	<note type="degree">.......... · ..... · .. · .. ···.·····.····.</note>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>··········47<lb/> R. Bullough, S. Olafsson, Yu-Zhong Chen, and J. Timonen<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Nonlinear Differential Equations in Physics and Their Geometrical<lb/> Integrability Properties ........................................... 71<lb/> L.-L. Chau<lb/> Integrability Off Criticality and Quantum Integrable Systems ..................... 79<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>P. Mathieu<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Quantization of the Chiral Solitonic Bag Model . ................................. 87<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>N.K. Pak and T. Yilmaz<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>(2) Operator Algebras<lb/> Structure of Superselection Sectors in Low-Dimensional Quantum<lb/> Field Theory ..................................................... 95<lb/> K. Fredenhagen<lb/> xi<lb/> Cyclic Cohomology, Supersymmetry and [{AIS States<lb/> The [{MS States as Generalized Elliptic Operators ............... 105<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>D. Kastler<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Symmetries of Quantum Space, Braid Representation, and<lb/> Classification of Subfactors ......................................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>111<lb/> A.Ocneanu<lb/></address>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>New Kinematics (Statistics and Symmetry) in Low-Dimensional QFT<lb/> with Applications to Conformal Q FT2</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<note type="degree">........................... 119<lb/> B. Schroer<lb/> Infinite Index Embeddings ...................................................... 145<lb/> R. Herman<lb/></note>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>(3) Conformal Field Theory<lb/> Non-Compact Current Algebras and Heterotic Superstring Vacua ................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>141<lb/> 1. Bars<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Aspects of Perturbed Conformal Field Theory, Affine Toda Field<lb/> Theory and Exact S-Matrices .................................... 169<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>H.W. Braden, E. Corrigan, P.E. Dorey, and R. Sasaki<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Codes, Lattices and Conformal Field Theory ............... .....................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>183<lb/> P. Goddard<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Topics on Conformal Field Theory ............................................. 185<lb/> C. Itzykson<lb/> Feigin-Fuchs Representation of Conformal Field Theory ........................ 181<lb/> D. N emeschansky<lb/> Coulomb-Gas Construction on Higher-Genus Riemann Surfaces ................. 189<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>J. Bagger and M. Goulian<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Conformal Algebras and Non-linear Differential<lb/> Equations .......................................................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>203<lb/> 1. Bakas<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>S Matrices of the TricriticaI Ising 1&apos;v[ode! and Toda Systems .....................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>213<lb/> P. Christe<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Quantum Groups, Braiding Matrices and Coset Models .........................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>223<lb/> H. Itoyama<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Gauged WZW Models and the Coset Construction of Conformal<lb/> Field Theories ...................................................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>231<lb/> D. Karabali<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Flat Connection, Conformal Field Theory and Quantum Group ................. 251<lb/> M. Kato<lb/> Classical and Quantum Calabi-Yau Manifolds .................................. 251<lb/> R. Schimmrigk<lb/> Conformal Field Theories and Category Theory ................................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>211<lb/> R. Brustein, Y. Ne&apos;eman,</address>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>and S. Sternberg<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>xii<lb/> Quantum Backlund Transformations and Conformal Algebras ................... 279<lb/> T. Curtright<lb/> A Coset-Construction for Integrable Hierarchies .... ............................ 291<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>F.A. Bias and K. de Vos<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Away From Criticality: Some Results From the S Matrix Approach ............. 297<lb/> G. Mussardo<lb/> Normal Ordered Products and Parafields in Conformal Field Theory ........... 309<lb/> W. Nahm<lb/> Chiral Gauge Field Theory in Two Dimensions ................................. 315<lb/> J. Quackenbush<lb/> Monodromy Properties of Conformal Field Theories and Quantum Groups ......</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>323<lb/> P. Valtancoli<lb/></address>

	<email>(</email>

	<div type="abstract">4) Quantum Groups<lb/> Matrix elements of unitary representations of the quantum<lb/> group SUq (l, 1) and the basic hypergeometric functions .</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>.......... 331<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>K. Ueno, T. Masuda, K. Mimachi, Y. Nakagami, M. Noumi, and Y. Saburi<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<note type="degree">A</note>

	<note type="title">q-Analogue of the Lie Superalgebra OSp{2,1</note>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>) and its<lb/> Metaplectic Representation ... .................................... 345<lb/> C. Devchand<lb/> q-Deformation of SU(l, 1) Conformal Ward Identities and q-Strings ............ 353<lb/> A. LeClair<lb/> Q-Deformation of 8£(2, c) x ZN and Link Invariants . ........................... 359<lb/> R.C. Lee<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<reference>Quantum Group Duality in Vertex Models and Other Results in<lb/> the Theory of Quasitriangular Hopf Algebras</reference>

	<note type="degree">. .................... 373<lb/> S. Majid<lb/> (5) Strings<lb/></note>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Physics at the Planck Length and p-Adic Field Theories ........................ 387<lb/> LY. Aref&apos;eva<lb/> Non-Archimedean Geometry and Applications to Particle Theory ................ 399<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>P.R. Frampton<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Beyond Conformal Field Theory ............................................... 409<lb/> P. Nelson<lb/> Hidden Symmetries of Strings and Their Relevance for<lb/> String Quantization ............................................. 415<lb/> K. Pohlmeyer<lb/> Hamiltonian Flows, SU{oo), SO (co), USp{oo), and Strings ..................... 423<lb/> C. Zachos<lb/> A Geometric Approach To The String BRS Cohomology . ....................... 431<lb/> R. Aratyn<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">xiii<lb/></note>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Progress in Multi-Genus Calculations for the Spinning String</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<note type="degree">...................</note>

	<address>445<lb/> A. Parkes<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>The Minimal Set of the Generators of Dehn Twists on a High Genus<lb/> Riemann Surface ...... · ................. · ...... · ................ 455<lb/> C.-Z. Zha<lb/> Strings and Teichmueller Space ................................................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>465<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>K. Bugajska<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Holomorphic Differentials on Punctured Riemann Surfaces . ..................... 475<lb/> R. Dick<lb/> Anomalies, BRS Symmetry and Superconnections ............................... 485<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>A.C. Hirshfeld<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>General Covariance and Strings . ............................................... 493<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>F.R. Klinkhamer<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Spontaneous Symmetry Breaking in 4-Dimensional Heterotic String ............. 497<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>J. Maharana<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Superghost Fields in N = 2 Superconformal Algebra .............................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>505<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>S. Nam<lb/> (6) Topological QFT<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Topological Quantum Field Theories: Relations Between Knot Theory and<lb/> Four Manifold Theory ........................................... 513<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>B. Grossman<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Topological Quantum Theories and Representation Theory ...................... 533<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>P. Woit<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Topological Chern-Simons Gauge Theories and &quot;New&quot; Knot/Link Polynomials</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<email>.. 547<lb/></email>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>y-S. Wu<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Observables in Topological Yang-J&apos;vIills Theory and the Gribov Problem .......... 563<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>H. Kanno<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Linking</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<note type="title">the Gauss-Bonnet-Chern Theorem, Essential Hopf JHaps and<lb/> Nlembrane Solitons with Exotic</note>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Spin and Statistics ............... 571<lb/> C.-H. Tze<lb/> Moduli Spaces and Topological Quantum Field Theories ... ...................... 585<lb/> J. Sonnenschein<lb/> Knots in Physics .............................................................. 593<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>M.U. Werner<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>(7) Geometry and Supergeometry<lb/> Supermanifold, Symplectic Structure and Geometric Quantization<lb/> of BRST Systems ............................................... 60S<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>S.-M. Fei, H.-Y. Guo, and Y. Yu.<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Ambitwistors and Conformal Gravity . .......................................... 621<lb/> C. LeBrun<lb/> xiv<lb/> Toward Classification of Classical Lie Superalgebras ............................ 633<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>D.A. Leites<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Status of the Algebraic Approach to Super Riemann Surfaces . ................... 653<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>J.M. Rabin<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Projective Embeddings of Complex Supermanifolds ..............................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>669<lb/> R.O. Wells<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Some Results on Line Bundles over SUSY-Curves .............................. 675<lb/> C. Bartocci, U. Bruzzo,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>and D. Hernandez Ruiperez<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Instantons From Supersymmetric Conformal Chiral Scalar<lb/> Superfield Theories .............................................. 681<lb/> S. Catto<lb/> Einstein-Hermitian Bundles over Complex Surfaces . ............................ 689<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>F.J. Flaherty<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Symplectic Reduction of the Minimally Coupled lvlassless<lb/> Superparticle in D= 1 0 ........................................... 693<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>J. Hamad, J.A. Shapiro, S. Shnider, and C.C. Taylor.<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>(8) Gravity<lb/> Quantum Gravity and the Berry Phase ......................................... 703<lb/> G. Venturi<lb/> Gravity and Lorentz Breakdown in Higher-Dimensional<lb/> Theories and Strings ............................................ 715<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>V.A. Kostelecky and S. Samuel<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Current Algebra and Extended 2D Gravity With Higher Spin Gauge Field ....... 727<lb/> Y. Matsuo<lb/> The Parametric lvlanifold Picture of Space-Time ................................</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>741<lb/></address>

	<reference>Z. Perjes<lb/> Gravity as an 50(3,2</reference>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>) Gauge Theory .......................................... 757<lb/> S. Gotzes<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">(9) Others<lb/></note>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Heuristics of Solitary Waves in Non-Integrable Field Theories .................. 767<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>D.K. Campbell<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Lattice Approach of the Antiferromagentic Heisenberg lvlodel<lb/> in 2+1 Dimensions and the</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Hopf Chern-Simons Terms ........... 769<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>W.-Z. Li<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Is It Possible To Do Canonical Quantum Field Theory Rigorously? ............. 779<lb/> R.N. Sen<lb/> A Global Theory of Parametrized Quantum Mechanics . ......................... 787<lb/> L.N. Chang and</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">Y. Liang<lb/> xv<lb/> Principal Bundles Versus Lie Groupoids in Gauge Theory 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 79.&apos;3<lb/> MoE. Mayer<lb/> Static and Axially Symmetric Soliton Solutions to the Self-Dual SU(.&apos;3)<lb/> and SU(2) Gauge Fields in a Euclidean Space 0000000000000000000080.&apos;3<lb/> DoBo Papadopoulos<lb/> Superalgebra and Superspace of Vector Spinor Generators 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 81.&apos;3<lb/> So Rajpoot<lb/> Participants 0 0</div>

	<phone>0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 819<lb/></phone>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>A uthor Index</titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<phone>0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 @BULLET 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 827<lb/> Subject Index 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 829<lb/></phone>

	<note type="other">xvi<lb/></note>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>INTRODUCTION TO THE 18TH CONFERENCE ON &apos;DIFFERENTIAL GEOMET-<lb/>RICAL METHODS IN THEORETICAL PHYSICS&apos;<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Konrad Bleuler<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Institut fur Theoretische Kernphysik<lb/> University of Bonn<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Nussallee 14-16<lb/> D-530o Bonn<lb/> W-Germany<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">With greatest pleasure and with deep thankfulness towards our<lb/> community of mathematicians and physicists I am looking back<lb/> over all these years of beautiful and friendly meetings with-<lb/>in the framework of our long lasting series. They were held<lb/> in different countries and attended by scientists of differ-<lb/>ent background and different ideas: There was, however, one<lb/> general, invariant and common aim, namely a fruitful and open-<lb/>minded exchange between representatives of the two sciences,<lb/> mainly within the framework of recent developments with its<lb/> far-reaching achievements in both domains. Although this ex-<lb/>change should rather be looked upon as a renewal of important<lb/> contacts, which existed (after a longer period of separation)<lb/> already in the course of earlier periods, connected to de-<lb/>cisive renewals, slight, perhaps subconscious, feelings of a<lb/> deep-rooted separation, or perhaps, a droplet of fear in bet-<lb/>ween the two camps, may occasionally still be felt. In this<lb/> connection it should be emphasized that these contacts became<lb/> due to the latest breathtaking developments -in particular<lb/> through the impact and the far-reaching consequences of the<lb/> &apos;Strings&apos; -not just important but absolutely &apos;vital&apos; for<lb/> future research. In connection with our search for a new and<lb/> deeper basis it may be remembenrlthat the ultimate scope of<lb/> theoretical physics has always been the discovery of natural<lb/> (abstract but natural and, in a way, simple) mathematical<lb/> structures hidden far behand empirical facts. This calls, how-<lb/>ever for a long way of successive steps, mainly with the help&apos;<lb/> of intermediate phenomenological theories. It should, however,<lb/> be emphasized that the beauty and simplicity of really basic<lb/> physical laws is revealed only when expressed in terms of the<lb/> corresponding (partly pre-existing and partly to be discover-<lb/>ed) mathematical concepts. In other words: Existing structures<lb/> of mathematics are, in a way, re-discovered through empirical<lb/> evidence, whereas -on the other side -insights and practic-<lb/>al needs in physical research lead in some cases to the creat-<lb/>ion of new and basic mathematical domains. These far-reaching<lb/> relations between abstract thoughts and facts of nature was<lb/> looked at by some of our greatest scientists (e.g. Einstein,<lb/> Pauli, Dirac, Wigner, a.s.o.)as an unexpected, even super-<lb/>DIfferential Geometric Methods in Theorelical PhYSics<lb/> Edited by L.-L. Chau and W. Nahm, Plenum Press, New York, 1990<lb/> human wonder, or, in different terms, a great mystery. These,<lb/> as many of you might say, old-fashioned, even forgotten view-<lb/>pOints were, in a way, revived in the course of our meetings<lb/> and became, in fact, a leading aim.<lb/> The main themes of our discussions were, therefore, those<lb/> which naturally called for this exchange and came up in the<lb/> course of our series, i.e. since &apos;71: Starting with General<lb/> Relativity (G.R.), i.e. a classical domain of common interest<lb/> since its foundation, we went on with -extensively studied -<lb/>&apos;Geometric Quantisation&quot; in all its different forms, leaving<lb/> us, however, with the insight that no canonically invariant<lb/> and unique &apos;Quantisation-scheme&apos; for an arbitrary classical<lb/> system does (nor should!) exist. The next important topic -<lb/>basiC for recent developments in physics -was &apos;Supersym-<lb/>metry&apos;, i.e.&apos;Super-Lie-algebras&apos;,&apos;Superspaces&apos;, a.s.o., which<lb/> -suggested, or better, founded by physicists, i.e. Wess and<lb/> Zumino -represents by now (according to a remark made before)<lb/> a new and important domain of mathematics, which now stands<lb/> in its own right. A similar, even more imPFessive situation<lb/> stems from the advent of non-Abelian (and non-local!) Gauge-<lb/>theory: It was, originally, based on a most natural and in-<lb/>tuitive geometrical idea taken over (in &apos;29) by H. Weyl from<lb/> G.R. suggesting a gauge theoretical interpretation of the<lb/> Maxwellian field. Enlarged (in &apos;54) by Yang-Mills to the non-<lb/>-Abelian case, it led to an englobing formulation of all<lb/> basic fields in physics as well as (in ideal cases) to a<lb/> satisfactory field-quantisation, a fact which points to a<lb/> deep relation between geometry and the quantum theory. In<lb/> our present-day situation, non-Abelian Gauge appears to be<lb/> the underlying principle of all basic laws in physics, i.e.<lb/> Gravitation (G.R.) Electroweak (GWS) and String (QeD) inter-<lb/>actions. On the other side it appears appealing to observe<lb/> that very much the same principle constitutes also an import-<lb/>ant tool in pure mathematics. In other words: A geometric<lb/> principle which embraces the entire realm of known empirical<lb/> data (leading, through QeD, to a complete theoretical basis<lb/> for Hadrons and Nuclei as well as, through GWS, to a most<lb/> satisfactory half-phenomenological description of electro-<lb/>weak processes) constitutes, at the same time, the major in-<lb/>gredient for prooving, according Donaldson, the special (un-<lb/>expected!) topological properties of R(4). We thus find un-<lb/>expectedly a certain number of &apos;mysterious&apos; relations bet-<lb/>ween apparently separated domains.<lb/> Up to this point, mathematical structures with their most<lb/> successful and intuitive viewpoints are still under control<lb/> or are governed through the overwhelming and most extended<lb/> realm of empirical facts: The choice of the various Gauge<lb/> groups as well as the numerical values of certain parameters<lb/> are entirely due to a comparison to experimental data. This<lb/> situation has, however, drastically changed, even inverted,<lb/> with the advent of Strings. Mathematical arguments, i.e.<lb/> Simplicity, inner logics and, as a main point, consist8ncy<lb/> (cp. the longstanding problem of quantizing Gravitation)<lb/> prevail against direct comparisons with physical facts which,<lb/> for the time being, seem<lb/> to loose their basic importance.<lb/> This situation aroused, of course, a widespread criticism.<lb/> We should, however, not forget that we have to deal, in fact,<lb/> with a kind of an intermediate stage towards a deeper under-<lb/>2<lb/> standing of nature, and that the few (partial) successes as<lb/> well as the various failures aroused an enormous interest for<lb/> further and deeper research! This &apos;tantalizing&apos; situation led,<lb/> in fact, to a far-reaching and fruitful, to a large extent<lb/> mathematical,research: Well-known examples are the revival of<lb/> &apos;Braidgroups&apos; in their connections to &apos;Knots and Links&apos;,<lb/> which, in turn, led to the really basic topological concept<lb/> of &apos;Jones&apos; Polynomials&apos;. At the same time, these groups are<lb/> intimately related to the fundamental &apos;Yang-Baxter&apos; equations,<lb/> which lead, in turn, to the connection of these various con-<lb/>cepts to Statistical Mechanics and, finally, as a last, de-<lb/>cisive step, to the central problem, namely conformal String<lb/> theory, i.e. the origin of these important developments. In<lb/> short, a large number of unexpected relations between<lb/> apparently independent mathematical domains was, again, re-<lb/>vealed just through various valuable attempts for reaching,<lb/> with the help of the &apos;Strings&apos;, a deeper and consistent under-<lb/>standing of physical laws.<lb/> Another major consequence of the string attempt -in relat-<lb/>ion to the (enforced!) introduction of extreme dimensions,<lb/> i.e. the Planck length -represents the renewal of an old<lb/> question related to the very basis of physics, namely the<lb/> structure of space-time in small dimensions. Many of us may<lb/> have forgotten that B. Riemann wrote, as a final sentence of<lb/> this famous thesis on &apos;his&apos; geometry, more than 100 years<lb/> ago: While this (i.e. his) geometry might be natural and suit-<lb/>able for large dimensions, a different (e.g. discrete) geo-<lb/>metry should be considered for extremely small spaces. This,<lb/> in fact, most impressive and, in a way, unexpected hypothesis<lb/> within the second part of this sentence was -after such a<lb/> long interval of time -remembered, or better, revived by<lb/> A. Connes when introducing his basic &apos;non-commutative Geo-<lb/>metry&apos;. Although its general and consistent use as a new<lb/> basis for physics altogether is far from being accomplished,<lb/> it appears most appealing to realize its connection and gene-<lb/>ral relation to 2-dim. QFT according K. Osterwalder et al on<lb/> one side</div>

	<reference>and D. Kastler on the other (cp. Com.Math.Phys.118,<lb/> 1-14 (1988) and 121, 345-450 (1989»</reference>

	<div type="abstract">. This &apos;discovery&apos; of an-<lb/>other &apos;unexpected&apos; relation between so far definitely se-<lb/>parated domains enlarging the analogous situation about<lb/> &apos;Knots and Links&apos; a.s.o. (mentioned above) might represent a<lb/> hint as to the existence of a far deeper theoretical view-<lb/>point -so far hidden -hopefully explaining a.o. all these<lb/> strange and unexpected relations. We are thus in a most in-<lb/>teresting, even breath-taking period of research in which<lb/> again, i.e. after the advent of Relativity and Quantur.1Theory<lb/> the very basis of physics is under critical discussion and<lb/> seriously questioned. I think that this fact endows this<lb/> week&apos;s discussion with a special interest and with a far-<lb/>-reaching scientific aim.<lb/> The central problem is -among others -to relate these far-<lb/>-reaching, mainly mathematical, research on one side with<lb/> the really enormously anlarged realm of empirical evidence<lb/> on t~e other. The ancient and characteristic polarisation,<lb/> whic~, at the same time, represents the real interest and<lb/> drivi~g force in research, appears by now in a most acute<lb/> for~.<lb/> 3<lb/> I should, however, not end without conveying, in the name of<lb/> all of us, the heartiest thanks to our organizers,<lb/> Ling-Lie Chau and Werner Nahm, for organizing the 18th<lb/> meeting at this wonderful spot, and I should not forget to<lb/> thank, at the same time, the organizers of all these former<lb/> meetings in</div>

	<address>France, Poland, Italy, Israel and in Germany.<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>4<lb/> BAXTERIZATION<lb/> V.F.R. Jones @BULLET<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Centre for Mathematical Analysis<lb/> Australian National University<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>GPO Box 4<lb/> Canberra ACT 2601<lb/> Australia<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">In statistical mechanics one is interested in the globally observable properties of a<lb/> system with an enormous number of degrees of freedom. One approach to the analysis<lb/> of such systems is to define simplistic mathematical models which can be calculated<lb/> exactly. The first example is the Ising model, solved by Onsager in 1944. A state of the<lb/> system is defined by a configuration of + and -signs (spins) at the vertices of a square<lb/> lattice in the plane. Each edge of the lattice is to be thought of as an interaction and<lb/> contributes an energy E( a, a&apos;) to the total energy where a, a&apos; are the spins at the ends<lb/> of the edge. Thus in the Ising model the total energy of a state (T is<lb/> L kWl,jai+l,j +k2a i,ja i,j+l<lb/> t,j<lb/> The partition function is then :lefined (for any system) to be<lb/> Z = L exp( -E(a)j kT)<lb/> Note that Z depends on some parameters (kl&apos; k2, kT). We will adopt the convention<lb/> of summing up this dependence of Z (in any model) by a single &quot;parameter&quot; called the<lb/> &quot;spectral parameter&quot; A. Thus Z = Z(A).<lb/> The partition function does not make sense for an infinite system so we consider<lb/> rectangular approximations to the system with N vertices and let ZN be the corre-<lb/>sponding partition function (the boundary conditions need to be treated in some way,<lb/> e.g., periodic). Then the free energy per site is defined as F(A) = lim tlog(Zn),<lb/> N~oo<lb/> where the union of the appproximating rectangles is the whole lattice. One would like<lb/> to calculate F(,\) explicitly as a function of A. This is called &quot;solving&quot; a model.<lb/></div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>* Home Institution: Mathemati.:s Department, University of California, Berkeley,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Berkeley, CA<lb/> 94720, USA<lb/></address>

	<reference>Differential Geometric Methods in Theoretical Physics<lb/> 5<lb/> Edited by L.-L. Chau and W. Nahm. Plenum Press. New York, 19&apos;1O<lb/></reference>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>A BAXTER STRATEGY<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<div type="abstract">The most successful technique in solving models is the method of transfer matrices.<lb/> One concocts a matrix T(A) (depending on the horizontal dimension m of the approx-<lb/>imating rectangle) such that trace (T(At) is the partition function for the m x n<lb/> rectangle. The largest eigenvalue of T( A) then gives the limit of F( A) as n -+ 00.<lb/> Unfortunately the size of T(A) grows exponentially with m so diagonalization is not<lb/> straightforward.<lb/> Baxter&apos;s idea was to consider systems for which the transfer matrices commute<lb/> among themselves for different values of A, thus T(A)T(A&apos;) = T(A&apos;)T().,). Then the<lb/> T(A)&apos;S have a common eigenvector v and T(A)V = f().,)v. By a detailed analysis of the<lb/> symmetries and analytic dependence of the matrix entries of T()&quot;) on A, the Baxter<lb/> program is then able to nail down a finite list of possible functions !().,), in particular<lb/> the largest. By an act of faith this !max( A) does actually occur and the model is solved.<lb/> But how is one to find systems for which the transfer matrices commute? It is nat-<lb/>ural to factorize the matrix T()&quot;) as Rm(A)Rm-l().,) ... Rl(A) where each Ri corresponds<lb/> to adding an energy contribution at the ith position. Then one can ask the question: is<lb/> there a local condition, involving the Ri&apos;s, which guarantees that the T()&quot;)&apos;s commute?<lb/> Suppose that for each A and ).,&apos; there is a third A&quot; such that (letting Ri(A&apos;) = R: etc.)<lb/> (YBE)<lb/> and<lb/> RiRj = RjRi for Ii -jl ~ 2.<lb/> Then an easy computation (see [Ba]) shows that<lb/> {RmR::&apos;(R;&quot;)-l }TT&apos; = T&apos;T{ Rll (R,{)-l RD ..<lb/> Thus up to boundary terms the transfer matrices commute. It is to be hoped, and<lb/> indeed true in a host of examples, that the boundary conditions can be defined so that<lb/> these te;-ms disappear and we have commuting transfer matrices.<lb/> Using this method Baxter defined and solved a model (the &quot;8 vertex model&quot;) that<lb/> generalized the &quot;six vertex method&quot; solved using a Bethe ansatz technique by Lieb.<lb/> The theory of &quot;quantum groups&quot; was designed by Jimbo and Drinfeld to produce<lb/> examples of R:s satisfying YBE. They certainly find such examples for any simple Lie<lb/> algebra g and any finite dimensional representation of g (see [Ji] and [Dr]). Note that<lb/> there is a free parameter q in these Ri(A) solutions.<lb/> THE BRAID GROUPS<lb/> A geometric braid on n strings is a way to tying two horizontal sticks together with<lb/> the strings so that the tangent vector to each string always has a non-zero vertical<lb/> component. Thus<lb/> is an example of a 4-string braid. Braids form a group with concatenation as operation.<lb/> 6<lb/> Thu, if a ~ N a n d P ~ R. tben ap ~ :ill:. The identit.y element i&quot;<lb/> obviou,ly the b&lt;aid ill. and the inve,,, of a bmid i, obtained by &quot;fi~t.ing it in<lb/> a mirror and turning it upside down.<lb/> Thus for each n we have a group En which has a natural surjection onto the<lb/> symmetric group 5&quot; given by permutation of the end points.<lb/> If we define O&quot;i, for 1 :::; i &lt; n as the braid<lb/> I I X I I<lb/> i+ 1<lb/> then the following relations are easy to see<lb/> (Br)<lb/> (fiO&quot;j = 0&quot;)0&quot;; if Ii -jl 2: z.<lb/> E. Artin proved that the braid group is actually equal to the group presented on<lb/> 0&quot;1, ... ,0&quot;10-1 with relations (Br). Thus to define a representation of the braid group it<lb/> suffices to find matrices O&quot;i satisfying (Br).<lb/> The similarity between (B:-) and (YBE) is striking and one could look for repre-<lb/>sentations of En using the Ri(&apos;\)&apos;S of solvable models. The actual way to get rid of<lb/> the spectral parameter to get a nontrivial representation may be subtle. Typically<lb/> one will have to let the A&apos;s go to infinity in some controlled way. But in the cases of<lb/> models obtained from quantum groups this always works so we get, for every simple<lb/> Lie algebra g, and every finite dimensional representation of it, a representation of En,<lb/> for every n, depending on a parameter q.<lb/> KNOTS AND LINKS<lb/> A knot is a smooth non-s,~lf intersecting curve in 53. Two knots are equivalent<lb/> if there is a diffeomorphism of 53 taking one onto the other. Knots always admit<lb/> projections onto n 2 whose singularities are at worst double points so one may always<lb/> draw a picture which adequately, but highly non-uniquely, represents the knot.<lb/> 7<lb/> e.g.<lb/> 0<lb/> C()J CQJ c~ ~~<lb/> the unknot<lb/> trefoil<lb/> figure 8<lb/> Conway knot<lb/> Links are &quot;knots with several components&quot;,<lb/> e.g.<lb/> 00<lb/> ® c@ ~<lb/> unlink on<lb/> Hopf<lb/> Whitehead<lb/> Borromean<lb/> 2 components<lb/> Link<lb/> Link<lb/> rings<lb/> It is in general difficult to tell, from looking at pictures of knots, whether they<lb/> are the same or not. What one needs are invariants, i.e., entities associated with the<lb/> knot in 3-space rather than &apos;just the picture. Most invariants are obtained by looking<lb/> at the topological space obtained when the knot is removed from 3-space and doing<lb/> some algebraic topology. The simplest such invariant is the order of the homology<lb/> mod N of the canonical 2-fold cover of the complement of the knot. It was one .of the<lb/> first invariants used in knot theory. Another well known invariant, discovered in 1928<lb/> by J. Alexander [AJ, is the Alexander polynomial b.L(t) which is obtained from the<lb/> homology of the infinite cyclic cover of the knot. For the trefoil b..= t-I -1 + t and<lb/> for the Conway knot b. = l.<lb/> Given a braid a E En, it may be turned into an oriented link by &quot;closing&quot; it as<lb/> below<lb/> a<lb/> closure =<lb/> 1\<lb/> a<lb/> It is a result of Alexander that any oriented link may be obtained in this way. So<lb/> it was natural to look for invariants of links by studying representations of the braid<lb/> groups. In particular one may look at representations coming from solvable models as<lb/> described above. Since the partition function is given by the trace, it is natural to take<lb/> the trace of the matrix given by the braid. The remarkable result is that, if the trace<lb/> is slightly modified (corresponding to special boundary conditions), all models coming<lb/> from quantum groups give polynomial invariants (in the variable q) of links in this way.<lb/> This was proved by Rosso and Reshetikhin. Thus to every simple Lie algebra g and<lb/> every finite dimensional representation of it there is a knot polynomial.<lb/> 8<lb/> The simplest example is for sl2 in its 2-dimensional representation. The corre-<lb/>sponding polynomial is called VL(q), and the corresponding model is a 6-vertex model.<lb/> As examples, vtrefoil = q+q3_ q4, Vfig.8 = q-2_ q-1+1_q+q2, Vconway = complicated.<lb/> The n-dimensional representations of sin combine to form a 2-variable polynomial PL<lb/> known as the HOMFLY polynomial and the sympletic and orthogonal algebras (in<lb/> their defining representations) combine to form the Kauffman polynomial FL.<lb/> It is indeed a bizarre way to obtain knot invariants: we took a link, turned it into a<lb/> braid, used some infinite limit in the spectral parameter of a solvable model to obtain<lb/> a braid group representation and then took a modified trace of the braid to get our<lb/> invariant! It must be said that this process is not very well understood at this stage. It<lb/> is possible to avoid the use of braids by using the statistical mechanical model directly<lb/> on an arbitrary link diagram and calculating its partition function. In the infinite limit<lb/> of the spectral parameter one obtains an invariant. But the role of solvability and the<lb/> reason for the infinite limit remain obscure. (See also [W].)<lb/> BAXTERIZATION<lb/> In a small attempt to understand the correspondence between solvable models<lb/> and knot theory I propose the following procedure: take a knot invariant, turn it (if<lb/> possible) into a coherent sequence of braid group representations, and then Baxterize<lb/> (if possible) by inserting a spectral parameter so that YBE is satisfied and so that the<lb/> original braid group representation is the infinite limit in the spectral parameter of the<lb/> Baxterized version.<lb/> The simplest way to Baxterize the O&quot;;s is what I call selJ-Baxterization where RiP)<lb/> actually belongs to the algebra generated by O&quot;i. I know of many cases where this is<lb/> possible, the first two I shall give are uniVErsal Baxterizations<lb/> 1) Hecke case<lb/> If the O&quot;:s satisfy a quadratic equation it is possible to renormalize them so that<lb/> 0&quot;; + 0&quot;;1 = xl<lb/> Then we simply put<lb/> R ( &apos;)<lb/> A<lb/> -A -1<lb/> ; /\ = e O&quot;i + e 0&quot;;<lb/> Equation (YBE) follows immediately.<lb/> BIRMAN-MURAKMvII-WENZL CASE (see [BW])<lb/> Suppose that O&quot;;s have the following property for some numbers x and a:<lb/> (BMW)<lb/> 1<lb/> (define Ei = -(O&quot;i + 0&quot;:-1) -1)<lb/> x<lb/> &apos;<lb/> E; = (a+a-1-x)-lEi<lb/> E ·~±l E· -a&apos;FIE· E ~±1 E· -a&apos;F1E·<lb/> lvi_l 1 -<lb/>1,<lb/> ,vi+l 1 -<lb/>l<lb/> EWi&apos;FJO&quot;i = E;Ei±l<lb/> (the reader should understand these relations by representing Ei by a &quot;braid like&quot;<lb/> object ~ , an idea due to Kauffman). Then one may show with some pain that<lb/> satisfies (YBE). The result can also be deduced with a different kind of pain, from<lb/> limbo&apos;s paper [Ji].<lb/> 9<lb/> Thus whenever a braid group representation factors through the Hecke or BMW<lb/> algebras it can be Baxterized.<lb/> ABELIAN BAXTERIZATION<lb/> Abelian Baxterization is when the Rj()&quot;)&apos;s commute among themselves for different<lb/> values of).,. Self-Baxterization is necessarily abelian Non-abelian. Baxterization occurs<lb/> in quantum group theory. For the adjoint representation of S/3, the Ri ().,)&apos; s do not<lb/> commute. I will return to this later.<lb/> To see an example of abelian Baxterization which is not self-Baxterization I turn<lb/> to the main example of this talk (also seen in [KMM]), where we see that the simplest<lb/> of all knot invariants, the homology of the double cover mod N, can be Baxterized.<lb/> Let Dn be the algebra on generators Ul, U2, ... , U n-l with relations uf = 1, u/u/+] =<lb/> WU/+IU/(W = _e 27r / N ), UkU/ = U/Uk if 11-kl 2: 2. Then it is easy to show that if we<lb/> N-l<lb/> .<lb/> define O&apos;k = I: wj2ui, that the braid group relations are satisfied. It is equally easy<lb/> j=O<lb/> to see that the trace on Dn defined by tr(w) = 0 if w is a non-scalar product of u;s,<lb/> has the right property (Markov) to define a link invariant. In [GJl it is shown that the<lb/> absolute value of this invariant is, at least for N odd, the order of the homology of the<lb/> 2-fold branched cover mod N. One can attempt to Baxterize these representations but<lb/> if one looks in [FZl one finds that the models already exist. The Fateev Zamolodchikov<lb/> model has transfer matrices<lb/> Rk().,)=~[rr sin(7ra/N+).,/2N) ]1Ij<lb/> .<lb/> sin(7r(a + l)/N -).,/2N) k<lb/> )=0 a=O<lb/> Taking the limit)., -+ ioo we obtain O&apos;k as above.<lb/> If N is a prime (or 6) it is easy to see that Rk().,) is in the algebra generated<lb/> by O&apos;k, so we have self-Baxterization. For other values of N this is not true but the<lb/> Baxterization is clearly abelian.<lb/> FURTHER EXAMPLES<lb/> There are many known knot invariants that can be turned into traces of braid<lb/> group representations. The number of representations of the fundamental group of the<lb/> complement into a finite group is one due to Kuperberg. But the one that is most<lb/> tempting to try at this stage is the homology of higher branched covers mod N. These<lb/> may be obtained from the Burau representation as in [GJl. To develop the theory in<lb/> an analogous way to the mod 2 case one may proceed as follows (suppose N is an odd<lb/> prime).<lb/> Let F be a quadratic extension of Z/NZ with involution * and let 5 E F be<lb/> any element with S &apos;&quot; S· = 5-1, write Im(a) = ~=~: for a E F Then to replace<lb/> the algebra Dn previously defined we let Dn,s be the (complex) algebra on generators<lb/> uf,a E F,I = 1, ... ,n -1 with relations (w = e 27ri / N )<lb/> , a b _<lb/> (8+8-1 )Im(ab&apos;L,a+b<lb/> .£/ U/ -w<lb/> u/<lb/> a b<lb/> 2lm(iib) b<lb/> a<lb/> u/ [1/+ 1 = w<lb/> U/+1U/<lb/> u&apos;tA = utuk for Ik -II 2: 2<lb/> 10<lb/> Then it may be deduced for [GJ] or shown directly that if (Tj = L wa&apos;au,[, then<lb/> aEF<lb/> the braid relations are satisfied.<lb/> &apos;vVe conjecture that these representations can be Baxterized.<lb/> CONCLUDING REMARKS<lb/> Besides the probability of new solvable models, what are the lessons to be learned<lb/> from Baxterization? I believe the biggest is that YBE is in some sense more natural<lb/> than the braid relations. Let me give two reasons for thinking this, based on au&apos;&apos;<lb/> examples.<lb/> 1) In the Fateev Zamolodchikov model one may calculate the structure of two<lb/> algebras: one the algebra generated by Rl (A), R 2 ( A), ... , Rn( A), the other the algebra<lb/> generated by (Tl,(T2, @BULLET@BULLET. ,(Tn&apos; When N is a prime (or 6) these algebras are the same. In<lb/> the other cases the first algebra is natural and simple to describe: it is the algebra of<lb/> fixed points for the involution on Dn given by Uj -+ ujl. The second algebras seem<lb/> quite unpleasant.<lb/> 2) In the theory of quantum groups one may consider the commutant of the repre-<lb/>sentations of Uh(g) in the tensor powers of an irreducible representation. It is known<lb/> that, unlike in the classical limit where it is only true for sin, the braid group generates<lb/> the commutant for all representations of sl2 and the smallest representations of the<lb/> A, B, C, D series. On the other hand this is not true for the adjoint representation of<lb/> s13. But it is precisely in this case that the Rj(A) matrices generate more than the<lb/> braid group. One is naturally led to the question: is the commutant of Un (g) always<lb/> equal to the algebra generated by the R;(A)?<lb/> REFERENCES<lb/> [A]<lb/> [Ba]<lb/> [BW]<lb/> [Dr]<lb/> [FZ]<lb/> [GJ]<lb/> [Ji]<lb/> [KMM]<lb/> [W]<lb/> J. Alexander.<lb/> R. Baxter, &quot;Exactly solved models in statistical mechanics&quot;, New York Aca-<lb/>demic Press, 1982.<lb/> J. Birman, H. Wenzl &quot;Braids, link polynomials and a new algebra&quot;, Trans.<lb/> AlVIS (to appear).<lb/> V. Drinfeld &quot;Quantum groups&quot;, Proc. lCM, 1986.<lb/> V. Fateev and A. Zamolodchikov, &quot;Self-dual solutions of the star-triangle rela-<lb/>tions in ZN models&quot;, Phys. Lett. 92A, 37-39 (1982).<lb/> D. Goldschmidt and V. Jones &quot;Metaplectic link invariants&quot;, Geometric Dedi-<lb/>cat a (to appear).<lb/> M. Jimbo, &quot;Quantum R-matrix for the generalized Toda system</div>

	<reference>&quot;, Comm.<lb/> Math. Phys. 102,537-547 (1986).<lb/> T. Kobayashi, H. Murakami, J. 1\1 urakami, &quot;Cyclotomic invariants for links&quot;,<lb/> Proc. Japan Acad., 2:;,.5-238 (1988).<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">E. &apos;vVitten, &quot;Gauge theories an integrable lattice models&quot;, lAS Preprint, 1989.<lb/> 11<lb/></note>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Geometric Classification of Commutative Algebras of<lb/> Ordinary Differential Operators*<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>MOTOHICO MULASE<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Department of Mathematics<lb/> and<lb/> Institute of Theoretical Dynamics<lb/> University of California<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Davis, CA 95616<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">Dedicated to the memory of Professor Michio Kuga<lb/> 1. The purpose of this paper is to give a geometric classification of all<lb/> commutative algebras consisting of linear ordinary differential operators<lb/> whose coefficients are scalar-valued functions.<lb/> The problem of determining commuting ordinary differential operators<lb/> has a long history in mathematics -it started in 1879. Since then it has<lb/> been studied by many people in various contexts and from different<lb/> motivations. The so-called rank one case (see Section 2 for definition)<lb/> was essentially worked out in the 1920&apos;s and the most general theorem<lb/> in the rank one case was obtained by Krichever and Mumford in 1970&apos;s.<lb/> We will present here a complete solution of this problem which is valid<lb/> for all ranks and generalizes naturally the theorem of Krichever in terms<lb/> of the geometry of vector bundles on algebraic curves.<lb/> Let B be a commutative algebra of linear ordinary differential opera-<lb/>tors with scalar-valued functions as coefficients. We say two operators P<lb/> and Q commute with one another if the operator product p. Q coincides<lb/> with Q . P. We impose the following conditions on B.<lb/> (B-1) B is a C-algebra with the identity operator 1 E B.<lb/> (B-2) B has an operator P of order n &gt; 0 such that its leading<lb/> coefficient is 1 and the other coefficients have power series<lb/> expansion at one point. In other words, B has a monic op-<lb/>erator which is regular at a certain point.<lb/> Since we can always add the identity operator to a given commutative<lb/> algebra, (B-1) is not a restriction for B . The second condition (B-2)<lb/></div>

	<note type="other">*Research supported by NSF Grant DMS 8610730, The Institute for Advanced Study,<lb/> and The Aspen Center for Physics.<lb/></note>

	<reference>Differenlial Geometric Methods in Theoretical Physics<lb/> 13<lb/> Edited by L.-L. Chau and W. Nahm. Plenum Press. New York. 1990<lb/></reference>

	<div type="abstract">looks serious. For example, e[x dd x 1 is a commutative algebra of ordinary<lb/> differential operators but it does not satisfy (B-2). However, if we change<lb/> the coordinate x by u = log x, then the operator x dd x becomes<lb/> d<lb/> du d<lb/> x -=x· -. -<lb/>dx<lb/> dx du<lb/> d<lb/> = -,<lb/> du<lb/> which is monic. It means that the notion of monicness depends on the<lb/> choice of a coordinate. In general, if we use the coordinate u defined by<lb/> then f( x) c: r becomes a monic n-th order differential operator in u.<lb/> Thus it is not a severe condition to require the existence of a monic<lb/> operator in B. We can simply change the coordinate to make one of the<lb/> operators in B monic. Similarly, if an operator is given in a practical<lb/> situation, we can find a point at which all the coefficients have power<lb/> series expansion. Therefore, (B-2) is not a strong restriction, either.<lb/> Let us choose a coordinate x so that the operator P is monic and<lb/> is regular at x = o. Thus every coefficient of P is an element of the<lb/> ring e [[xl] of formal power series in x. We identify two commutative<lb/> algebras Bl and B2 if there is an invertible function f = f(x) E e [[xl]<lb/> such that<lb/> (1)<lb/> In this paper, we present a bijective correspondence, or a dictionary,<lb/> between the set of commutative algebras of ordinary differential opera-<lb/>tors satisfying (B-1) and (B-2), and a moduli space of certain geometric<lb/> data consisting of an algebraic curve, a smooth point on it, a vector bun-<lb/>dle on the curve, a local covering of the curve defined on a neighborhood<lb/> of the point and a local trivialization of the bundle near the given point.<lb/> Professor Michio Kuga has worked in the area of mathematics where<lb/> number theory, algebraic geometry and the theory of differential equa-<lb/>tions meet together [Ku]. After I finished my work on the Schottky<lb/> problem [Ml-2], I spent one year at Stony Brook with him. I really<lb/> enjoyed discussing mathematics and exchanging mathematical dreams<lb/> with him. Around that time, I started to think about the higher rank<lb/> analogue of the Krichever construction and the classification problem of<lb/> the commuting differential operators.<lb/> 14<lb/> When the final answer to this problem was obtained, I was truly sur-<lb/>prised by the deep interplay between algebraic geometry and the theory<lb/> of differential equations [M3]. Today, I wish I could tell him this result,<lb/> and ask him about its possible relation to number theory.<lb/> 2. In order to give the precise statement of the main theorem, let us<lb/> define the moduli space M;!&quot;&quot;(O, -1) of quintuples (C,p, F, 7r, ¢) which is<lb/> formed by the following objects:<lb/> -C is an irreducible complete algebraic curve, i.e. a compact RiemaIlll<lb/> surface with (or without) singularities;<lb/> -p is a smooth point of C;<lb/> -F is a torsion free sheaf of Oc-modules of rank r such that H O ( C, F) =<lb/> HI (C, F) = o. If C is a non-singular curve of genus g, then F is a<lb/> vector bundle on C of degree r(g -1) with no non-trivial holomorphic<lb/> sections;<lb/> -7r : Uo ---; Up is an r-sheeted covering ramified only at p = 7r(0) E Up,<lb/> where Uo is an open disk of C with center at the origin 0, and Up C C<lb/> is an open neighborhood of p E C;<lb/> -¢: Flu p ~ 7r*Ou o (-l) is an Oup-module isomorphism, where Flu p<lb/> is the restriction of the vector bundle F on Up and 7r * OU o ( -1) is the<lb/> direct image by the covering map 7r of the twisted line bundle OU o ( -1)<lb/> on Uo defined by the divisor {O} of Uo.<lb/> Since 7r*Ou o ( -1) is a trivial vector bundle of rank r on Up, we can say<lb/> that ¢ gives a local trivialization of F on Up.<lb/> We say that two quintets (C, p, F, 7r1, ¢I) and (C, p, F, 7r2, ¢2) are iso-<lb/>morphic if there is an automorphism h : Uo ~ Uo and a line bundle<lb/> automorphism 1jJ : OU o ( -1) ~ OU o ( -1) such that 7r1 = 7r2 0 hand<lb/> ¢I = ¢2 0 7r * (1jJ ). Let us denote the set of all isomorphism classes of<lb/> quintets by M;!&quot;&quot;(O, -1). Now we can state the main theorem.<lb/> MAIN THEOREM.<lb/> Let Br be the set of all commutative algebras B of rank r consisting of<lb/> ordinary differential operators with scalar-valued function as coefficients<lb/> satisfying (B-1) and (B-2), where the rank of B is defined by<lb/> rankB = G.C.D.{ordQ I Q E B} .<lb/> Then there is a natural bijection<lb/> .<lb/> ~<lb/> +(<lb/> )<lb/> J.1r.Br --M r 0,-1<lb/> for every r &gt; O.<lb/> In other words, there is a bijective correspondence between the fol-<lb/>lowing objects:<lb/> 15<lb/> Analytic Object. A commutative algebra oflinear ordinary differential<lb/> operators of rank r satisfying (B-1) and (B-2). Two of such algebras are<lb/> identified by (1).<lb/> Geometric Object. An isomorphism class of a quintet (C,p,F,7f,¢)<lb/> consisting of a curve, a point, a vector bundle, a local covering and a<lb/> local trivialization.<lb/> REMARK: In the case of rank one, the isomorphism relations of the<lb/> quintets almost completely wipe out the information of 7f and ¢. There-<lb/>fore, Mt(O, -1) is exactly the same as the moduli space of the data<lb/> (C, p, 1:-, v), where 1:-is a generic line bundle of degree 9 -1 and v is a<lb/> non-zero tangent vector of C at p. Thus our theorem reduces directly<lb/> to the theorem of Krichever and Mumford [KJ, [Mum].<lb/> Verdier [V] obtained a different classification of commutative rings of<lb/> ordinary differential operators. But since he uses the parabolic structure<lb/> and the connections of the vector bundles, and since he does not incor-<lb/>porate the identification of (1), his result has a rather different flavor<lb/> from the point of view of the work of Krichever and Mumford.<lb/> 3. Since the key ideas of the theorem emerged from the earlier works<lb/> of many mathematicians, let us sketch the history of this problem. We<lb/> will concentrate on the old part of the history here, because an extensive<lb/> review of recent works on this subject can be found in [PW].<lb/> Since differential operators do not usually commute, it is natural to<lb/> ask what happens if they do. As far as I know, the first per.son who asked<lb/> this question and tried to give a systematic answer was G. Wallenberg.<lb/> In his paper [W] of 1903, Wallenberg studied the classification problem<lb/> of pairs of commuting ordinary differential operators. He mentioned that<lb/> this problem did not seem to be studied before, even in the fundamental<lb/> work of G. Floquet [F]. But he credited Floquet that the case of two<lb/> operators of order one has been worked out in [F].<lb/> Floquet&apos;s 1879 paper [F] is 130-page long and seems to be considered<lb/> as one of the standard references of ordinary differential equations in his<lb/> time. Among other things, he established the Euclid division algorithm<lb/> for ordinary differential operators.<lb/> Let P and Q be ordinary differential operators of order m and n,<lb/> respectively. If m 2: n and the leading coefficient of Q is invertible, then<lb/> there are operators pi of order m -nand R of order less than n such<lb/> that<lb/> P=PIQ+R.<lb/> 16<lb/> Thus the system<lb/> is equivalent with<lb/> {<lb/> P1jJ = 0<lb/> Q1/J = 0<lb/> { Q1/J = 0<lb/> R1jJ = 0 ,<lb/> which has lower order than the first one. From the modern point of<lb/> view, we can say that Floquet studied &apos;V-modules. In fact, he proved<lb/> the following: let D K be the set of all ordinary differential operators<lb/> with coefficients in the field J{ = C((x)) of formal Laurent resies in x.<lb/> Then every D K-module is generated by a single element. Since he was<lb/> interested in the non-commutative nature of the ring D K, he did not<lb/> ask the question of Wallenberg.<lb/> It is easy to determine all commuting operators of order one. Wallen-<lb/>berg started from this point. In [W], he gave a complete determination<lb/> of commuting operators P and Q when<lb/> 1. ordP = ordQ = 2, and<lb/> 2. ord P = 1 and ord Q = n &gt; 0 .<lb/> So far still everything is easy. Then he studied the case of ord P = 2<lb/> and ord Q = 3, and noticed that the Weierstrass elliptic function appears<lb/> in the coefficients of these operators (cf. Eq. (2)). He dealt with a few<lb/> more examples such as order 2 and 5, but did not obtain any general<lb/> theorem. Maybe Wallenberg&apos;s attempt was too much ahead of time.<lb/> Indeed, the first general result toward the classification problem was<lb/> only established 20 years later.<lb/> In 1923, Burchnall and Chaundy [Be] started the systematic investi-<lb/>gation on this problem, without knowing the previous work of Wallen-<lb/>berg. One of their remarkable theorems asserts<lb/> FIRST THEOREM OF BURCHNALL-CHAUNDY. Let P and Q be linear<lb/> ordinary differential operators of positive order. If P and Q commute,<lb/> tben tbey satisfy a non-trivial polynomial relation f(P, Q) == 0, wbere<lb/> f().., f-L) E C[).., f-LJ is a non-zero polynomial in two variables.<lb/> Let us illustrate why this is true. So let P be a second order operator<lb/> and Q be of order three. As we observed in Section 1, we can assume<lb/> that P is monic. Note that every operator which commutes with a monic<lb/> operator of positive order must have a constant leading coefficient. Thus<lb/> the leading coefficient of Q is a constant. Therefore, we can choose a<lb/> constant Cl E C such that Q2 -c1P 3 has order less than 6. Since<lb/> Q2 _ c1P 3 commutes with P, its leading coefficient is again a constant.<lb/> 17<lb/> So we can find another constant C2 so that Q2 -C1 P 3 -C2PQ becomes<lb/> an operator of order less than 5. We can continue this procedure until<lb/> we obtain an operator<lb/> of order less than 2. If ordR &lt; 1, then R must be a constant because<lb/> it commutes with P. If ordR = 1, then we can choose constants C6<lb/> and C7 such that P -C6R2 -C7R becomes a constant. In any case,<lb/> we have obtained a non-trivial polynomial relation among P and Q !<lb/> This argument works in the general situation and gives a proof of the<lb/> above theorem. (Note that this argument does not work for the quasi-<lb/>commuting pairs. See Section 7.)<lb/> Thus a pair of commuting operators produces a plane algebraic curve.<lb/> Let us work out an explicit example due to Wallenberg. We choose<lb/> (2)<lb/> {<lb/> P = (lx)2 -2u(x)<lb/> Q = (lx) 3 -3u (x) lx -~ u&apos; (x) ,<lb/> where u&apos;(x) is the derivative of u(x) with respect to x. It is an easy<lb/> calculation to show that P and Q commute if and only if u satisfies<lb/> u lll = 12uu&apos; .<lb/> We can integrate this equation twice to obtain<lb/> (3)<lb/> where g2 and g3 are the constants of integration. Therefore, P and Q of<lb/> (2) commute if and only if their coefficients are given by the Weierstrass<lb/> elliptic functions and their degenerations, since g2 and g3 in (3) are<lb/> arbitrary. If u satisfies (3), then P and Q satisfy a polynomial relation<lb/> Q 2 = p3 _ g2 P _ g3<lb/> 4<lb/> 4 &apos;<lb/> which defines a plane cubic curve. It was already known to Wallenberg<lb/> that every commuting pair of operators of order 2 and 3 can be reduced<lb/> to this example by a simple transformation. In this sense this example<lb/> is a universal one and the appearance of the elliptic function is essential.<lb/> When P and Q commute, the simultaneous eigenvalue problem<lb/> (4)<lb/> 18<lb/> {<lb/> P1j; = ).,1jJ<lb/> Q1j; = fL1j;<lb/> makes sense. Since<lb/> 0= f(P,Q)1fJ = f(&gt;&quot;,J.l)1fJ,<lb/> the eigenvalues &gt;. . and J.l must satisfy the same polynomial relation.<lb/> Therefore, the plane curve we obtained is a spectral curve. Moreover,<lb/> a simple linear algebra argument shows that if f(&gt;&quot;, J.l) = 0, then there<lb/> exists a non-trivial solution of (4). If one uses the technique of asymp-<lb/>totic expansion of 1fJ, then it is not so hard to see that the dimension of<lb/> the simultaneous eigenspace is equal to the greatest common divisor of<lb/> the order of P and Q. Thus, we can construct a vector bundle of rank<lb/> r = G.C.D.(ordP,ordQ) on the plane curve {(&gt;..,J.l) E C 2 If(&gt;&quot;,J.l) =<lb/> O} whose fiber at (&gt;.., J.l) is the corresponding simultaneous eigenspace.<lb/> There is a functorial way of extending this eigenspace bundle to the<lb/> point at infinity of the spectral curve. Therefore, we obtain a compact<lb/> Riemann surface by attaching a point at infinity to the plane curve and<lb/> a globally defined vector bundle on it. In other words, we have con-<lb/>structed the data (C, p, F) from the commutative algebra B = C [P, QJ<lb/> generated by P, Q and 1, where C is a compact Riemann surface which<lb/> may have singularities, p is the point at infinity and F is a vector bundle<lb/> of rank r = G.C.D.(ordP ,0rdQ) = rankB. In our example of (2), Cis<lb/> an elliptic curve, p is the point at infinity and F is a line bundle.<lb/> Let us denote by M 1 the moduli space of all data (C, p, L, v) consisting<lb/> of an algebraic curve of arbitrary genus g, a smooth point p E C, a line<lb/> bundle Lon C of degree g-l which has no non-trivial global holomorphic<lb/> sections, and a non-zero tangent vector v E TpC. (The tangent vector<lb/> comes from the monicness assumption of the operator.) The second<lb/> amazing theorem due to Burchnall and Chaundy states the following.<lb/> SECOND THEOREM OF BURCHNALL-CHAUNDY. Let Bl be the set of<lb/> commutative algebras of ordinary differential operators of rank 1 satis-<lb/>fying (B-1), (B-2). Then there is a canonical bijection between Bl and<lb/> M l ;<lb/> These theorems were forgotten for more than half a century. Mean-<lb/>time, in the middle of 1970&apos;s, Krichever [K] re-discovered these theorems<lb/> without knowing the earlier work of Burchnall and Chaundy. A com-<lb/>plete proof of these theorems using the modern language of algebraic<lb/> geometry was given by Mumford [Mum].<lb/> Here comes a natural question: which kind of geometric data corre-<lb/>spond to Br for r ;:::: 2 ?<lb/> 19<lb/> An obvious candidate is the moduli space Mr of the data (C, p, F, v),<lb/> where F is now a vector bundle of rank r and degree reg -1) such that<lb/> HO(C, F) = o. But it does not work, because Br is far larger than Mr.<lb/> 4. In order to prove the Main Theorem, we use the original technique<lb/> of Burchnall and Chaundy as well as its modernized version due to<lb/> Mumford. We also need another machinery, which is believed to be<lb/> rather modern, but is actually very old: that is the theory of pseudo-<lb/>differential operators.<lb/> Let us to go back to the history once again. 1. Schur, inspired by the<lb/> 1903 paper of Wallenberg, proved the following theorem in 1905. (In the<lb/> same year he obtained also the famous Schur&apos;s lemma.)<lb/> SCHUR&apos;S OTHER LEMMA. Let Bp be the set of alllinear ordinary differ-<lb/>ential operators which commute with a given operator P of order n &gt; O.<lb/> Then B p is a commutative algebra.<lb/> The theorem is rather surprising, because it does not hold for the<lb/> case of matrices and partial differential operators. Schur&apos;s proof is the<lb/> following. As before, we can assume that P is monic. The first thing<lb/> he did is to define the n-th root of P. He showed that there is a unique<lb/> monic pseudo-differential operator<lb/> (5)<lb/> d<lb/> (d)-l<lb/> (d)-2<lb/> L = -+ ao + al -<lb/>+ a2 -<lb/>+ ...<lb/> dx<lb/> dx<lb/> dx<lb/> of order one such that Ln = P. (He credited S. Pincherle [P]&apos; which<lb/> appeared in 1897, for the technique of pseudo-differential calculus. The<lb/> idea of fractional powers of operators is due to Schur himself.) Let<lb/> Q E Bp be an arbitrary operator of order, say m. Since Q commutes<lb/> with P, its leading coefficient is a constant. Therefore, there is a constant<lb/> Co E C such that Q-coLm has order m-1 or less. Since L commutes with<lb/> P, Q -coLm also commutes with P. Therefore, its leading coefficient is<lb/> again a constant, and hence there is Cl E C so that Q -coLm -c1L m -1<lb/> is of order m -2 or lower. By continuing this process infinitely many<lb/> times, he obtained<lb/> 00<lb/> (6)<lb/> Therefore,<lb/> (7)<lb/> 20<lb/> where C ( ( z )) denotes the set of all formal Laurent series in z with finite<lb/> poles at z = O. But since C((L-1 )) is commutative, so is Bp!<lb/> Let us consider the abstract version of Schur&apos;s argument. Since Q<lb/> is a differential operator, m of (6) is always positive. Thus we have a<lb/> subalgebra<lb/> (8)<lb/> A C C((z))<lb/> satisfying the condition<lb/> (9)<lb/> AnC[[zJ]=c.<lb/> A commutative algebra B satisfying (B-1) and (B-2) produces a pair<lb/> (A, L), where L is a monic pseudo-differential operator of order 1 ob-<lb/>tained by taking the n-th root of P, and A is a subalgebra of C((z))<lb/> with (9) obtained by replacing L -1 in (6) by z.<lb/> Now the question: how can we go back from an abstract algebra A<lb/> satisfying (8) and (9) to the algebra B of ordinary differential operators?<lb/> An easy answer is this: simply replace z by L -1. But then how do we<lb/> know that the resulting algebra consists of only differential operators?<lb/> In other words, how can we find an operator L so that the algebra<lb/> B = {a( L -1 ) I a( z) E A}<lb/> obtained by replacing z by L -1 in A contains only differential operators?<lb/> In order to answer this question, we need another idea.<lb/> 5. In their fundamental work [GD] on completely integral systems<lb/> appeared in 1975 and 76, Gel&apos;fand and Dikii introduced negative and<lb/> fractional powers of operators in this field. But actually the same tech-<lb/>nique had been known to Pincherle and Schur for more than 70 years<lb/> before. Thus many of these modern theories on this subject have deep<lb/> historical background, even though it was not recognized until recently.<lb/> Then M. Sato [Sa] discovered a remarkable correspondence between an<lb/> infinite dimensional Grassmannian and the pseudo-differential operators<lb/> of Schur and Gel&apos;fand-Dikii.<lb/> vVe have already encountered the set C (( z)) of all formal Laurent<lb/> senes. Let V = C((z)) and V(v) = C[[zl] . z-/.I. Then the filtration<lb/> ... :J V(v+l) :J V(v) :J V(v-l) :J ...<lb/> defines a topology in V. We define the Grassmannian G(J.L, v) of index J. L<lb/> and level v as the set of all closed vector subspaces W of V such that<lb/> both W n V(v) and V I(W + V(v)) have finite dimensions and<lb/> dim(W n V(v)) -dim (V I(W + V(v))) = J. L .<lb/> 21<lb/> This is indeed the Grassmannian of Fredhohn operators of index p,. The<lb/> big-cell of the index 0 Grassmannian is defined by<lb/> G+(O, v) -= {W E G(O, v) I W n V(v) = V /(W + V(v)) = O} .<lb/> In 1981, Sato found a bijective correspondence between the Grassman-<lb/>nian G(O, 0) and the set of monic pseudo-differential operators<lb/> (10)<lb/> ( d)-1<lb/> (d)-2<lb/> S=1+s 1 (x) -<lb/>+S2(X) -<lb/>+ ...<lb/> dx<lb/> dx<lb/> of order zero which have certain type of singularities in their coefficients<lb/> Sj(x). In particular, if Sj(x)&apos;s are all regular at x = 0, i.e. Sj(x) E C [[xl]<lb/> for all j 2: 1, then S of (10) corresponds bijectively to a point of the<lb/> big-cell G+(O,O). Unfortunately this correspondence is not canonical,<lb/> because it depends on the choice of a basis for V. The corresondence<lb/> becomes completely canonical if one uses G+(O, -1) instead of G+(O, 0).<lb/> Thus one obtains the following.<lb/> THEOREM 1. Let r m be the set of all monic zeroth order pseudo-<lb/>differential operators of the form (10) such that all the coefficients are<lb/> in C [[xl]. Then there is a canonical bijection<lb/> r m ~ G+(O, -1) .<lb/> We can choose an invertible function fEe [[x]] so that Schur&apos;s oper-<lb/>ator L of (5) becomes<lb/> 1<lb/> d<lb/> (d)-l<lb/> (d)-2<lb/> f·L·f-=-+O+Ul(X) -<lb/>+U2(X) -<lb/>+ ....<lb/> dx<lb/> dx<lb/> dx<lb/> Then there is an operator S E r m such that S· dd x . S-1 is equal to the<lb/> above expression. Therefore, if we start with f· B . f-1 instead of B<lb/> (and which we identify anyway by (1)), then we have an operator P E B<lb/> such that S-1 . P . S = (ix) n. It is easy to see that every operator<lb/> commuting with (ix) n for some n 2: 1 has only constant coefficients.<lb/> Therefore, we have<lb/> where a = lx and we identify z = a-I. Note that &quot;replacing Z-I by L&quot;<lb/> simply means that changing a by sas-1 = L. Thus the operator S E r m<lb/> connects the algebra B and the abstract algebra ACe (( z)). So we can<lb/> 22<lb/> replace the pair (A, L) by another pair (A, W), where W E C+(O, -1)<lb/> is the point of the Grassmannian corresponding to S. We call (A, W) a<lb/> Schur pair.<lb/> 6. A connection between the Grassmannian and the geometric data<lb/> consisting of pointed algebraic curves and vector bundles on them was<lb/> discovered by G. Segal and G. Wilson [SW] in 1983. They dealt with<lb/> the GrassmaIlllian from the point of view of loop groups. Hence they<lb/> used the Hilbert space H(r) of Cr-valued square integrable functions<lb/> on a circle in order to obtain an extended moduli space of curves and<lb/> vector bundles of rank r. Then they defined an isomorphism H( r) ~<lb/> H(l) and brought the higher rank situation to the single GrassmaIlllian,<lb/> which is the analytic version of Sato&apos;s C(O, 0). However, the isomorphism<lb/> between H(r) and H(l) is not canonical.<lb/> In order to find a canonical bijection between the data of the Grass-<lb/>mannians and the geometric data of pointed curves and vector bundles,<lb/> we use Schur pairs. We call (A, W) a Schur pair of rank r, index J-l and<lb/> level v if<lb/> 1. WE C(J-l, v) and<lb/> 2. C cAe V is a subalgebra such that AW c W by<lb/> multiplication of V = C((z)) and<lb/> r = rank A = C.C.D.{pole order of a(z) at z = 0 I a(z) E A} .<lb/> Let Sr(J-l, v) denote the set of all Schur pairs of rank r, index J-l and<lb/> level v.<lb/> The geometric counterpart of the set of Schur pairs is the moduli space<lb/> M r(J-l, v) of quintets (C, p, F, 7r, ¢), where C, p and 7r are as in Section 2,<lb/> F is now an arbitrary torsion free sheaf of rank r Vc-modules such that<lb/> and<lb/> is an OU p -module isomorphism. Note that in the case of rank one, 7r gives<lb/> a local coordinate on Up and hence our quintet becomes the quintuple<lb/> of Segal-Wilson.<lb/> We have the following theorem.<lb/> THEOREM 2. There is a canonical bijection<lb/> (11 )<lb/> 23<lb/> for every r &gt; 0, J.L E Z and v E Z. Moreover, there are the following<lb/> canonical isomorphism under this correspondence:<lb/> HO(C, F) ~ W n V(v) and<lb/> Hl(C, F) ~ V I(W + V(v») .<lb/> Roughly speaking, Xr ,/i,v(C,p,F,7r,¢) = (A, W) is defined by<lb/> A = holomorphic functions on C \ {p}, and<lb/> W = holomorphic sections of F\ C\ {p} @BULLET<lb/> In [M3]&apos; this bijection is obtained as a fully faithful functor between<lb/> anti-equivalent categories.<lb/> As the final step to prove the main theorem, we need the following<lb/> THEOREM 3. Let (A, W) E Sr(O, -1) be a Schur pair of rank r, in-<lb/>dex 0 and level -1 such that W belongs to the big-cell C+(O, -1) of<lb/> the Grassmannian, and let 5 E r m be the pseudo-differential operator<lb/> corresponding to the point W by the Sato correspondence (Theorem 1).<lb/> Then B = S . A . S-1 is a rank r commutative algebra of ordinary dif-<lb/>ferential operators, where we regard A as a subring of C (( a-I)) by the<lb/> identification z = a-I.<lb/> Let D denote the set of all linear ordinary differential operators with<lb/> coefficients in C [[xl]. Then for a given algebra A with (8) and (9),<lb/> the condition S . A . S-1 C D gives a system of nonlinear ordinary<lb/> differential equations among the coefficients of S which was studied in<lb/> [M2, Section 1]. Theorem 3 tells us that this system has a regular<lb/> solution if and only if there is a point WE C+(O, -1) such that AW c<lb/> W.<lb/> Schur showed that every B E Br gives a pair (A, L) and hence, by<lb/> Theorem 1, the Schur pair CA, W) E Sr(O, -1). Now Theorem 3 tells us<lb/> how to go back from (A, W) to B. On the other hand, we have a bijection<lb/> Xr,/i,V of (11) by Theorem 2. Combining these two constructions, we<lb/> obtain the main theorem.<lb/> One of the most important motivations of studying commuting or-<lb/>dinary differential operator is their relation with completely integrable<lb/> systems, and this point of view of the problem is entirely missing in<lb/> the classical works I mentioned above. For the recent deep works on<lb/> commuting operators and completely integrable systems, I refer to two<lb/> books [N] and [NMPZ].<lb/> A detailed discussion of the topics of this paper is given in [M3].<lb/> 24<lb/> 7. As we saw in Section 3, one of the key steps of our classification<lb/> theorem is the Burchnall-Chaundy theory: [P, QJ = 0 implies a polyno-<lb/>mial relation. Being motivated by the recent theory of two dimensional<lb/> quantum gravity, a natural question arises here: what happens is we<lb/> have quasi-commutativity [P, -QJ == 1 ?<lb/> Certainly, the argument of Section 3 does not apply.<lb/> THEOREM 4. Let P and Q ~e linear ordinary differential operators sat-<lb/>isfying tbe quasi-commutativity condition<lb/> [P, QJ = c = constant.<lb/> If c i= 0, tben tbe operators cannot satisfy any non-trivial relation of tbe<lb/> form<lb/> finite<lb/> L cijpiQi = 0<lb/> I,J<lb/> witb constant coefficients.<lb/> PROOF: Let<lb/> finite<lb/> f(X, Y) = L cjjXiyi<lb/> i,j<lb/> be a polynomial such that f(P, Q) == 0 in this order. If this equation<lb/> is non-trivial with respect to Q, then we can choose such a polynomial<lb/> with the lowest degree in Q. Note that [P, f(P, Q)J = 0, i.e.<lb/> finite<lb/> L CijcjpiQj-1 = 0 .<lb/> i,i<lb/> But this equation has a lower degree in Q, hence f(X, Y) does not<lb/> depend on Y.<lb/> This is the point where the quantum and the non-commutative geom-<lb/>etry start, but we have to stop this article here.<lb/> References<lb/> [BC]<lb/> J.L.</div>

	<reference>Burchnall and T.W. Chaundy: Commutative ordinary dif-<lb/>ferential operators, Proc. London Math. Soc. Ser. 2, 21 (1923)<lb/> 420-440; Proc. Royal Soc. London Ser. A, 118 (1928)</reference>

	<div type="abstract">557-583.<lb/> 25<lb/> [F]<lb/> [GD]<lb/> [K]<lb/> [Ku]<lb/> [Ml]<lb/> [M2]<lb/> [M3]<lb/> [Mum]<lb/> [N]<lb/> [NMPZ]<lb/> [P]<lb/> [PW]<lb/> [Sa]<lb/> 26<lb/> G. Floquet: Sur la theorie des equations differentielles lineaires,<lb/></div>

	<email>Ann. Sci. de</email>

	<reference>l&apos;Ecole Norm. Super., 8 (1879) Suppl., 3-132.<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">LM. Gel&apos;fand and L.A. Dikii: Asymptotic behavior of the re-<lb/>solvent of Sturm-Liouville equations and the algebra of the<lb/></note>

	<reference>Korteweg-de Vries equations, Russ. Math. Surveys, 30 (1975)<lb/> 77-113; Fractional powers of operators and Hamiltonian sys-<lb/>tems, Func. Anal. Appl. 10 (1976) 259-273.<lb/> LM. Krichever: Methods of algebraic geometry in the theory of<lb/> nonlinear equations, Russ. Math. Surveys 32 (1977) 185-214.<lb/> M. Kuga: Galois&apos; Dream, (translated by S. Addington from<lb/> the Japanese text), Birkhiiuser, to appear.<lb/> M. Mulase: Algebraic geometry of soliton equations, Proc.<lb/> Japan Acad. Ser. A, 59 (1983) 285-288</reference>

	<div type="abstract">.<lb/> _ _ _ _ : Cohomological structure in soliton equations and<lb/> jacobian varieties, J. Diff. Geom. 19 (1984) 403-430.<lb/> _ _ _ _ : Category of vector bundles on algebraic curves and<lb/> infinite dimensional Grassmannians, Intern. Journ. Math. 1<lb/> (1990) to appear.<lb/> D. Mumford: An algebro-geometric constructions of commut-<lb/>ing operators and of solutions to the Toda lattice equations,<lb/> Korteweg-de Vries equations and related non-linear equations,<lb/></div>

	<reference>In Proc. Internat. Symp. on Alg. Geom., Kyoto 1977, Ki-<lb/>nokuniya Publ. (1978) 115-153.<lb/> S.P. Novikov, ed.: Integrable systems, London Math. Soc. Lec.<lb/> Notes Ser. 60, Cambridge Univ. Press (1981).<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>S.P. Novikov, S.V. Manakov, L.P. Pitaevskii and V.E. Za</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">-<lb/>kharov: Theory of solitons -The inverse scattering method,<lb/> Consultants Bureau, New York (1984).<lb/> S. Pincherle: Memoire sur Ie calcul fonctionnel distributif,<lb/> Math. Ann.</div>

	<phone>49 (1897) 325-382.<lb/></phone>

	<note type="other">E. Previato and G. Wilson: Vector bundles over curves and<lb/></note>

	<reference>solutions of the K P equations, Proc. Symp. Pure Math. 49<lb/> (1989) 553-569.<lb/> M. Sato: Soliton equations as dynamical systems on an infinite<lb/> dimensional Grassmannian manifold, Kokyuroku, Res. Inst.<lb/> Math. Sci., Kyoto Univ. 439 (1981) 30-46.<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">[SN]<lb/> [Sc]<lb/> [SW]<lb/> [V]<lb/></note>

	<reference>[W]<lb/> M. Sato and M. Noumi: Soliton equations and universal Grass-<lb/>mann manifold (in Japanese), Sophia Univ. Lee. Notes Ser.<lb/> in Math. 18 (1984).<lb/> L Schur: Uber vertauschbare lineare Differentialausdriicke,<lb/> Sitzungsber. der Berliner Math. Gesel. 4 (1905) 2-8.<lb/> G.B. Segal and G. Wilson: Loop groups and equations of K dV<lb/> type, Pub!. Math. LH.E.S. 61 (1985) 5-65.<lb/> J.-1. Verdier: Equations differentielles algebriques, Seminaire<lb/> de lEcole Normale Superieure 1979-82, Birkhauser (1983) 215-<lb/>236.<lb/> G. Wallenberg: Uber die Vertauschbarkeit homogener linearer<lb/> Differentialausdriicke, Archiv der Math. u. Phys., Drittle<lb/> Reihe 4 (1903) 252-268.<lb/> 27<lb/></reference>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>GEOMETRICAL ASPECTS OF SOLVABLE TWO DIMENSIONAL MODELS<lb/> ABSTRACT<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>K. Tanaka<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Department of Physics<lb/> The Ohio State University<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Columbus, Ohio 43210<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">It was noted that there is a connection between the non-linear two-dimensional<lb/> (2D) models and the scalar curvature r, i.e. when r = -2 the equations of motion of<lb/> the Liouville and sine-Gordon models were obtained. Further, solutions of various<lb/> classical nonlinear 2D models can be obtained from the condition that the appro-<lb/>priate curvature two form n = 0, which suggtests that these models are closely<lb/> related. This relation is explored further in the classical version by obtaining the<lb/> equations of motion from the evolution equations, the infinite number of conserved<lb/> quantities, and the common central charge. The Poisson brackets of the solvable<lb/> 2D models are specified by the Virasoro algebra.<lb/> SCALAR CURVATURE<lb/> Models of field theory are very useful laboratories for understanding the dy-<lb/>namics of fields in a relatively simple manner. But there are very many such models<lb/> and it will be very useful to find a common origin for them. the bosonic models,<lb/> Liouville, sine-Gordon, and non-linear (j models in two dimensions, were previously<lb/> obtained from a common Lagrangian.! In order to minimize the complexity of these<lb/> various models, we limit ourselves to two dimensions. Let gAB (A, B = 0, 1) be<lb/> the metric on a two-dimensional manifold, where the indices 0 and 1 refer to time<lb/> and space, respectively. We parametrize the metric as<lb/> 9 =PR-Q2,<lb/> (1)<lb/> where P, Q, and R are functions of x and t. The Riemann curvature tensor is given<lb/> by<lb/> 1 [ 8 2 g AD<lb/> 8 2 gAC<lb/> RABCD = 2&quot; 8x B 8x c + 8x A 8x D<lb/> 8 2 gB D<lb/> 8 2 gAC ]<lb/> 8x A 8x c<lb/> 8x B 8x D<lb/> (2)<lb/> + (rFADr~c -rFACr~D)&apos;<lb/> Differential Geometnc ,&apos;vIethods in Theoretical Physics<lb/> 29<lb/> Edited by L..L. Chau and W. Nahm. Plenum Press. New York. 1990<lb/> where r is the affine connection given by<lb/> (3)<lb/> In two dimensions there is only one independent component of the Riemann tensor<lb/> that must be proportional to the scalar curvature T. SO we have 2<lb/> 2<lb/> T = -ROlOl &apos;<lb/> g<lb/> (4)<lb/> The scalar curvature T can then be written after some algebraic manipulations<lb/> as<lb/> 1 [[ P z -Qt ]<lb/> [ R t -Qz] ]<lb/> T = -gl/2<lb/> gl/2<lb/> z + gl/2 t<lb/> 1 [P<lb/> Q<lb/> If].<lb/> +22 P&quot;, Q&quot;,<lb/> (5)<lb/> g<lb/> P t Qt Rt<lb/> where the last term is a determinant and the subscripts denote partial derivatives.<lb/> In the models discussed here, the determinant term does not contribute, in which<lb/> case<lb/> We first obtain the well-known Liouville and sine-Gordon models. 3 We note<lb/> that for<lb/> [<lb/> eP<lb/> 0]<lb/> gAB = 0 eP<lb/> the Liouville equation<lb/> I(<lb/> ) _ P<lb/> 2&quot; pzz + pu -e<lb/> results from Eqs. (5) and (6) for T = -2. For the metric<lb/> [<lb/> 1<lb/> AB -<lb/>g<lb/> -<lb/>cosa<lb/> cos a]<lb/> 1<lb/> &apos;<lb/> one obtains, from Eqs. (5) and (8) when T = -2,<lb/> at&quot;, = sina,<lb/> (6)<lb/> (7)<lb/> (8)<lb/> (9)<lb/> Recently it has been pointed out that many equations in physics have a geomet-<lb/>rical integrability origin. 4 It is expected that the present approach will provide an<lb/> alternative method for gaining a deeper understanding of these nonlinear equations.<lb/> 30<lb/> CURVATURE FORM<lb/> There is, therefore, a connection between the non-linear two-dimensional mod-<lb/>els and the scalar curvature r. This method of generating equations of motion<lb/> is limited because the metric gAB in two dimensions has three independent com-<lb/>ponents. On the other hand, the curvature two-form n obtained from the affine<lb/> connection r has in general six independent parameters, so when one takes n = 0,<lb/> additional equations of motion such as the Korteweg-de Vries (KdV) equation and<lb/> modified Korteweg-de Vries (MKdV) equation were obtained. 5 We are interested in<lb/> obtaining equations of motion from n = 0, because the information we gain in the<lb/> process may be useful in obtaining their solutions.<lb/> The popular method of solution 6 for certain nonlinear differential equations is<lb/> to set up the linear scattering problem in the x variable, choose the time dependence<lb/> of eigenfunctions, solve at t = 0, and then determine the solution at later times from<lb/> the scattering data. The two first-order equations are<lb/> (10)<lb/> (11)<lb/> where 1] is the eigenvalue, all the quantities are functions of x and t, and the sub-<lb/>scripts are partial derivatives.<lb/> From V&quot;,t = Vt &apos;&quot; and the requirement 1] is time independent, Tft = 0, we obtain<lb/> -A&quot;, + qC -r B = 0,<lb/> qt -B&quot;, + 2TfB -2Aq = 0,<lb/> rt -C&quot; -21]C + 2Ar = o.<lb/> (12)<lb/> One expands A, B, and C in terms of Tf and solves the equations. Equations (10)<lb/> and (11) can be written as<lb/> av R<lb/> R V&apos;<lb/> -a +rSTn = 0, m = 0,1,<lb/> xTn<lb/> R,S = 1,2, XO = t xl = x,<lb/> (13)<lb/> that is, vanishing of the covariant derivative of V, where r~Tn are components of<lb/> the affine connection. The r § = r §rndx= is the one-form with values in SL(2,R).<lb/> The curvature two-form is<lb/> n~=dr~+r¥!\r~, r=()&quot;,X&quot;&quot; a=1,2,3,<lb/> (14)<lb/> where<lb/> 31<lb/> It was shown from (10), (11), and (14),<lb/> n =dJ;!\ dt {( -A:z: + qC -rB)X1<lb/> + (qt -B:z: + 2&quot;1B -2qA)X2<lb/> +h -C:z: -2TJC + 2rA)X3}<lb/> (15)<lb/> Therefore, the condition n = 0 is equivalent to the requirement that the<lb/> eigenvalue of &quot;1 is time independent as given in Eq. (12). The following choices of<lb/> the components of the affine connections yield the equations of motion of various<lb/> models considered here. There does not seem to be a systematic way of formulating a<lb/> given nonlinear equation into the condition n = O. The structure of the coefficients<lb/> of Xl&gt; X 2, and X3 are quite restrictive.<lb/> (a) MKdV: Ut + 6U2u:z: + U:z::z::z: = 0,<lb/> -r~l = (&quot;1 u)<lb/> -u -TJ &apos;<lb/> (16)<lb/> (b) NLS [nonlinear Schrodinger equation]: iUt + U:z::z: + 21uI 2 u = 0,<lb/> r R _ (11 u)<lb/> -<lb/>51 -<lb/>-u· -&quot;1 &apos;<lb/> (17)<lb/> (c) KdV: Ut + 6uu:z: + U:z::z::z: = 0,<lb/> R_(&quot;1<lb/> u)<lb/> -r51 -<lb/>-1 -&quot;1 &apos;<lb/> (18)<lb/> SOLUTIONS OF THE NONLINEAR MODELS<lb/> In order to solve the equations for the models (a) and (b), one notes 7 that<lb/> all the terms are of odd powers in the amplitude u, or q of r~l because q = u or<lb/> q ~ U:z:. This means that if we write the solution q in terms of sech (hyperbolic<lb/> secant) the equations are expressible in terms of odd powers of sech with the aid of<lb/> tanh 2 8 = 1 -sech 2 8. One then needs to match the coefficients of the odd powers<lb/> of sech to satisfy the equations of motions. The sign of the argument () is arbitrary.<lb/> 32<lb/> Equations (10) and (11) suggest 1}t = e±&apos;1% and Vi = e±C1;t(i = 1,2), respectively,<lb/> where al is the real part of the constant term Ac of A. So a reasonable choice for the<lb/> argument is (} = -TJX -at. The imaginary part of Ac will be put in an exponential<lb/> factor that multiplies the sech. The argument is 2(} because of the definition of the<lb/> constant part of A,<lb/> We thus start with a form of solution<lb/> q = N sech2(}e 2i &amp;2 t ,<lb/> (} = -TJX -alt.<lb/> (a) MKdV: From (16), (19), (20), and (21), we get<lb/> (} = -TJX + 4TJ 3 t,<lb/> l&apos; = q = Nsech( -27]x + 87]3 t ),<lb/> and upon substitution in the MKdV equation, obtain the solution<lb/> (b) NLS: From (17), (19), (20), and (21), we get<lb/> and<lb/> l&apos; = q = 2TJsech( _2TJx)e 4i &apos;1&apos; t<lb/> as a solution.<lb/></div>

	<phone>(19)<lb/> (20)<lb/> (21)<lb/> (22)<lb/> (23)<lb/> (24)<lb/></phone>

	<div type="abstract">(c) KdV: This equation does not consist of odd powers of l&apos; but a solution can<lb/> be obtained from a solution of M K dV.<lb/></div>

	<reference>From (18), (20) and (21)<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">(25)<lb/></note>

	<div type="abstract">and we obtain the MKdV solution<lb/> q = 27]sech( -2TJx + 87]3 t ).<lb/> (26)<lb/> The Miura transformationS<lb/> (27)<lb/> 33<lb/> gives a solution u of the KdV equation<lb/> u = 47]2 (sech 2 2B + isech2B tanh 2B).<lb/> (28)<lb/> SCALAR CURVATURE AND GEOMETRY<lb/> The notion of scalar curvature and curvature two forms in two dimensions<lb/> is useful in discussing nonlinear equations. Conformal field theory on Riemann<lb/> surfaces plays an important role in understanding the dynamics of string theory. It<lb/> is therefore interesting to discuss the relation of scalar curvature r to the geometry.<lb/> To set the notation, the element of length ds for a Minkowski metric gAB 1S<lb/> given by<lb/> gAB = (1 0)<lb/> o -1 .<lb/> On the light cone x+ = t + x<lb/> x_ = t -x and<lb/> In complex coordinates,<lb/> z=t+ix<lb/> ZO = z,<lb/> z&apos; = z<lb/> z = t -ix,<lb/> 8z = ~(8t -i8x ),<lb/> 8i. = ~(8t + i8,,).<lb/> 2<lb/> (29)<lb/> (30)<lb/> If two metric tensors gij and gij in spaces Vn and Vn in n dimensions are related<lb/> by gij = e 2tT gij then Vn and Vn are conformal spaces and the transformation is a<lb/> conformal transformation. 1 In V2 , every metric is conformal to a constant metric or<lb/> any Vi can be mapped conformally on a flat space 9 52&apos;<lb/> In two dimensions, we parametrize the metric as gAB = (~ ~) and obtain<lb/> the s~alar curvature r given in (5). The square of the element of length is<lb/> ds 2 = Pdt 2 + 2Qdtdx + Rdx 2 @BULLET<lb/> (31)<lb/> Equations of motion of various models are obtained from a given gAB and r. We<lb/> rewrite ds 2 and r in the z coordinates with the aid of (29) and (30), and get the<lb/> following relations.<lb/> 34<lb/> and<lb/> ds 2 = P&apos;dz 2 + 2Q&apos;dzdz + R&apos;dz 2<lb/> = Aldz + /-Ldzl2<lb/> P&apos; = ~(P -R -2iQ) = A/-L*,<lb/> 4<lb/> 1<lb/> A = -(P + R + 2.;9) &gt; 0<lb/> 4<lb/> R&apos; = ~(P -R + 2iQ) = A/-L,<lb/> I/-LI &lt; 1<lb/> 4<lb/> Q&apos; = ~(P + R) = ~A(l + 1/-L12),<lb/> 4<lb/> 2<lb/> ( P&apos; QI)<lb/> gAB = Q&apos; R&apos; ,<lb/> , -P&apos;R&apos; Q,2 -<lb/>9<lb/> 9 -<lb/>-<lb/>--4&quot;&apos;<lb/> (32)<lb/> (33)<lb/> (34)<lb/> up to a determinant that is suppressed. Equation (34) can be obtained from (5) by<lb/> making the substitutions t ..</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>.... z, x ...... z, g ...... g&apos; etc ..<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">We obtain ds 2 and r in the w coordinates by defining<lb/> dw = dz + /-Ldz,<lb/> (35)<lb/> or<lb/> dz = n(dw -/-Ldw),<lb/> From (32) and (35) one gets<lb/> (36)<lb/> Also one has from (35)<lb/> or<lb/> (37)<lb/> aw = n(ar. -/-Laz )<lb/> ar. = aY, + /-Law<lb/> The r in the w coordinates can be obtained from that in x coordinates by substi-<lb/>tuting t ..</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>.... w, x ...... w, P = R = 0, Q ...... ~<lb/> ~<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>.</address>

	<email>;g ...... y</email>

	<div type="abstract">&apos;9). = -A, 2<lb/> (38)<lb/> There is no suppression of a determinant term in (38) because of the relation<lb/> P=R=O.<lb/> 35<lb/> Let us put<lb/> (39)<lb/> From (36), (38) and (39), one obtains rand r&apos; for A and Ae 2 0&quot;, respectively<lb/> 4<lb/> r = --(inA)&quot; ..<lb/> A<lb/> (40)<lb/> ,<lb/> -20&quot; (<lb/> 8<lb/> )<lb/> r = e<lb/> r -&gt;:0&quot;&quot; ..<lb/> (41)<lb/> We consider the relation of r to the geometry. Riemann surface for any algebraic<lb/> function is topologically a sphere with g handles, where g is the genus of the surface.<lb/> How is sign of r related to geometry? If (string) world sheet is a compact Riemann<lb/> surface of genus g, the (topological invariant) Euler characteristic on manifold M is<lb/> defined as 10<lb/> Recall (39) and (41)<lb/> and<lb/> x = 2 -29<lb/> X(M) = ~Jd2zv&apos;iifr.<lb/> 471&quot;<lb/> ,<lb/> -20&quot;(<lb/> 8<lb/> )<lb/> r = e<lb/> r --0&quot;&quot; ..<lb/> A<lb/> ).2<lb/> Igl=-<lb/>4<lb/> Let us normalize 0&quot; by requiring l l<lb/> or<lb/> then<lb/> 1J2 Ii&quot;:!<lb/> 1J2,A<lb/> X = -<lb/>d zy Iglr = r -<lb/>d z-= r<lb/> 471&quot;<lb/> 471&quot;<lb/> 2<lb/> (42)<lb/> (43)<lb/> Let M be a compact Riemann surface without boundary or window, then the<lb/> uniformization theorem 12 states there are three distinct compact Riemann surfaces<lb/> up to holomorphic equivalence(a) sphere g = 0 (b) torus<lb/> g = 1 (c) upper half<lb/> plane g &gt; 1.<lb/> We find that 13 r = X = 2, for 9 = OJ r = X = 0, for g=1j and r = X = -2 for<lb/> 9 = 2.<lb/> POISSON BRACKETS FROM VIRASORO ALGEBRA<lb/> The Poisson brackets of various solvable two-dimensional models are specified<lb/> by the Virasoro algebra. As a result, their equations of motion result from appro-<lb/>priate evolution equations. These models share an infinite number of conserved<lb/> quantities and the same central charge, and are related by suitable changes of dy-<lb/>namical variables.<lb/> 36<lb/> Conformal field theory in two dimensions (2D) plays an important role in string<lb/> &apos;theory and solvable 2D models. We have noted that the solution of various classical<lb/> nonlinear 2D models can be obtained from the condition that the appropriate cur-<lb/>vature two-form n = o. This suggests that these models are closely related among<lb/> themselves; here we further explore the close relations among the models. The con-<lb/>dition for solvability is the existence of an infinite number of conserved quantities.<lb/> We focus our attention on these conserved quantities and the central charge c in the<lb/> classical version of the Virasoro algebra which specifies the Poisson brackets. We<lb/> begin with the Poisson bracket of the Virasoro generators Ln and obtain the Poisson<lb/> bracket of their Fourier transform u( x). The KdV equation for the amplitude u( x)<lb/> then follows from the evolution equation given a suitable HamiItonian. J4 ,IS The<lb/> infinite set of co=uting conserved quantities involved (which include the Hamil-<lb/>tonian) and the central charge are obtained.<lb/> The Virasoro algebra for classical systems is expressed in terms of the Poisson<lb/> bracket,<lb/> i{Ln,Lm} = (n -m)Ln+m + 1~c(n3 -n)on+m,O,<lb/> (44)<lb/> where Ln are the Virasoro generators and c is the central charge. We introduce the<lb/> field u(x), when the time dependence is suppressed,<lb/> 00<lb/> L -in&quot;<lb/> 1<lb/> e<lb/> --<lb/>n<lb/> 4&apos;<lb/> (45)<lb/> u(x) = 21i .E<lb/> n= -&lt;X&gt;<lb/> where the scale factor 21i is a parameter chosen to yield the appropriate co=uta-<lb/>tion relation in the quantized field theory, and the constant ~ is included to remove<lb/> the 0&apos; term from the Poisson bracket of u(x) that results from (44). The periodic<lb/> boundary condition u(t, x + 271&quot;) = u(t, x) is imposed throughout, and it is assumed<lb/> that u(x) has continuous x derivatives of any order. From (44) and (45), we obtain,<lb/> {u(x),u(y)} = 271&quot;1i[-01ll(X -y) + 2u(x)0&apos;(x -y) + 2u(y)0&apos;(x -y)],<lb/> (46)<lb/> where the primes on the .5 function are derivatives with respect to x, provided the<lb/> central charge is chosen to be<lb/> c = 3/li.<lb/> ( 47)<lb/> Observe the formal anology of Eq. (46) with the quantum commutator of stress-<lb/>energy tensors, which also represent the Virasoro algebra in the context of conformal<lb/> field theory. Periodic boundary condition u( t, x + 271&quot;) = u( t, x) is imposed through-<lb/>out.<lb/> The infinite set of conserved quantities Hn ofthe KdV model are given b y14-I7<lb/> where<lb/> n :2: 0,<lb/> WI =u<lb/> n-I<lb/> W n +l == -L WrW n -r -w~.<lb/> r=l<lb/> ( 48)<lb/> ( 49)<lb/> 37<lb/> The W2 to Ws that result from (49) are<lb/> It is shown that I4 -I1<lb/> ,<lb/> W2 =-u<lb/> &quot;<lb/> 2<lb/> W3 = U -u<lb/> W4 = -u&apos;&quot; + 4uu&apos;<lb/> Ws = u&quot;&quot; -4uu&quot; -3u&apos;2 + 2u 3<lb/> {Hn,Hm} = 0<lb/> Indeed, the KdV equation follows from the evolution equ.ation<lb/> Ut = {u,H},<lb/> provided HI is picked as the Hamiltonian so that<lb/> Ut = {u, 4~1i. J dx -u 2 } = U zzz -6u(x)u z (x).<lb/></div>

	<phone>(50)<lb/> (51)<lb/> (52)<lb/> (53)<lb/></phone>

	<div type="abstract">&quot;\Ve pause here and remark on the physical significance of the conserved prop-<lb/>erties of the KdV equation. The equation of motion of the KdV Lagrangian I8<lb/> yields<lb/> or for u = cPz<lb/> Ut -6uu z -U zzz = 0 .<lb/> This is another form of the KdV equation that follows from (53) upon U -&gt; -u.<lb/> The Hamiltonian density for L is<lb/> Therefore the integral corresponds to H2 of (48)<lb/> Hz = --<lb/>dxws = --<lb/>dx u + -U z<lb/> 1 J 1 J (3 1 2)<lb/> 4~1i.<lb/> 2~1i.<lb/> 2<lb/> The KdV equation describes shallow water waves, where the amplitude U is pro-<lb/>portional to the square root of the depth us seen from the solution (28). The Hz<lb/> expresses the conservation of energy of shallow water waves.<lb/> Write the KdV equation (53) as a conservation equation of density T and flux<lb/> X i.e.<lb/> 38<lb/> aT ax<lb/> -+ -= 0<lb/> at ax<lb/> &apos;<lb/> where<lb/> T=u,<lb/> If T and X are integrable for -00 &lt; x &lt; 00, then 1t J:&apos;:&quot;oo u dx = -XI~oo = 0 or<lb/> Ho = const where u is a solution of the KdV equation. T may be regarded as the<lb/> density of the flux so Ho = const expresses the conservation of mas:;. Similarly,<lb/> u(Ut -U zzz + 6uu z ) = 0 can be written as a conservation equation where T = tu 2 ,<lb/> X = 2u 3 -uU zz + tu;, and J:&apos;:&quot;oo u 2 dx = const or HI = const which expresses the<lb/> conservation of momentum of the water waves described by the KdV equation. I7<lb/> The KdV equation is invariant under the scale transformation u -+ A 2 U, t -+ T I A 3 ,<lb/> X -+ XI A, &apos;&quot; -+ A&lt;/&gt;, as this sy=etry holds for the evolution equation ( 52) and the<lb/> Poisson bracket (46).<lb/> To obtain the other two dimensional nonlinear models one can proceed to<lb/> transform amplitudes from u(x) to p(x) via u(x) = p2(X) + pz(x), where the sub-<lb/>script denotes derivative with respect to the :z: variable, and obtain the Poisson<lb/> bracket of p( x). As a consequence, the modified Kortcweg de Vries (MKdV) equa-<lb/>tion, sine Gordon (S-G) equation, and Liouville (L) equation are obtained from the<lb/> evolution equation for a suitable Hamiltonian. I9 When vex) = p2 + ipz is formed,<lb/> another form of the KdV equation follows. The conserved quantities and care<lb/> shared by the KdV, MKdV, SG and L models. Finally, the additional transforma-<lb/>tion p( x) = &apos;if;z( x) + &apos;if; + ( x) is made, and the nonlinear Schrodinger (NLS) equation<lb/> is obtained from the evolution equation. 2o The Virasoro algebra employed above<lb/> is not a degeneracy sy=etry, i.e. its generators do not represent charges that<lb/> co=ute with the Hamiltonian. Instead, they constitute the dynamical variable<lb/> (amplitude) of the system, and the algebra serves to specify its dynamics through<lb/> their nontrivial co=utators with the Hamiltonian.21<lb/></div>

	<note type="grant">This work was supported in part by the u.s. Department of Energy under<lb/> Contract No. EY-76-C-02-1415*00.<lb/></note>

	<reference>REFERENCES<lb/> 1. H. Bohr, B. Hou, and S. Saito, Nuovo Cimento A 84, 237 (1984); K. Tanaka,<lb/> ibid. 93, 63 (1986).<lb/> 2. S. Weinberg, Gravitation and Cosmology (Wiley, New York, 1972).<lb/> 3. N.K. Mishra and K. Tanaka, Phys. Rev. D 36, 3722 (1987); L. Dolan, ibid.<lb/> 15, 2337 (1977).<lb/> 4. L.L. Chau, in proceeding of Seminare de Mathematique, Montreal, 1985<lb/> ( unpublished).<lb/> 5. M. Crampin, F.A.E. Pirani and D.C. Robinson, Lett. Math. Phys. ~, 15<lb/> (1977).<lb/> 6. M.J. Ablowitz, D.J. Kaup, A.C. Newell, and H. Segur, Phys. Rev. Lett. 31,<lb/> 125 (1973).<lb/> 7. K. Tanaka, J. Math. Phys. 30,172 (1989).<lb/> 8. R.M. Miura, J. Math. Phys. ~, 1202 (1968).<lb/> 39<lb/> 9. L.P. Eisenhart, Riemannian Geometry, (Princeton University Press, Princeton,<lb/> 1949).<lb/> 10. M. Green, J. Schwarz and E. Witten, Superstring Theory, (Cambridge<lb/> University Press, 1986).<lb/> 11. O. Alvarez, Nuc!. Phys. B216, 125 (1983).<lb/> 12. W. Abikoff, The Real Analytic Theory of TechmiilIer Space (Springer-Verlag<lb/> New York, 1980).<lb/> 13. K. Tanaka, New Theories in Physics, World Scientific, Singapore, 1988.<lb/> 14. J.L. Gervais, Phys. Lett. 160B, 277 (1985); J.L. Gervais, ibid. 160B, 279<lb/> (1985).<lb/> 15. R. Sasaki and 1. Yamanaka, in Proceedings of the &quot;Conformal Field Theory<lb/> and Solvable Lattice Models&quot;, Nagoya University, 1987.<lb/> 16. B.A. Dubrovin, V.B. Matveev and S.P. Novikov, Usp. Math. Nank 31, 55<lb/> (1976).<lb/> 17. C.S. Gardner, J. Math. Phys. 12,1548 (1971).<lb/> 18. P.G. Drazin and R.S. Johnson, &quot;Solitons: an introduction&quot; (Cambridge<lb/> University Press, Cambridge, England, 1989).<lb/> 19. K. Tanaka, The Ohio State University preprint.<lb/> 20. M. Omote et al, Phys. Rev. 35, 2423 (1987).<lb/> 21. C. Zachos, private co=unication.<lb/> 40<lb/></reference>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>EXPLICIT SOLITON-GENERATING BACKLUND TRANSFORMATIONS<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>H. C. Yen<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Department of Physics<lb/> National Tsing Hua University,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Hsinchu, Taiwan 30043<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>J. C. Shaw<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Department of Applied Mathematics<lb/> National Chiao Tung University,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Hsinchu, Taiwan<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">Some 2-d nonlinear differential equations (NLDE) can be regarded as<lb/> the integrability condition for certain linear systems l possessing a free<lb/> spectral parameter A:<lb/> (1)<lb/> where ¢, U, V are all square matrix functions of x, t and A, and U, V are<lb/> rational functions of A. Thus the compatibility condition fo~ Eq. (1),<lb/> U t -Vx + [U,V] = 0<lb/> for all A,<lb/> (2)<lb/> corresponds exactly to the NLDE under consideration. A very general and<lb/> powerful method to derive new solutions from a given seed solution of such<lb/> NLDE is the Riemann problem technique~-4 and a particular special case of<lb/> this method provides a systematic scheme for constructing purely solitonic<lb/> solutions 3 . Here we briefly describe some results of this scheme and<lb/> indicate to what physically interesting models it has been applied.<lb/> Given a solution uO(x,t) of the NLDE [and hence the associated UO(A),<lb/> VO(A)], one can compute the corresponding wave function ¢O(x,t;A) from<lb/> Eq. (1). Let ~1 and ~2 = ~1-1 be two matrix functions parametrized by<lb/> 1 -<lb/>P ex, t),<lb/> (3)<lb/> where Al and ~l are two suitably chosen points in the complex A-plane,<lb/> and P is an undetermined projection matrix, with p2 = P. Then we tentatively<lb/> define utA) and VeAl by<lb/> Differentiul Geornerrtc A1erhods in Theoret/cal Physics<lb/> Edited by L.-L. Chou and W. ~ahm. Plenum Press. Now York. 1990<lb/> 41<lb/> (4)<lb/> Since we wish to extract a new solution u(x,t) from so defined U(A) and<lb/> V(A), they are required to possess the right A-structure so that Eq. (2)<lb/> will give exactly the desired NLDE. For example, we must at least demand<lb/> that the RHS of Eqs. (4) be free of pole singularities at Al and ~I&apos; This<lb/> immediately leads to a constraint on the projection matrix P,<lb/> (5)<lb/> [plus a parallel equation involving dt and V O ; in the following such<lb/> parallel equations will be omitted but understood]. Eq. (5) can be ex-<lb/>plicitly solved in terms of ¢o. In the case of 2x2 matrix, for example,<lb/> P can be written as<lb/> (6)<lb/> where (a,S) and (y,o) are two suitably chosen constant vectors.<lb/> After removing the apparent pole terms from the RHS of Eq. (4), we<lb/> obtain<lb/> which becomes an explicit Backlund transformation (BT) between the seed<lb/> solution uO(x,t) and the new solution u(x,t), provided the RHS of Eq. (7)<lb/> has the correct A-structure that a U(A) is supposed to have. Thus u is<lb/> now explicitly calculable in terms of U O and ¢o, and, in addition, the<lb/> wave function ¢ corresponding to the new solution u is merely algebraically<lb/> related to the old wave function ¢o by<lb/> (8)<lb/> When the correct boundary behavior is also implemented, the new<lb/> solution u wi 11 have one more &quot;sol i ton&quot; in its phys ical contents than the<lb/> seed solution u O @BULLET Thus Eq. (7) becomes an explicit &quot;adding-one-soliton&quot;<lb/> BT. One can also use Eqs. (5) and (7) to derive a more familiar (but non-<lb/>explicit) BT if one so wishes. The above constructive procedure can be<lb/> iterated to algebraically generate a sequence of solutions with ever in-<lb/>creasing soliton numbers. Quite a few well-known 2-d NLDE&apos;s, including<lb/> K-dV, mK-dV, NLS, s-G and Liouville eqs., can be treated in this manner.<lb/> The 2-d principal chiral field equation is another important system<lb/> in physics that can be treated in this way. The linear system in this case<lb/> can be chosen to be 5<lb/> -1<lb/> -1<lb/> (A-I)di;&lt;l&gt;<lb/> (g di;g)&lt;j&gt;,<lb/> -(A+I)d n ¢ = (g dng)¢·<lb/> (9)<lb/> Eq. (9) fits nicely into the soliton-generating scheme described above, and<lb/> one can easily write down an explicit BT [Eq. (7)] for the principal chiral<lb/> fields, as well as derive the more familiar but non-explicit BT6:<lb/> -1<lb/> -1<lb/> 0<lb/> g di; g -gO di; g<lb/> -1<lb/> 1<lb/> g d n g -gO-d n gO<lb/> 42<lb/> k di;(go-l g ),<lb/> -kdn(go-lg).<lb/> (10)<lb/> Basically the same method is applicable to the principal chiral model with<lb/> a Wess-Zumino term, and to the super-symmetric principal chiral model, with<lb/> or without a Wess-Zumino term7 , because they all have a linear system of<lb/> the same type as Eq. (9).<lb/> Now the self-dual Yang-Mills (SDYM) equation in J-formulation has an<lb/> associated linear system8 ,4<lb/> (A3_-3 )¢ = (J-1 3 J)¢ ,<lb/> z Y<lb/> Y<lb/> (11)<lb/> which has some similarity in structure with Eq. (9), but differs from it<lb/> by having four instead of two variables in the eqs. However, two of the<lb/> four degrees of freedom do not actually enter Eq. (11) and hence only<lb/> become free parameters of the system. In particular, the poles Al and WI<lb/> of Eq. (3) must now depend on these two parameters. Except for this com-<lb/>plication, the same procedure for constructing soliton solutions goes<lb/> through for the SDYM eq., resulting the algebraic generation of one-mono-<lb/>pole4 and one-instanton9 solutions from the vacuum solutions. It is also<lb/> possible to derive a more conventional-looking but non-explicit BT9:<lb/> (12)<lb/> where<lb/> (13)<lb/> Finally, the most interesting case among all integrable systems of the<lb/> type we have been discussing here is the supersymmetric Yang-Mills (SSYM)<lb/> eq. in 4 ordinary plus N super dimensions, since it contains as a subset<lb/> the full Yang-Mills eq.lO when N = 3,4. The SSYM linear system in J-<lb/>formulation can be written as 11<lb/> (14)<lb/> which is again a bit similar in structure to Eq. (11). with, however, a<lb/> major difference. Eq. (14) is now a 2-parameter instead of I-parameter<lb/> linear system. After a lot of trials and errors, we now feel that the<lb/> special Riemann problem technique as discussed in this paper is probably<lb/> not quite capable of dealing with this 2-parameter linear system12 . It<lb/> seems likely that here one needs a complete reformulation of the Riemann<lb/> problem for two complex variables.<lb/> Notice that there is no such difficulty for the self-dual SSYM eq.,<lb/> because in this special case Eq. (14) is reduced to a one-parameter linear<lb/> system:<lb/> (15)<lb/> 0,<lb/> 43<lb/> The soliton-generating procedure is again applicable, resulting, for ex-<lb/>ample, the construction of a super one-instanton solution9 from the vacuum<lb/> solution.<lb/> In conclusion, we have seen that the special Riemann problem technique<lb/> provides a direct and unified method to generate soliton solutions for many<lb/> nonlinear equations, which are characterized by an associated I-parameter<lb/> linear system. However, the same method would probably not work for 2-<lb/>parameter linear systems.<lb/></div>

	<note type="other">Acknowledgements<lb/> We thank L.-L. Chau for many discussions and collaboration. This<lb/> work is supported by the National Science Council of R.O.C.<lb/></note>

	<reference>References<lb/> 1. P. D. Lax, Comm. Pure Appl. Math. 21,467 (1968); V. E. Zakharovand<lb/> P. B. Shabat, SOy. Phys. JETP 34,~2 (1972); M. J. Ablowitz, O. J.<lb/> Kaup, A. C. Newell and H. Segur:-Phys. Rev. Lett. 31, 125 (1973);<lb/> Stud. App1. Math. ~, 249 (1974)<lb/> --<lb/>2. M. F. Atiyah and R. S. Ward, Comm. Math. Phys. ~, 117 (1977);</reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>E.<lb/> Corrigan, D. B. Fairlie, P. Goddard and R. G. Yates</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>, Comm. Math. Phys.<lb/> 58,223 (1978); V. E. Zakharov and A. V. Mikhailov, SOY. Phys. JETP<lb/> 74, 1953 (1978); V. E. Zakharov and P. B. Shabat, Funct. Anal. Appl.<lb/> 13, 166 (I979)<lb/> 3. S. Novikov, S. V. Manakov, L. P. Pitaevskii and V. E. Zakharov,<lb/> &quot;Theory of Solitons&quot;, Consultants Bureau, New York 1984<lb/> 4. P. Forgacs, Z. Horvath and L. Palla, Phys. Rev. 023, 1876 (1981); Nucl.<lb/> Phys. B229, 77 (1983)<lb/> 5. V. E. Zakharov and A. V. Mikhailov, SOY. Phys. ,JETP 47,1017 (1978);<lb/> L.-L. Chau Wang, in Proceedings of Guanzhou Conference on Theoretical<lb/> Particle Physics, Jan. 1980, Canton<lb/> 6. K. Pohlmeyer, Comm. Math. Phys. 46, 207 (1978); L. V. Cheredrik,<lb/> Teor. Mat. Fiz. 38, 120 (1979);</reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>A~T. Ogielsky, M. K. Prasad, A. Sinha<lb/> and L.-L. Chau Wang, Phys. Lett. ~</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>, 387 (1980)<lb/> 7. T. 1. Curtright and C. K. Zachos, Phys. Rev. 021, 411 (1980);<lb/> Z. Popowicz and L.-L. Chau Wang, Phys. Lett. 98B, 253 (1981); G.<lb/> Bhatracharya and S. Rajeev, Nuc1. Phys. 8246. 157 (1984); K.-C. Chou<lb/> and Y.-B. Oai, Commun. Theor. Phys. (China) 3, 767 (1984); H. J. de<lb/> Vega, preprints LPTHE 85/23 and 85/53; M. C. B. Abdalla, Phys. Lett.<lb/> B152, 21S (1985); S. J. Gates, C. M. Hull and M. Rocek, Nucl. Phys.<lb/> B248, 157 (1984); T. L. Curtright and C. K. Zachos, Phys. Rev. Lett.<lb/> 53, 1799 (1984);</reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>P. Oi Vecchia, V. G. Knizhnik, J. L. Petersen and P.<lb/> Rossi</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>, Nucl. Phys. B253, 701 (1985); E. Abdalla and M. C. B. Abdalla,<lb/> Phys. Lett. B1S~, S9-cT985); L.-L. Chau and H. C. Yen, Phys. Lett.<lb/> B177, 368 (1986)<lb/> 8. A. Belavin and V. E. Zakharov, Phys. Lett. 73B, S3 (1978); K. Pohlmeyer.<lb/> 44<lb/> Comm. Math. Phys. 72, 37 (1980); G. Sartori:-Nuovo Cimento 56A, 73 (1980);<lb/> L.-L. Chau, M. K. Prasad and A. Sinha, Phys. Rev. 023, 2321-cT981); ibid<lb/> 024, 1574 (1981)<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>9. L.-L. Chau, J. C. Shaw and H. C. Yen</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>, Int. J. Mod. Phys. A4, 2715<lb/> (1989)<lb/> 10. E. Witten, Phys. Lett. 77B, 394 (1978); M. Sohnius, Nucl. Phys.<lb/> B136, 461 (1978); L.-L. Chau, M.-L. Ge and C.-S. Lim, Phys. Rev. 033,<lb/> 1056 (1986).<lb/> 11. I. V. Volovich, Phys. Lett. 129B, 429 (1983); C. Oevchand, Nucl. Phys.<lb/> B23? 333 (1984); L.-L. Chau,~L. Ge and Z. Popowicz, Phys. Rev. Lett.<lb/> 52, 1940 (1984)<lb/> 12. J. Hamad and M. Jacques, J. Math. Phys. 27, 2394 (1986); J. Tafel,<lb/> J. Math. Phys. 28, 240 (1987); N. Suzuki:-Comm. Math. Phys. ~, 155<lb/> (1987); C. Oevchand, preprint THEP 88/13.<lb/> 45<lb/></reference>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>INTEGRABILITY CONDITIONS:<lb/> RECENT RESULTS IN THE THEORY OF INTEGRABLE MODELS<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>R. K. Bullough, S. Olafsson, and Yu-Zhong Chen<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Department of Mathematics<lb/> UMIST,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>POBox 88<lb/> Manchester M60 lQD, UK<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>J. Timonen<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Physics Department<lb/> University of Jyvaskyla<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>SF-40100 Jyvaskyla, Finland<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">I<lb/> INTRODUCTION<lb/> This paper reports various results achieved recently in the theory of<lb/> integrable models.<lb/> These are summarised in the Fig.l!<lb/> At the Chester<lb/> meeting [1] two of the authors were concerned [1] with the local<lb/> Riemann-Hilbert problem (double-lined box in the centre of Fig.l), its limit<lb/> as a non-local Riemann-Hilbert problem used to solve classical integrable<lb/> models in 2+1 dimensions (two space and one time dimensions) [2,3], and the<lb/> connection of this Riemann-Hilbert problem with Ueno&apos;s [4] Riemann-Hilbert<lb/> problem associated with the representation of the algebra gl(oo) in terms of<lb/> Z®Z matrices (Z the integers) and the solution of the K-P equations in 2+1.<lb/> We were also concerned [1) with the construction of the integrable models<lb/> in 1+1 dimensions from the loop algebras g = gS[:&gt;&apos;,A-1 ] where g is a simple<lb/> finite dimensional Lie algebra and A IE: C.<lb/> Extensions to super-Lie algebras<lb/> and super-integrable models in 1+1 were also sketched [1,5,6].<lb/> The paper identified three particular &apos;centres&apos; of classical integrability<lb/> in 1+1 dimensions:-(i) the Lax pair Vx = Uv, Vt = VV; U,V IE: g = sl(N,C); (ii)<lb/> the loop algebras and the KSA (Kostant-Symes-Adler [5,7]) theorem; and<lb/> (iii) the Sklyanin bracket (T(:&gt;&apos;)~T(j.l)} = [T(:&gt;.)0T(j.l),r(:&gt;.,j.l)] (where T is a<lb/> monodromy matrix, A,J.i. IE: C and r(:&gt;&apos;,J.i.) is the classical &apos;little r-matrix&apos;<lb/> [8,9,10]).<lb/> As befits a meeting on &apos;Geometry and Physics&apos; the present paper is<lb/> concerned to trace a connection between one piece of &quot;real physics&quot; and<lb/> another piece of &quot;real physics&quot; via a significant part of the mathematics<lb/> (i.e. mathematical physics) now surrounding the integrable models:<lb/> this<lb/> mathematics is that summarised in the Fig. 1.<lb/> The first piece of real<lb/> physics (on which we can scarcely dwell here) concerned the propagation<lb/> of intense (gigawatt cm-2 at peak) short (n sec.) optical pulses in a<lb/> resonant medium [11-15] and it was where the interest of one of the<lb/> authors (RKB) in solitons [16] (as well as much of that subject [15])<lb/> actually began. The second piece of real physics is much more recent and<lb/></div>

	<reference>Differential Geometric Methods in Theoretical Physics<lb/> Edited by l.-L. Chau and W. Nahm, Plenum Press. New York, 1990<lb/></reference>

	<div type="abstract">47<lb/> concerns solitons as thermal excitations in real systems -particularly in<lb/> the ferromagnetic CsNiFs and the antiferromagnetic TMMC [17], in biological<lb/> molecules like DNA [18,19], and in high-Tc superconductivity [20].<lb/> These<lb/> references since 1982 form the particular &apos;EXPERIMENTS&apos; output from Fig.l,<lb/> and the calculations to this end form the route from top left to top right<lb/> on that Figure (there are of course very many other applications of soliton<lb/> theory to &quot;real&quot; physical problems now -some are in, for example, [12] -<lb/>but we cannot touch on these here).<lb/> This paper will be concerned<lb/> primarily with the route top left to top right on Fig.l mentioned: the idea<lb/> of the paper is to show how the classical r-matrix and the quantum<lb/> R-matrix for classical and quantum integrable models in 1+1 dimensions<lb/> respectively, may be used to evaluate the classical and quantum partition<lb/> functions<lb/> (1)<lb/> in which Seep] is the appropriate classical action.<lb/> The &apos;EXPERIMENTS&apos;<lb/> output follows eventually from the calculation of this functional integral.<lb/> Functional integrals<lb/> symplectic manifold J.1 =<lb/> Canonical variables IT(X,T),<lb/> the quantum cases, Seep]<lb/> Hamiltonian form (21,22]<lb/> (1), quantum or classical, are taken over a<lb/> R2 00 with closed differential 2-form &apos;19-: d r:J = o.<lb/> ep(X,T) satisfy a bracket {IT,ep} = SIx-x&apos;) and, in<lb/> is the Wick rotated classical action taken in<lb/> S[ep]= J~dT [iJ~LdxIT(X&apos;T)ep&apos;T(X&apos;T)-H[ep]]<lb/> (2)<lb/> in which H[ep] is the classical Hamiltonian (i=~ and ep&apos;T. aepjaT).<lb/> Integration (on R 9 R) is over the space-time torus ((X,T) E: R2: -L ~ x &lt; +<lb/> L, 0 ~ T &lt; f3) and tr 1 = T = temperature: the Tr in (1) implies periodic<lb/> boundary conditions (b.c.s) in f3 while periodic b.c.s in x are assumed so<lb/> that, eventually L ... 00 in finite density thermodynamic limit (see below).<lb/> Note that, despite the formal Wick rotation, (X,T) E: R2 and classical<lb/> trajectories evolve in 1M under H in real time T. Note also that n = 1 in<lb/> the classical action (2). In classical limit n ... 0 this action becomes [22]<lb/> S[epj= J~-H[ep]dT = -f3H[ep] .<lb/> (3)<lb/> If H(ep] is quadratic in the canonical momenta IT(X,T), the action (2) with n ~<lb/> o can be reduced to the usual Lagrangian action by integration on fJ) IT.<lb/> The measure in (1) is then the Feynman measure [23]. The symplectic<lb/> measure f}IT1Jep in (1) is simpler than the Feynman measure [21,22]. It is<lb/> the same in both the classical and quantum cases, i.e. whether Seep] is (3)<lb/> or (2).<lb/> The symplectic measure must be used with (3) in the classical<lb/> cases -Feynman&apos;s measure for the partition function exploits the Wick<lb/> rotation and is interpreted differently [23].<lb/> By evaluating (1) for an integrable model in 1+1 dimensions we find<lb/> the free energy density lim FL-l = lim (-tr 1 L-1 1n Z): F is the Helmholtz<lb/> L--<lb/>1-+00<lb/> free energy.<lb/> We shall be primarily concerned in this paper with the<lb/> sine-Gordon (s-G) model with classical Hamiltonian<lb/> H[ep]<lb/> Yo-1 JdX[~Yo2TT2 + ~x2 + m 2 (l-cos ep)]<lb/> (4)<lb/> (in which Yo &gt; 0, Yo E: R is a coupling constant; m &gt; 0, m E: IR is a mass and<lb/> {IT,ep} = Sex-x&apos;»~ and with its free energy density lim FL-l, as well as<lb/> 1-+00<lb/> with the sinh-Gordon (sinh-G) model<lb/> H[ep] = Yo-l fdx [~Y02IT2 + ~~ + m 2 (cosh ep -1)]<lb/> (5)<lb/> 48<lb/> (where Yo, m &gt; 0) and its free energy density.<lb/> have equations of motion<lb/> m 2 sinh $<lb/> These (classical) models<lb/> (6)<lb/> (7)<lb/> respectively. They are covariant and integrable in 1+1, while by canonical<lb/> transformation IT ... Yo-~&apos; $ ... Yo~&apos; analytical continuation in Yo (yo&apos;&quot; -Yo),<lb/> and inverse canonical transformation, s-G (sinh-G) becomes sinh-G (s-G).<lb/> Other relevant classical integrable models are the nonlinear Schrodinger<lb/> (NLS) models<lb/> (8)<lb/> with immediate continuation in the coupling constant c : c &gt; 0 is &apos;repulsive&apos;<lb/> NLS, c &lt; 0 is &apos;attractive&apos;. Moreover, the methods sketched in this paper to<lb/> calculate quantum and classical Z apply to all of the integrable models in<lb/> 1+1 with finite density thermodynamic limits [19].<lb/> They apply to models<lb/> with classical Lax pairs Vx = Uv, Vt = Vv and U,V IE: sl(2,C) -which<lb/> includes s-G, sinh-G, both NLS models, the Landau-Lifshitz model, the<lb/> Heisenberg ferromagnet, for example; but they apply also to, for example,<lb/> the so-called Toda lattice [24] where U,V IE: g = sl(N,C)(N&gt;2) and more<lb/> generally (the Toda lattice of [24], to be distinguished from Toda&apos;s lattice<lb/> [15,18,19], is a sequence of quantum integrable models involving arbitrarily<lb/> many coupled fields:<lb/> the beginnings of the classical Toda lattice were<lb/> found in [25] (and refer Chapter III in [15]).<lb/> But because there were<lb/> apparently no Backlund transformations we thought (in 1976-1977) that the<lb/> system could not be integrable [15,25]. The equation referred to in [26] is<lb/> in [25]). Note in any case that U,V involve a spectral parameter I; IE: C, and<lb/> U,V IE: g, g the loop algebra g = g ® [1;,1;-1] -see the connections Loop<lb/> Algebras ... Integrable Model (which can then be taken back up to Lax Pair)<lb/> in Fig!.<lb/> The Fig.1 as presented now mildly extends that Figure in [1].<lb/> New<lb/> features included are:-(i) the &apos;route&apos; Lax pair ... compatibility (zero<lb/> curvature) ... monodromy matrix T IE: G ( ..</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>. Sklyanin bracket) ... (TrT) ...<lb/> Hamiltonians ... Integrable Model<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">Ut -Vx + [U,V] = 0<lb/> (9)<lb/> This route, already well known [27], is now included to stress the<lb/> fundamental significance of classical &apos;complete integrability&apos;, in the sense of<lb/> Liouville-Arnold [28,29], to all of the mathematical structure exposed in<lb/> Fig.(l). The second new route is (ii) The route Loop Algebras... (quantum<lb/> deformation)... RA = ~R, Hopf algebra... (Dual)... Hopf Algebra 6T = T®T,<lb/> Quantum Groups ... Quantum Inverse Method R NT = NT R or Bethe Ansatz<lb/> +-&gt; R-matrix, Yang-Baxter Relation<lb/> (ooI) (I®R)(ooI) = (I®R)(ooI) (I®R)<lb/> (10)<lb/> The third new route is (iii) The two routes Oriented 3-manifold M, Covariant<lb/> (invariant) theory<lb/> s = ~rr fMTr (AA dA + ;AA AA A)<lb/> (11)<lb/> = integral of Chern-Simmons 3-form ... Knot (link) Polynomials and also ...<lb/> Conformal Field Theory.<lb/> These new routes (iii) are traced back to the<lb/> braid groups in, for example, [30] and are treated in [31].<lb/> They are<lb/> included in Fig.1 only because this 3-manifold theory must relate to the<lb/> 49<lb/> 01<lb/> o<lb/> &quot;SOLITONS&quot;<lb/> U, F al\d oJr<lb/> art&apos;<lb/> N x<lb/> N l&apos;Ih.</div>

	<idno>trices E (<lb/> SI~N,(:))<lb/></idno>

	<note type="other">1 &quot; &quot; g::&apos;<lb/> U, 1/<lb/> gilN,C<lb/></note>

	<idno>__ ~..L_________<lb/> ::._--:<lb/> P&quot;iodi, b.c&apos;, 00<lb/> r L., P,i,<lb/></idno>

	<email>inte.gra.ble<lb/></email>

	<idno>L~tlice .Models<lb/> 1/1., =<lb/> V.&quot;.<lb/></idno>

	<note type="other">ml+1d!ffieflSJOns<lb/> &apos;ft=V,p<lb/> monodromy matrices<lb/> or<lb/> &quot;&apos; H ~ L,,,,<lb/> cl &quot; =<lb/> 0&quot;<lb/> T=OL,_<lb/> L<lb/></note>

	<reference>Fig.l Overview of generalised &apos;Soliton&apos; theory<lb/> a.a of date (Augu5t, 1988).A<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">htLrd arrow indicates that a minimal connection<lb/> (at least) between the<lb/> &apos;boxes&apos; is already achieved: diLShed arrowlI indicate expectation by the au-<lb/>thors that such colluection can be achieved, or better. Note the (%penmen!al<lb/></note>

	<reference>output from the partition function Z, top right! For neutron scattering<lb/> ex·<lb/> periments on the 1+1 dimensional ferromagnetic CsNiF3<lb/> d. Ref. 27 and<lb/> references; for DNA c.f. e.g. Refs. 16,28 and references; fOI<lb/></reference>

	<idno>high Tc super-<lb/>conductivity<lb/> d., e_g,Ref.29.<lb/> I &apos;<lb/> I&apos;-.Hilb~<lb/> ~_~~ SPil~~J<lb/> r----O&gt;-------&gt;-.-+===----.. _.,. .... _ _<lb/> =C-____ _<lb/> periodic.<lb/> --~-!<lb/> L ~il.rtitj;n Fun(~ion<lb/></idno>

	<note type="other">or rapidly vanishlng<lb/> be&apos;s<lb/> for<lb/> ~!t d~~::siJ~~<lb/></note>

	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Symmetries of KP-I and KP-Il Algebra<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<reference>(Km.K.1 ~ 0<lb/> iK&quot;&quot;T .. ] = t(m+n)K..,+n-l<lb/> 1&apos; 1&quot;&quot;,,1&apos; ,,1 = j(m-n)Tm+,.</reference>

	<idno>_2<lb/> -~---------<lb/>00<lb/> dim<lb/> reps<lb/> R-matrix<lb/> Yang-</idno>

	<reference>Baxter Relation<lb/> (R®/)(/®R)(R®I)<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">classical or quant.um integrable models<lb/> I<lb/> &quot;<lb/> Braid Group<lb/> 9.9j<lb/> = gjg,<lb/></note>

	<idno>Ii -j<lb/> I?: 2<lb/> 9,9.+19.<lb/> = 9,+19.9,+1<lb/> v<lb/> .I~<lb/> ;;&apos;<lb/> ~<lb/> c<lb/> 111<lb/> g<lb/> [<lb/> ]:<lb/> Oriented 3-manifold M<lb/> covariant (invariant) theory<lb/> t&gt;J<lb/> X<lb/> &apos; &quot;<lb/> t&gt;J<lb/> &apos; &quot;<lb/> i:<lb/> t&gt;J<lb/> Z<lb/> ~<lb/> ~<lb/> ~<lb/> fr<lb/> ~ §<lb/> ..<lb/> &apos;&lt;<lb/> ~<lb/> c<lb/> [.<lb/> t<lb/> ..<lb/> &quot;<lb/> (&quot;l<lb/></idno>

	<div type="abstract">z<lb/> ~<lb/> b<lb/> z<lb/> &gt;<lb/> 5<lb/> =<lb/> f; fM Tr(A /I<lb/> A<lb/> + ~A 1\<lb/> A 1\<lb/> A)<lb/> = Integral of<lb/> Ch(·rn·Sirnr,ns J.form<lb/> integrable models in 2+1 as well as to the solvable lattice models in 3+0 -<lb/>but these theories have still to be found.<lb/> In this paper we retrace routes (i) and (ii).<lb/> But we are primarily<lb/> concerned with the route Periodic b.c.s (top left in Fig.l) .... H[U] .... H [p],<lb/> Action-Angle Variables .... Partition Functions<lb/> z = ~~ exp S(p]<lb/> (12)<lb/> for 1+1 dimensional classical or quantum integrable models .</div>

	<note type="degree">...... generalised<lb/> Bethe Ansatz ....... Quantum Inverse Method. Implicitly</note>

	<div type="abstract">we are also concerned<lb/> with Zfi!JZ Matrices e gl(co) .</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>... Bose-Fermi Equivalence .... Riemann Surface<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Genus 00 .</address>

	<note type="degree">... S[p] .... Hilbert Space .... Partition Function</note>

	<div type="abstract">with Z given in (12).<lb/> It is primarily from (12) rather than (1) that the output &apos;EXPERIMENTS&apos;<lb/> derives, and our strategy of calculation is to transform (1) ~o (12),<lb/> expressed in terms of action-angle variables with proper measure ;JJ~. &apos;t.4e<lb/> strategy is to &apos;throw&apos; all of the actual difficulty of the calculation into::tJ~<lb/> and the problem then is to calculate (jflJ. . This way, with:Jf~ determined, the<lb/> actual functional integrals for Z, quantum or classical, become wholly<lb/> innocent -all ordering problems are eliminated for example -and the role<lb/> of Z as a functional ,iRtegral becomes simply to minimise the free energy F.<lb/> The calculation of ~~ for classical lim F/L is concerned with classical<lb/> r-matrix theory:<lb/> the calculation of ~~for quantum lim F/L is concerned<lb/> L-+co<lb/> with R-matrix theory: and the two measures are different. It is plain from<lb/> Fig.l that these objects, Rand r, must enter into the calculations.<lb/> Note<lb/> (Fig.l) how the quantum integrable models in 1+1<lb/> relate to the solvable<lb/> models in 2+0 and the n-vertex models (IRF and SOS models [32,33]). The<lb/> connection with Jones&apos;s paper [34] is evident. Note, for example, how, by<lb/> following across to Conformal Field Theories and Virasaro Algebras and<lb/> Strings, Saito [35] has been able to sketch a connection through Mulase&apos;s<lb/> work [36] to the integrable classical K-P equations in 2+1 dimensions.<lb/> We<lb/> believe these connections need still to be thoroughly worked out however.<lb/> II<lb/> SOME &quot;REAL PHYSICS&quot;<lb/> The remarks in ~I must be enough on the Fig.l as such. We develop<lb/> the mathematical physics of the paper in §~III and IV, so in this ~I we add<lb/> a few (very brief) further remarks on the &quot;real physics&quot; we have already<lb/> mentioned.<lb/> The &apos;EXPERIMENTS&apos; output from expressions (12) for Z is referenced in<lb/> e.g. [17-20].<lb/> In [20] and references, Hubbard type lattice models are<lb/> introduced as models of high-T c superconductivity.<lb/> In [20], in the<lb/> continuum and scaling limits, two integrable quantum s-G models emerge (in<lb/> the charge and spin sectors respeclively).<lb/> Bose-Fermi equivalence of s-G<lb/> to the Massive Thirring Model (MTM -see Fig.l and gIV) is exploited to see<lb/> superconducting fluctuations in a massless TM correlation function at high<lb/> temperatures (~10000K).<lb/> In [17] the classical s-G model is derived as a<lb/> model of the ferromagnetic CsNiF 3 in a transverse magnetic field at<lb/> temperatures 3 0 K t{. rr 1 t{. l50J(. The thermal excitations which determine<lb/> the<lb/> neutron<lb/> scattering<lb/> cross-sections<lb/> are<lb/> investigated.<lb/> The<lb/> low<lb/> temperature asymptotic expansion for the. free energy of s-G (given by<lb/> continuation from our equation (76) in<lb/> ~ IV below) can provide specific<lb/> heats for this model. Similar theory applies to the anti-ferromagnetic TMMC<lb/> [17]. In e.g. [18,19] and references, incomplete calculations of the number<lb/> of solitons thermally excited in the biological molecule DNA at body<lb/> temperatures (310 0 K) are given. An inference from the results of ~IV of<lb/> this paper is that the so-called &apos;Davydov soliton&apos; proposed to explain some<lb/> 51<lb/> features of the infra-red spectrum of the ex-helix of biological proteins<lb/> breaks up at body temperatures [37].<lb/> This is all very real physics and<lb/> the reader can consult these papers to find it.<lb/> For the earlier physics of 19S8-1973 (optical pulse propagation in a<lb/> resonant medium) we should perhaps only remind the reader that such a<lb/> medium without level degeneracy [12,15] is modelled semi-classically [11-1S]<lb/> by 2-level atoms coupled to Maxwell&apos;s c-number electromagnetic equations.<lb/> The 2-level atom has an SU(2) representation: SU(2) is a double cover of<lb/> SO(3): SO(3) is the group of transformations of the rigid pendulum and its<lb/> group manifold is the Bloch Sphere [ll,lS].<lb/> An optical pulse of &quot;area&quot; 8<lb/> [11,12], a 8-pulse, tips the Bloch vector through polar angle 8, and a<lb/> 211-pulse tips it by 211 taking the initial atomic state (spin-down = atomic<lb/> ground state) via spin-up (excited state) back to spin-down. No energy is<lb/> absorbed, though there is actually a Berry phase of 11 from the double<lb/> cover which is SU(2) -compare Venturi [38].<lb/> Consequently, a resonant<lb/> dielectric of 2-level atoms traversed by the 211-pulse becomes transparent<lb/> to that pulse and this is the very real physics of &apos;self-induced<lb/> transparency (SIT)&apos; [l1-13,lS].<lb/> For the present brief discussion the equations of motion for SIT (the<lb/> RMB and SIT equations [l1-13,IS]) are simply those of a set of rigid<lb/> pendulums coupled by linear springs and these are the equations (S) of the<lb/> s-G model, for suitable m 2 (and n = c = 1). It is relevant to the §In of<lb/> the present paper that the<lb/> classical s-G model has kink, antikink and<lb/> (kink-antikink pair) breather solutions [11,12,15] while there is &quot;radiation&quot;,<lb/> harmonic type solutions 41 = E: cos(wt -kx + S)· which for small enough<lb/> amplitude E: E: R linearise the s-G model to the Klein-Gordon (K-G) model<lb/> (13)<lb/> with dispersion.<lb/> (14)<lb/> We call these harmonic solutions &apos;phonons&apos; later in this paper.<lb/> The K-G model also plays an important role in the real physics of<lb/> CsNiF3 in that it is crucial to the calculation of both quantum and classical<lb/> Z for s-G and sinh-G. This becomes very apparent in ~IV below, notably in<lb/> equation (7S).<lb/> In the classical calculation of (12) for s-G, ZKG, the<lb/> partition function of the K-G equation (13), renormalises Z for s-G [39].<lb/> We now turn to the mathematical physics of this paper.<lb/> III<lb/> TWO SIGNIFICANT &apos;ROUTES&apos; IN MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS<lb/> These are the routes (i) and (ii) itemised in §I.<lb/> (i)<lb/> Flat connection is the Sklyanin bracket<lb/> The Lax pair Vx = Uv, Vt = Vv (U,V E: g = g 0 [1;, 1;-1] can be<lb/> expressed [15] in terms of the I-form<lb/> o = Udx + Vdt<lb/> (15)<lb/> and dv = Ov. Compatibility of this pair of linear equations in the column<lb/> vector v requires the Poincare integrability condition d 2 v = 0 so<lb/> e = dO -0 A 0 = 0<lb/> (16)<lb/> 52<lb/> which for isospectral flows t;t :: 0 [15] is the Nonlinear Evolution Equation<lb/> (NEE) which is (9).<lb/></div>

	<note type="other">Conversely the NEE (9) is integrable (can be solved),<lb/> since an inverse method is available [3], ·if Vx :: Uv, Vt :: Vv.<lb/> But (16) is thE&quot; condition that a certain curvature a :: O.<lb/> Note [15]<lb/> that a :: 0 is invariant under arbifrary gauge transformations v .... v&apos; :: Bv,<lb/> det B :: 1, for which 0 .... 0&apos; :: dBB-l + BOB-l. Evidently a .... a&apos; :: BaB-l and<lb/> a</note>

	<div type="abstract">:: 0 iff a&apos; :: O.<lb/> The NEE (9) is [a/ax-u, a/at-V] :: 0 and U,V are<lb/> coefficients of a flat connection (in the trivial vector bundle ~2 x eN with<lb/> v(x,t,t;) taking values in the fibre eN [27]). Along a curve Y t ~ X ~ (xo,t o )<lb/> .... (x,t) one usefully defines the space and time ordered transport<lb/> coefficient<lb/> Oy = exp U y 0)<lb/> (17)<lb/> with the evident property 0Yl+ Y2 = ny2nyl&apos; If<lb/> Ln = I + fyn 0 &apos;&quot; I + fyn (Udx + Vdt)<lb/> (18)<lb/> and<lb/> (19)<lb/> then Oy = lim ON as the partitions become dense. Then<lb/> v .... Vy = Oy v<lb/> (20)<lb/> is parallel transport of v, while under gauge transformation<lb/> (21)<lb/> Vanishing curvature (flat connection) means Oy depends only on the<lb/> end points (Ko,le) and (x,t), i.e. v(x,t) :: ny v(XQ,to) satisfies dv :: Ov at<lb/> (x,t).<lb/> The existence of an infinity of conservation laws for the NEE (9)<lb/> follows by taking a closed loop for y so that Oy :: r. We did this rather<lb/> differently from a :: 0 in [15,40,41] developing the theory of prolongation<lb/> structures. But for the present purposes let us here follow [27] -so take<lb/> the closed curve y and for it the square box in ~2 formed by the straight<lb/> lines (-L,to ) .... (L,t o ) .... (L,t 1 &gt; to) ... (-L,t 1 ) ...</div>

	<note type="other">(-L,t o )&apos; Thus at fixed t :: to<lb/> make parallel transport along x: x :: -L to x :: +L and define</note>

	<div type="abstract">, under<lb/> periodic b.c.s in x of period 2L, the monodromy matrix<lb/> TL (t;,t o ) = exp fL U(x,to,t;) dx<lb/> -L<lb/> U t g :: sl (N,C) ® [t;,t;-1]<lb/> N(N-l) independent fields<lb/> (say) and U is an<lb/> &lt;t&gt;(x, t)<lb/> [3).<lb/> If<lb/> (22)<lb/> NxN matrix containing up to<lb/> s±<lb/> S<lb/> tl<lb/> exp<lb/> toU(±L,t,t;)dt,<lb/> periodic b.c.s in x mean S+ :: S_ (s S). Since the flat connection means<lb/> (23)<lb/> periodicity in x means<lb/> (24)<lb/> and AL s TrTL(t 1 ) :: TrTL(to ) is independent of time t.<lb/> Then AL :: AL(t;)<lb/> depending only on the spectral parameter t; t IC.<lb/> Evidently (22) means for U t g that the monodromy matrix TL t G, the<lb/> 53<lb/> group G with<lb/> algebra g.<lb/> Then since U E: g, the loop algebra g :: g ®<lb/> [1;,1;-1], TL :: TL(I;,t) E: G the loop group with algebra g. The monodromy<lb/> matrix (22), defined through (18) and (19) (and see below) is defined on a<lb/> symplectic manifold. This is implicit in the statement [15] that the spectral<lb/> transform (ST) is a canonical transform (Fig.I) (in Fig.I the Lax pair is &apos;i&apos;x<lb/> :: U&apos;i&apos;, &apos;i&apos;t :: V&lt;jJ and the ST derives from &lt;jJx :: U&lt;jJ : &apos;i&apos; is an N x N matrix made<lb/> up of N independent N-column vectors v).<lb/></div>

	<note type="other">The ST is &lt;jJx :: U&lt;jJ with initial<lb/> data U(x,O) at t :: 0 .... spectral data S(O) at t :: O. Then &lt;jJt :: V&lt;jJ gives S(t)<lb/> at t</note>

	<div type="abstract">&gt; 0 [15] and this can be inverted [3] via the local R-H problem with or<lb/> without Marchenko .equation [3,15] to U(x,t) solving the NEE (9) as shown in<lb/> Fig. I.<lb/> This is the classical inverse (or ST) method [15] and this is<lb/> canonical [15].<lb/> (The conservation laws follow [15,40,41].)<lb/> Still it seems<lb/> TL(I;) is defined on a symplectic manifold because the loop algebras lead<lb/> via the KSA theorem [1,5,7] to the evolution equations<lb/> (25)<lb/> where Urn&apos; Un E: fir :: g ® [1;,1;-1], which contain (9) as particular examples.<lb/> Results (25) are demonstrated [1,5,7] by appeal to the observa.!-ion of<lb/> Kirillov [7] that the co-adjoint orbits of the group G (loop group G [5,7])<lb/> in the dual g* (dual g*) of the algebra g (loop algebra g) define a<lb/> symplectic manifold.<lb/> It follows that there is a bracket, the Kirillov bracket [5,7] and that<lb/> this can be replaced by a usual Poisson bracket [7], { ... } :: P.B. on the<lb/> symplectic manifold<lb/> 1M:: 1R2 00 for the elements of TL(I;).<lb/> It was the<lb/> discovery of Sklyanin [42] that the N2 possible brackets between these<lb/> elements could be written in the form<lb/> (26)<lb/> where ® is Kronecker product, [ ... ] is the N2 x N2 matrix commutator, and<lb/> the N2 x N2 matrix r(A,.u), E: g ® g, is the &apos;little r-matrix&apos; [8,10,27].<lb/> Typically r(A,.u) depends on A-.u, A, .u E: C. The matrix trace of (26) means,<lb/> with t.L(A) :; TrTL(),), that<lb/> (27)<lb/> There is a continuous infinity of independent constants in involution<lb/> (commuting under the P.B.) and the NEE (&apos;flow&apos;) (9) is a continuously<lb/> infinite dimensional completely integrable (Hamiltonian) system.<lb/> The<lb/> quantity 1nt.(I;) , also constant, expanded about some point ~ E: C, is a<lb/> generator of Hamiltonians which can be identified with those found [7] from<lb/> the loop algebras.<lb/> Thus, for integrable field models in 1+1, all of the<lb/> classical models are completely integrable Hamiltonian systems and this fact<lb/> underlies all of the structure of Fig.I.<lb/> Moreover, the situation is<lb/> essentially<lb/> the<lb/> same<lb/> in<lb/> 2+1<lb/> dimensions,<lb/> for<lb/> example<lb/> the<lb/> K-P,<lb/> Davey-Stewartson and 3-wave interaction equations [3] are completely<lb/> integrable [43].<lb/> However, we must take notice of boundary conditions (b.c.s). Complete<lb/> integrability of the models in 1+1 was first proved for x E: IR with vanishing<lb/> b.c.s at :I: 00.<lb/> It remains true (of course) under periodic b.c.s (as (27)<lb/> shows). However, nothing is proved in 2+1 dimensions except for vanishing<lb/> b.c.s at infinity [43] and no extension of the Sklyanin bracket (26) is<lb/> known.<lb/> In the calculation of Z for models integrable in 1+1 we take a<lb/> finite density thermodynamic limit under periodic b.c.s of period 2L letting<lb/> 2L .... &quot;&quot;.<lb/> Our method for Z connects action-angle variables under these<lb/> periodic b.c.s with the well known ones [15,27] under vanishing b.c.s at :I:<lb/> 00.<lb/> Although these latter are calculated at zero density [15,27], the<lb/> connection can still be established at finite density to O(L -1) as L .... &quot;&quot;. It<lb/> is this relationship between action-angle variables under periodic b.c.s with<lb/> 54<lb/> those under vanishing b.c.s at :I:: 00 which establishes the proper form of<lb/> the measure:;a /1.<lb/> No comparable analysis for integrable models in 2+1<lb/> dimensions is found yet.<lb/> (ii) Deformed loop algebras are dual to the quantum groups G q<lb/> This is the route Loop Algebras ~ (Quantum Deformation) ~ RA<lb/> ~,<lb/> Hopf Algebra .... (Dual) -+ Hopf Algebra 6T = T ® T -+ Quantum Inverse Method<lb/> RT ® T = T ® TR in Fig. 1. The final condition is<lb/> (28)<lb/> ().,J.I to: C) in which &apos;fL(A) is the appropriate extension of TL(A) to the<lb/> quantum case (it is the quantum monodromy matrix [8,10]).<lb/> R().,/1) is the<lb/> quantum R-matrix and the TL(J.I) lie in the &apos;quantum group&apos; G q (which is a<lb/> semi-group): G q is a deformation of the group G ::3 TL(/1), it 1S an algebra<lb/> with group-like &apos;structure factors&apos; R(A,/1) and &apos;commutation relations&apos;, for<lb/> the elements of &apos;fL(A) for the quan.tum integr~ble model, given by (28).<lb/> The matrix trace of (28) means, with 6L(A) .. Tr TL(A), that<lb/> (29)<lb/> quantum integrability conditions, and In6L(t;), t; to: C is a generator of<lb/> (&apos;operator&apos;) Hamiltonians H.<lb/> Following ego Jimbo [44] and Drinfeld [45], consider the algebra<lb/> g = sl(2) and &apos;deform&apos; it with parameter q .. e t &apos;&quot; l(t .. O). In Cartan-Weyl<lb/> basis sl(2) .... slq(2), i.e. [h,e] = 2e, [h,f] = -2f, [e,f] = h goes to<lb/> [h,e)<lb/> 2e, (e,f) = -2f, (e,f] (k2 k-2)/(q _ q-1)<lb/> (sinh ht)/(sinh t)<lb/> (30)<lb/> where k 2 = qh: t -+ 0 (q -+ 1) takes slq(2) to sl(2). Other useful relations<lb/> are kek-1 = qe, kfk-1 = q-lf (t .. 0).<lb/> The two-dimensional representation<lb/> of sl(2), h = 03&apos; e = 0+, f = 0_ has the corresponding representation of<lb/> slq(2), h = 03&apos; e = 0+, f = 0_ with k 2 = q03 = diag (q,q-1), k2-k-2 = diag<lb/> (q -q-l, q-1 -q) = (q _ q-l)03&apos;<lb/> The deformed algebra slq(2) is a Hopf algebra H (a quasi-triangular Hopf<lb/> algebra as defined in [46]):<lb/> for our purposes the feature of a Hopf<lb/> algebra is co-multiplication [46].<lb/> Two spins 8 1 ,S2 add in quantum<lb/> mechanics as 8 = 8 1 ® 1 + 1 ® 8 2 acting in the Hilbert space I S1 ,m l &gt;<lb/> I S2,m2&gt;&apos; A corresponding representation independent formula for a &lt;i: sl(2)<lb/> is a .... e.(a) = a ® 1 + 1 ® a with multiplicative property e.(ab) = e.(a)e.(b).<lb/> So for slq (2) set the co-multiplications<lb/> e.(h)<lb/> e.(e)<lb/> h ® I + I ® h,<lb/> e ® k + k-1 ® e, e. (f) = f ® k + k-1 ® f .<lb/> (31)<lb/> From e.(h) one finds e.(k) = k ® k, while e.(e) and e.{f) are chosen to induce<lb/> an automorphism of gq&apos; Thus<lb/> e.(e)e.(h)<lb/> e.(h)e.(e)<lb/> he ® k + hk-1 ® e + e ® kh + k-1 ® he<lb/> 55<lb/> so<lb/> [A(h), A(e)] = [e,h] 0 k + k-i 0 [e,h] = 2A(e);<lb/> (32)<lb/> similarly [A(h), A(f)] = -2A(f) , while [A(e), A(f)] = [e,f] 0 k 2 + k-2 0 [e,f] =<lb/> (sinh t)-1 [sinh ht 0 k Z + k-2 0 sinh ht] = ~(sinh t)-1 [k z 0 k Z -k-z 0<lb/> k-z] = (sinh A(h)t)j(sinh t)!<lb/> Now observe that apart from<lb/> (31)<lb/> there must be the second<lb/> co-multiplication<lb/> A(h)<lb/> h 0 1 + 1 0 h<lb/> A(e)<lb/> e 0 k-1 + k 0 e, A(f) = f 0 k-i + k 0 f<lb/> (33)<lb/> inducing the automorphism [Ah, A(e)] = 2A(e)<lb/> co-multiplications (31) and (33) are associative.<lb/> addition of spins we need<lb/> a 0 1 0 1 + 1 0 a 0 1 + 101 0 a<lb/> (id 0 A) 0 Aa ~r (A 0 id) 0 A a<lb/> (see [46]) and also<lb/> (id 0 A) 0 Aa = (A 0 id) 0 A(a) @BULLET A 3 (a)<lb/> etc. of gq = slq(2). Both<lb/> From the abstract notion of<lb/> (34)<lb/> (35)<lb/> The two distinct laws of quantum addition (co-mulitplication) map a quantum<lb/> algebra to itself and become identical when q ... 1. We must expect them to<lb/> be equivalent and therefore there must be a relation between them.<lb/> This<lb/> relation is<lb/> RA(a)<lb/> A(a)R, a € gq&apos; R € g 0 g<lb/> (36)<lb/> (g, R form the quasi-triangular Hopf algebra [46]). If (36) is true for all a<lb/> €<lb/> g, it is a very overdetermined system and R satisfies the Yang-Baxter<lb/> relation [8,10]<lb/> (37)<lb/> The indices label the &apos;spaces&apos;: R12 € gl 0 gz which is extended to R12 0 I<lb/> € gi 0 gz 0 g3&apos; etc. Proofs of the Yang-Baxter relation in e.g. [8,10] are<lb/> &apos;physical&apos;. Proof in e.g. [46] computes id 0 T 0 AR in two ways using (A 0<lb/> id)R = RiZ R Z3 &apos; (id 0 A)R = R 13 R12 (T U 0 v = v 0 u, the &apos;twist&apos; map [46]).<lb/> The Yang-Baxter relation (37) is Onsager&apos;s star triangle relation [8,10,33]<lb/> and is also the condition for a factorisable S-matrix [8,10,33].<lb/> Thus R in<lb/> (36) is indeed the quantum R-matrix. So far it has no spectral parameter.<lb/> We specifically interpret sl(2) as sl(2,1I:) with its deformation slq(2,q.<lb/> We can add extra roots eo&apos; f o , ho = Af ell , A-ieell&apos; h (ell the highest root, A €<lb/> C).<lb/> This is equivalent to using the loop algebra g = g 0 [A,A-1]. Then g<lb/> deforms to gq = gq 0 [A,A-i ], an infinite dimensional Hopf algebra, and the<lb/> spectral parameter A € II: enters throughout all of the argument so far.<lb/> In<lb/> particular, it enters the Yang-Baxter relation (37). Conveniently we take it<lb/> in the form<lb/> (38)<lb/> where A,J.1 € C.<lb/> In general R12 = R 1Z (A,.u) etc., but typically R 12 ().&quot;J..I) =<lb/> R 12 (A-/.1) for the quantum models:<lb/> the A + /.1 in (38) is a conservaton of<lb/> momentum (parametised by A,/.1).<lb/> 56<lb/> The Hopf algebra H<lb/> H, we can note that<lb/> sl q (2) has a dual K. If M (~ ~] ~ K, dual to<lb/> [~~) (e) = [8 6)<lb/> (39)<lb/> so that heel = 1, ale) = c(e) = dee) = o. Similarly a(k) = q~, d(k) = q-~,<lb/> c(k) = b(k) = 0 and, by defining the product able)<lb/> ab(e) = (a ® b)~e (a ® b) (e ® k + k-1 ® e)<lb/> a(e)b(k) + a(k-1 )b(e)<lb/> o + q-~ = q-~<lb/> and similarly for baCe), which proves to be q~, one has<lb/> ab(e) = q-1 ba(e) .<lb/> (40)<lb/> (41)<lb/> This is one of the equations found by Manin [41] for the &apos;group&apos; G q of the<lb/> &apos;quantum plane&apos;.<lb/> At this point we would like to make plain that these very simple and<lb/> explicit computations which have taken us from equation (30) onwards to<lb/> (40) were all explained to us by R Sasaki.<lb/> Dr Sasaki is currently at the<lb/> University of Durham, UK, and he is also a co-author of [24].<lb/> Manin&apos;s &apos;quantum plane&apos; Rq(210) is the set (x,y) such that<lb/> xy = q-1yx .<lb/> (42)<lb/> There is the dual set (~,~) ~ Rq(OI2) such that ~= -q~~, ~2 = n 2 = O. If<lb/> [~:] = M[~] ~ Rq(210) (where a,b,c,d in M commute with x,y but not, in<lb/> general, with each other) the coefficients of X2, y2 and xy derived from<lb/> (42), x&apos;y&apos; = q-l y &apos;x&apos;, require<lb/> ac<lb/> ab<lb/> MT[;J also (MT is the transpose of M), then<lb/> q-1 ba, cd = q-1 dc, bc = cb<lb/> (43a)<lb/> (43b)<lb/> (and q ,;. -1). We call the six equations (43a,b) Manin&apos;s G q relations. It is<lb/> easily checked that the M&apos;s are multiplicative. If q = 1, M ~ G = Gl(2). So<lb/> if q ,;. 1 (and q ,;. -1) M ~ G q the &apos;deformed&apos; or &apos;quantum group&apos; Gl q (2). If<lb/> we define<lb/> detq M<lb/> ad -q-1 bc = da -qcb = 1<lb/> (44)<lb/> Gq .= Slq(2). It is easily checked that detq MM&apos; = detqM.detqM&apos;. There is<lb/> an Inverse<lb/> Mrl = (det M)-l ( ~ -qbJ<lb/> q<lb/> -q lc a<lb/> since M-1M = 1. But M-l ~ G q -l not G q .<lb/> semi-group, not a group.<lb/> (45)<lb/> So M ~ G q = K form a<lb/> The &apos;language&apos; of Hopf algebras is co-multiplication (K is a Hopf algebra).<lb/> We define ~M = M ® M, i.e. ~(a) = a 0 a + b 0 c, ~(b) = a 0 b + b 0 d, etc.<lb/> (0 is the symbol of co-multiplication here).<lb/> Then we find ~(a)~(b) = q-l<lb/> ~(b)~(a), c.(a)c.(c) = q-1 c.(c)c.(a), etc. and this is an automorphism of the G q<lb/> relations.<lb/> 57<lb/> These results all extend to arbitrary G q = Slq(N).<lb/> extension of (42) when N = 3 is (x,y,Z),Si.(X,y,z)T = 0 where<lb/> Sl = [0 rq<lb/> -1/q 0<lb/> o 0 ~ O] , etc.<lb/> An obvious<lb/> (46)<lb/> and this extends to arbitrary N &gt; 3. Note the essentially &apos;trivial&apos; way in<lb/> which G = GI(N) deforms to G q = Gl q (N). However, except that q could be<lb/> any power of q, other deformations have to be trivial.<lb/> The R-matrix, which arises at (36) from the two co-multiplications from<lb/> gq = slq(2) introduced at (30), proves to be<lb/> H = [q-l 0 0 0 1<lb/> o<lb/> 1 0 0<lb/> o (q-Lq ) 1 0<lb/> o 0<lb/> 0 q-l<lb/> With this same R-matrix all of the G q relations (42) can be written<lb/> HM&apos; M&quot; = M&quot; M&apos;H<lb/> (47)<lb/> (48)<lb/> where M&apos; = M Q I, M&quot; = I Q M, I is the 2x2 unit matrix and Q is Kronecker<lb/> product: M&apos; derives from M in the space &apos;1&apos;, M&quot; from M in &apos;2&apos;. Evidently<lb/> M e: Gq the qua!ltum group through (48) and associativity proves to be<lb/> guaranteed under the Yang-Baxter relation (37):<lb/> the indices label the<lb/> spaces again, as noted by (37).<lb/> If we now use prime to indicate the order in the elements of M e: G q ,<lb/> the G q relations (48) can be written RM Q M&apos; = M&apos; Q MR. Since M e: G<lb/> deforms to satisfy these G q relations while G q = K, the dual of H, and H is<lb/> the deformation G q of the algebra g of G, we can deform ~he monodromy<lb/> matrix TL e: G (argument of (i) above, &apos;Flat connecti!::m&apos;) to TL e: G q . This<lb/> induces a quantisat.ion (non commutative elements of TL) on T L . Then since<lb/> TL e: G -+ TL().) e: G, .the loop group with loop algebra g = g ~ p.,A-1 ], we<lb/> can deform TL(A) to TL(A) satisfying the quantum loop group, G q , relations<lb/> and these would be<lb/> (49)<lb/> We explain the label N, not L, in one moment. Otherwise (49) is exactly the<lb/> result (28) looked for. It imposes &apos;natural&apos; quantisation on the elements of<lb/> TN(A) (=TL(A» and it impl~es the qua.ntum integrabili~y condition [~(A),<lb/> .6N (J.I)] = 0 (&apos;!.Vhich is (29): .6N().) = Tr TN(A». Then Inl&gt;N(A) is a generator<lb/> of operator H&apos;s.<lb/> The quantum group relation (49) is that found directly in [8] for<lb/> particular quantum integrable models (this is the &apos;quantum inverse method&apos;<lb/> [8,10]).<lb/> From the local la~tice transition matrix Ln(A) associated with the<lb/> spectral problem vn+l = Ln(A) vn (deriving from, and reducing to, the<lb/> spectral problem Vx = Uv for classical fields) one derives exactly (49) with<lb/> . , r . .<lb/> @BULLET<lb/> TN(A) = R Ln(A) = LN().).LN-IC).), . . . . L-N().) (refer back to ON (19) and TL<lb/> (22».<lb/> The Ln(A) depend (linearly) on quantised quantities cIl n (t) [10]<lb/> deriving from quantised fields cIl(x,t) with the appropriate commutation<lb/> relations.<lb/> Periodic b.c.s are assumed on the lattice, there are 2N lattice<lb/> points in a period, there is a lattice spacing. ao (s.!ly), and 2L = (2N + l)ao&apos;<lb/> This explains the switch of label N -+ L in TL -+ TN&apos;<lb/> Eyidently (49) gives<lb/> the quantum commutation relations for the elements of T().) corresponding<lb/> to the particular quantum model. In fact the R-matrix R(A,J.I) (which can be<lb/> written R(A-J.l) and satisfies the Yang-Baxter relations (38) as explained)<lb/> 58<lb/> determines ol}e whole &apos;hierarchy&apos; of integrable quantum models whose<lb/> Hamiltonians H are found from Int.(A).<lb/> We now see that the &apos;natural&apos;<lb/> quantisation of the integrable<lb/> quantum<lb/> models<lb/> coincides with<lb/> the<lb/> &apos;quantisation&apos; which is the appropriate quantum group with relations (49).<lb/> We find the argument to the &apos;quantum groups&apos; beautiful<lb/> and<lb/> certainly remarkable (the qu.antum inverse method came first after all<lb/> [8,10]). The actual remarks made in this III are all we can say on it here<lb/> and these are partly heuristic.<lb/> We hope they are at least sufficient to<lb/> show the elegance of the structure. Our next task is to turn, in the IV<lb/> next, to the main point of the paper and use R-matrix theory to compute<lb/> the quantum partition functions Z for integrable models defined by (1).<lb/> Our strategy is to transform (1) to (12) so that we can use R to calculate a<lb/> quantum measure<lb/> /.1 -as was explained already in 1. To do this we need<lb/> explicit forms of R.<lb/> Thus before going to IV we look at three particular<lb/> R-matrices.<lb/> Despite the elegance of the quantum groups, rather more<lb/> direct methods can be effective in finding R&apos;s.<lb/> We show this here by<lb/> deriving R&apos;s for g = SU(N) from a simple ansatz. Our second example<lb/> introduces the G = s1(2,«:) R-matrices for the s-G and sinh-G models and<lb/> derives their corresponding r-matrices by classical limit. We use these R-<lb/>and r-matrices in the IV.<lb/> We take the Yang-Baxter relations (37) in indexed form<lb/> R~~(A) R kY (A+J.1) ~~(/.1) = R~ R~q(A + /.1) R km {3(A)<lb/> J&quot; .<lb/> ocp<lb/> IJ,.<lb/> &quot;P JY<lb/> oc<lb/> (50)<lb/> -<lb/>-<lb/>«{3<lb/> In (50) R 1Z (A-/.1) E: gl ® gz in (37) becomes Rj9 (A) in which (joc) determines<lb/> &apos;blocks&apos; in the matrix R (from the space &apos;2&apos;) and (9{3) determines elements<lb/> of the &apos;block&apos; (from the space &apos;I&apos;). If g = SU(3) i.e. g = SU(3) ® [A,A-l],<lb/> then a solution of (50) can be found by making the ansatz [48]<lb/> (51)<lb/> After some considerable algebra one finds many terms cancel and the<lb/> solution is [48]<lb/> f(A) = (n -3A)/3n ; n E: R, A E: «:<lb/> (52)<lb/> From (49) by expanding lnt.().) about A = 0 one finds from the coefficient of<lb/> A an integrable lattice model which is the spin chain model with Hamiltonian<lb/> -+-+<lb/> -+-+<lb/> H = ±(2n)-1 t (4S n .S n +l) + 4(Sn, Sn+I)Z<lb/> (53)<lb/> where<lb/> (54)<lb/> (and ~ n E: R is the coupling constant). Obviously the analysis extends<lb/> ~mm~diately to g = SUrN), while for SU(2), R(A) = en -2).) (2n)-1 I + ~ (; x<lb/> 0, 0<lb/> the Pauli matrices. Then H corresponding to (53) is the lattice<lb/> quantum Heisenberg ferromagnet or anti-ferromagnet.<lb/> In IV we work on the classical s-G and sinh-G models. For quantum<lb/> s-G, in terms of &apos;bare&apos; rapidities 0&lt;0, 0&lt;0&apos;<lb/> = [1 0 0 0]<lb/> o abO<lb/> o b a 0<lb/> 000 1<lb/> (55)<lb/> 59<lb/> where<lb/> a = i(sin ~ Yo)![sinh ~(oo -00&apos; + i~ Yo)]<lb/> b<lb/> [sinh ~(ao -ao&apos;)]!(sinh ~(oo -00&apos; + i~ Yo)]<lb/> (56)<lb/> in which Yo is the &apos;bare&apos; coupling constant of s-q (compare the classical<lb/> (4». As Yo ... 0 with commutators [ ... ] ... i{ @BULLET@BULLET. J and TN(A) ... TN(A) one easily<lb/> finds from (49) with R-matrix (55) that<lb/> (57)<lb/> where<lb/> ~ (I 0 I -03 0 03]!(sinh (00-00 &apos;)]<lb/> -~ (01 0 02 + 02 0°1 ] cosh (oo-oo&apos;)!(sinh (00-00 &apos;)] (58)<lb/> in which 00 = i-1 InAo = ~ 0:0, 0:0&apos; = i-lInAo &apos; = ~ 0:0&apos;. However, one can see<lb/> that S is a permutation matrix and the particular quantum R which is (55)<lb/> with (56) differs from the R&apos;s considered so far by a factor S:<lb/> such<lb/> factors change nothing in R-matrix theory [8,10] except some details (e.g.<lb/> the Yang-Baxter relation (37) becomes (R 0 I) (I 0 R) (R 0 I) = (I 0 R) (R 0<lb/> I) (I 0 R) (in g 0 g 0 g) -see Fig.1 -by incorporating such a permutation<lb/> matrix [8,10]. We can therefore ignore the term in S in (57) to see that<lb/> (59)<lb/> in which the r-matrix is given by (58).<lb/> This is exactly the Sklyanin<lb/> bracket (26) here regained as a classical limit from the quantum groups.<lb/> This indicates the consistency of the classical and quantum theories -route<lb/> (i), &apos;Flat connection&apos; above and this route (ii), &apos;Deformed loop algebras&apos;.<lb/> Strictly Yo ... 0 in semi-classical limit: r of order Yo emerges from (I -R)<lb/> as Yo ... 0 so<lb/> (60)<lb/> as Yo ... o. It then follows from the Yang-Baxter relation (37) that<lb/> (61)<lb/> the &apos;c1assical Yang-Baxter relation&apos;.<lb/> We now have enough machinery to evaluate the functional integrals (1)<lb/> and (12) for the s-G and sinh-G models.<lb/> The r-matrix for sinh-G derives<lb/> from (58) for s-G by continuation Yo ... -Yo.<lb/> IV<lb/> EVALUATION OF THE PARTITION FUNCTIONS<lb/> We have pointed out that our methods for evaluating quantum or<lb/> classical Z make the canonical transformation from expression (1) for Z to<lb/> expression (12): in the quantum case S[~] is given by (2); in the classical<lb/> case it is (3). In transforming to (12) all 0&apos; &quot; the difficulties in calculating Z<lb/> are thrown into computing the measure ftj/J.<lb/> Since S[~] and S(p) are<lb/> classical actions it might appear that only the classical r-matrix can figure<lb/> in the calculations. Apparently this remains true of expression (1) since in<lb/> the quantum case S[~] is the classical action (2) -so it would be<lb/> interesting to know how the quantum integrability theory from the R-matrix<lb/> enters the calculation. But by transforming to (12) we find we can use R<lb/> to compute ~/J in the quantum case and r to compute ~ in the classical<lb/> 60<lb/> case and<lb/> the<lb/> two measures are not the same even though<lb/> the<lb/> transformation (1) to (12) is canonical.<lb/> This &apos;trick&apos; carries with it a further consequence.<lb/> In the quantum<lb/> case S[$] is given by (2). Since Z is to be real and positive if F = -rrl<lb/> lnZ is to be real, it is natural to remove the if~dT IT(X,T)$ T(X,T) for<lb/> o<lb/> ,<lb/> each label x by setting it equal to 2rrim(x) where m(x), labelled by x, is an<lb/> integer.<lb/> This step becomes more illuminating in terms of action-angle<lb/> variables.<lb/> It is convenient to work first with the sinh-G model which is simpler<lb/> than the s-G model:<lb/> the classical sinh-G, although integrable, has no<lb/> solitons; the s-G does have solitons (kinks, anti kinks and breathers, ~ I).<lb/> For sinh-G H[$] is given by (5).<lb/> Under canonical transformation, with $<lb/> defined for x If: R with vanishing b.c.s at ± co, H[$] -&gt; H[p] given by<lb/> H(p)<lb/> [coW(k) P(k) dk<lb/> (62)<lb/> w(k)<lb/> (63)<lb/> and<lb/> {P(k), Q(k&apos;)} = b(k -k&apos;)<lb/> (64)<lb/> The phase spaces are 0 ~ P(k) &lt; co, 0 ~ Q(k) &lt; 2rr and the motion is<lb/> confined to a continuously infinite dimensional torus.<lb/> For the evaluation of (12) the action S[p] in the classical case is<lb/> -~[p].<lb/> For (12) in the quantum case S[p] corresponding to (2) discretizes<lb/> to<lb/> S[p) = f~dT {irN P n Q n T -H[P)}<lb/> o<lb/> n=-N<lb/> &apos;<lb/> (65)<lb/> with<lb/> +N<lb/> _<lb/> 1:<lb/> w(k n ) P n .<lb/> n=-N<lb/> H[p]<lb/> (66)<lb/> hPe modes k n are the allowed modes i.e. lhose contributing to the measure<lb/> ~p as we explain shortly. _The modes k n are ~ense in !he thermodynamic<lb/> limit L -&gt; co I!nd P n &lt;-+ P(kn)dk n i.e. P n +-+ P(k)dk where k is dense (and is<lb/> the limit of k n ): (Pm&apos; Qml = bnl&amp; and 0 &quot; Q m &lt; 2fT so we can think of P n as<lb/> 0(1) -see below. The measure IJ11 is<lb/> &lt;l+-<lb/>+N<lb/> dPndQn<lb/> rXJ p = lim IT<lb/> -2 r r<lb/> N-&gt;oo n=-N<lb/> (67)<lb/> and the normalisation by 2rr is actually the usual normalisation by h: h = 1<lb/> ~ h = 2rr. Note that as a matter of convenience we overcount on n with -N<lb/> &quot; n &quot; N not -N ~ n &lt; N, but this introduces no error in the limit L -&gt; 00<lb/> (i.e. N -&gt; co).<lb/> The allowed elements ctPn dQ n /2rr in 2J P (67) depend on the indices<lb/> labelling the allowed modes k n : we compute these shortly. To remove the<lb/> term in i in the action (65) set<lb/> J~dT Pn Qn,T = f Pn dQn = 2rrmn<lb/> (68)<lb/> with the mn integers (for each n). The integral of period ~ is wrapped mn<lb/> 61<lb/> times around the torus labelled by n. This is Bohr quantisation, but it is<lb/> not semi-classical quantisation as we shall see.<lb/> There are now two natural choices for the integers mn:<lb/> 0, 1 (fermions)<lb/> (69a)<lb/> 0, 1, 2, ... (bosons)<lb/> (6gb)<lb/> We shall make each of these choices working with fermions in the one case<lb/> and bosons in the other. We shall see that these two choices are entirely<lb/> equivalent to each other and we are apparently exploiting &apos;bose-fermi<lb/> equivalence&apos;. As noted in Fig.1 bose-fermi equivalence is implicit from the<lb/> connection Z x Z Matrices ~ gl(oo) .</div>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>... Bose-Fermi Equivalence .......... Partition<lb/> Function</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">eqn. (12):<lb/> the algebra gl(oo) has two representations, one in the<lb/> Lie algebra of free fermion products the other in terms of vertex operators<lb/> on a bosonic space [49].<lb/> However, there are obviously very many other<lb/> choices for a real free energy.<lb/> One of these is integers other than the<lb/> two cases (69a,b) of course, but we do not know how to handle these other<lb/> cases.<lb/> Choices (69) fit naturally into the theory as we shall see and in<lb/> fact quantisation is still imposed as &apos;quantum group&apos; quantisation. &apos;We can<lb/> find explicit 2-body S-matrix phase shifts ~, Ab for these two choices, and<lb/> these phase shifts determine t~e measures &quot;ittJi. ConseR,uently there are two<lb/> different quantum measures<lb/> Jif for fermions and ~ Jib for bosons, and<lb/> there is yet a third measure<lb/> Ji c for the classical case. We shall see that<lb/> condition (69a) (fermions) is already implicit in the quantum inverse method<lb/> as it is so far used [8,10].<lb/> It is also implicit in the method of quantum<lb/> Bethe ansatz as it is used [50].<lb/> As used the QIM and quantum BA are<lb/> equivalent but the QIM exposes the R-matrix-quantum-group structure.<lb/> A<lb/> new feature in our analysis is the choice (69b), description in terms of<lb/> bosons.<lb/> Notice that conditions (69) mean that the functional integral (12) is<lb/> reduced to the classical form for which S[p] = -!3H[p] (indeed the functional<lb/> integral (1) is reduced to the classical form with action S[&lt;I&gt;] given by (3))<lb/> but the extra quantum conditions (69a) or (69b) apply in the quantum case.<lb/> It is possible to impose these conditions as such when there are<lb/> action-angle variables i.e. the classical model is completely integrable:<lb/> if<lb/> we impose the conditions JdT1T&lt;I&gt; T = 2rrm(x) first mentioned, complete<lb/> integrability is not required but&apos; the meaning is obscure -there is in<lb/> general no torus to integrate around.<lb/> In order to calculate the classical measure ~Jic for sinh-G one route<lb/> is the following:<lb/> from the bare r-matrix, which is (58) with Yo ... -Yo&apos;<lb/> construct a classical integrable lattice with the same r-matrix. This can be<lb/> done [51] and the idea is due to Izergin and Korepin [52]. For this sinh-G<lb/> lattice we can find action-angle variables under periodic b.c.s of period 2N<lb/> [51].<lb/> One can then take the classical thermodynamic limit N ... co at finite<lb/> density. If ao is the lattice spacing 2L = (2N + 1)80 so the limit is L ... co<lb/> at finite density.<lb/> At L &lt; 00 one can establish a connection, to O(L -1),<lb/> between<lb/> the<lb/> action-angle<lb/> variables<lb/> under<lb/> periodic<lb/> b.c.s<lb/> and<lb/> the<lb/> action-angle variables under vanishing b.c.s at ± co [51].<lb/> A rather more<lb/> direct method, the &apos;Poisson bracket method&apos;, which starts from the Sklyanin<lb/> bracket (59), is described in [53].<lb/> In either method the connection<lb/> depends on<lb/> (70a)<lb/> (70b)<lb/> 62<lb/> In (70a) Z depends on A (and is a term in the monodromy matrix Ln for the<lb/> sinh-Gordon lattice [51,53]):<lb/> X &apos;&quot; 2-~ (I + i 0 1 ) and the 0i are Pauli<lb/> matrices. The scattering matrix SeA), (70b), is the usual scattering matrix<lb/> of the spectral transform (ST) method ( I) and a(A) is a constant of the<lb/> motion:<lb/> thus In a().) generates H[p] for sinh-G (Fig.l).<lb/> In terms of S().)<lb/> the Sklyanin bracket (59) becomes<lb/> (71 )<lb/> where r±(A,~) are found from r().,~).<lb/> By either method the result one finds is the condition on the allowed<lb/> modes [51,53,54]<lb/> in which k n = 2,!Tqn .!--1, qn all inJeger different for each n, and where as<lb/> before Pm +-+ P(km)dk m (i.e. P(k)dk) as L -&gt;... In (72) and what follows L<lb/> replaces 2L (i.e. the underlying period of periodic b.c.s is L not 2L). The<lb/> phase shift ,\;(k,k&apos;) in (72) is a classical phonon-phonon phase shift (recall<lb/> sinh-G only has harmonic type, i.e. phonon, solutions, I)<lb/> ~c(k,k&apos;) = -~ Yom 2 [kw(k&apos;) -k&apos;w(k)]-l<lb/> (73)<lb/> Notice the important feature of the thermodynamic limit now achieved:<lb/> since Pm = 0(1) and Pm +-+ P(k)dk as L -&gt; 00, then since dk = O(L-l), P(~) =<lb/> O(L) as L -&gt; 00. This allows us to define a finite particle density p(k) =&apos;<lb/> L-1P(k) for L .... 00 [54].<lb/> Notice that everything derives from the r-matrix for sinh-G, including<lb/> the classical phase shifts &apos;\;. Thus the r-matrix determines everything for<lb/> the functional integral (12) in the classical case.<lb/> If we note that H[p] is<lb/> discretized to (66) for the sinh-G model and the k n are determined by (72)<lb/> with (73) we may see that the functional integral (12) can be evaluated by<lb/> iterating (72) [10,54],<lb/> It is remarkable that the resultant iterated series<lb/> can be put in the form [54]<lb/> ~ FL-l = (2n~)-1 f:oodk In(~(k» -(2n~)-2 f:oodq [W(q)]-l {:oodk<lb/> x ~c(k,q)d(lnw(k»/dk + (2rr~)-3 ~-oodp[W(p»)-l I:oodq<lb/> x 6c(q,p)~q ([W(q»)-l ~-oodk 6cCk,q)d(lnw(k)/dk)<lb/> -~(2n~)-3 f: dq[w( q) ]-2 [ [00 dMc(k, q)d(lnw(k) /dk) r<lb/> + .. , ..<lb/> (74)<lb/> And although this expansion is no better than strictly asymptotic (in the<lb/> parameter frl: it is a low temperature expansion) it is formally summed to,<lb/> i.e. is the iteration of,<lb/> ~ FL-l = (2n~)-1 f: .. dk In(~(k»<lb/> E:(k) = w(k) + (2rr~)-1 f: .. dk&apos; (d6 c (k,k&apos; )/dk)ln(~(k&apos;»<lb/> (75)<lb/> and w(k) is the dispersion relation (63). In both (74) and (75) L replaces<lb/> 2L as noted at (72).<lb/> In this way the evaluation of the functional integral<lb/> (12) in the classical case for sinh-G, for which S[p] = -/3H[p], is re,duced to<lb/> 63<lb/> solving a nonlinear integral equation.<lb/> That solution has the asymptotic<lb/> eKpansion (74).<lb/> Moreover, all the integrals in (74) can be done and the<lb/> result is the asymptotic eKpansion [54]<lb/> lim FL-1 = m~1[~4(M~)-1 -~(~)-2 +~(~)-3 -~(~)-4 + .. ]<lb/> ~<lb/> 6<lb/> 16<lb/> 126<lb/> + FKG<lb/> (76)<lb/> where FKG = ~lao-1(lnrrJ3e-1ao-1 + ~mao) and M = 8mYO-1. To get FKG&apos; the<lb/> free energy density of K-G equation (13), in this form we must use the<lb/> dispersion relation (14) with a cut-off 2rrao -1 on the first integral of the<lb/> iteration which is (72). It may be identified as 2rr over the lattice spacing<lb/> as the lattice theory shows.<lb/> FKG diverges classically, a classical u.v.<lb/> divergence, as a o .... O.<lb/> We can regain (76) directly from the functional<lb/> integral (1) with 8[&lt;11] given by (3) for sinh-G.<lb/> The method, the transfer<lb/> integral method, makes no appeal to the complete integrability of sinh-G.<lb/> Thus the TIM serves as a check on the evaluation of (12) instead of (1) (a<lb/> remarkable check in our view for e.g. (76) is only asymptotic and methods<lb/> of matched asymptotics are needed to find it by TIM [54]).<lb/> This check also serves to check the quantum theory.<lb/> The quantum<lb/> cases are more complicated because sinh-G is relativistic.<lb/> In these cases<lb/> one uses the R-matrix (55), with Yo .... -Yo&apos; to derive the condition for<lb/> quantum pseudo-particles<lb/> kn = kn -r A(~on -~om)<lb/> (77)<lb/> m&quot;n<lb/> where k n = mo&apos;sinh OOn and mo&apos; = &apos; -&apos; m0 2 sin }i Yo is the mass of a<lb/> pseudo-particle (mo is the unrenormalised sinh-G mass m):<lb/> and<lb/> sinh ~(~Q -~o&apos; -&apos;-&apos;iyo)<lb/> sinh ~(~o&apos; -~o -&apos;-&apos;iYo)<lb/> (79)<lb/> deriving from b given in expression (56). One now works with fermions to<lb/> fill the Dirac sea so that phonons become eKcitations (and holes) from this<lb/> Dirac sea.<lb/> We are not yet able to work directly with bosons in this<lb/> renormalisation procedure.<lb/> where<lb/> The (renormalised) result is [54]<lb/> kn = k n -r Af(k n , km)<lb/> m&quot;n<lb/> Af(k, k&apos;) = -2 tan-1 [m2sin }iyo&quot; [kw(k&apos;) -k&apos;w(k) ]-1]<lb/> (80)<lb/> (81)<lb/> and Yo&quot; is renormalised: Yo&quot; = Yo[1+Yo/8rr]-1. It is important that (81) is<lb/> the smooth branch -2rr &lt; 1!.t &lt; O. One can now see that (80) is exactly (72)<lb/> with 1!.t replacing Ac and with Pm = 0, 1. This is the condition (69a)<lb/> (fermions) !<lb/> For bosons one again uses (72) with P n = 0, 1, 2, ... and with Ab<lb/> replacing Ac: Ab derives from 1!.t by<lb/> Ab(k, .k&apos;) = Af(k, k&apos;) + 2rre(k&apos; -k)<lb/> (82)<lb/> where e(k) is the unit step. Thus Ab is no longer the smooth branch and<lb/> Ab(k -k&apos;) .... 0 as k -k&apos; .... ± co. Note that with A(k, k&apos;) = i In 8(k, k&apos;), S(k<lb/> = k&apos;) = -1 (fermions) and = +1 (bosons) as expected.<lb/> 64<lb/> By using (72) with P n = 0, I in the form (80) (fermion~ and in the<lb/> form P n = 0, 1, 2, @BULLET. with (82) (bosons) we find that Z = f (J:r/.l. exp S[pJ,<lb/> equation (12), in which S[pJ = -{3H[pJ and R[pJ discretizes to (66), can be<lb/> reduced to the two systems of integral equations [54]<lb/> V! FL-l = /.I. Ii -(2rrf3)-1 f--&lt;&gt;oln(l+ e-.a€(k)dk,<lb/> ~(k) = w(k) -/.I. -(2rrf3)-1 J:~(dAf(k, k&apos;)/dk) x<lb/> x In(l + e-.a€(k&apos;»dk&apos;<lb/> (83)<lb/> and<lb/> lim FL-l = (2rrf3)-1 [ In(l -e-~(k»dk,<lb/> ~<lb/> -~<lb/> €(k) = w(k) + (2rrf3)-1 r:~(~(k, k&apos;)/dk) In(l -e-~(k&apos;»dk&apos; . (84)<lb/> In the fermion case we introduce a chemical potential /.I. and evaluate f~/.I.f<lb/> N<lb/> exp -f3[H[p)-/.I.N) where N = [ P n (then Ii = lim 2N/(2L) -and 2L ~ L). Since<lb/> n=-N<lb/> L~<lb/> (82) means dAb/dk = dAf/dk -2rrS(k&apos; -k), (83) with /.I. = 0, becomes (84)<lb/> when In (1 + e-.a€(k» = -In (1 -e-~(k». Thus (84) and (83) are &apos;bose-<lb/>fermi equivalent&apos; (refer back to Fig.l where bose-fermi equivalence traces<lb/> back to the representations of gl(~». The fermions result (83) was found<lb/> in [55] for the quantum (normally ordered) repulsive NLS model (8) for<lb/> which, however, w(k) = k 2 and tor = -2lBn-l(c/k -k&apos;). Evidently there is<lb/> the bose-fermi equivalent form of this result.<lb/> Finally note that the<lb/> classical results (75) follow in the classical limit Yo ... 0 on the bose results<lb/> (84): evidently Ab with its jump of 2rr at k = k&apos; becomes Ac expression (73)<lb/> with a pole at k = k&apos; in semi-classical limit Yo ~ 0: sin liyo&quot; ... liyo &gt; 0 in<lb/> semi-classical limit. The classical repulsive NLS model results follow in a<lb/> similar way [54].<lb/> There is a similar argument which evaluates (12) for the classical and<lb/> quantum s-{} models. Although quantum s-G is bose-fermi equivalent to the<lb/> quantum Massive Thirring model (€I), like for sinh-G we are so far only<lb/> able to evaluate (12) for quantum s-G by renormalising in terms of<lb/> fermions, namely renormalisation is MTM renormalisation. A very complete<lb/> argument for lim FL-1 is then given in terms of fermions in [53).<lb/> ~<lb/> However the functional integral is not evaluated there:<lb/> one uses instead<lb/> our so-called generalised Bethe ansatz method [10,39,54] (and see Fig.l)<lb/> which defines an entropy S and a free-energy F = E -trlS (E is the<lb/> energy H); then one minimises F.<lb/> Results concide with the fun~ional<lb/> integral methods quantum or classical and it is plain that once Ct:f /.I. is<lb/> determined by (72) quantum or classical the role of the functional integral<lb/> is simply to minimise F -a point already mentioned in. §I.<lb/> In the functional integral methods for the s-G model, quantum or<lb/> classical , there are subtilties about the action S[p]. In the classical case<lb/> S[pJ = -f3H[p] and [39]<lb/> (85)<lb/> comparing with (62).<lb/> This Hamiltonian has only kink and antikink<lb/> contributions (M = Bmyo -1 is the classical kink = antikink mass) and<lb/> phonons:<lb/> there are no breather contributions (e.g. [lO,15J) and §I). We<lb/> find this is a consequence of the classical finite density thermodynamic<lb/> 65<lb/> limit [10,53,56] in which classical particles with two degrees of freedom, the<lb/> breathers, are involved. We find this way [39] that the classical functional<lb/> integral (12) reduces to<lb/> lim FL-l = (2rrf3)-1 [ooW(X) In(f3€(x) )dX<lb/> L-&gt;oo<lb/> -2(2rrf3)-1 [ooE(X) e-!3E(X)dx<lb/> (86)<lb/> with<lb/> €(x)<lb/> w(x) + (2rrf3)-1 J:oo(dA/dX) In(/3€(x&apos; )dX&apos;<lb/> + 2(2rr.B)-1 J:oo(dAk/dX) e-~(x&apos;)dx&apos;<lb/> E(x)<lb/> E(x) -2(2rr.B)-1 J:oo(dAkk/dX ) e-/3E(x&apos;)dx&apos;<lb/> -(2rrf3)-1 J:oo(dAk/dx) In(/3€(x&apos; )dx&apos;<lb/> (87)<lb/> where w(x) = m cosh x and E(x) = M cosh x, rapidities are used, and the<lb/> phase shifts 6kk, 6k (k is &apos;kink&apos; = &apos;antikink&apos;) and 6 are given in [39,53].<lb/> In particular with k = m sinh x, etc., 6(k, k&apos;) = ~Yom2[kw(k&apos;) -k&apos;w(k)]-l<lb/> and is the analytic continuation in Yo of the phonon-phonon phase shift for<lb/> sinh-G, equation (73).<lb/> The quantum functional integral for s-G uses the &apos;renormalised&apos;<lb/> classical H[p]<lb/> (88)<lb/> in which PQ = 2rrQ/L is a translational momentum and 6Q Q&apos; = sin (Q&apos;Yo&quot;/16),<lb/> Yo&quot; = Yo/[l -Yo/8rr]: M involves the renormalised mass&apos; M of s-G [53]. It<lb/> is Bohr quantisation analogous to (69) which puts PQ = 2rrQ/L and 6Q Q&apos; as<lb/> quoted. The classical breather masses are 2M sin 6Q for each breather Q<lb/> and ° ~ 6 Q &lt;}ffr: the 6Q are internal canonical momenta (more precisely the<lb/> 4Yo-1 6 Q are, with conjugate ~Q in ° ~ ~Q &lt; 8rr: {4Yo-1 6 Q, ~m} = SQm<lb/> [10,15,22]). Thus corresponding to (69)<lb/> J:[4(Yo &quot;)-1 6Q &lt;l&gt;Q,T]dT = f 4(Yo&quot;)-1 6Q d&lt;l&gt;Q = 2rrQ&apos;<lb/> (89)<lb/> i.e. 6Q Q&apos; = lI&apos; Yo&quot;/lG. It is interesting that the &apos;classical&apos; action -f3H[p] (88)<lb/> needs &apos;Yo&quot; not Yo&apos; We use classical s-G lattice theory to show no phonons<lb/> contribute to (88) and that breathers do [51,53].<lb/> By using the<lb/> renormalised phase shift equations analogous to (72) (and given in [53].<lb/> This explains why the renormalised Yo&quot; enters (88)) we can expect that the<lb/> functional integral (12) will reduce to (details are not complete)<lb/> in agreement with the generalised BA method [53].<lb/> In (90) Mll = 2M<lb/> sin(lIYo &quot;/16), Ms = M, a renormalised kink (antikink) mass, €lI = €Q(O:lI), €s<lb/> = €s(&lt;Xg), and /./Q, /./s are chemical potentials for each &apos;particle&apos;. As in<lb/> ,<lb/> -1<lb/> &apos; -1<lb/> (88) the number Nb = [BrrY o &quot; ] (= integral part) and Nb = [8rry o ]-1 = Nb-l.<lb/> 66<lb/> The energies IE: Q, IE: s satisfy<lb/> -/3€:n,<lb/> + e<lb/> J()<lb/> (91)<lb/> The phase shifts are given in [53]. The same result has been reached in<lb/> several different ways by other people (and ourselves) using quantum<lb/> Bethe ansatz.<lb/> One has used the equivalence of the spin -}2 XYZ model in<lb/> continuum limit to the quantum MTM, fermi-bose equivalent to quantum s-G<lb/> [57]. These results illustrate yet again the &apos;total connectivity&apos; which forms<lb/> the Fig.!.<lb/> In classical limit (90) with (91) reduces to the results for<lb/> classical s-G (86) with (87) [57,58].<lb/> The iteration of this classical system<lb/> gives an asymptotic expansion which is the analytical continuation in Yo<lb/> (found by the Transfer Integral Method) of the low temperature asymptotic<lb/> expansion (76) for sinh-G [39,53,56].<lb/> This checks all of the classical<lb/> calculations from (12) for s-G and checks the quantum calculations from<lb/> (12) also. It checks r-and R-matrix theory and the &apos;quantum groups&apos;!<lb/> REFERENCES<lb/> 1.<lb/></div>

	<reference>R K Bullough and S Olafsson, in: &quot;Proc. 17th Intl. Conference on Diff.<lb/> Geometrical Methods in Theoretical Physics&quot; (Chester Meeting, August<lb/> 1988) A Solomon ed., World Scientific, Singapore. To appear 1989.<lb/> 2.<lb/> Zhuhan Jiang and R K Bullough, J. Phys. A: Math. Gen. 20:L429 (1987).<lb/> 3.<lb/> P J Caudrey, Physica 6D:51 (1982); in:<lb/> &quot;Soliton Theory a Survey of<lb/> Results&quot; A P Fordy ed., Manchester UP, Manchester (1989) and<lb/> references.<lb/> 4.<lb/> Kimio Ueno in: &quot;Vertex Operators in Mathematics and Physics&quot; Math.<lb/> Sciences Research Institute Publications tt3 J Lepowsky, S Mandelstam<lb/> and I Singer eds, Springer-Verlag, New York (1984) pp.291-302.<lb/> 5.<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>R K Bullough, Yu-Zhong Chen, S Olafsson and J Timonen</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>in: &quot;Proc. of<lb/> the Ohiron Colloquium&quot; P Lochak, M Balabane and C Sulem eds,<lb/> Springer Lecture Notes in Mathematics, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg<lb/> (1989). To appear.<lb/> 6.<lb/> S Olafsson, J Phys A: Math. Gen. 22:157 (1989).<lb/> 7.<lb/> S Olafsson and R K Bullough, and references. To be published (1989).<lb/> 8.<lb/> P P Kulish and E K Sklyanin in Proc. Tvarminne Symp., Finland, 1981,<lb/> J Hietarinta and C Montonen eds, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (1982).<lb/> 9.<lb/> A G Reyman and M A Semenov-Tian-Shansky, Commun. Maths. Phys.<lb/> 105:461 (1986).<lb/> 10.<lb/> R K Bullough, in:<lb/> &quot;Solitons&quot; M Lakshmanan ed., Springer Series in<lb/> Nonlinear Dynamics, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (988) pp.250-281.<lb/> 11</reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>.<lb/> J C Eilbeck, J D Gibbon, P J Caudrey and R K Bullough, J Phys</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>. A<lb/> 6:1337 (1973).<lb/> 12.<lb/> R K Bullough, &apos;Solitons&apos; in:<lb/> &quot;Interaction of Radiation with Condensed<lb/> Matter.<lb/> Vol. I&quot; IAEA-SMR-20/51, IntL Atomic Energy Agency, Vienna<lb/> (1977) pp.381-469.<lb/> 13.<lb/> R K Bullough, P W Kitchenside, P M Jack and R Saunders, Physica<lb/> Scripta 20:364 (1979).<lb/> 14.<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>P J Caudrey, J D Gibbon, J C Eilbeck and R K Bullough,</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>Phys. Rev.<lb/> Letts 30:237 (1973).<lb/> 67<lb/> 15.<lb/> &quot;Solitons&quot;, Springer Topics in Current Physics 17, R K Bullough and<lb/> R J Caudrey eds, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (1980).<lb/> 16.<lb/> R K Bullough and F Ahmad, Phys. Rev. Letts 27:330 (1971).<lb/> 17.<lb/> J Timonen and R K Bullough, Phys. Letts 82A:183 (1981).<lb/> 18.<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>R K Bullough, D J Pilling, Yi Cheng, Yu-Zhong Chen and J Timonen,<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Journal de Physique,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Colloque C3</address>

	<email>. Suppl. au</email>

	<reference>n 0 3, 50:C3-41 (1989).<lb/> 19.<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>R K Bullough, J Timonen, Yu-Zhong Chen, Yi Cheng and M Stirland</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>in:<lb/> &quot;Proc. IntI. Workshop on Nonlinear Evolution Equations:<lb/> integrability<lb/> and spectral methods&quot; (Como, Italy, July 1988)<lb/> A P Fordy and A<lb/> Degasperis eds, Manchester UP, Manchester (1989).<lb/> 20.<lb/> G T Zimanyi, S A Kivelson and A Luther, Phys. Rev. Letts 60:2089<lb/> (1988).<lb/> 21.<lb/> C Itzykson and J B Zuber, &quot;Quantum Field Theory&quot;, McGraw-Hill, New<lb/> York (1980).<lb/> 22.<lb/> R K Bullough, in:<lb/> &quot;Nonlinear Phenomena in Physics&quot; F Claro ed.,<lb/> Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (1989) pp.70-102.<lb/> 23.<lb/> R P Feynman and A R Hibbs, &quot;Quantum Mechanics and Path Integrals&quot;,<lb/> McGraw-Hill, New York (1965).<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>24.<lb/> H W Braden, E Corrigan, P E Dorey and R Sasaki,</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>&quot;Aspects of<lb/> Perturbed Conformal Field Theory, Affine Toda Field Theory and Exact<lb/> S-Matrices&quot;. Paper this meeting.<lb/> 25.<lb/> R K Dodd and R K Bullough, Proc. Roy. Soc. London A 352:481 (1977).<lb/> 26.<lb/> P Christe, &quot;S-Matrices of the Tricritical Ising Model and Toda System&quot;.<lb/> Paper this meeting.<lb/> 27.<lb/> L D Faddeev and L A Takhtajan, &quot;Hamiltonian Methods in the Theory<lb/> of Solitons&quot;, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (1987).<lb/> 28.<lb/> J Liouville, Journal de Math. 20:137 (1855).<lb/> 29.<lb/> V<lb/> I<lb/> Arnold,<lb/> &quot;Mathematical<lb/> Methods<lb/> of<lb/> Classical<lb/> Mechanics&quot;,<lb/> Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (1978).<lb/> 30.<lb/> E Witten, in: &quot;IXth IntI. Congress on Math. Phys.&quot; B Simon, A Truman<lb/> and I M Davies eds, Adam Hilger, Bristol (1989).<lb/> 31.<lb/> Yong-Shi Wu, &quot;Topological Chern-Simons Gauge Theories and New<lb/> Hierarchies of Knot/Link Polynomials&quot;. Paper this meeting.<lb/> 32.<lb/> R J Baxter, &quot;Exactly Solved Models in Statistical Mechanics&quot;, Academic<lb/> Press, New York (1982).<lb/> 33.<lb/> M Wadati and Y Akutsu, in:<lb/> &quot;Solitons&quot; Springer Series in Nonlinear<lb/> Dynamics, M Lakshmanan ed. Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg<lb/> (1988)<lb/> pp.282-306.<lb/> 34.<lb/> Vaugh Jones, &quot;Baxterization&quot;. Paper this meeting.<lb/> 35.<lb/> S Saito, Phys. Rev. D 36:1819 (1987).<lb/> 36.<lb/> M Mulase, J. Diff. Geom. 19:403 (1984).<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>37.<lb/> R K Bullough, Yu-Zhong Chen and J Timonen.</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">To be published.<lb/> 38.<lb/> G Venturi, &quot;Quantum Gravity and the Berry Phase&quot;.<lb/> Paper this<lb/> meeting.<lb/> 39</note>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>.<lb/> J Timonen, M Stirland, D J Pilling and R K Bullough,</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>Phys. Rev. Letts<lb/> 56:2233 (1986).<lb/> 40.<lb/> R Sasaki and R K Bullough in:<lb/> &quot;Nonlinear Evolution Equations and<lb/> Dynamical Systems&quot; Lecture Notes in Physics 120, M Boiti, F Pempinelli<lb/> and G Soliani eds, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg (1980) pp.315-337.<lb/> 41</reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>.<lb/> R Sasaki and R K Bullough, Proc. Roy. Soc. London</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>A, 376:401 (1981).<lb/> 42.<lb/> E Sklyanin, LOMI Preprint E-3-1979 (1979).<lb/> 43.<lb/> Z Jiang,<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>&quot;Integrable<lb/> Systems<lb/> and<lb/> Integrability&quot;,<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>PhD<lb/> Thesis,<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>University of Mancheseter</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<reference>(Feb. 1987).<lb/> 44.<lb/> M Jimbo, Lett. Math. Phys. 10:63 (1985).<lb/> 45.<lb/> V G Drinfeld, Soviet Math. Dokl. 27 (No.1):68 (1983); &quot;Quantum Groups&quot;<lb/> in: Proc. Inti. Congo of Mathematicians, Berkeley (1987) pp.789-820.<lb/> 46.<lb/> S<lb/> Majid,<lb/> &quot;Quasitriangular<lb/> Hopf<lb/> Algebras<lb/> and<lb/> the<lb/> Yang-Baxter<lb/> Equations&quot;, Int. J. Mod. Phys. A (1989). To appear.<lb/> 47.<lb/> Yu I Manin, Ann. Inst. Fourier, Grenoble 37, 4:191 (1987).<lb/> 68<lb/> 48.<lb/> I Paczek, &quot;Statistical Mechanics of Some Integrable Quantum Spin<lb/> Systems in One Dimension&quot;, PhD Thesis, University of Manchester. To<lb/> be submitted (1990).<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">49.<lb/> M Jimbo and T Miwa, &quot;Integrable Systems and Infinite Lie Algebras&quot;<lb/> in:<lb/> &quot;Integrable Systems in Statistical Mechanics&quot;,</note>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>G M D&apos;Ariano,<lb/> A Montorsi and M G Rasetti</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>eds, World Scientific, Singapore (1985).<lb/> 50.<lb/> H B Thacker, Rev. Mod. Phys. 53:253 (1981).<lb/> 51.<lb/> Yi Cheng, &quot;Theory of Integrable Lattices&quot;, PhD Thesis, University of<lb/> Manchester (Jan. 1987).<lb/> 52.<lb/> A G Izergin and V E Korepin, Lett. Math. Phys. 5:199 (1981).<lb/> 53.<lb/> Yu-Zhong Chen, &quot;Statistical Mechanics of the Classical and Quantum<lb/> 1+1 Dimensional Integrable Models&quot;,<lb/> PhD<lb/> Thesis,<lb/> University of<lb/> Manchester (July 1989).<lb/> 54.<lb/> R K Bullough, D J Pilling and J Timonen, J. Phys. A:<lb/> Math. Gen.<lb/> 19:L955 (1986).<lb/> 55.<lb/> C N Yang and C P Yang, J. Math. Phys. 10:1115 (1969).<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>56.<lb/> J Timonen, Yu-Zhong Chen and R K Bullough, Nucl. Phys. B</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>(Proc.<lb/> Suppl.) 5A:58 (1988).<lb/> 57.<lb/></reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Nu Nu Chen, M D Johnson and M Fowler</docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>, Phys. Rev. Letts 56: 507<lb/> (1986); 56: 1427 (E) (1986).<lb/> 58.<lb/> J Timonen, R K Bullough and D J Pilling, Phys. Rev. B 34:6525 (1986).<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">69<lb/> NONLINEAR DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS IN PHYSICS AND THEIR<lb/> GEOMETRICAL INTEGRABILITY PROPERTIES<lb/></note>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Ling-Lie Chau<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Department of Physics<lb/> University of California<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Davis, CA 95616<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">INTRODUCTION<lb/> The attempt of this line of research is to try to treat Yang-Mills, and gravitational<lb/> fields as nonlinear systems, and try to see how much they possess the geometrical<lb/> integrability properties that have been the guiding force in many two-dimension non-<lb/>linear systems. Though the study so far has been quite formal and mathematical,<lb/> the ultimate goal we have in mind is for particle physics: to solve the full Yang Mills<lb/> and gravitational fields, and to formulate new ways to quantize the fields.<lb/> Recently linear systems and conservation laws have been constructed for the<lb/> extended conformal supergravity theories, [11 which have been shown to be the con-<lb/>sequences of light-like integrability in curved extended superspace. [2J This completes<lb/> the picture of a unifying description of equations of motion from the point of view<lb/> of geometrical integrability and marks possibly the beginning of a new chapter of<lb/> formulating quantum field theories using these understandings.<lb/> The generic structure of geometrical integrability properties can be summarized<lb/> in Fig. 1.<lb/> The heart of the matter is first to find linear systems with parameters. The linear<lb/> systems are usually of the form<lb/> \7 x7J;(X, Y) = 0,<lb/> \7y 7J;(X, Y) = 0,<lb/> where \7 x, \7 yare some generalized covariant derivatives in some general-<lb/>ized geometrical spaces; e.g.<lb/> (complexified) space-time space plus complex<lb/> Differenrial Geometric Methods in Theoretical Physics<lb/> 71<lb/> Edited by l..l.</div>

	<reference>Chau and W. Nahm. Plenum Press. New York. 1990<lb/></reference>

	<div type="abstract">LINEAR SYSTnMS _<lb/> .. non-local consorvation laws<lb/> /&quot;<lb/> !i.icnlli .. --I3T<lb/> finite R-H transforms ---... solutions<lb/> oquations<lb/> Infinitesimal R-H<lb/> local<lb/> Affine IIlgebra<lb/> conservation<lb/> laws<lb/> current algebra<lb/> in spectrum space<lb/> (Cp3)<lb/> ?<lb/> Fig. 1. Some Generic Structures of integrable Non-linear systems<lb/> parameterSj[5-12! (complexified) space-time with superspace extensions plus [13-14]<lb/> I<lb/> t<lb/> [15-19] I<lb/> . . I<lb/> comp ex parame ersj<lb/> oop spacesj noncommutatlve geometnca spacesj etc.<lb/> The integrability of tf; requires [\7 x, \7 y} = 0, i.e. curvatureless. The equations<lb/> of motion or the original nonlinear systems then follow from this generalized cur-<lb/>vatureless condition. It is from these linear systems with parameters that powerful<lb/> methods can be used to generate new solutions. The general theme of these meth-<lb/>ods are gauge transformations of tf;, and through its analyticity properties in the<lb/> complex parameters that the so-called nonlocal conservation laws can be derived and<lb/> that the original nonlinear differential equations are converted into integral equations<lb/> in the complex-parameter space, i.e., the finite Riemann-Hilbert (RH) transforma-<lb/>tions. The RH transforms satisfy group properties and their infinitesimal elements<lb/> form the Affine Kac-Moody algebra, which can be viewed as the result of the current<lb/> algebra in the complex parameter space. Another branch of development is to derive<lb/> parametric Bianchi-Backlund transformation (BT) from a special kind of finite RH<lb/> transformation. Such BT&apos;s historically were found by guesswork and now we have<lb/> a more general understanding of their origin. From the BT&apos;s with parameters, local<lb/> conservations can be derived, and another nonlinear system, the Ricatti equations<lb/> 72<lb/> can be constructed. The Ricatti equations then can be shown to share the same<lb/> linear systems.<lb/> The beautiful and surprising thing is that so many equations of motions in physics<lb/> possess these geometrical integrability properties when the proper formulations and<lb/> proper extended spaces are found. The two dimensional systems include chiral mod-<lb/>els: principal; symmetric-space; superized; chiral models with Wess-Zumino term and<lb/> its superized version; the Ernest equations (which are reduced systems of station-<lb/>ary axially symmetric Einstein equations and also static axially symmetric self-dual<lb/> Yang-Mills equations); Sine-Gordon equations, KdV equations, Liouville equations in<lb/> the SL(2C) formulations. All the developments in the chart have been done for these<lb/> two-dimensional systems. The four dimensional models includes self-dual Yang-Mills;<lb/> supersymmetric Yang-Mills; and the conformal supergravity equations. All of them<lb/> have been shown to have infinite nonlocal conservation laws and linear systems, from<lb/> which integrability properties of varied degrees as listed in Fig. 1 have been derived.<lb/> For my reviews and many other reports on related developments see Refs. [7,18,28].<lb/> The important extended space that has emerged from such studies is the ex-<lb/>tended superspace. Irrespect to whether Nature has manifesting representation of<lb/> superspaces as supersymmetrical particle states or actual superspaces, superspace<lb/> has already demonstrated its richness as a useful framework to look at our physical<lb/> equations and may turn out to be an essential part of physical description as complex<lb/> number is.<lb/> Because of limitation in space, I shall only list the recent work done with my<lb/> collaborators:<lb/> I. Supergravity Theories<lb/> La. D = 4: It has been shown that light-like integrability conditions for n 2: 5,<lb/> 6,7, 8 lead to conformal supergravity equations of motion. (2)<lb/> Lb. D = 4: Linear systems have been constructed from all (n = 1, ... , 8) the<lb/> light-like integrability conditions. 1) These linear systems help to solve the light-like<lb/> constraints and thus equation of motion for n = 5, 6, 7, 8; and helps to solve the<lb/> light-like constraints for n = 1, 2, 3, 4 for off-shell formulation.<lb/> Lc. D = 10, n = 1: It has been shown that light-like integrability constraints<lb/> lead to equations (Poincare) of motion only if an additional algebraic constraint<lb/> is imposed. (3)<lb/> Thus the light-like integrability constraints can allow an off-shell<lb/> formulation of the theory.<lb/> 73<lb/> Ld. D = 10, n = 1: Linear systems and conservation laws can be constructed for<lb/> the light-like integrability conditions, (4) and thus useful for the off-shell formulation<lb/> of the D = 10, n = 1 supergravity theory. In. the construction of the linear systems<lb/> and conservation laws, it is essential to use the bi-spinor representation for the light-<lb/>like vectors.<lb/> II. Supersymmetric Yang-Mills Theories<lb/> In addition to the similar developments (15-18) as mentioned in section I for<lb/> D = 4, supergravity theories, our recent new addition is the construction of linear<lb/> systems, and an infinite number of nonlocal conservation laws using the bi-spinor<lb/> representation (19) for any light-like vector in D = 6 and 10. These will be certainly<lb/> useful for constructing new solutions in D = 6 and 10, and then in D = 4 by<lb/> dimensional reduction.<lb/> III. Progresses Made For The D = 4, Self-Dual Yang-Mills Equation<lb/> lILa. Permutability property has been shown to be true for the Chau-Prasad-<lb/>Sinha Biicklund transformations (BT). (20)<lb/> III.b. The sequence, Parametric BT --&gt; Riccati --&gt; linear systems, has been con-<lb/>structed for the self-dual Yang-Mills equations. (21)<lb/> III.c. A generalized Backlund transformation, which is capable of generating<lb/> instanton solutions has been constructed for the (supersymmetric) self-dual Yang-<lb/>Mills equations. (22)<lb/> IV. The D = 2 Theories<lb/> IV.a. The Ernst equations which are reduced non-linear systems of static and ax-<lb/>ially symmetric Einstein, or Yang-Mills equations: linear systems, infinite-nonlocal<lb/> conservation laws, finite Riemann-Hilbert transforms, and infinitesmal RH trans-<lb/>form =&gt; Kac-Moody algebra; Backlund transformations, etc. have been thoroughly<lb/> discussed. (23)<lb/> IV.b. All the integrability properties as listed in IV.a. have been constructed for<lb/> the sup.er-chiral equations with Wess-Zumino term. (24)<lb/> IV.c. A general gauge covariant formulation, as well as all the integrability prop-<lb/>erties have been constructed for general symmetric-space chiral fields. (25)<lb/> V. General Integrability Discussions:<lb/> 74<lb/> V.a. A unifying derivation of BT has been given from the point of view of infinite<lb/> Riemann-Hilbert transformation. (26)<lb/> V.b. A general discussion of Kac-Moody algebra has been made from the point<lb/> of view of infinite Riemann-Hilbert transformation. (27)<lb/> Concluding Remarks<lb/> Now we are ready to move forward in two fronts: first, finding solutions to the full<lb/> Yang-Mills equations. The essential new feature in the search for classical solutions<lb/> for the full Yang-Mills and supergravity equations is the use of superspace, and to<lb/> develop two-complex-variable Riemann-Hilbert transform, contrasting to the one-<lb/>complex-variables Riemann-Hilbert transform used in two-dimensional systems and<lb/> the self-dual Yang-Mills systems. And second, quantizing the super-Yang-Mills and<lb/> supergravity fields from these new points of view. (28)<lb/> ACKNOWLEDGEMENT<lb/> I would like to thank the Organizers of the conference and the host members of<lb/> Swansea University for the stimulating conference and for their warm hospitality.<lb/></div>

	<reference>REFERENCES<lb/> 1. Chau, L.-L., &quot;Linear Systems and Conservation Laws of Gravitational Fields<lb/> in Four Plus Extended Superspace&quot;, Phys. Lett. Bm (1988) 238.<lb/> 2. Chau, L.-L. and Lim, C.-S., Phys. Rev. Lett. QQ, 294 (1986).<lb/> 3. Chau, L.-L. and Milewski, B., &quot;Light-Like Integrability and Supergravity Equa-<lb/>tions of Motion in D = 10, N = 1 Superspace&quot;, UCD-87-05-R*; and Chau L.-L.<lb/> and Lim, C.-S. to appear in Mod. Phys A. 1989.<lb/> 4. Chau, L.L. and B. Milewski &quot;Linear Systems and Conservation Laws in D=10,<lb/> N =1 Supergravity&quot;, to appear in Phys. Lett.<lb/> 5. For general discussions on such equations, see, for example, G.L. Lamb, Jr.,<lb/> &quot;Elements of Soliton Theory&quot; (Wiley, New York, 1980); M.J. Ablowitz and<lb/> H. Segur, &quot;Solitons and the Inverse Scattering Transform&quot; (SIAM, Philadel-<lb/>phia, 1981); F. Calogero and A. Degasperis, &quot;Spectral Transform and Solitons,<lb/> I&quot; (North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1982).<lb/> 6. Faddeev, L.D. and N. Yu. Reshetikhin, Annals of Physics 167 (1986) 227;</reference>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>E.K.<lb/> Sklyanin, L.A. Takhtadzhyan, and L.D. Faddeev, Teoreticheskaya i Matematch-<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<reference>eskaya Fiziks, Vol. 40 (1979) 194.<lb/> 75<lb/> 7. Chau, 1.-L., in Proceedings of Nonlinear Phenomena, Mexico, 1982, Lecture<lb/> Notes in Physics 189 (Springer-Verlag, New York, 1983).<lb/> 8. Novikov, S., S.V. Manakov, L.P. Pitaevskii and V.E. Zakharov, &quot;Theory of<lb/> Solitons: The Inverse Scattering Method&quot; (Consultants Bureau, New York,<lb/> 1984).<lb/> 9. Yang, C.N., Phys. Rev. Lett. 38 (1977) 1377. S. Ward, Phys. Lett. 61A (1977)<lb/> 81. Y. Brihaye, D.B. Fairlie, J. Nuyts, R.F. Yates, JMP 19 (1978) 2528.<lb/> 10. Atiyah, M.F. and R.S. Ward, Commun. Math. Phys. 55 (1977) 117.<lb/> 11. Atiyah, M.F., V.G. Drinfeld, N.J. Hitchin and Yu.L Manin, Phys. Lett. A 65<lb/> (1978) 185.<lb/> 12. Corrigan, E.F., D.B. Fairlie, R.G. Yates and P. Goddard, Commun. Math. Phys.<lb/> 58 (1978) 223.<lb/> 13. Salam, A. and J. Strathdee, Phys. Lett. ,un, 353 (1974). For review see<lb/> J. Scherk, in Recent Development in Gravitation (Plenum, New York, 1979);<lb/> B. Zumino, in Proceedings of the NATO Advanced Study Institute on Recent<lb/> Developments in Gravity, Cargese, 1978 (Plenum, New York, 1979), p. 405;<lb/> J. Wess and J. Bagger, Supersymmetry and Supergravity (Princeton Univ. Press,<lb/> Princeton, N.J., 1983).<lb/> 14. Witten, E., Phys. Lett. 11B., 394 (1978); M. Sohnuis, Nuc!. Phys. liUQ, 461<lb/> (1978) .<lb/> 15. Volovich, LV., Phys. Lett. l2.9B., 429 (1983).<lb/> 16. Devchan, C., Nuc!. Phys. B.2.3.8., 333 (1984).<lb/> 17. Harnard, J., Hurtubise, J., and Shnider, S., Supersymmetric Yang Mills Equa-<lb/>tions and Supertwistors, Annals of Physics (to appear).<lb/> 18. Chau, 1.-L., Ge, M.-1., Popowicz, Z., Phys. Rev. Lett. 52,1940 (1984); Chau,<lb/> 1.-1., Ge, M.-L., Lim, C.-S., Phys. Rev. D33, 1056 (1986). &quot;Vertex Operators<lb/> in Mathematics and Physics&quot;, Proceedings of the 1983 Berkeley Workshop,<lb/> Eds. Lepoulsky, Mandelstam, Singer.<lb/> 19. Chau, L.-1. and Milewski, B., Phys. Lett. 198 (1987) 356.<lb/> 20. Chau, L.-L. and Chinea, F.J., Lett. in Math. Phys. il, 189 (1986); Chau,<lb/> L.-L., Yen, H.-C., Chen, H.-H., Chinea, F.J., Lee, C-R., Shaw, J.-C., Mod.<lb/> Phys. Lett. 1,285 (1986).<lb/> 21. Chau, L.-L. and Yen, H.-C., J. Math. Phys. 2B., 1167 (1986).<lb/> 76<lb/> 22. Chau, L.1., J.C. Shaw, and H.C. Yen, Int. J. of Mod. Phys. 1. (1989) 2715.<lb/> 23. Chau, 1.-L., Chou, K.-C., Hou, B.-Y., Song, X.-C., Phys. Rev. 34D, 1814<lb/> (1986).<lb/> 24. Chau, L.-L. and Yen, H.C., Phys. Lett. B177, 368 (1986).<lb/> 25. Chau, 1.-L., Hou, B.-Y., Phys. Lett. 145B, 347 (1984); Chau, L.-L., Hou,<lb/> B.-Y., Song, X.-C., Phys. Lett. 15lE, 421 (1985).<lb/> 26. Chau, L.-L., Ge, M.-1., &quot;Finite Riemann-Hilbert Transformation and A Uni-<lb/>fying Derivation of Backlund Transformation&quot;, UCD-87-(1987).<lb/> 27. Chau, L.-L., Ge, M.-L., Yen H.-C., J. of Math. Phys. 30 (1989) 166.<lb/></reference>

	<note type="other">28. For a recent review on the field: see Chau, L.1., &quot;Geometrical Integrability and<lb/> Equations of Motion in Physics: A Unifying View,&quot; talk given at the Workshop<lb/> held at</note>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Nankai Institute of Mathematics, Nankai University</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Tianjin, China.<lb/></address>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>77<lb/> INTEGRABILITY OFF CRITICALITY<lb/> AND QUANTUM INTEGRABLE SYSTEMS·&apos;··<lb/> Pierre MATHIEU<lb/> Departement de physique, Universite Laval<lb/></affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Quebec, Canada, G1 K 7P4<lb/></address>

	<div type="abstract">ABSTRACT: Using the equivalence between the Virasoro algebra and<lb/> the Hamiltonian structure of integrable systems of the Korteweg-de<lb/> Vries type, it is shown that in conformal field theories, there are<lb/> three infinite families of commuting conserved integrals of normal<lb/> ordered polynomials of the energy-momentum tensor.<lb/> For minimal<lb/> conformal models, there are three distinguished relevant degenerate<lb/> scalar fields and it turns out that the perturbation with one of these<lb/> fields preserves one infinite family of conserved commuting<lb/> integrals. The relation with Toda systems and the supersymmetric<lb/> extension are briefly discussed.<lb/></div>

		</front>
	</text>
</tei>
