<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei>
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="1340758"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<front>
<lb/>
	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Monte Carlo generators for central exclusive diffraction<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Maarten Boonekamp, Creighton Hogg, James Monk, Andrew Pilkington &amp; Marek Tasevsky<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<div type="abstract">Abstract<lb/> We review the three Monte Carlo generators that are available for simulating<lb/> the central exclusive reaction, pp → p + X + p.<lb/> 1 Introduction<lb/> The central exclusive mechanism is defined as pp → p + X + p with no radiation emitted between the<lb/> intact outgoing beam hadrons and the central system X. The study of central exclusive Higgs boson<lb/> production has been aided with the recent development of Monte Carlo simulations to enable parton,<lb/> hadron and detector level simulation. The three generators that we shall examine here are DPEMC<lb/> [1], EDDE [2] and ExHuME [3]. From an experimental perspective, it is important to examine both<lb/> the similarities and differences between the models in order to assess the physics potential in terms of<lb/> forward proton tagging at the LHC [4].<lb/> Each of the Monte Carlos implements a different model of central exclusive production that is<lb/> either perturbative or non-perturbative. ExHuME is an implementation of the perturbative calculation of<lb/> Khoze, Martin and Ryskin [5], the so-called &quot; Durham Model &quot; . In this calculation (depicted in fig 1(a)),<lb/> the two gluons couple perturbatively to the off-diagonal unintegrated gluon distribution in the proton.<lb/> The Durham approach includes a Sudakov factor to suppress radiation into the rapidity gap between the<lb/> central system and the outgoing protons and which renders the loop diagram infra-red safe. The bare<lb/> cross section is suppressed by a soft-survival probability, S 2 , that accounts for additional momentum<lb/> transfer between the proton lines that lead to particle production that could fill in the gap. The current<lb/> ExHuME default takes S 2 to be 0.03 at the LHC.<lb/> In contrast, DPEMC and EDDE treat the proton vertices non-perturbatively. This is acheived in the<lb/> context of Regge theory, by pomeron exchange from each of the proton lines. DPEMC follows the Bialas-<lb/>Landshoff approach [6] of parameterising the pomeron flux within the proton. DPEMC also sets the<lb/> default value of S 2 to 0.03 at the LHC. EDDE uses an improved Regge-eikonal approach [7] to calculate<lb/> the soft proton vertices and includes a Sudakov suppression factor to prohibit real gluon emission. There<lb/> is no explicit soft-survival factor present in EDDE: it is assumed that the Regge parameterisation includes<lb/> the effect of additional interactions between the proton lines. For further details of the calculations<lb/> underlying both DPEMC and ExHuME please refer to [8].<lb/> The connection between the parton level process and the hadronic final state is not the same in<lb/> the three Monte Carlos. Both ExHuME and EDDE are linked to Pythia [9, 10] for final state parton<lb/> showering and hadronisation. DPEMC however, overrides the HERWIG [11] internal γγ interactions in<lb/> e + e − collisions to simulate double pomeron exchange.<lb/> The processes available are similar in each Monte Carlo. Perhaps the most interesting is Higgs<lb/> boson production with all subsequent decays. In addition, di-jet production is included in all three<lb/> generators. None of the Monte Carlos yet includes the next-to-leading order 3 jet process, which could<lb/> be an important, or even the dominant, background to the central exclusive H → b ¯ b search channel.<lb/> Finally, inclusive double pomeron exchange (shown in figure 1(b)) will also act as a backgound to<lb/> the exclusive process as there are 2 protons in the final state. These processes are always accompanied by<lb/> pomeron remnants in the central system and it may be a challenge experimentally to separate these from<lb/> the system of interest. Two models for these processes are the Cox-Forshaw model (CF), implemented in<lb/> POMWIG [12], and the Boonekamp-Peschanski-Royon model (BPR) [13] that is included in DPEMC.</div>

		</front>
	</text>
</tei>
