<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei>
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="1345913"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<front>
<lb/>
	<docTitle>
	<titlePart>Midrapidity Hyperon Production in pp<lb/> and pA Collisions<lb/></titlePart>
	</docTitle>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>G.H. Arakelyan, C. Merino, and Yu.M. Shabelski<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<note type="other">Presented by C. Merino at Initial Stages 2014 (IS2014)<lb/> The 2nd International Conference on the<lb/> Initial Stages in High-Energy Nuclear Collisions<lb/> Napa Valley, CA, USA, 3-7 December, 2014<lb/></note>

	<div type="abstract">Abstract In this paper we present the description of the production of strange and<lb/> mulistrange baryons in a wide energy region, from CERN SpS up to LHC, in the<lb/> framework of the Quark-Gluon String model.<lb/> The Quark-Gluon String model (QGSM) [1, 2, 3] is built on the Dual Topo-<lb/>logical Unitarization, nonperturbative notions of QCD, and Regge Theory based<lb/> phenomenology. The QGSM has been successfully used for the description of mul-<lb/>tiparticle production processes in hadron-hadron [4, 5] and hadron-nucleus [6] colli-<lb/>sions. In the case of interaction with a nuclear target, the Multiple Scattering Theory<lb/> (Gribov-Glauber Theory) is implemented.<lb/> Though it is not the direct aim of the present paper, one has to note that such an<lb/> approach based on the analysis of Feynman and reggeon diagrams has been already<lb/> used [7, 8] to study the anysotropic flows, and, in particular, the elliptic flow v 2 in<lb/> collisions of hadrons and nuclei at high energies, questions so extensively discussed<lb/> during this conference.<lb/> The significant differences observed in the yields of baryons and antibaryons in<lb/> the central (midrapidity) region are connected with [3, 9] the special structure of<lb/></div>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>G.H. Arakelyan<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>A.Alikhanyan National Scientific Laboratory (Yerevan Physics Institute),</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Yerevan, 0036, Armenia.<lb/></address>

	<email>e-mail: argev@mail.yerphi.am<lb/></email>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>C. Merino<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Departamento de Física de Partículas, Facultade de Física and Instituto Galego de Física de Altas<lb/> Enerxías (IGFAE), Universidade de Santiago de Compostela,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Santiago de Compostela 15782, Gal-<lb/>iza, Spain.</address>

	<email>e-mail: carlos.merino@usc.es<lb/></email>

	<byline>
	<docAuthor>Yu.M. Shabelski<lb/></docAuthor>
	</byline>

	<byline>
	<affiliation>Petersburg Nuclear Physics Institute, NCR Kurchatov Institute,</affiliation>
	</byline>

	<address>Gatchina, St.Petersburg 188350,<lb/></address>

	<email>Russia. e-mail: shabelsk@thd.pnpi.spb.ru<lb/></email>

		</front>
	</text>
</tei>
