<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei>
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<front> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org <lb/> Research <lb/> Cite this article: Holland J, Sparling G. 2013 <lb/>Null electromagnetic fields and relative <lb/>Cauchy–Riemann embeddings. Proc R Soc A <lb/>469: 2012.0583. <lb/>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rspa.2012.0583 <lb/>Received: 4 October 2012 <lb/>Accepted: 19 December 2012 <lb/> Subject Areas: <lb/> geometry, mathematical physics <lb/> Keywords: <lb/> twistor theory, Cauchy–Riemann manifolds, <lb/>Cauchy–Riemann embeddings, <lb/>null electromagnetic fields, <lb/>shear-free congruences <lb/> Author for correspondence: <lb/> Jonathan Holland <lb/>e-mail: jeh89@pitt.edu <lb/> Null electromagnetic fields <lb/>and relative Cauchy–Riemann <lb/>embeddings <lb/> Jonathan Holland and George Sparling <lb/> Department of Mathematics, University of Pittsburgh, <lb/>301 Thackeray Hall, Pittsburgh, PA 15260, USA <lb/> This paper applies the notion of relative Cauchy– <lb/>Riemann (CR) embeddings to study two related <lb/>questions. First, it answers negatively the question <lb/>posed by Penrose whether every shear-free null <lb/>rotating congruence is analytic. Second, it proves <lb/>that, given any shear-free null rotating congruence in <lb/>Minkowski space, there exists a null electromagnetic <lb/>field that is null with respect to the given congruence. <lb/>In the course of answering these questions, we <lb/>introduce some new techniques for studying null <lb/>electromagnetic fields and shear-free congruences, <lb/>in general, based on the notion of a relative <lb/>CR embedding. <lb/></front>

			<body> 1. Introduction <lb/> A null geodesic congruence F in (signature (1, 3)) <lb/>Minkowski space M is a foliation of an open set <lb/>in Minkowski space by oriented null geodesics. Such <lb/>a foliation generates a tangent vector field k  a  . The <lb/>congruence F is said to be shear free, if there exists a <lb/>complex null vector field m a  (called a connecting vector for <lb/>the congruence) such that <lb/>[k, m] <lb/> a  = 0, k <lb/> a m a  = 0, and k <lb/> [a  m <lb/> b  ¯ <lb/> m <lb/> c]  = 0. <lb/>The congruence is rotating, if in addition m  [a  ¯ <lb/> m b  [m, ¯ <lb/> m] c]  = 0. <lb/>Shear-free congruences were introduced in Robinson [1] <lb/>and linked to the study of null solutions of the <lb/>electromagnetic fields. They remain an important tool in <lb/>the study of algebraically special solutions of Einstein&apos;s <lb/>equations [2–5]. Trautman [6] gives a detailed history. <lb/>An electromagnetic field is a two-form F such that <lb/>dF = 0, d  F = 0, <lb/>where  is the duality operator. A non-zero field F is said <lb/>to be null if <lb/> F ab F <lb/> ab  = F ab  ((F) <lb/> ab  = 0, <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote"> c <lb/> 2013 The Author(s) Published by the Royal Society. All rights reserved. <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></note>

			<page> 2 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> Z <lb/> N <lb/>Q <lb/> Figure 1. The submanifold N is two-sided embedded in Q if it can be realized as the intersection of a complex surface with Q. <lb/> It is (essentially) one-sided embedded if the complex surface exists only on one side. (Online version in colour.) <lb/> where F = F ab  dx  a  ∧ dx  b  and F ab  = −F  ba  . One can show that a field F is null, if and only if the <lb/>energy–momentum tensor T ac  = −F  a <lb/>b F cb  + <lb/> 1 <lb/>4  g ac F bd F bd  splits as an outer product T ac  = k a k c  for <lb/>some non-zero null vector k a  , the principal null direction of the field. If F is a null electromagnetic <lb/>field, then k a  is the tangent vector for some shear-free congruence (lemma 7.1). In that case, F is <lb/>said to be adapted to k a  . <lb/>This paper answers two distinct but related questions. First, it establishes a foundation for the <lb/>theory of shear-free congruences of geodesics in Minkowski space. We prove that a given shear-<lb/>free congruence corresponds to a certain CR submanifold N of the indefinite hyperquadric of CP  3 <lb/> (projective twistor space in this context; figure 1). Kerr, as cited in Penrose [7], has shown that the <lb/>aforementioned result holds in the case of analytic congruences, where the shear-free congruence <lb/>may be represented as a holomorphic surface in CP  3 ; the CR manifold N is then the intersection <lb/>of this holomorphic surface with the hyperquadric. In this paper, we drop the assumption of <lb/>analyticity and work in the smooth setting and show that one still obtains this CR manifold N <lb/> (theorem 5.2). Conversely, given a CR submanifold N of the hyperquadric (which obeys some <lb/>genericity criteria) one obtains a shear-free congruence (theorem 5.3). <lb/>In the smooth category, there does not exist, in general, a holomorphic surface associated with <lb/> N (theorem 6.1); however, we prove here that, if the Levi form of N is non-degenerate, then there <lb/>is in twistor space a unique complex two-surface Z with boundary such that N is the boundary of <lb/> Z. The key notion here is that of a relative embedding of CR manifolds, defined in §2. While, by a <lb/>result of Jacobwitz &amp; Trevès [8], not every three-dimensional strictly pseudo-convex CR manifold <lb/>is embeddable, it is known that a solution of the vacuum Einstein equations equipped with a <lb/>shear-free congruence defines a three-dimensional CR manifold that is (abstractly) two-sided <lb/>embeddable [9]. However, §3 constructs a CR manifold that is a co-dimension two submanifold of <lb/>the signature (2, 2) real hyperquadric in CP  3 that can only be ambiently realized as the boundary <lb/>of a complex two-surface on one side. Such a relative embedding is termed an essential one-sided <lb/>embedding. <lb/> It is significant that, in general, the CR manifold N need not be real analytic and yet <lb/>corresponds to a shear-free rotating congruence. The construction of §3 exhibits such a non-<lb/>analytic N, contrary to the observation in Penrose [7, p. 361]: &apos;These (non-analytic) exceptional <lb/>cases appear to occur only when the rotation also vanishes&apos;. Subsequent to Penrose [10], it <lb/>seems unlikely that he would have retained this perspective. In fact, in Penrose &amp; Rindler [11], <lb/>the possibility of the existence of non-analytic rotating shear-free congruences is acknowledged <lb/>(without providing a construction), and their hypothetical properties are discussed. In spite of <lb/>this, the assumption of analyticity seems to have entered the lore of the subject, particularly <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote"> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></note>

			<page> 3 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> in regards to the complex worldline approach of Newman and others [12]. Quite recently, <lb/>non-analytic congruences have been studied in Baird &amp; Eastwood [13], although the congruences <lb/>there have zero rotation. Non-analytic congruences with zero rotation are readily constructed <lb/>from the null rays emanating from a non-analytic worldline in real Minkowski space. It is <lb/>substantially more difficult to construct non-analytic congruences with non-zero rotation. <lb/>Second, the paper applies these results to a class of solutions of the electromagnetic field <lb/>equations, addressing the following question: given a shear-free rotating congruence k  a  , what <lb/>is the space of solutions of the field equations which are adapted to k a  ? We prove that the space <lb/>of solutions corresponds to the space of all holomorphic sections of the canonical bundle of the <lb/>complex surface (with boundary) Z in a neighbourhood of the boundary, or alternatively to (2, 0)-<lb/>forms on the CR manifold N which are closed with respect to the tangential Cauchy–Riemann <lb/>operator (lemma 8.2 and theorem 8.3). A special case of this result is the existence of local solutions <lb/>to the electromagnetic field equations adapted to k a  . This special case is discussed in Tafel [14] <lb/>using rather different techniques. In Lewandowski and co-workers [15,16], special solutions of <lb/>the Einstein equations are also algebraically found by similar methods. <lb/> 2. One-sided embeddings of Cauchy–Riemann manifolds <lb/> We follow here standard definitions of CR manifolds and the tangential CR complex (cf. [17]). <lb/>A CR manifold is a smooth manifold M of dimension 2n + 1 together with a distribution of <lb/>complex n-planes T  1,0  M ⊂ TM ⊗ C with complex conjugate bundle T  0,1  M such that T  1,0  M ∩ <lb/> T  0,1  M = 0 and which is integrable in the sense of Frobenius (i.e. the Lie bracket of two local <lb/>sections of T  1,0  M is again a section of T  1,0  M). If M is a CR manifold, then the annihilator of <lb/> T  1,0  M in T  *  M ⊗ C is denoted by Ω  0,1  M and its complex conjugate by Ω  1,0  M. Because T  1,0  M is <lb/>integrable in the sense of Frobenius, Ω  1,0  M and Ω  0,1  M each generate differential ideals J and ¯ <lb/> J , <lb/>respectively, in ΩM ⊗ C. <lb/> The tangential Cauchy–Riemann complex is defined as follows in Hill &amp; Nacinovich [17]. Let <lb/> Q <lb/> 0,1  (M) = <lb/> (Ω  1  (M) ⊗ C) <lb/> Ω  1,0  (M) <lb/> . <lb/>Then, Q  0,1  (M) is the dual space of T  0,1  M. For f ∈ C  ∞  (M) ⊗ C, define ¯ <lb/> ∂  b f ∈ Q  0,1  (M) to be the co-set <lb/>of df modulo Ω  1,0  (M). More generally, because dJ ⊂ J , we have dJ k  ⊂ J  k  for all integers k ≥ 0 <lb/>(where J  0 := Ω(M) ⊗ C, and J  k  is the ideal generated by the k-fold wedge products of sections <lb/>of J ). Upon passing to the quotient, d induces a mapping <lb/>  : <lb/> J  k <lb/> J  k+1  → <lb/> J  k <lb/> J  k+1  . <lb/>Let Q p,j  (M) be the graded part of J  p  /J  p+1  of degree (p + j). Thus <lb/> Q <lb/> p,j  (M) = <lb/> (J  p  ∩ Ω  p+j  (M) ⊗ C) <lb/> (J  p+1  ∩ Ω  p+j  (M) ⊗ C) <lb/> by definition. Note that <lb/> | Q p,j  : Q <lb/> p,j  (M) → Q <lb/> p,j+1  (M) <lb/> because d is a graded differential of degree +1. We write  <lb/>  = ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  and call ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  the tangential Cauchy– <lb/>Riemann operator. The tangential Cauchy–Riemann (or just CR) complex is then the complex <lb/>0 → Q <lb/> p,0  (M) <lb/> ¯ <lb/> ∂  b <lb/> − → Q <lb/> p,1 <lb/> ¯ <lb/> ∂  b <lb/> − → · · · , <lb/>where by convention Q  0,0  = C  ∞  (M) ⊗ C. Let Q be the bigraded module Q = <lb/> p,q Q p,q  . This is <lb/>indeed a complex, for ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  is given as the composition dd = 0 modulo a suitable ideal. When <lb/>a distinction is needed in the action of ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  on the Q p,j  , denote by ¯ <lb/> ∂ <lb/> p,j <lb/>b  the (graded) part of the <lb/>co-boundary that maps Q p,j  → Q p,j+1  . <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 4 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> The Levi form is the Hermitian form <lb/> L : (T <lb/> 1,0  (M) ⊕ T <lb/> 0,1  (M)) × (T <lb/> 1,0  (M) ⊕ T <lb/> 0,1  (M)) → <lb/> T(M) ⊗ C <lb/> T  1,0  M ⊕ T  0,1  M <lb/> defined on sections v, w by <lb/> L(v, w) = <lb/> 1 <lb/>2i <lb/>[v, ¯ <lb/> w] mod T <lb/> 1,0  M ⊕ T <lb/> 0,1  M. <lb/> Note that L behaves as a tensor under change in basis sections, and therefore represents a well-<lb/>defined bundle map. If L(v, v) = 0 only for the zero vector, then M is called strictly pseudo-convex. <lb/>If M and N are two CR manifolds, then a morphism of CR structures is a smooth function <lb/> f : M → N such that <lb/> f  *  T <lb/> 1,0  M ⊂ T <lb/> 1,0  N. <lb/> A morphism is an embedding if it is a smooth embedding in the sense of differential topology. <lb/>The following definition is due to Hill [18]. (Manifolds with boundary are all C  ∞  smooth, and <lb/>smooth up to the boundary, which is regarded as part of the manifold.) <lb/> Definition 2.1. A complex manifold with abstract boundary is a real 2n-dimensional manifold <lb/> M with boundary, together with an involutive distribution of complex n-planes on M, denoted <lb/> T  1,0  M, such that T  1,0  M ∩ T  1,0  M = 0. <lb/>In definition 2.1, T  1,0  M will be called the holomorphic structure of M. Let Ω  0,1  M be the sheaf <lb/>of annihilators of T  1,0  M. A mapping f : M → N between two complex manifolds with boundary is <lb/> holomorphic if f  *  T  1,0  M ⊂ T  1,0  N. If M is a manifold with boundary, let ∂M be the boundary of M and <lb/> M o  = M − ∂M be the interior of M. Note well that M is a complex manifold by the Newlander– <lb/>Nirenberg theorem, and that the tangential part of T  1,0  M along ∂M determines a CR structure <lb/> T  1,0  (∂M), so that the boundary of a complex manifold with boundary is a CR manifold. <lb/> Definition 2.2. A complex manifold with concrete boundary is a complex manifold with <lb/>abstract boundary which is locally isomorphic to some domain with boundary in C  n  . <lb/>Hill [18] proves the inequivalence of these two definitions. For the rest of this paper, &apos;manifold <lb/>with boundary&apos; shall mean &apos;manifold with concrete boundary&apos;. <lb/> Definition 2.3. Let N be a CR manifold and Y a complex manifold with boundary. Let f : N → <lb/> Y be an embedding of real manifolds with boundary such that f (N) ⊂ ∂Y and f  *  (Ω  1,0  (∂Y)) ⊂ <lb/> Ω  1,0  (N). Then, f is said to be a one-sided embedding of N in Y. <lb/> If X is a complex manifold, and N is a (real) hypersurface in X with f : N → X the inclusion, <lb/>then f is also a local one-sided embedding of N in the following sense. For each p ∈ N, there exists <lb/>an open neighbourhood U of p in X such that U − N has two components, call them U  +o  and <lb/> U  −o  . Let U  +  and U  −  denote the closures of U  +o  and U  −o  in U. Then, U  +  and U  −  are complex <lb/>manifolds with boundary N ∩ U, and f  ±  : N ∩ U → U  ±  are CR embeddings. <lb/> Definition 2.4. Let Y be an n + 1-dimensional complex manifold, Q an embedded CR <lb/>submanifold of Y of real dimension 2n + 1, and N a CR manifold embedded in Q. <lb/> 1. The triple (Y, Q, N) is called a two-sided (resp. one-sided) relative embedding if there <lb/>exists a complex submanifold (resp. complex submanifold with boundary) Z of Y such <lb/>that N = Z ∩ Q. We call Z the two-sided (resp. one-sided) extension of N in Y. <lb/> 2. The triple (Y, Q, N) is called an essential one-sided relative embedding if it is a one-sided <lb/>relative embedding that cannot be extended to a two-sided relative embedding. <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote"> 3. An essential one-sided embedding <lb/> Let CP <lb/> 3 denote the complex projective three-space, equipped with projective coordinates <lb/> (z, v, u, w). The aim of this section is to prove the following. <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></note>

			<page> 5 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> Theorem 3.1. Let Q   be the hyperquadric |z|  2  + |v|  2  − |u|  2  − |w|  2  = 0 in CP  3  . There exists an essential <lb/>one-sided relative embedding of a strictly pseudo-convex CR manifold into Q   . <lb/> For convenience, let us work on the affine subset of CP  3 given by v = 0, and normalize <lb/>coordinates so that v = 1. Let Q be the locus of points (u, w, z) such that <lb/> ρ(u, w, z) <lb/> def <lb/> = 1 + |z| <lb/> 2  − |u| <lb/> 2  − |w| <lb/> 2  = 0. <lb/>The CR submanifold N of Q shall be given as a graph <lb/> N = {(u, w, z) : z = wg(u)}, <lb/> where g is a function defined on the whole complex plane. We impose the following conditions <lb/>on g: <lb/> 1. The domain of analyticity of g is the complex plane slit from 1 to ∞ along the positive <lb/>real axis: C − [1, ∞). <lb/> 2. g(u) is continuous at u = 1. <lb/>3. g(u) vanishes to infinite order at u = 1 in the sense that lim  u→1  (g(u)/(u − 1)  k  ) = 0 for every <lb/>positive integer k. Furthermore, the restriction of g to C − (1, ∞) is C  ∞  at u = 1. <lb/>4. g(u) does not vanish away from 1. <lb/>5. |g(u)| ≤ <lb/> 1 <lb/>3 on its domain. <lb/>An example of g(u) satisfying these requirements is the following: <lb/> g(u) = <lb/>  1 <lb/>3 exp(−(1 − u)  −1/4  ), u = 1, <lb/>0, <lb/> u = 1, <lb/>along the branch of the logarithm for which −π ≤ arg(1 − u) &lt; π. Then, g(u) is analytic at every <lb/>point of the slitted plane and continuous at u = 1. Furthermore, writing 1 − u = r e iθ with r ≥ 0 <lb/>and θ ∈ [−π , π), it follows that <lb/> |g(u)| = <lb/> 1 <lb/>3 <lb/>exp <lb/> −r <lb/> −1/4  cos <lb/> θ <lb/> 4 <lb/> , <lb/>so that evidently lim  u→1  (g(u)/(u − 1)  k  ) = 0 and moreover, because cos(θ/4) ≥ 1/ <lb/> √ <lb/> 2 on <lb/> −π ≤ θ &lt; π, <lb/> |g(u)| <lb/> 2  ≤ <lb/> 1 <lb/>9 <lb/>exp <lb/> − <lb/> r <lb/> 4 <lb/>  −1/4 <lb/> ≤ <lb/> 1 <lb/>9 <lb/>, <lb/>whence |g(u)| ≤ <lb/> 1 <lb/>3 . <lb/>Let E be the closed region in C  2 defined by 2|u| 2  + |w|  2  ≤ 2. Let <lb/> t(u, w) = 1 + |wg(u)| <lb/> 2  − |u| <lb/> 2  − |w| <lb/> 2 , <lb/>and let T = {(u, w) ∈ E : t(u, w) = 0}. Let N   be the graph of z = wg(u) over T; thus <lb/> N <lb/>  = {(u, w, wg(u)) : (u, w) ∈ E, t(u, w) = 0}. <lb/> Lemma 3.2. There is a neighbourhood U of (u, w, z) = (1, 0, 0) such that N  ∩ U is a smooth <lb/>submanifold of Q containing the point (u, w, z) = (1, 0, 0). <lb/> Proof. The fact that N  ∩ U contains the point (1, 0, 0) is immediately verified from the definition. <lb/>Because N   is a smooth graph over T, it suffices to show that T is a submanifold with boundary of <lb/> E in a neighbourhood the point (u, w) = (1, 0). On the boundary of E, t(u, w) = |w|  2  (|g(u)|  2  − <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote"> 1 <lb/>2  ) ≤ 0 <lb/>with equality if and only if |u| = 1 and w = 0, by the conditions on g and by the definition of the <lb/>region E. At the point q = (1, 0), we have (by the conditions on g again): dt(q) = −du − d ¯ <lb/> u. Hence, <lb/>for any vector v at q pointing towards the interior of E, we have i  v  dt(q) &gt; 0. The restriction of t to <lb/> E is C  ∞  . By the Whitney extension theorem, choose a C  ∞  extension h of t| E  to all of C  2 . It follows <lb/>by the implicit function theorem that the zero locus of h in a sufficiently small neighbourhood of q <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></note>

			<page> 6 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> is a submanifold of that neighbourhood. Now dh = dt on E, and because i  v  dh(q) &gt; 0 for interior-<lb/>pointing vectors at q, and t ≤ 0 on the boundary of E, it follows that t &lt; 0 for points outside E <lb/> sufficiently near q. Hence, a portion of the zero locus of h in a sufficiently small neighbourhood of q <lb/> lies entirely within E. Moreover, within that neighbourhood, it touches the boundary only at q. <lb/> Now let N = N  ∩ U as in lemma 3.2. <lb/> Lemma 3.3. The triple (C  3 , Q, N) is an essential one-sided relative embedding. <lb/>Proof. T is strictly pseudo-convex. The Levi form of T is represented by ∂ ¯ <lb/> ∂t = (|g(u)|  2  − 1) dw ∧ <lb/> d ¯ <lb/> w + 2i(g   (u)g( ¯ <lb/> u)w du ∧ d ¯ <lb/> w) + (|g   (u)|  2  |w|  2  − 1) du ∧ d ¯ <lb/> u. As u → 1, g(u), g   (u) → 0, so this is a <lb/>negative definite form in a sufficiently small neighbourhood of (u, w) = (1, 0), and so T is strictly <lb/>pseudo-convex. <lb/> The smooth embedding of T in Q given by j : (u, w) → (u, w, wg(u)) is a CR embedding. The CR <lb/>structure T  1,0  (T) is generated by the vector field <lb/> L = (|w| <lb/> 2  g( ¯ <lb/> u − 1)g <lb/>  (u) − ¯ <lb/> u) <lb/> ∂ <lb/>∂w <lb/> − ¯ <lb/> w(|g(u)| <lb/> 2  − 1) <lb/> ∂ <lb/>∂u <lb/> . <lb/>Note in particular that L annihilates t. Now, because the function j is holomorphic, it suffices to <lb/>check that j  *  L annihilates the defining relation for Q, namely we need j  *  Lρ = 0. However, this is <lb/>precisely the statement that L annihilates t, because t = ρ • j. <lb/>The triple (C  3 , Q, N) is a one-sided relative embedding. Indeed, the embedding j of E into C  3 is <lb/>holomorphic, and C  ∞  up to the boundary. Also, N = j(E) ∩ Q ∩ U (for some open set U). So j(E) <lb/> is a one-sided holomorphic extension of N into the interior of Q. <lb/>The one-sided relative embedding is essential. Assume that N had a two-sided holomorphic <lb/>extension Z, say. Because du and dw are linearly independent on restriction to N, they remain <lb/>linearly independent on Z locally in a neighbourhood of p. By the implicit function theorem, <lb/> Z may be given locally as a graph z = q(u, w) with q holomorphic in a polydisc  r  ((1, 0)) for <lb/>polyradius r = (r, r) sufficiently small. Consider the function wg(u) − q(u, w) in  r  ((1, 0)). This <lb/>function vanishes identically on the hypersurface T ∩  r  ((1, 0)). But T was proven to be pseudo-<lb/>convex. Therefore, by the Lewy extension theorem [19], wg(u) − q(u, w) vanishes identically in <lb/> E ∩  r  ((1, 0)) (after possibly shrinking r if necessary). But, by the choice of g, for all integers k <lb/> we have lim  u→1  (g(u)/(1 − u) k  ) = 0. It follows that q(u, w) and all of its derivatives must vanish at <lb/> (1, 0), which implies that q(u, w) is identically zero in  r  ((0, 1)). Thus, g vanishes identically in a <lb/>neighbourhood of u = 1, which is contrary to the choice of g. <lb/> The proof of theorem 3.1 is now complete. <lb/> Remark. The example constructed in this section fails to be two-sided embeddable at one <lb/>point only. Ideally, one should be able to construct an example of a CR submanifold N of the <lb/>hyperquadric which fails to be two-sided embeddable at all of its points, perhaps by using a <lb/>method analogous to that of Lewy [20]. However, it is not known whether such a construction is <lb/>possible. <lb/> 4. The relative extension theorem <lb/> Lemma 4.1. Suppose that N is an abstract CR manifold of dimension 2k − 1. Suppose also that <lb/>there exists a CR embedding Φ : N → C  n . Then, there exists locally a CR embedding Ψ : N → C  k and a <lb/>holomorphic submersion π : C  n  → C  k such that Ψ = π • Φ. <lb/> Proof. We work locally at a point of Φ(N), which we shall choose to be the origin of C  n  , by a <lb/>suitable translation. By the rank theorem, it is possible to choose coordinates <lb/> (ζ , z, w) ∈ C <lb/> n−k  × C × C <lb/> k−1  = C <lb/> n <lb/> such that Φ(N) may be written as a graph <lb/> Φ(N) = {(ζ , z, w) ∈ C <lb/> n  = C <lb/> n−k  × C × C <lb/> k−1  : ζ = G(x, w), y = g(x, w)} <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 7 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> (where z = x + iy) with G and g smooth functions defined on R × C  k−1  which vanish at the origin, <lb/>together with their first partials. (These last two statements are furnished by taking a suitable <lb/>affine change of the coordinates.) <lb/>Thus, we may define a hypersurface in C  k  , N  0 say, by <lb/> N  0  = {(z, w) ∈ C × C <lb/> k−1  : y = g(x, w)}. <lb/> Now, N may be written as a graph over N  0 in the obvious way, <lb/> p = (x + ig(x, w), w) → Ψ (p) = (G(x, w), x + ig(x, w), w). <lb/> Define the mapping π by π(ζ , z, w) = (z, w). Then, π |  Φ(N)  is the inverse of Ψ . But π itself is <lb/>holomorphic, so that Ψ and π |  Φ(N)  are CR isomorphisms onto their respective images. <lb/> Now suppose a given CR manifold Q is embedded as a hypersurface in C  n  with non-<lb/>degenerate Levi form of signature (k, l), with k ≥ 2, l ≥ 1, in a neighbourhood of a point x  0  ∈ Q. <lb/> Suppose also that we have a (2k − 1)-dimensional strictly pseudo-convex CR manifold N which <lb/>is CR embedded in Q, with x  0 lying in N. Then, lemma 4.2 holds: <lb/> Lemma 4.2. Near x  0 , N has a one-sided extension into C  n . The direction of the extension is the direction <lb/>of the concavity of N. <lb/>Proof. N is given as a CR submanifold of C  n  . As in lemma 4.1, we may choose a mapping π and <lb/>an embedding Ψ such that Ψ = π • Φ. In particular, there exist holomorphic coordinate functions <lb/> (z  1 , . . . , z n  ) on C  n  and (w  1 , . . . , w k  ) on C  k  with <lb/> z <lb/> i  = w <lb/> i  • π for i = 1, . . . , k. <lb/> Also, for i = k + 1, . . . , n, the functions z i  can be pulled through to define functions on Ψ (N). These <lb/>functions will be CR on Ψ (N), because the z i  are holomorphic. But, Ψ (N) is a strictly pseudo-<lb/>convex CR submanifold of C  k  near Ψ (x  0  ). Hence, by the Lewy extension theorem, each z i  , for <lb/> i = k + 1, . . . , n, extends to a holomorphic function on the side of the concavity of Ψ (N), say  <lb/>  i  . <lb/>Now z i  = ˜ <lb/> z i  defines a holomorphic graph in C  n  over the concave side of Ψ (N), which gives the <lb/>one-sided extension. <lb/> It should be remarked that the given local extension is unique (or at least its germ at a point <lb/>of N is unique), for if two extensions were given, then the difference of their graphing functions <lb/>must be zero on Φ(N), and thus identically zero everywhere by the Lewy extension theorem. <lb/> Theorem 4.3. N has a global one-sided extension. Furthermore, any two such extensions agree on <lb/>another possibly smaller extension. <lb/>Proof. N may be covered by a locally finite system {U  α  } of neighbourhoods, such that each <lb/> U  α  admits a one-sided extension (by the lemma). Because of the uniqueness of local one-sided <lb/>extensions, these local one-sided extensions must agree on the overlaps U  α  ∩ U  β  , and so patch <lb/>together to give a global extension. <lb/> The same set of arguments, only using the two-sided Lewy extension theorem, prove the <lb/>following. <lb/> Theorem 4.4. If N is Levi non-degenerate and indefinite (instead of pseudo-convex), then, near x  0 , N <lb/>has a two-sided extension into C  n . <lb/> 5. Twistor space <lb/> The purpose of this section is to review some standard facts about twistor space (in the flat <lb/>case), and to fix notation for later sections. More detailed accounts can be found in Penrose &amp; <lb/>Rindler [11] or Huggett &amp; Tod [21]. <lb/>Let T be a four-dimensional complex vector space (called twistor space) equipped with the <lb/>standard representation of SL(4, C). One of the basic constructions of twistor theory is to exploit <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 8 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> the isomorphism of SL(4, C) with Spin(6, C), the simply connected cover of the conformal group <lb/>in four dimensions in order to express data on Minkowski space in terms of data on twistor space <lb/>and vice versa. Concretely, the SL(4, C) structure on T is realized by fixing a non-zero element  ∈ <lb/> ∧  4  T  *  . This, in turn, defines a complex bilinear form on ∧  2  T via q(X, Y) = (X ∧ Y), thus realizing <lb/>the isomorphism SL(4, C) ∼ = Spin(6, C). In the projectivization, P(∧  2  T), the zero locus of q is none <lb/>other than the Klein quadric, and is identified with the Grassmannian of two-planes in T, Gr 2  (T). <lb/> The metric associated to q is degenerate on q = 0, but only in the complex scaling direction (along <lb/>which q is preserved up to scale). So q defines a complex conformal structure on Gr 2  (T). The <lb/>quadratic form q is conformally flat in any affine slice of the Klein quadric, so Gr 2  (T) is locally <lb/>conformally flat. In the setting of interest, Gr 2  (T) is called conformal compactified complexified <lb/>Minkowski space, and is denoted M  C  . <lb/>By definition of the quadratic form q, two points X, Y ∈ P(∧  2  T) are null-related if and only if <lb/> X ∧ Y = 0. In particular, two points of M  C  are null-related if and only if the corresponding two-<lb/>planes in T share a line in common. This incidence relation allows P(T) to be recovered from M  C <lb/> as one of the two (topologically distinct) sets of completely null two-planes in M  C  : the α-planes <lb/> are those whose annihilator at each point of M  C  is an anti-selfdual two-form on M  C  , and the <lb/> β-planes are those annihilated by a selfdual two-form. <lb/>The tautological bundle of Gr 2  (T) is the sub-bundle of T × Gr 2  (T) whose fibre over a point <lb/> x ∈ Gr 2  (T) is the two-plane in T defined by x. This bundle is denoted by ¯ <lb/> S  *  , and is called the <lb/>primed co-spin bundle. Let S be the quotient bundle of T × Gr 2  (T) by ¯ <lb/> S  *  . This is the spin bundle. <lb/>An essential fact is that the tangent bundle of M  C  is naturally identified with S ⊗ ¯ <lb/> S. Indeed, more <lb/>generally if Taut denotes the tautological bundle for the Grassmannian Gr  k  (C  n  ) and Taut <lb/> op is the <lb/>quotient (C  n  × Gr  k  (C  n  ))/Taut, then there is a natural isomorphism <lb/> TGr k  (C <lb/> n  ) ∼ = Hom(Taut, Taut <lb/> op  ). <lb/> Breaking the conformal invariance can be achieved by selecting a point I ∈ M  C  . Then the <lb/>metric, depending on X ∈ M  C  away from the null cone of I, given by g X  = q(dX, dX)/q(I, X)  2 is <lb/>flat. The stabilizer of I is the Poincaré group plus dilations (the semidirect product S(GL(2, C) × <lb/> GL(2, C)) C  4 ). <lb/>Real Minkowski space can also be described from the twistor point of view. Here, we introduce <lb/>a (2, 2) signature Hermitian form h on T that is compatible with the chosen SL(4, C) structure, <lb/>giving a reduction of the structure group to SU(2, 2). The idea is then to exploit the isomorphism <lb/>of SU(2, 2) with the spin group spin(2, 4) associated to the conformal group of a real Lorentzian <lb/>metric in four dimensions (via a 4 : 1 cover). To this end, let N be the null cone of h in T. The space <lb/>of complex two-planes lying in N, denoted M, is compactified real Minkowski space. Then, M is a <lb/>four-dimensional real submanifold of M  C  . The induced metric is real and Lorentzian, if the point <lb/> I is required to be on N and hence real. <lb/>The process of associating the real Minkowski space to the real quadric N is also reversible. <lb/>In the real case, the real hypersurface PN ⊂ PT is a CR manifold with Levi signature (1, 1). It can <lb/>be identified with the space of null geodesics in M. The projective spheres associated to the null <lb/>cones at each point in M each carry a canonical complex structure. The CR structure on PN is the <lb/>unique CR structure such that the image of each of these spheres under the null geodesic spray is <lb/>a holomorphic curve. The rest of the section is devoted to establishing this fact. <lb/> (a) Complex structure on the projective sphere <lb/> Let V be an oriented four-dimensional real vector space. Suppose that V is equipped with a time-<lb/>oriented Lorentzian structure whose future null cone is the set N  + ⊂ V. The sphere is the quotient <lb/>of N  +  (minus the vertex) by the multiplicative group of positive dilations. <lb/>Let H be the tangent vector field to N  +  that generates the positive dilations, and let H  ⊥  be the <lb/>orthogonal complement of the vector field H with respect to the Lorentzian structure on V. The <lb/>tangent bundle of the sphere is identified with sections of the quotient bundle E = H  ⊥  /span(H) <lb/> that are homogeneous of degree zero. The exterior product with H defines an isomorphism of <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote"> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></note>

			<page> 9 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> E with the two-dimensional space H ∧ H  ⊥  . The duality operator  preserves this subspace, and <lb/>satisfies  2  = −Id. This gives the sphere its complex structure. In particular, E ⊗ C splits into a <lb/>direct sum of a pair of one-dimensional eigenspaces M ⊕ ¯ <lb/> M of eigenvalues i and −i, respectively. <lb/>It is convenient to have a section of M in coordinates. Suppose that V carries linear coordinates <lb/> (v  0 , v  1 , v  2 , v  3  ) in terms of which the Lorentzian quadratic form is <lb/> (v <lb/> 0  ) <lb/> 2  − (v <lb/> 1  ) <lb/> 2  − (v <lb/> 2  ) <lb/> 2  − (v <lb/> 3  ) <lb/> 2 , <lb/>(5.1) <lb/>and the metric is therefore g  V  = (dv  0  )  2  − (dv  1  )  2  − (dv  2  )  2  − (dv  3  )  2 . Then, modulo H and up to an <lb/>overall scaling, a section of M has the form <lb/> M = <lb/> v <lb/> 2  ∂ <lb/>∂v  1  − v <lb/> 1  ∂ <lb/>∂v  2 <lb/> + i <lb/> v <lb/> 3  ∂ <lb/>∂v  0  + v <lb/> 0  ∂ <lb/>∂v  3 <lb/> . <lb/>(5.2) <lb/> (b) The tangent bundle and null geodesic spray <lb/> Let M be a four-dimensional manifold and TM   its tangent bundle with the zero section deleted. <lb/>Let π : TM  → M be the projection map. Local coordinates x i  defined on M induce fibre coordinates <lb/> v  i  on TM   defined by writing a vector field X in terms of the partials ∂/∂x  i  : X = v  i  (X)(∂/∂x  i  ). The <lb/>double tangent bundle TTM   is a bundle over TM   with a local basis of 2n vector fields ∂/∂x  i  , ∂/∂v  i  . <lb/>The vertical subspace of TTM   , denoted by VTM   , is the kernel of dπ : TTM  → TM   . This is locally <lb/>spanned by the vector fields ∂/∂v  i  . <lb/>There is a canonical diffeomorphism-invariant endomorphism λ : TTM  → TTM   of the double <lb/>tangent bundle that is the generator of translations in the fibres of TM. It is given in these local <lb/>coordinates by λ = dx  i  ⊗ ∂/∂v  i  . Note that the image and kernel of λ are both VTM   . In particular <lb/> λ  2  = 0. The endomorphism λ allows us to define differentiation up the vertical direction. To wit, if <lb/> X ∈ TTM   and f is a function on TM   , then define D X f = L  λX  f . The other relevant diffeomorphism-<lb/>invariant structure on TM   is the Euler vector field H, which is the generator of scaling in the fibres. <lb/>In local coordinates H = v  i  ∂/∂v  i  . <lb/>Suppose now that M is equipped with a Lorentzian metric g. This defines a quadratic form G <lb/> on TM   . The zero locus of G, denoted by N , is the fibration of null cones. The one-form α defined <lb/>by α(X) = D X G is a symplectic potential on TM   . The geodesic spray is the Hamiltonian vector <lb/>field V defined by Vdα = dG. Note that λV = H. The integral curves of V project to affinely <lb/>parametrized geodesics on M. Because V is everywhere tangent to N , geodesics that start on N <lb/> must stay on N . These are the null geodesics, and the restriction of V to N is the null geodesic <lb/>spray. <lb/>Because the integral curves of V are geodesics, in local coordinates we have <lb/> V = v <lb/> k  ∂ <lb/>∂x  k  − Γ <lb/> k <lb/>ij  v <lb/> i  v <lb/> j  ∂ <lb/>∂v  k  , <lb/>(5.3) <lb/>where Γ  k <lb/>ij  are the Christoffel symbols of the metric on M. <lb/> (c) Twistor space <lb/> Assume that M is also oriented. Twistor space PN is the space of (unparametrized) null geodesics <lb/>in M, which is the quotient of N by the two-parameter group of diffeomorphisms generated by <lb/>the null geodesic spray V and Euler vector field H. Let M be the complex line bundle of vertical <lb/>vector fields on PN that gives the complex structure on each of its fibres. Let M be given by <lb/>(5.2) in local coordinates. If M is conformally flat, then the complex vector fields M, [V, M] are in <lb/>involution with V and H, and therefore descend to a CR structure on the quotient. Involutivity <lb/>follows at once by using a local coordinate chart in which the metric has the form (5.1), and <lb/>applying (5.3) and (5.2). <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 10 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> (d) The connection and horizontal vectors <lb/> The Levi–Civita connection associated to the metric g on M allows us to lift any C  1 curve in M <lb/> through a point to a C  1 curve γ (t) through any point X ∈ TTM   in the fibre over x for small time, by <lb/>parallel translation of X along γ . This is the horizontal lift of the curve to the tangent bundle. The <lb/>tangent vector to the lifted curve is a vector in TTM   , and is called a horizontal vector. A vector is <lb/>horizontal if and only if it is in the kernel of the operator P : TTM  → VTM   given by <lb/> P = (dv <lb/> k  + dx <lb/> i  Γ <lb/> k <lb/>ij  v <lb/> j  ) ⊗ <lb/> ∂ <lb/>∂v  k  . <lb/>Invariantly, P = <lb/> 1 <lb/>2  (Id  TTM  + L  V  λ). The space of horizontal vectors H = ker P is a complementary <lb/>subspace to VTM   in TTM   . The operator P has image VTM   and satisfies P  2  = P, and so is <lb/>the projection operator P : TTM  → VTM   associated to this splitting. Note in particular that the <lb/>dynamical vector field V is horizontal. <lb/> (e) Umbral bundle <lb/> We describe here a vector bundle, known as the umbral bundle [22], on N that is needed to develop <lb/>the theory of shear-free congruences. The pullback bundle π  −1  TM ∼ = TN /VN is isomorphic via <lb/>Id − P to the bundle H of horizontal vectors. The metric g on M lifts to a metric in the pullback <lb/>bundle, and so defines a metric on horizontal vectors denoted by g  H  . Along N , V is a null <lb/>vector with respect to g  H  , and so V lies in its own orthogonal complement V  ⊥ ⊂ H. Define <lb/>the umbral bundle to be the vector bundle E = V  ⊥  /span(V). The bundle H ∼ = π  −1  TM inherits <lb/>an orientation from M. The metric and orientation define a duality operator on ∧  2  H which <lb/>preserves the subspace V ∧ E. Select a horizontal complex vector field M   in V  ⊥ ⊗ C such that <lb/> (V ∧ M   ) = −i(V ∧ M   ). This vector field is defined uniquely up to an overall factor, and modulo <lb/>multiples of V. <lb/> Lemma 5.1. M  ≡ 0 (mod V, [V, M]). <lb/>Proof. Modulo vertical directions, the identity M  = −[V, λM   ] holds. However, λM   is a vertical <lb/>vector such that H ∧ λM   is anti-selfdual, and therefore λM   is a representative of a section of M. <lb/> Thus, λM  = aH + bM for some scalars a and b. Taking Lie brackets with V, using the fact that <lb/>[H, V] = V, and projecting out the vertical directions establishes the lemma. <lb/> (f) Null geodesic congruences <lb/> A null geodesic congruence is a non-vanishing null geodesic vector field k throughout a region of <lb/>space–time. Equivalently, this is a smooth (local) section s k  : M → N of the null cone bundle over <lb/> M whose image is foliated by the null geodesic spray. The pullback of the umbral bundle <lb/>associated along s k  is the bundle of two-planes k  ⊥  /span(k) consisting of vectors orthogonal to <lb/> k, modulo multiples of k itself [22]. Note that the metric descends to a negative definite form in <lb/> k  ⊥  /span(k). <lb/> The umbral bundle associated to s k  carries a natural complex structure. Wedging with k gives <lb/>a natural linear isomorphism k  ⊥  /k ∼ = k ∧ k  ⊥  . The duality operator preserves k ∧ k  ⊥  , because the <lb/>orthogonal complement of k ∧ k  ⊥  is ∧  2  k  ⊥ + k ∧ TM and this also annihilates k ∧ k  ⊥  under the <lb/>wedge product. Because  2  = −1, the eigenspaces of  define a complex structure on k ∧ k  ⊥  and <lb/>therefore also on k  ⊥  /k. Let m be a null section of k  ⊥ ⊗ C such that the co-set of m modulo k <lb/> is an element of the +i eigenspace of the star operator, scaled so that g(m, ¯ <lb/> m) = −1. Now, there <lb/>exists a unique null vector field n such that g(m, n) = 0, g(k, n) = 1. The quadruple of null vectors <lb/> (k, n, m, ¯ <lb/> m) is a null tetrad. <lb/> The distortion tensor ∇  a k b  descends to a bilinear form on k  ⊥  /k. The trace-free symmetric part <lb/>is called the shear of the congruence. The skew part is called the rotation. <lb/> A shear-free congruence k is called regular in an open set U ⊂ M if the image N of U in PN <lb/> under the natural projection along k is a three-dimensional smooth submanifold, and the natural <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 11 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> projection is a submersion of U onto N. The following theorem is well known in the analytic <lb/>category, going back at least to the work of Sommers [5]. See, for instance, references [9,11,23]. <lb/> Theorem 5.2. A regular shear-free null geodesic congruence in an open set U ⊂ M defines an embedded <lb/>CR submanifold N of PN. The Levi form of this CR manifold is non-degenerate if and only if the rotation <lb/>of the congruence is non-zero. <lb/>Proof. Complete the vector k to a null tetrad basis k, n, m, ¯ <lb/> m such that the only non-vanishing <lb/>inner products are k · n = n · k = −m · ¯ <lb/> m = − ¯ <lb/> m · m = 1 and with k ∧ m, n ∧ ¯ <lb/> m and k ∧ n − m ∧ ¯ <lb/> m all <lb/>anti-selfdual and k ∧ ¯ <lb/> m, n ∧ m and k ∧ n + m ∧ ¯ <lb/> m all selfdual. In terms of the basis, the shear and <lb/>rotation are the scalars <lb/> σ = (L  k g)(m, m) = −2g([k, m], m) <lb/> ρ = idk <lb/>  (m, ¯ <lb/> m) = ig([m, ¯ <lb/> m], k). <lb/> (Here, the notation k   := g(k, −) means that the metric has been used to lower the index of the <lb/>vector field k.) <lb/> The vector field m descends up to scale to the three-dimensional space of geodesics that <lb/>form the congruence if and only if [k, m] ∧ k ∧ m = 0. Write [k, m] = g([k, m], k)n + g([k, m], n)k − <lb/> g([k, m], m) ¯ <lb/> m − g([k, m], ¯ <lb/> m)m. Because k is a null geodesic and m is orthogonal to k, it follows that <lb/> g([k, m], k) = 0. Hence, [k, m] ∧ k ∧ m = −g([k, m], m) ¯ <lb/> m ∧ k ∧ m. Thus, k is shear free if and only if <lb/> m descends to a complex direction field on the quotient space. This generates a CR structure. <lb/>The Levi form of the CR structure is given by i[m, ¯ <lb/> m] (mod k, m, ¯ <lb/> m). Writing [m, ¯ <lb/> m] in the tetrad, <lb/>the Levi form is ig([m, ¯ <lb/> m], k) = ρ, the rotation of the congruence. <lb/>It remains to show that the CR structure of a shear-free congruence is compatible with the CR <lb/>structure on twistor space. The null vector field k defines a section s : M → N of the null cone <lb/>bundle. The null geodesic spray is tangent to this section, because k is a geodesic, and s  *  k = V. <lb/> The vector s  *  m is in V  ⊥  , and satisfies (V ∧ s  *  m) = −i(V ∧ s  *  m). Because this property also <lb/>characterizes M   , s  *  m ≡ 0 (mod VTM, V, H, M   ). It is therefore sufficient to show that Ps  *  m ≡ 0 <lb/> (mod H, M). It is shown in Holland &amp; Sparling [22] that Ps  *  m = λs  *  (m  a  ∇  a k). This is a linear <lb/>combination of H = λs  *  k and M = λs  *  m if and only if m a  ∇  a k is a linear combination of k and m, if <lb/>and only if k is shear free. <lb/> The converse is also true in the rotating case. Let π  1 : PN → PN be the quotient by the <lb/>null geodesic spray, and π  2 : PN → M be the natural projection onto Minkowksi space. The <lb/>null geodesic in M associated to each point L ∈ N is the subset π  2  (π <lb/> −1 <lb/> 1  (L)) ⊂ M. <lb/> Theorem 5.3. Let N be a pseudo-convex CR submanifold of PN. For each L ∈ N and each point p ∈ <lb/> π <lb/> −1 <lb/> 1  (L), there is an open neighbourhood U ⊂ M of π  2  (p) and V ⊂ PN of L such that the null geodesics in <lb/>V ∩ N define a regular rotating shear-free congruence in U. <lb/>Proof. It is sufficient to prove that the restriction of π  2 to π <lb/> −1 <lb/> 1  N is a submersion, as the statement <lb/>of the theorem then follows by an application of the inverse function theorem. Let k be the <lb/>restriction of the null geodesic spray V to the fibres of π  1 over N and let X be a complex vector <lb/>field in a neighbourhood of p that commutes with k such that (π  1  )  *  X is a non-vanishing local <lb/>section of T  1,0  N. We claim that π  2 *  k, π  2 *  X, π  2 *  ¯ <lb/> X, π  2 *  [X, ¯ <lb/> X] are linearly independent. <lb/>Choose a complex vector field M on PN that is a representative of a non-vanishing section <lb/>of the line bundle M, and let M   be a section of the umbral bundle E. These can each be <lb/>chosen so that [M, ¯ <lb/> M] = 0. Because the Levi form of PN is non-degenerate, the six vector fields <lb/> M, ¯ <lb/> M, V, M   , M   , [M   , ¯ <lb/> M] form a basis of the tangent space of PN , and, in particular, the last four <lb/>of these must project down to a basis of the tangent space of M because the first two are in the <lb/>kernel of this projection. Because N is CR embedded into PN, and M and M   descend to a basis <lb/>of T  1,0  PN, X has the form X = αM + βM   . Because X commutes with k, β cannot vanish, and so <lb/> (π  2  )  *  X is a non-zero multiple of (π  2  )  *  M   . Likewise, (π  2  )  *  ¯ <lb/> X is a non-zero multiple of (π  2  )  *  M   . <lb/>Finally, because the Levi form of N is non-degenerate, [X, ¯ <lb/> X] is independent of V, M, ¯ <lb/> M, M   , M   , <lb/>and so has a non-trivial component in the direction of [ ¯ <lb/> M, M   ]. <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 12 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> 6. Non-analytic congruences <lb/> In this section, we prove the main result of this work: <lb/> Theorem 6.1. There exist non-analytic congruences of null geodesics whose shear vanishes, and whose <lb/>rotation is non-zero. <lb/> We need the following fact (attributed to Kerr in Penrose [7]) about the relationship between <lb/>the CR submanifold and the structure of the congruence: <lb/> Lemma 6.2. An embedded CR submanifold N ⊂ PN is the intersection of PN with a complex-analytic <lb/>submanifold of CP  3  if and only if the associated congruence is a real-analytic shear-free congruence of null <lb/>geodesics. <lb/>Proof. A real-analytic congruence is by definition a null geodesic whose tangent vector field <lb/> k is a real-analytic function of the coordinates of Minkowski space in some open set U in <lb/>the real Minkowski space. We may thus extend k to a complex-analytic null vector field on a <lb/>neighbourhood of U in the complexified Minkowski space. When k is descended to the leaves of <lb/>the twistor foliation, we obtain a complex-analytic submanifold of PT, as required. The converse <lb/>follows by reversing the line of argument. <lb/> Proof of theorem 6.1. By theorem 3.1, there exists an essentially one-sided embeddable CR <lb/>manifold N ⊂ PN with non-degenerate Levi form. Such a manifold is not the intersection of <lb/> PN with a complex analytic submanifold. Hence, by lemma 6.2, the shear-free congruence <lb/>associated to N is non-analytic, and by theorem 5.2 the rotation of the associated congruence <lb/>is non-vanishing. <lb/> 7. Null electromagnetic fields <lb/> A two-form F on an open set in M is a source-free (or homogeneous) electromagnetic field if the <lb/>following field equations hold: <lb/>dF = 0, d  F = 0, <lb/>where  is the duality operation associated to the metric. If we let G = F + i  F, then the equations <lb/>assume the simple form dG = 0, and because F is real, G determines F completely. In this language, <lb/>solutions of the homogeneous electromagnetic field equations correspond to complex two-forms <lb/> G that obey dG = 0 and which are anti-selfdual (G = −iG). We concentrate on the case where the <lb/>field tensor is null, i.e. <lb/> g  ∧  2  TM  (F, F) = g  ∧  2  TM  (F, F) = 0, <lb/>or in terms of G, g  ∧  2  TM  (G, G) = 0. A field G satisfying this equation is also called null. Thus, G is <lb/>null if and only if F is null. <lb/> Lemma 7.1. Let G be a non-zero complex anti-selfdual null two-form. Then, G = k   ∧ m   , where k and <lb/>m are mutually orthogonal null vectors with k real. If, in addition, G is closed, then k is tangent to a <lb/>shear-free null geodesic congruence. <lb/> A field G of the form G = k   ∧ m   , as in the lemma, is called adapted to k. Thus, G is adapted to <lb/> k if and only if the associated Maxwell field F is itself null and adapted to k. <lb/>Proof. Because G is anti-selfdual, g  ∧  2  TM  (G, G) = 0 implies that G ∧ G = 0, so G splits as an <lb/>exterior product G = u   ∧ v  for some (complex) linearly independent vectors u and v. Now, <lb/> u   ∧ G = 0, so again by self-duality uG = 0, and so u is null and orthogonal to v. Likewise, v <lb/> must also be null. Next, we claim that at any point where G is not zero there is a real vector k, <lb/> necessarily null, in the linear span of u and v. Because G is anti-selfdual, ¯ <lb/> G is anti-selfdual, so <lb/> G ∧ ¯ <lb/> G = 0, whence the claim. <lb/>Now suppose that dG = 0. It follows that L  k G = 0. Using the decomposition G = k   ∧ m   , this <lb/>implies (L  k k  ) ∧ m   ∧ k   = 0, or L  k k   ≡ 0 (mod k   , m  ). But, because L  k k   is real, this implies that <lb/> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></body>

			<page> 13 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> L  k  k   = αk  for some α. Now because k is null, L  k k   = k a  ∇  a k   . So k a  ∇  a k   = αk  . The constant α <lb/> can be absorbed by rescaling k (and so also rescaling m), so that k a  ∇  a k   = 0, and thus k is a null <lb/>geodesic. Finally, <lb/>0 = m <lb/>  ∧ L  m G = −k <lb/>  ∧ m <lb/>  ∧ m <lb/> a  ∇  a m <lb/>  . <lb/>Applying duality gives 0 = =k, m a  ∇  a m = σ/2. <lb/> 8. Local existence <lb/> The classical theorem on local existence of solutions of the null field equations for flat space–time <lb/>and analytic congruences is due to Robinson [1] and Sommers [5]: <lb/> Theorem 8.1. Let k be a vector field tangent to an analytic shear-free congruence of null geodesics. Then, <lb/>there exists locally a solution of the electromagnetic field equations F that is adapted to k. The freedom in <lb/>the solution is described by a holomorphic function of two complex variables. <lb/> We may drop the assumption of analyticity of the congruence, provided that we assume that <lb/>the congruence is rotating throughout its domain. Let k be a shear-free congruence. Assume that <lb/>the domain of k is restricted to an open region such that the CR manifold N ⊆ PN and quotient <lb/>mapping π from the domain of the congruence to N are smooth, as in §5f. <lb/> Lemma 8.2. Let k be a shear-free congruence. Let G be a anti-selfdual non-vanishing two-form. The <lb/>following conditions are equivalent: <lb/>1. There is a ¯ <lb/> ∂  b -closed (2, 0) form H on N such that G = π  *  H. <lb/>2. G is a null solution of the electromagnetic field equation and is adapted to k. <lb/>Proof. Locally, N is the quotient of an open set U in M by the leaves of the foliation defined by <lb/> k via a submersion φ : U → N. <lb/> Suppose that H is a given ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  -closed (2, 0) form on N, and let G = φ  *  H. If H is closed, then so is <lb/> G. Recall the definition of ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  : Q  2,0  → Q  2,1 where <lb/> Q <lb/> 2,0  = Ω <lb/> 1,0  ∧ Ω <lb/> 1,0 and Q <lb/> 2,1  = <lb/> Ω  1,0  ∧ Ω  1,0  ∧ Ω  1 <lb/> Ω  1,0  ∧ Ω  1,0  ∧ Ω  1,0 . <lb/>The operator ¯ <lb/> ∂  b  is the induced mapping of d on the indicated quotient spaces. However, in the <lb/>above expression for Q  2,1 , the space Ω  1,0 is two dimensional, and so its triple exterior product <lb/>vanishes. Thus <lb/> Q <lb/> 2,1  = Ω <lb/> 1,0  ∧ Ω <lb/> 1,0  ∧ Ω <lb/> 1 and d <lb/> 2,0  = ¯ <lb/> ∂ <lb/> 2,0 <lb/> b  . <lb/>Hence, dH = 0. So it follows that G = φ  *  H is closed. Now k   and m   descend to a basis of Ω  1,0 , so <lb/> G must have the form μk  ∧ m   . So condition 1 implies condition 2. <lb/>Conversely, if G = μk  ∧ m   is a closed form, then L  k G = i k G = 0, and therefore G descends to <lb/>a closed (2, 0)-form H on N. <lb/> Assume now that k is rotating. Then, N is strictly pseudo-convex, and so there is a one-sided <lb/>holomorphic extension Z. Now consider the sheaf of ¯ <lb/> ∂-closed (2, 0)-forms on Z which are C  ∞  up <lb/>to the boundary N. Any section of this sheaf in a neighbourhood of a point on N will induce a <lb/>local solution of the electromagnetic field equations on N. Because Z can be locally embedded <lb/>into C  2 , any local holomorphic section of the canonical line bundle of C  2 will induce a section <lb/>of the aforementioned sheaf by restriction, and thus a local solution of the electromagnetic field <lb/>equations which is null with respect to k a  . <lb/>If now G  1 and G  2 are two non-zero null anti-selfdual electromagnetic fields adapted to k, <lb/> then the associated (2, 0)-forms H  1 and H  2 on N satisfy H  2  = fH  1 for some CR function f on N. <lb/> By Lewy&apos;s extension theorem, f can be extended on one side to a holomorphic function on the <lb/>complex surface Z whose boundary is N. <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote"> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from <lb/></note>

			<page> 14 <lb/></page>

			<body> rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org  Proc R Soc A 469: 2012.0583 <lb/> .  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . <lb/> To summarize, we have: <lb/> Theorem 8.3. If k is a shear-free rotating congruence, then there exists locally a solution of the <lb/>electromagnetic field equations which is null with respect to k. The freedom in the solution is described <lb/>by the boundary value of a holomorphic function of two variables. A global solution exists if and only if <lb/>there exists a global ¯ <lb/> ∂  b -closed (2, 0)-form on the CR manifold N associated with the congruence. <lb/> The authors gratefully acknowledge the many helpful improvements suggested by the referees. <lb/></body>

			<listBibl> References <lb/> 1. Robinson I. 1961 Null electromagnetic fields. J. Math. Phys. 2, 290–291. (doi:10.1063/1.1703712) <lb/>2. Robinson I, Trautman A. 1960 Spherical gravitational waves. Phys. Rev. Lett. 4, 431–432. <lb/>(doi:10.1103/PhysRevLett.4.431) <lb/>3. Robinson I, Trautman A. 1962 Some spherical gravitational waves in general relativity. Proc. <lb/>R. Soc. Lond. A 265, 463–473. (doi:10.1098/rspa.1962.0036) <lb/>4. Kerr RP, Schild A. 1965 Some algebraically degenerate solutions of Einstein&apos;s gravitational <lb/>field equations. In Applications of Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations in Mathematical Physics <lb/> (ed. R Finn), pp. 199–209. Proceedings of Symposia in Applied Mathematics, vol. XVII. <lb/>Providence, RI: American Mathematical Society. <lb/>5. Sommers P. 1976 Properties of shear-free congruences of null geodesics. Proc. R. Soc. Lond. A <lb/> 349, 309–318. (doi:10.1098/rspa.1976.0075) <lb/>6. Trautman A. 1999 On complex structures in physics. In On Einstein&apos;s path (ed. A Harvey), <lb/>pp. 487–501. New York, NY: Springer. <lb/>7. Penrose R. 1967 Twistor algebra. J. Math. Phys. 8, 345–366. (doi:10.1063/1.1705200) <lb/>8. Jacobowitz H, Trèves F. 1982 Nonrealizable CR structures. Invent. Math. 66, 231–249. <lb/>(doi:10.1007/BF01389393) <lb/>9. Lewandowski J, Nurowski P, Tafel J. 1990 Einstein&apos;s equations and realizability of CR <lb/>manifolds. Class. Quantum Grav. 7, L241. (doi:10.1088/0264-9381/7/11/003) <lb/>10. Penrose R. 1983 Physical space-time and nonrealizable CR-structures. Bull. Amer. Math. Soc. <lb/> (N.S.) 8, 427–448. <lb/>11. Penrose R, Rindler W. 1988 Spinors and space-time, vol. 2. Cambridge Monographs on <lb/>Mathematical Physics, 2nd edn. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press. <lb/>12. Adamo TM, Newman ET, Kozameh C. 2012 Null geodesic congruences, <lb/>asymptotically-flat spacetimes and their physical interpretation. Living Rev. Relativ. 15. <lb/> (http://arxiv.org/abs/0906.2155) <lb/>13. Baird P, Eastwood M. 2010 CR geometry and conformal foliations. (http://arxiv.org/ <lb/>abs/1011.4717). <lb/>14. Tafel J. 1985 On the Robinson theorem and shearfree geodesic null congruences. Lett. Math. <lb/>Phys. 10, 33–39. (doi:10.1007/BF00704584) <lb/>15. Lewandowski J, Nurowski P. 1990 Algebraically special twisting gravitational fields and CR <lb/>structures. Class. Quantum Grav. 7, 309–328. (doi:10.1088/0264-9381/7/3/007) <lb/>16. Lewandowski J, Nurowski P, Tafel J. 1991 Pure radiation field solutions of the Einstein <lb/>equations. Class. Quantum Grav. 8, L83. (doi:10.1088/0264-9381/8/4/003) <lb/>17. Hill CD, Nacinovich M. 2000 A weak pseudoconcavity condition for abstract almost CR <lb/>manifolds. Invent. Math. 142, 251–283. (doi:10.1007/s002220000089) <lb/>18. Hill CD. 1988 What is the notion of a complex manifold with a smooth boundary? In Algebraic <lb/>analysis, vol. I (eds M Kashiwara, T Kawai), pp. 185–201. Boston, MA: Academic Press. <lb/>19. Lewy H. 1956 On the local character of the solutions of an atypical linear differential equation <lb/>in three variables and a related theorem for regular functions of two complex variables. Ann. <lb/>Math. 64, 514–522. (doi:10.2307/1969599) <lb/>20. Lewy H. 1957 An example of a smooth linear partial differential equation without solution. <lb/> Ann. Math. 66, 155–158. (doi:10.2307/1970121) <lb/>21. Huggett SA, Tod KP. 1994 An introduction to twistor theory, vol. 4. London Mathematical Society <lb/>Student Texts, 2nd edn. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press. <lb/>22. Holland J, Sparling G. 2011 Causal geometries, null geodesics, and gravity. (http://arxiv.org/ <lb/>abs/1106.5254). <lb/>23. Adamo TM, Newman ET. 2010 The real meaning of complex Minkowski-space world-lines. <lb/> Class. Quantum Grav. 27, 075009. (doi:10.1088/0264-9381/27/7/075009) <lb/></listBibl>

			<note place="footnote"> on April 13, 2015 <lb/>http://rspa.royalsocietypublishing.org/ <lb/>Downloaded from </note>


	</text>
</tei>
